Check, please.
Look, Daddy, a volcano.
It's very pretty.
Now drink up your volcano.
All right. We're going. Mommy's waiting.
Daddy, please. Just one more minute.
- No. We're going.
- No.
- Yes. Yes.
No.
Until I ended up
flatlining at the hospital.
But I survived. And instead of
letting that scare me,
I kept on going.
Until...
my first daughter was born.
And now, I look at my girls...
and my husband,
who has been standing by me for so long.
Think which one you're going to pull out.
- I always think, man.
- No, you don't.
They didn't lock you up this time
because you're not 18 yet.
Next time, they're going to
lock you up, brother.
Come on.
Well, you're not thinking.
Stealing might get you money,
you can tap
some cheerleader's ass,
you can show off riding
in some pickle-colored Thunderbird,
but tell me what's going to happen
if you shoot a pregnant woman
or an old man, huh?
You know what'll happen?
The guilt will suck you down to the bone.
Stealing isn't worth it.
Going to church, reading the Bible...
and believing in Jesus, brother,
that's your ticket.
Yeah.
You think it's a fantasy, right?
Huh?
Come here, man. Get up. Come here.
See that truck? Beauty, isn't it?
I won it at a friend's raffle.
- No shit.
- No shit. You know what?
It wasn't luck. It was Jesus who wanted
me to have that truck.
That's bullshit. I bet you stole it.
Jesus gave me that truck.
And as He who gives
and He who takes away.
Yeah, right.
He doesn't give a shit about us.
Come back. Come back.
Take off the hat.
Take off that hat.
God even knows when a single hair moves
on your head.
You're wrong, Nick.
So, this is death's waiting room.
These ridiculous tubes.
These needles swelling my arms.
What am I doing in this pre-corpse club?
What do I have to do with them?
I don't know when
anything began anymore...
or when it's going to end.
Who will be the first to lose his life?
He, in the coma?
Or me?
All right. You can get dressed now.
Your Fallopian tubes
are severely damaged.
It, uh, looks like you had
some kind of an infection...
that, uh, wasn't taken care of properly.
We can try surgery,
but I have to tell you, I think, uh,
the probabilities are pretty slim.
Look.
Excuse me for asking this, but it's
important that you tell me the truth.
Have you ever had an abortion?
- Yes.
- Any reason?
I had already separated from my husband
when I got pregnant,
- and I...
- No. I meant a medical reason.
- My husband's dying.
- I'm sorry?
Paul, my husband, he's dying,
and I want to have his baby.
We can operate then and hope you get
pregnant within three or four months.
He's got one month left, at most.
- How'd it go?
- Not good, Reverend.
In one ear, out the other.
- Be patient.
- All it takes is one sheep
in a thousand, Jack. Come on.
Afternoon, Reverend.
Hey, Wolf, you still having
that birthday party Wednesday?
- My place, brother.
- Cool.
I may be late, Jack.
I have Bible class on Wednesday.
- Let it go.
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
Here, hold this.
- I will hurt you, boy.
- Paul. Paul!
- ... Motherfucking dead!
Back off. Back off.
- I told you to think.
- Fuck you!
- Hit me. Hit me. Hit me, eh?
- Jack! Jack! Jack! Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey, Jack!
Come on! Come on!
Leave it, Jack. He's a kid, Jack.
- He's a punk, Reverend.
- No, he's a kid.
You think, Jack. You think.
'For those who are making decisions
that affect our life,
... we must call out to God
to give them His wisdom...'
Daddy's home. I'll see you tomorrow, Tam.
I'll pick the boys up after school
if you want me to.
Daddy!
- Hello.
- Hey, babe.
How's my queen?
- And Hercules?
- You don't have a queen.
Freddy, help me out.
- I got the cooler
from the religious center.
- Good.
- Dad, are we going to go buy a dog now?
- Help me out.
Freddy, we agreed no dogs.
Grab the other handle. Lift it up.
You said if I got good grades,
you'd buy me one.
Your sister has allergies,
and dog hair is bad for her.
Bad for her, not me. Get me a dog.
- Freddy, leave it alone.
- Well, at least get me a hamster.
- Well, we'll see.
- We'll see.
You always say you promise.
Hey, Wolf. You back, motherfucker?
Lock down six!
Six down!
Whoo! I win.
Age before beauty.
You're such a sore loser.
- Do you want to go to the Jacuzzi
for a while?
- Shit.
No, I can't. Michael and the girls
are waiting for me already.
Okay.
Well, call me later.
I'll call you.
Cristina?
And you get away from leading
your family like a man of God...
ought to lead his family in prayer...
and reading the word of God
and the things of God...
- and bringing them to the house of God,
- Amen.
Then you're opening the door for the
devil to come in and slay your family.
- Amen.
- Jesus is our light.
- Jesus is our hope.
- Jesus is our forgiveness.
Jesus is our forgiveness.
Jesus is the water
that quenches my thirst.
If you're saved
and you know it, say "Amen."
- Amen.
- Everybody up on your feet.
- Jesus is our light.
Hey, honey, I'm home.
- Hi.
- Jesus, you scared me.
- How are you feeling?
- I feel great.
Have you been smoking again?
Oh, for fuck's sake, Paul.
You know if they find out
you're smoking, they'll take you
off the transplant list.
If I don't smoke, I'll go fucking nuts.
Better nuts than dead.
Is that necessary?
I don't know how the hell you get them.
Baby! Baby! Baby! Baby!
Baby! Oh, God!
Call an ambulance!
Baby!
Call a fucking ambulance! Goddamn it!
Please, do something.
Baby!
Come on, please.
Hey, Al, you want a Coke?
Jack, boss wants to talk to you.
He wants to see you now.
Come on. We both know
I'm not a caddie yet,
but I'm working at it.
And I'm learning, Brown.
Man, I swear to God,
I'm not going to let you down.
- No, Jack, that's not the problem.
- What's the problem?
The problem is some members have started
complaining about your tattoos.
- I got a long-sleeved shirt.
- No, man... No long-sleeved shirt...
- You can't see it.
- Is going to cover that one
on your neck right there.
You're going to start wearing a scarf.
Look, Jack. This club is for people
different from me and you.
No. You know, I don't drink.
I don't steal.
I'm clean. Tell me, why me?
Look, I know you're clean.
That's why I hired you.
But this decision
comes from the administration.
And if I don't follow through,
they're going to fuck me too.
Look, I cut you a hefty severance check,
and you can pick it up
on the way to the cashier's.
Try to understand.
Okay. Good. So, is there any pain?
My head hurts a little bit.
That's normal. That's because of the
blood pressure medicine.
We'll get you something else
to make you feel better.
- Thank you.
- I brought...
- ...what you asked for.
- Oh, my God.
Oh. Is that my heart?
The culprit.
Which one is he?
That's him with the brown vest.
He's putting the bag up on top right now.
You okay?
Come here.
I want to kill him.
We have to kill him.
Thank you, Lord, for keeping us together,
for filling us with love
and for giving us this meal.
- Amen.
I got fired from the club today.
Because of your good pal Brown, right?
- He had nothing to do with it.
- It's mine!
- You believe that, Jack?
- Yes, I do.
- Ow!
- Freddy, stop it.
- Mommy, Freddy hit me in the arm.
- Which arm, baby?
- This one.
- Jack, don't start.
Hold out your other arm
and let your brother hit you.
- Give me it!
- Jack, no!
Hold it out.
Whoever slaps you on the right cheek,
turn the other to him also.
Hit her. Don't be afraid.
- Jack, no!
- Hit her!
Isn't that great. Wonderful.
Great parenting, Jack.
Good job. It's okay. Shh.
He didn't hurt her.
There's no hitting in this house.
You understand?
Get in the corner!
Do I put the chocolate chips
in now, Mommy?
That's right, honey, and then stir.
Stir really quick.
Laura, put that back. Come on.
- When is Daddy coming?
- Soon. Now let's
get this finished, honey.
- Mmm!
- None for you.
Mmm!
No, Laura, stop it now.
Next Friday, ask Lupe to stay the night.
I can't stay, because I invited the
company managers over for dinner.
I fired her.
What, you fired her? Why?
She made me feel like a cripple.
Oh, goddamn it, Paul.
So, now who's going to cook for you?
Who's going to clean up after you?
Who's going to take care of you?
Who?
I can do it for myself.
Oh, you can do it by yourself?
I can't do it anymore, Paul.
Really, I can't.
What are you doing?
I'm just... What?
What does it feel like I'm doing?
Don't. Don't. You might hurt yourself.
I'm not going to hurt myself.
Besides, I need you to...
- Huh?
- I went to a fertility clinic.
Oh good, more doctors. Mary, I can't
have this discussion again.
No, this is a... this is a specialist.
He said that with surgery,
I might get pregnant.
- You need to donate sperm and then...
- Mary, no.
I could take care of him.
But I can't. So what's the point?
This is what I most want in the world.
Do it for me, please.
This'll be $58.95.
Thank you.
Did you find everything you need, sir?
I'll have, uh...
Oh, you know what? I left my wallet.
It's going to be hot.
Great.
When does my brother plan to show up?
He said he'll be back by six.
One hundred percent pure golden lager.
Are you out of your mind?
- Pretty much.
- Oh, it's warm.
- Okay, well, hey, if you want to
drink lemonade all night...
- No, no, no, no.
Just give it here. Give me...
Katie? Laura?
Where are you guys?
"To repeat the message, press one.
To delete it..."
Hi, sweetheart, it's Dad. I was hoping
we could have lunch one day next week.
Give me a call.
Hi, honey. I'm on my way home.
- If you need me to pick up
anything along the way...
- Look, Daddy, a pigeon!
Girls, no, don't touch. Laura, stop it.
Give me a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
To send a message, press...
Hello.
Speaking.
What?
Where?
Stay here. I'll be right back.
Now, Mary, you understand that even if
the operation is successful,
artificial insemination
doesn't always work.
It doesn't matter. We want to try.
Paul?
Yeah.
Now, Paul, um...
This is about having a child
And with your condition,
you know you probably
won't ever meet him.
Mm-hmm. Well, life goes on, right?
Yeah, right.
I'd like you to put on one of these
gloves to avoid contaminating the sample.
And, uh, try to make it
all land in the receptacle.
When you're done, just leave it in here.
In case you need a little inspiration.
Hey, big boy, what are you doing?
- Oh, yeah, you ready to party?
- Yeah, well, I'm here now.
Oh, yeah! Yeah!
Oh, there you go!
Good, come on. Come on!
Dr. Swann, call the operator.
Excuse me. My husband and daughters
were in an accident,
- ...and I was told to come here.
- What were their names?
Michael, Catherine and Laura Peck.
Okay.
Excuse me for a minute.
- Cris?
- What happened, sweetheart?
I don't know.
They haven't told me anything yet.
- It's going to be all right.
- Yeah, everything will be okay.
Don't worry.
Okay, what is the most important
question for safe sex?
What time does your husband get home?
That's good, huh? Yeah.
His Highness has arrived.
Let's see what he comes up with.
Serve up that chili.
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
It's 7:00. What are you going
to make up this time... traffic?
You preaching the word? The entire
congregation has been waiting for you.
It's your party, remember?What's wrong?
Have you been drinking?
- No.
- You didn't drink again, did you?
I just ran over a man and two girls.
You're lying, right?
I was driving home...
Took a turn...
a little too quickly,
I didn't see them crossing.
Can't you go any faster?
Baby, hold on.
I love you.
Deep breath.
Good.
- Your lungs are clear.
- I got a question for you.
- Yeah.
- Whose heart do I have?
Uh, I can't tell you.
It's hospital regulations.
Just like the donor's family
doesn't know your name either.
- But you know.
- Yes.
This is your heart now. That's all that
should matter to you.
- I want to know who saved my life.
- If you want, you can write...
an anonymous letter to the family
through the donor's association.
Personally, I think it's better
that you don't know.
Mrs. Peck? I'm Dr. Jones.
- What happened to my family?
- Please, sit down.
No, I... I'm okay. What happened?
Well, your husband and your daughters
were hit by a car,...
... and we had to perform emergency
surgery on your husband.
Your husband suffered multiple
skull fractures,
and we had to remove blood clots
from around the brain.
He's in critical condition,
and we're concerned that he's
showing low brain activity.
What? Is he going to be all right?
We're doing the best we can.
And what about my daughters?
Your youngest daughter
was brought in with severe bleeding.
She just wasn't able to
get here in time.
I'm very sorry. They...
They both died in the accident.
No.
No. Oh, my... Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh, my God!
No! Oh, my God!
Do... Oh!
Wh... Where are they?
Where... Where are they?
Mrs. Peck, your girls are here, and you
can see them if you like, but...
- I want to see them.
- Mrs. Peck, I wouldn't recommend it.
Oh, God, Daddy. Oh, Daddy!
I'm very sorry. If you'll excuse us,
we have to get back to Mr. Peck.
Uh, I'm very sorry.
Oh, God! Oh!
We want dinner!
Marianne, we'd like some dinner in here!
Tell Reverend John to stay. Make sure no
one notices and get everyone to leave.
- What happened?
- Trish, just do what I tell you!
Okay, baby. It's going to be okay.
- It's going to be okay.
- Yeah.
Come on. Start the truck up.
Start the truck up.
Pull it in. Come on, baby.
Hey, Jack.
What are you doing here, man?
Just came to pick up my things, Brown.
Why don't you let me
buy you a couple of beers?
I don't drink, Brown.
How about a Diet Coke?
You know, I've been talking to a buddy
of mine about hooking you up with a job.
I've been telling him all about you.
So, what do you say, huh? I've been
feeling shitty about what went down.
- Come on.
- I understand.
So, what do you say?
As you know, the doctors did everything
they could to save your husband's life,
but he has shown no brain activity.
We're here to help you with some of the
final decisions that need to be made.
We have a patient...
...who is gravely ill.
I'm here to give you some information
on organ donation.
Are you willing for your husband to
donate his heart?
- Can we discuss this another time?
- I'm afraid not.
I can give you time to discuss it,
but this is a decision that needs to
be made soon.
Paul?
Paul, the beeper.
It's the hospital.
I think they've got a heart.
Hello? Yes, I'm calling on
behalf of Mr. Paul Rivers.
Yes.
Okay. Yes, I understand.
Where do I have to take him?
Good luck, my love.
Hello.
Does your shoulder bother you?
- Why?
- Because I was watching you swim before,
and you have a wide stroke.
If you bring it in tighter,
you get a better glide.
Thanks for the advice.
Do you mind if I join you?
- Actually, I was just leaving.
- Here you go.
Maybe just until you finish?
No. Maybe next time.
Did you know that eating alone can cause
kidney damage? And that's bad.
Well... Okay, sorry.
Hello?
Hello, is Ana there?
What?
- Is Ana there?
- Hang on a sec.
Ana. Ana!
Telephone.
Hello.
Hello?
Who was that?
Hi, honey, I'm on my way home.
If you need me to pick up anything
along the way, let me know.
Look, Daddy, a pigeon!
Girls, no, don't touch!
Laura, stop it.
Give me a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
Did you go?
Are they dead?
I'm going to turn myself in.
John says nobody saw you. Nobody.
They don't know the license plate
or what kind of car. Some asshole
even swears it was a cab.
Marianne, what would you do
if these were our children? Tell me.
But they're not. It didn't happen to us.
No, it didn't happen to us.
It happened to me.
What the fuck do you gain
by turning yourself in?
It's my duty, Marianne.
No, Jack, your duty is here with us.
With your family.
My duty's to God.
Please. Marianne,
Get out of my way.
Jack!
- Oh, buddy, right there!
- Yes!
My turn.
I think I better go back to the hospital.
- Hey, he deserves it.
- I thought your doctor said
you're not supposed to eat that.
I'm making up for lost time.
Lost time, not lost pounds.
We're going to have to
send you back for liposuction.
Well, here's to all those
who didn't think I was going to die.
Hear! Hear! Hear! Hear!
- To the first day of my new life.
- Congratulations.
- Cheers.
- It's good to have you home, man.
I knew you'd make it. I told you.
I also have an announcement to make.
I wanted to tell you that Paul and I
are going to be parents.
- That's great!
- There's a scary thought...
Paul being a parent.
- You kept this real quiet.
- Have you told your parents yet?
We're going to be parents.
We just don't know when yet.
I'm going to have an operation,
and then we're going to try
artificial insemination.
Terrific. Terrific.
Artificial insemination, huh?
Professor, do your female students know
you no longer have lead in your pencil?
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Oh! Come on!
Play nice!
Come on, let's pass the cake around.
Cut me a piece about half that size.
I can't wait to hear about this.
- Mr. Donneaud?
- Mr. Rivers?
Yeah.
Thanks for coming.
Sorry I couldn't cancel this
appointment, but the way I'm bowling
today, I probably should have.
Have a seat here. Park it right there.
Can I bring you something to eat?
- I'm not hungry.
- Honey, you need to eat something.
I'm fine, Dad.
When your mother died,
I thought I wasn't going to make it.
I felt the world was falling on me and
that I was never going to get up.
But, sweetie, life goes on.
You know what I thought when Mom died?
I couldn't understand
how you could talk to people again.
How you could laugh... again.
I couldn't understand
how you could play with us.
And no... no, that's a lie.
Life does not just go on.
Louise is getting fat, don't you think?
She's done nothing but eat
since Robert left her.
What? She looks okay to you?
Why did you tell everybody
we're having a baby?
I wanted to share our plans with them.
Oh. That's what I mean,
they're our plans.
Why does everyone have to
know our private life?
Why the fuss?
They're our best friends.
Yeah, but we haven't
even talked about it.
Oh, we haven't?
I thought this was more than settled.
Things change, Mary.
Something we have to think about.
I don't have anything to think about.
I've already made my decision.
Would you help me with the glasses?
So young.
You want me to stay with you tonight?
I'm okay. Thanks.
I just want to be alone.
Cris...
The police called.
They said you need to
go and press charges.
I'll go with you if you want.
I'm not going to do anything.
Y... This guy was... was some ex-con.
Are you really going to let him
just walk the streets?
What do you want me to do?
Well, he ran over
Michael and your daughters.
Nothing I can do
is going to bring them back.
Do you get that?
Hey, how are you doing?
- You found it okay?
- Yeah, I did.
The donor's name was Michael Peck.
He was 37 years old.
An architect and married.
This is the authorization
for transplant signed by
his wife, Cristina Williams Peck.
I have a copy of the medical report
if you care to see it.
And I also have the widow's
phone number and address
just in case you're interested.
How did Michael Peck die?
You might have seen it in the newspaper.
This guy named Jack Jordan ran over Mr.
Peck and his two little girls...
October 10th at 6:50 PM.
This Jack Jordan's a piece of work. He's
been in and out of jail since he was 16.
Car thief, small-time crook, drugs,
bad checks, alcoholism.
Last time he was in jail
has only been a few years ago.
You feeling okay, Mr. Rivers?
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
- Okay, I just, um...
- You want some water?
He was, uh, an architect.
What's the point in getting involved?
Mary, I want to know who I am now.
I don't think that's the way to do it.
What is then?
Look for it with me.
Let's look ahead together, not behind.
Damn it, Jack, it's your birthday and
you didn't even have one drink with me.
Why don't you come over to my place?
I'm having a party.
Yeah, I bet they're all
as boring as you are.
You'd be surprised. No, man, I'll pass.
Listen, I'll call you later
about that job, okay?
All right, man. All right.
Thank you.
Hey, Brown, you should.
I will.
Okay, now, we can schedule
the surgery, um,
I could get you in as early as Monday.
- Yeah.
- 9:00 AM.?
What's the percentage chance
that Mary will get pregnant?
Well, I can't offer you
a real number on that.
Um, you know, there's the damage
from the abortion...
that wasn't handled properly...
the blockage...
What abortion?
What abortion, Mary?
- I can explain.
- Explain what?
- There is an explanation.
- Uh-huh.
All that drama
about artificial insemination.
Kids' names.
You got pictures of our friends
babies all over the place.
Why?
So you can flush it
down the fucking toilet?
We've been a fraud for a long time, Mary.
Oh, yeah? Why didn't you tell me
that when you were sick, huh?
Or did you expect one of your girl-
friends to come and take care of you?
You came back because you wanted to.
Don't blame me for that.
I came back to take care of you
because I love you.
Or because you were feeling lonely.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I can't keep going like this.
The insemination, the child.
It's like we're trying to put a Band-Aid
on something that's just been bled dry.
It's finished.
But it... it isn't finished if we give
it a chance and have this baby.
When we could have, you didn't want to.
- We were separated, goddamn it!
- It's different now!
Yes, it's different.
- We going to go?
- You only know how to think about
yourself.
Close six!
Well, thanks for finally seeing me.
They tell me you don't want to eat.
I'm not hungry.
Jack... Jesus didn't come
to free us from pain.
He came to give us
the strength to bear it.
Maybe He wanted this pain for me.
No, He had nothing to do with this.
It was an accident.
No, it wasn't an accident.
Jesus chose me for this.
Jack...
Ask for the mercy of Jesus Christ.
If it was an accident,
why do I have to ask for His mercy?
"I will have mercy
on whom I will have mercy.
"I will have compassion
on whom I will have compassion.
- Don't be so prideful. That's a sin.
- "And the fearful and unbelieving.
- "And the abominable,
the murderers, the warmongers,
- Jack, listen to me.
"The sorcerers and the idolaters
and all liars...
- Jesus came to save us, not to damn us.
- "Shall have their part...
in the lake which burned
with fire and brimstone."
Revelation 21:8. Jesus, loves you.
But He also knows how to punish
arrogant sinners like you.
"As many as I love, I rebuke and chaste."
Revelation 3:19.
- Jesus betrayed me.
- Stop this shit, or you're
going straight to hell!
Hell?
This is hell. Right here!
You're damning your soul! You shut up now...
- ...and ask Christ to forgive you!
- Hey! Forgive me?
I did everything He asked me to do!
I changed!
I gave Him my life, and He betrayed me.
He put that fucking truck in my hands
so I could carry out His will.
Made me kill that man and those girls.
But hey, He didn't give me the strength
to stay and save them.
Don't blaspheme, you bastard!
Christ had nothing to do with this!
God even knows when a single hair moves
on your head.
And you taught me that.
We're going to pray for you, Jack.
Good evening, sir.
Excuse me.
Hey, just like old times, huh?
How the hell have you been?
Did you end up marrying that hunk you
brought around here last time?
- Yep.
- Yeah?
Is he a good lay?
How they make us suffer, huh?
It's all right.
I got some great candy for you.
I got Special "K," angel dust.
I got your all-time favorite.
And I got the newest of the new... R2.
This shit is all the rage.
You take two of these,
- You go straight to heaven.
- I'm not into chemicals.
Cristi, you're not
a cuddly little kitty now, are you?
Look, if you don't like them,
you don't pay for them.
- That's my girl.
- It's busy.
Hey, go easy on the booze tonight, right?
What the fuck are you...?
What the fuck are you doing?
- Would you get my car, please?
- Sure.
- What do you care, asshole?
- I can get you a cab.
- I don't need a fucking taxi.
- Just give me the glass, ma'am.
Here's your fucking glass.
You okay?
Stupid fucking asshole, move your car!
I'm fine. Get away from my car!
There's no damage. I'm fine.
Get away from my car.
- There's no damage.
- Excuse me, I know her.
I can drive her home.
- Is this any of your business?
- I'm your friend Paul
from the sports club.
- Yeah, well...
- Remember?
Yeah. Well, can you tell these
assholes to get away from me?
I'll drive her home.
It's not a big deal, okay?
Okay. All right?
You can't drive like this.
What do you care?
You're going to get arrested.
Let me drive you.
Please?
Damn it.
I sold the truck to pay for the lawyer.
I didn't ask for a lawyer.
Marianne, I didn't ask for a lawyer.
You want your children to spend
another two years without you?
Is that what you want?
This is God's will. So be it.
Two years ago,
you didn't believe in anything.
Now everything has to do with God.
I think I preferred you
the way you were before.
I was a fucking pig before.
Is that what you prefer?
At least it was you.
Now I don't have the slightest
fucking idea who you are.
Life has to go on, Jack,
with or without God.
- Hey, how you doing?
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Were you able to find anything out?
Jack Jordan's living in a cheap motel
lost out in the middle of nowhere.
Phone records.
One of his prison fishy pals
is from there.
- That was quick.
- Just a matter of checking the calls.
Phone number and address
for the motel he's living in.
Here's a pretty recent photo of Jordan.
It was taken the last time he was in jail.
- Were you able to get that
other thing that I asked about?
- Mm-hmm.
This is a clean gun, no record.
They call this an "orphan."
It is loaded.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Careful there, Hoss.
You don't have to cock it.
Just pull the trigger to shoot it.
This releases the cylinder.
I think we're set to go.
That's all I want to know.
- Thank you.
- Good luck to you.
Ma'am, it's been an hour since I called.
46, St. Vincent Street.
Thank you.
- Hello.
Some rain.
- Do you not have your car?
- No, but my taxi will be here
in a minute.
I'm right over here.
I'll give you a lift if you like.
No. Thanks.
I'm the guy who drove
your car home last week.
I'm sorry. I don't remember.
I left my jacket with you.
I'm sorry. I'll bring it by tomorrow.
Are Sure I can't give you a ride?
I'm right here.
Or do you want to swim?
Okay.
Hello.
- Thanks.
- You're very welcome.
Let me just give you my cell phone
number so you can have it.
Would you have lunch with me tomorrow?
What for?
Uh, you're going to have to eat
at some point, and I'm very worried
about those kidneys.
Come on. Lawrence's, 2:00.
It's very nearby.
- Please.
- Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
Great.
... we have construction on the ramp
coming from southbound 240 at Summer.
That ramp is closed until 6:00 PM. Use
Arlington Pike as an alternate. Also...
Forty at the new bridge,
they have the center lane closed.
Use southbound l-20 as an alternate.
Safe Driving believes so strongly
in minimum coverage.
They're easy, fast, affordable and reliable.
They're serious about minimum coverage.
1-800-SAFE-DRIVING.
Minimum coverage is the best option...
Look, Daddy, a pigeon! Daddy, look!
Girls, no, don't.
Don't touch it. Laura, stop it.
Give me a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
Good night, Mr. Peck.
- Hey, Lucio, don't forget
to do my garden on Saturday.
- No, sir, I won't forget.
Son of a bitch. What...?
Leave it to me, Marianne.
Sometimes it happens, sometimes it
doesn't. Everybody reacts differently.
That's why you've been vomiting so much.
So, what are you saying,
I've got to change medication?
Okay, I'm going to
be frank with you, Paul.
The heart that you're carrying
is going to give out soon.
I need you to stay in the hospital
until I can find you another heart.
- You want me to wait for a new heart.
- We don't have another choice.
I can't do that. I can't wait for
someone else to die, locked up
in a fucking room.
- I can't... I can't do it.
- Y... You're dangerously close
to heart failure, Paul.
You might die a lot sooner
than you think.
Let me ask you something, and I want you
to be really honest with me, okay?
If I stay...
will I be saved?
I can't guarantee it.
But if you don't
come back to the hospital,
you're condemning yourself
to a terrible death.
Your heart won't work anymore.
You'll die, asphyxiated.
It's an awful death, Paul.
You can't imagine it.
- At least here we could help you to...
- You can help me die better.
That's what you're saying.
You can help me die better.
Well, I'm not going to do that, okay?
I'd rather die outside.
I'm not going to do it again.
How much did the lawyer charge?
- Marianne, how much did the fucking
lawyer charge?
- Enough.
How much is enough, Marianne?
Enough so your children can
remember your fucking face.
You keep asking stupid questions,
I'm getting out at the next corner.
Hi, guys. We're home.
Daddy! Daddy! What'd you bring us?
I brought you a kiss.
- You didn't bring me a present, huh?
- No, just a kiss.
- We made you a cake.
- Thank you, sweetheart.
Freddy put the icing on it.
Freddy, are you going to
say hello to your father?
Freddy drew those for you.
I drew those ones.
- Mommy made the cake.
- Come here.
- Come look at the cake, Daddy.
- She did?
Come on, Daddy.
There is a number hidden in every act of
life, in every aspect of the universe.
Fractals, matter... that there's a
number screaming to tell us something.
- Am I boring you?
- No. No. I...
I'm sorry.
I guess I try to tell them
that numbers are a door...
to understanding a mystery
that's bigger than us.
How two people, strangers, come to meet.
There's a poem by
a Venezuelan writer that begins...
"The earth turned to bring us closer.
"It turned on itself and in us...
until it finally brought us
together in this dream."
That's beautiful.
There's so many things that have to
happen for two people to meet and...
Anyway, that's...
that's what mathematics are.
How long have you been swimming?
Oh, for years.
- It doesn't bore you?
- No. It's what makes me feel normal.
If I didn't swim or walk or do something,
I think I'd go crazy.
Thanks for lunch.
Yeah. Bye.
- Do you want to come in?
- No.
Thanks... Yes, I do want to come in.
Hey, can I ask you...
- Huh?
- Okay, I have a gun. Okay?
Don't look at me. Don't look at me.
Don't look at me. I'll shoot...
- I don't have any money.
- Turn around. Turn around. I'll shoot
you. Just turn around. Go.
- I don't have any...
- Walk. Walk. Walk!
- P... Put them up! Put your hands up!
- Why?
- Wait.
- Just walk. Go!
We're going to go down that
path right there. Do what I say
and then you won't get hurt.
- I don't have any...
- Go!
I'm not looking. Come on. Keep walking.
Go right down here.
Just keep walking. Keep walk...
I said don't look at me.
I'll shoot you in the head.
Keep your hands up! Walk! Over here.
Over here. Hey!
Come on, don't look at me.
Okay, keep going! Stop! Stop!
Right... Okay, uh... Stop!
T... Turn around.
But keep your hands on your head.
Keep your hands on your head!
G...Get-Get... Take your shoes off
and get down on your knees.
Uh, take off your shoes.
No, not that... not that one.
J... Just get down on your knees!
Get down on your knees!
Sir, please.
You shouldn't have done it.
Done what?
You shouldn't have done it!
Close your goddamn eyes!
- She looked me in the eyes.
- What are you talking about?
One of the girls that I killed,
she looked me in the eye.
She wanted to tell me something.
I just... I left her there.
I ran away.
I ran away. I ran away.
- I ran away. I ran away.
- Shh. Shh. Shh. Shh.
- You sticking with red?
- Sure.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I, um...
Sorry. I, uh... Dizzy.
Can I get you a glass of water
or something?
I think I should go home.
I'm sorry. I just, uh...
I like you a lot, Cristina.
It's been a long time since
I liked someone so much.
Can I see you again?
I'm a married woman.
I figured.
- Thanks.
- Good-bye.
Everybody!
- Look, Daddy. These are the zebras,
these are the lions.
- Very pretty, Gina.
- How could you draw a zoo if you've
never been to one?
- I've seen them in...
Stop fighting.
The lawyer called to remind you
you have to go sign on Monday.
- If you want, I'll go with you
to the church again.
- Daddy, in school they said...
you killed two girls and their daddy.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
- No.
- He killed them.
- It was an accident, sweetie.
You understand?
Oh, Jesus, every time
I look at my children...
Hello?
- Hello?
- Paul?
Wh... Who is this?
Cristina.
Did I wake you?
Hang on a second.
Hi.
- Did I wake you?
- No, that's okay.
Um, c... could you come to my house?
- Is something wrong?
- No, I just...
I just want you to come if you can.
Or if you want to.
Yeah. I'll be right there.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
It's 2:00 in the morning.
Who are you talking to?
I won't be long.
Where are you going?
- I said I won't be long.
- Exactly where and with who are
you going?
I thought you'd change
after the transplants.
And I thought you'd change
if I did. Neither of us changed.
- What's wrong?
- He's been shot in the chest.
- Come on.
- Shot in the... in the chest.
- He's been shot in the chest.
- Come on.
- Okay, how long has he been like that?
- He's dying, okay? We need a...
Okay, I'll go get a stretcher.
- Ma'am, he'll...
he'll be right back.
- It's okay.
Hang in there, baby. I shot him.
- You did what?
- I shot him.
Patrol, I need you to call the police.
It's an emergency, yes.
I'm right out front.
Hi.
Are you okay?
Cristina?
You kept me thinking all day.
You see, I haven't spoken
to anyone in months,
and, uh, I barely know you...
and I already need to talk to you.
And...
there's something the more I think
about, the less I understand.
Why the hell did you tell me
that you liked me?
Answer me, because I didn't
like you saying that at all.
You can't just walk up to a woman you
barely know and tell her you like her.
You-You can't. You can't do that.
You don't know what she's going through.
Or what she's feeling.
I'm not married.
- I...
- Come here.
It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
- No.
Cristina, wait.
- I have to tell you something.
- Okay.
- Please, kiss me.
Wait. Cristina. I...
Cristina.
I have Michael's heart.
- What...
- I have Michael's heart.
You understand what I'm saying?
It was transplanted into me at St.
Francis Hospital on October 11.
No. No.
I tried to tell you.
I just didn't know how to tell you.
- How dare you. How dare you!
- Cristina...
- How fucking dare you!
- I'm here for a reason.
Get out of my house!
- Cristina...
- Don't touch me!
Get out of my house now!
You make me sick!
I had a reason. Can't you see that?
You get out of my fucking...
Get the fuck out of my house! Okay.
You make me sick!
Get out!
Good morning.
Why did you look for me?
Because I needed to.
I don't want your fucking pity.
That wasn't it.
I was sick, Cristina. I was very sick.
I was dying when Michael
gave me his heart.
He saved my life.
I tried in every way that
I knew how to find out...
who had given me this heart.
And that's how I found out how
he and your daughters had died.
And it's very painful for me
to know how I got this heart.
And I couldn't sleep.
I just... I wanted to thank you.
I wanted to help in some way.
I just want to thank you for...
But I couldn't find you.
And then I saw you...
That day.
And now I can't be away from you.
I can't.
You don't have to be afraid.
I've got a good heart.
I'm scared too.
-
Why did you leave us, Jack? Why?
- I am where I have to be.
- Gina got really sick because
of the hamster. Jack, we need you...
- The past is like the Atlantic Ocean.
Back when I was mean,
about the decisions I make,
- that's my mirror.
- Just come back, please.
- That's my mirror.
- Jack, it doesn't matter.
- And I have to live with them
alone. Alone.
- Just come back to us, Jack.
- And I can't erase it.
No one can erase it.
- Your family needs you.
Jack...
We need to stabilize him before
we can get him to the hospital.
But right now what we really need
are units of B-positive blood.
I... I'm O-positive. Will that work?
Okay, open and close your fist
several times.
Unit 35, go ahead.
Okay, pal, you're free to go
for lack of evidence.
Your story doesn't check out
and contradicts our investigation...
and the statements made by
Mrs. Peck and Mr. Rivers.
I just need you to sign here.
What if I really am guilty?
Yeah, well, it happens.
Won't be the first time,
won't be the last.
What are you doing?
You've been lost for too many days,
don't you think, you prick?
Mary, I don't want to fight.
I want this to end well.
Oh, you think ending well means
disappearing for a few days?
You just waited till you got better
to tell me to fuck off.
- I'm going back to London.
- We can't keep doing this.
Really?
I'll have surgery and I'll be inseminated
with your child, with or without you.
- Mary, what for? Why?
- Because I want to.
- Well, I won't authorize that.
- No. Oh, no?
Well, you already have.
I have a signed copy of your
authorization to use your semen.
- Would you excuse me?
- I get what I want.
What do you gain? What do you gain?
You decide if you come
looking for me or not.
Hi, honey. I'm on my way home.
If you need me to pick up anything
along the way, let me...
Girls, no! Don't touch!
Laura, stop, it.
Give me a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
To repeat the message, press one.
To delete, press two.
Hi, honey. I'm on my way home.
If you need me to pick up anything
along the way, let me...
Girls, no! Don't touch!
Laura, stop, it.
Give a call on my cell.
I'll see you in a bit. Bye.
I'm grilling some chicken.
You want anything to eat?
No. Thanks.
- I can make you a sandwich if you...
- No. No, no, no! No!
Cristina. Cristina. Listen to me.
You don't need that shit.
You don't need it.
Don't tell me what I need.
Katie could have lived.
What?
She'd be alive right now,
but that bastard left her there...
lying in the street.
He left the three of them
like animals. He didn't care.
At least she could be here with me.
That son of a bitch is walking
the streets, and I can't even
go into their room.
What do you mean
he's walking the street?
I want to kill him.
You want to kill him?
I'm going to kill Jack Jordan.
I'm going to kill that son of a bitch.
Slow down. Wait. Just-Just slow down.
Slow down? Slow down
while I what? Huh? While I what?
Take it easy. Take it easy?
My husband and my little girls are dead
and I'm supposed to take it fucking easy?
I can't just go on with my life!
I am paralyzed here!
I am a fucking amputee, do you see that?
Who are you?
You owe it to Michael...
No, you've got his heart.
You're in his house fucking his wife
and sitting in his chair!
- We have to kill him!
- No, we... Not like this. Not like this.
Then how? Tell me how!
Katie died with red shoelaces on.
She hated red shoelaces.
And she kept asking me
to get her some blue ones,
and I never got her the blue ones.
She was wearing those fucking
red shoelaces when she was killed.
Oh, God.
You shouldn't have done it!
Close your... Close your goddamn eyes!
Oh.
You... murderer.
You just let them
lie there on the street.
Those two little girls,
you just let them die like dogs.
I should have killed you.
Now you disappear. Don't even go back to
the motel and get your things.
Just disappear.
- Mrs. Peck.
- How is he?
We weren't able to use
your blood for his transfusion.
We found very high levels
of illegal substances in your blood.
You're taking very high risks here.
Well, that's my problem.
In your state, I suggest
you stop using these substances.
- What are you talking about?
- You're pregnant, Mrs. Peck.
- You sure?
- You really need to start taking care
of yourself, Mrs. Peck.
We'll let you know when
Mr. Rivers is out of the O.R.
Where were you?
Did you kill him? Did you?
Why didn't you wake me up?
Where's the body?
Nobody will ever find the body.
I'm sorry.
We're going to go home now.
Let's just get out of here, okay? Yeah?
You okay?
It's okay, baby. Just lie down.
- Need rest. I need to rest.
- I know. I know.
I'm sorry.
I love you.
Oh.
Wake up.
Hmm? Hmm?
There's somebody outside.
Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God!
- You want to kill me?
- What's he doing here?
- Here I am.
Shoot me.
Go ahead. Kill him. Paul.
Oh, my God!
Do something!
Oh.
Oh, baby. Oh, no.
No. No. Oh, my God.
Baby. Baby. Baby. Oh, my God. Oh.
Baby. Oh, my God.
Baby. Baby. Baby. Baby.
Baby. Oh!
Oh, God! Call an ambulance.
Call a fucking ambulance!
How many lives do we live?
How many times do we die?
They say we all lose 21 grams...
at the exact moment of our death.
Everyone.
And how much fits into 21 grams?
How much is lost?
When do we lose 21 grams?
How much goes with them?
How much is gained?
21 grams.
The weight of a stack of five nickels.
The weight of a hummingbird.
A chocolate bar.
How much did 21 grams weigh?
To Maria Eladia.
And when loss was burnt,
the maize fields became green again