[ dog snarling and barking ]
[ thudding ]
[ whimpering and barking ]
[ rapid footsteps ]
[ engine revs loudly ]
[ tires screech ]
[ engine revs ]
[ engine turns off ]
Monty: look at this.
He's alive.
[ russian accent ] this dog --
how you call it? Bull pit?
No. Pit bull.
But that's not a pit bull.
I don't know.
I don't know what he is.
I bet he lost somebody
some money, though.
Give me your gun.
Shooting him?
Yeah.
Are you sick in the head?
They left him out here
to suffer and die like that.
They -- they -- they threw him
out the fuckin' window
And just kept on driving.
It's terrible.
It's terrible. Come.
People wait for us.
Come on.
They're used to waiting.
Poor little guy.
Jesus, I think he broke his hip.
[ barking ]
Oh! Ho! Shit!
[ growls ]
Ha ha!
[ barking ]
The fucker. He's got a lot
of bite left in him, huh?
I think bull pit
is not playing with you, monty.
Yeah. No shit.
Come.
You want police coming?
Oh, look, they used him like
a fucking ashtray, man.
What a bunch of assholes.
Let's get him in the trunk.
What?!
Yeah. There's a vet
emergency room right over here.
Come on.
I like this guy.
He tries to bite
your face off.
He is meat.
You want dog --
I buy you nice puppy tomorrow.
No, no. What the fuck
I want with a puppy?
Come on.
Where you go,
monty?
Monty, wait.
What the --
I not go near bull pit, monty.
This thing
is disgusting.
I told you, I told you --
it's not a pit bull.
He's -- look at him.
He's a good dog.
I can see it in his eyes.
He's a tough little bastard.
He wasn't lying down
for anybody.
Sometimes I think
you very stupid man.
Look at him. Come on.
If we wait much longer,
he's gonna be dead, all right?
You want to shoot him
with my gun.
That was a mercy thing.
He's not ready to go yet.
He wants to live.
Oh, he tell you this now?
No, but it's like
a baby, okay?
They don't bitch and scream
like that, you know?
They -- they see the doctor
coming with the needle.
That -- it's good for him
in the long run.
You have no baby.
I can't even talk to you,
kostya.
[ dog growling ]
Come on.
Come on, you little
son of a bitch.
Hey.
Will you quit standing there?
Will you fucking
help me out here?
Just -- just distract him
for me or something.
[ barking ]
Come on!
[ barking and whimpering ]
[ straining ]
Get the --
[ grunting ]
I'm trying to help you,
you little prick!
Huh? Come on.
Come on.
[ translation from spanish ]
who's more macho?
Monty is more macho!
What goes on
in your little head?
A little of the tricks,
a little of the quicks.
Boom. Bam. He's nabbed.
Yeah, little tricks,
little quicks.
Yeah.
You are bleeding.
You get bite.
Dog's blood.
God, you got to learn
to relax a little bit.
Live a little.
You have hole in neck
and blood is coming out.
[ chuckles ] little love bite
for saving his raggedy ass.
Rule number one -- you cannot
grab half-dead animals.
We have people
waiting for us.
People with money.
[ inhales sharply ]
ow.
You want to play
this cowboy!
No -- no --
dogboy in middle of highway.
Dogboy?
That's funny, kostya.
Yes, funny, funny.
You really mastered
the language.
You're bad luck, monty.
You bring bad luck on me.
Always everything
that can go wrong, go wrong.
It is not just you and me
anymore when we go out.
It's you and me and doyle.
Who's doyle?
Doyle! Doyle's law.
It's -- it's murphy.
What?
Who is murphy?
Who's murphy?
Who's doyle?
It's murphy's law --
"whatever can go wrong
will go wrong."
Him! Yes.
Yes, him.
[ engine turns over ]
[ tires squealing ]
[ engine revs loudly ]
[ slow instrumental music
plays ]
[ man chanting ]
[ chuckles ]
What's up there, monty?
Hey, doyle.
[ barking ]
easy, doyle.
Easy, doyle.
Easy. Easy.
What do you want, simon?
I'm, uh...
[ sniffs ] I'm hungry.
I woke up an hour ago.
I was hungry.
Nothing I can do about that.
Go up to 110th street.
110th street?
Come on, man.
I can't go up there.
I mean -- whoa.
Put that away.
[ barks ]
I, um -- I'm not --
I'm not looking for a mercy pop
or anything, you know.
I'm done, simon.
This morning, right,
I was shaving,
And I cut myself, like --
look, look --
Like four times, man.
Come on, monty!
Give me a break, man!
I can't go up to harlem.
Look at me.
The -- the "yos" --
They'll -- they'll eat me alive
up there, man.
I'm out of business, simon.
Okay? Take your jones
somewhere else. Leave me alone.
Are you afraid that I'm --
That I'm gonna narc
you out? I mean...
You know who I am.
It's me.
You're not listening to me.
It's simon.
I got touched.
Okay? I'm over.
Game over.
Five years I've been coming
to you, man -- five years!
Get out of here.
Get the fuck out of here.
Fine.
I'm -- I'm -- I'm leaving.
There's no need for you to be
all nasty about it, all right?
But I'll --
I'll remember this.
All right?
[ indistinct talking ]
This is dante.
[ dog barks ]
[ indistinct talking
and laughing ]
Aw, what's his name?
Doyle.
Hi, doyle.
[ indistinct talking ]
I'm telling you,
I don't think I'm gonna even
be eligible this year.
Woman: excuse me, sir?
Can I help you?
Hello?
Sorry, what?
Did you have an appointment
with someone?
Oh, no. No.
I used to go here.
I'm gonna have to ask you
to leave
And to take the dog
with you.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay. We'll just be a minute.
No dogs allowed
on the school grounds.
Okay. Okay.
I understand.
Check this out. Check this out.
Come here. He's all right.
Look at what
a little punk I was.
In the middle
with the ball.
I guess you weren't
the center.
No. No.
I started, though.
Freshman year.
I was on the varsity.
Point guard.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Still hold the all-time
assist record.
Mmh, no. Marvin ray broke
the record last year.
He did not.
He did too.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
I coach the girls team.
Well...We were
undefeated that year.
Then I got kicked off
the team for fighting,
And the whole thing
fell apart.
That's too bad.
Hey, listen, you know
where jacob elinsky is?
He's an old friend
of mine.
"now let us sport us
while we may,
"and now, like amorous birds
of prey,
"rather at once
our time devour
"than languish
in his slow-chapt power.
"let us roll all our strength
and all our sweetness
"up into one ball, and tear
our pleasures with rough strife
"thorough the iron gates
of life --
"thus, though we cannot make
our sun stand still,
Yet we will make him run."
Good.
That's good.
That's an excellent reading.
[ clears throat ]
What do people think?
What's going on here?
Luke.
Can I go
to the bathroom?
No, you went
20 minutes ago.
Uh, I have a, um --
a bladder infection.
The poem.
"to his coy mistress."
Andrew marvell.
Well, it's not real deep
or anything.
The guy wants to get laid,
And he's telling her
to give it up.
[ laughter ]
[ knocks on door ]
Excuse me...
For one minute.
Hey...
What's going on?
Hey, who's that?
Look who's here.
It's your buddy.
[ chuckles ]
Sorry to --
sorry to drop in on you.
I just wanted to
talk to you for a second.
W-what's going on?
Nothing. What --
What is this
you got going on here?
Teaching my class.
I guess.
In a circle like that?
Yeah.
Wow.
That's cool.
I like that.
Hey, class.
Hey.        Hey.
Hey.                        Hey.
Sorry to interrupt.
Just -- just a little,
slight change of plans.
I got to see
my father tonight,
And there's these people --
they're throwing me kind of a...
Going-away party,
right?
Yeah.
And, uh, so maybe you and frank
could meet up somewhere.
Maybe that place
with the...
Right.
Things
that frank goes to.
Yeah.
And I'll find you later?
Okay.
Yeah?
Of course.
All right.
This one's cute
with the red shirt.
I think she's giving me
the eye.
How do you do it, man?
I don't know how you do it.
Okay.
[ chuckles ]
so I'll see you later.
Yeah, maybe --
maybe like midnight, I think.
Midnight.
Midnight's...
Yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah. All right.
Okay.
Come on, buddy.
Have a nice day.
Sorry about that.
[ exhales ]
[ bell rings ]
[ indistinct talking ]
[ sighs ] oh, christ.
You have a minute?
Sure.
Yeah, come --
come on in.
I thought that no students
were allowed
In the teachers' lounge.
I won't squeal
on you.
Yeah. Take a seat?
What can I do for you?
I want to know why I got
a b-minus on my paper.
You got what you earned.
Nobody else in that class
can write,
And you know it!
I know it. Everyone knows it.
Don't worry about
everyone else.
You're not competing
with them.
Yeah, but I am. Okay?
I am competing with them.
When I apply to colleges --
you might have heard of this --
They -- they look at these
things called "grades."
And if your grades aren't
good enough then --
No, your grade's
gonna be fine.
Vincent piscella writes a story
about his grandmother dying,
And you give him an a-plus.
Meanwhile,
the night of the funeral,
You know where rhodes scholar
vince is?
Getting smashed at a basketball
party and slapping girls' asses.
I mean, what is that?
A charity a-plus?
I mean,
everyone is always writing
About their grandmothers dying,
and you -- you know -- why?
It's -- it's not because
it's so traumatic.
It's because
it's a guaranteed a-plus!
And you're
all sentimental like,
"oh, vince, that was very
powerful, very moving."
No, it wasn't.
You didn't care.
I didn't care.
Nobody cared.
That's what grandmothers do.
They die!
Sometimes...
Guys have a hard time
showing their emotions.
So...
Slapping my ass --
that's, uh --
Vince's way of mourning
his dead grandmother?
What did your mother say
When you --
when you got that?
When I got what?
Uh...[ exhales ]
Yeah.
She said, um...
[ chuckles ]
"where did you get
the money for that?"
Oh.
And?
And what did I say or...
Where did I get the money?
Well, what did you say?
I said, "he likes me."
Oh.
Does he?
No.
Why do you care so much?
Just curious.
So, um...
You're not gonna
change the grade?
No. I'm not gonna change
the grade.
Great! You know what?
This was a big waste
of my time!
Hold on.
[ door slams ]
[ sighing ] oh, god.
[ indistinct talking ]
[ tapping keyboard ]
just --
just cover my...
Don't freeze up on me,
you son of a...
[ telephone rings ]
yeah, slaughtery.
Yeah.
No, I can't talk right now.
Employment number's coming out.
All right, I just wanted
to let --
call you later.
I'm supposed to
meet you at mont--
Hey, frank, you coming out
with us tonight or what?
No, I got to meet
some friends tonight.
Big date, huh?
Who's the new bimbo?
Can I bang her first?
Yeah, you wish, brother.
No, it's more of
a going-away party.
Now, listen,
frank, the other thing...
You still holding onto
all those o.E.X. Contracts?
Yeah,
you better believe it.
Why? You nervous?
I don't like it, frank.
Claims numbers have dropped
three weeks straight,
And I don't feel comfortable
with this.
Claim numbers drop
so everybody thinks
employment's gonna be up?
Come on, sal.
Everybody -- frank,
look at me when I talk to you.
Everybody's thinking this
Because it's pretty
much always true.
I mean, when it rains outside,
people get wet.
Right or wrong, frank?
Not this time, sal.
I'm telling you.
I got a theory. Look at this.
Check these out.
Oh, good!
You've got a theory.
Look, frank --
fuck you and your theory.
Oh, that's good. Nice.
You're in
awfully deep here, frank.
You've got $60 million
of the bank's money --
$100 million.
Whoa ho!
$100-fucking-million?!
What are you two doing?
You want to be part of
the unemployment numbers?
Get back to work!
Sal, you knew they raised
my limit to $100 million.
A week ago --
they just raised your limit
a week ago
And you're already
maxing out?
What am I gonna do?
Sit on it?
Is that what you want?
First of all...
You're not gonna raise
your voice to me.
That's first off.
You cannot put me, you,
or this firm in jeopardy
By putting $100 million
in one idea!
Right or wrong? Come on!
Right or wrong. Yeah.
Listen...
I think we're in for
a low number, all right?
Like 140, 135.
I really don't give a shit
what you think, frank.
You're becoming a cowboy.
You come in here,
you're not even clean-shaven.
Frank, stop playing
with this fucking ball
and pay attention to me.
You come in here drinking
your red bullshit,
you stink like booze,
You're out all night partying --
and that's okay.
But when you become a cowboy,
that's when I draw the line.
I am still your boss,
and I am telling you now --
You sell half those contracts.
Do I make myself clear?
Do I make myself clear,
frank?
Do I make myself clear
to you?
Yeah.
Yes? Good.
Have a good day.
And by the way, we're still on
for Friday night.
Courtside, front row.
Don't be late.
It's mayhem down here
on the floor of the exchange.
Within moments, the unemployment
number's gonna be announced.
Salomon brothers,
along with most of the street,
Feel the number is
going to be high --
Around 250,000.
Uh, solly's looking for
a high number.
280,000 is their call.
Fuck salomon brothers.
Fuck, uh --
fuck salomon brothers?
Yeah, fuck salomon brothers.
They're hedging their bets.
Want everybody on their side
of the fence.
Uh, what's the --
what's the big deal with the
employment number anyway?
Phellan.
It's, uh, phelan.
Whatever. Look...
More jobs means fewer people
looking for work.
Means it's harder to find good
people to fill those jobs.
Means you got to raise wages
to get them.
Means inflation goes up.
You got it?
Yeah.
No, I didn't think so.
That's why I'm doing
what I'm doing,
And you're handing out
junk mail.
Now, get off my desk.
Sorry about that.
You know you're wearing
a striped shirt
With a striped tie --
you know that, right?
Yeah, I do it for that ladies.
Like...
Oh? Do the ladies ever
tell you that you look like
A fucking optical illusion?
Yeah?
Go away. Disappear.
Come on.
I'm out of here.
You better hop to,
sonny boy.
You know, it's funny --
I don't see you picking up the
phone to sell those contracts,
And I'm pretty sure I just heard
your daddy come over here
And cut off your allowance,
so I'm a little surprised.
You're not gonna disobey
a direct order, are you?
You know, marcuse...
Do I come into your bedroom
And tell you how to blow
your boyfriend? No.
Go away.
Hey, schultz!
Yo.
What are we looking at
for that unemployment number?
250, 270 --
somewhere in there.
Big number. Big.
[ whistles ]
Hey, frank --
we all right?
We're good.
Man on tv: ...Investors
and the market
In uncharted waters.
So who really knows?
The number is coming out.
New applications --
[ people gasping ]
[ indistinct talking ]
Get me out! Now, now, now!
Hold the phone!
That can't...
We goin' for a ride now!
Whoo!
Hey, where have you been?
I got up at 7:00 this morning.
You were already gone.
Yeah. I just...
I needed to walk around
a little, you know?
Hey.
How long you been sitting
on this stoop?
All day.
[ exhales ]
I've been waiting
for you.
It's a beautiful day.
Yeah, I guess it is.
Hey, mr. Doyle.
I missed you
this morning.
Come on.
Montgomery, I want you
to talk to me.
About what, nat?
About how
you're feeling.
Well, how do you think
I'm feeling?
Well, I'm asking because
I don't like to assume.
Well, good. Don't.
What do you want?
I want to be like
that girl in the x-men --
That one that can walk
through walls.
Go on.
[ doyle scampers ]
If I can't do that...
I don't know -- boom --
one shot to the head.
Problem solved.
[ door closes ]
[ exhales ]
Don't joke about that.
Who says I'm joking?
[ sighs ]
So, what are
we doing tonight?
Before you kill yourself,
that is.
Uncle nikolai is throwing me
a party down at bridge.
I figure
we all head down there.
[ container opens ]
Oh, come on.
Come on.
I have to go.
I got no choice, okay.
We might as well
try to have some fun.
I thought it was over
with those guys.
Yeah, it's almost over.
I mean, it's never really over
with these guys, but...
[ sighs ]
[ exhales ]
That's a nasty habit you have,
you know that?
Come take a bath with me.
No, not right now.
Go on. Go ahead.
[ sighs ]
Monty:
I can't see me being a --
a father.
Naturelle: no?
Well, I could see
you fathering children.
I couldn't see you
raising any. [ laughs ]
You think I want to
raise my own chalupas?
I don't raise
my own chalupas.
Oh, so -- well, we're definitely
not having any kids together
If you're gonna be
calling them "chalupas."
Oh, I -- I think
we would have very...
Very beautiful babies.
You don't think?
I think.
[ laughs ]
All right,
show me that.
What?
No. Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
We were just going
someplace so nice.
I can't believe
you did that.
I can't believe you --
why? Why?
You've lived in the
United States your entire life.
You've been to
puerto rico twice on vacation.
I'm -- you know,
I'm very proud of my heritage.
Yeah, but what does
that mean?
So I should get an irish flag
tattooed on my ass
Just 'cause my grandparents
were from there?
There's not enough room
On your skinny, white, flat ass
for an irish flag.
Yeah, well,
between you and me
The kids are gonna be
just about right then.
Kids?
[ doorbell rings ]
At this rate,
we're not having any.
[ doyle barking ]
It's probably
your mother.
[ doorbell rings ]
coming.
Doyle, cut it out.
Kostya, you have
the worst timing ever.
Man: sorry to bother you,
ma'am.
Is montgomery brogan in?
Monty.
Monty!
Montgomery brogan?
Yeah, that's me.
I'm agent flood with the drug
enforcement administration.
I can see that.
What is all this?
We've got a warrant
to search your apartment.
[ exhales ]
Are you serious?
Go -- go ahead.
[ growls and barks ]
Hey, easy, doyle.
Yeah, I don't see
any tags on that dog.
He's inside.
He doesn't need tags.
He better stay calm or I'll have
the pound come get him.
[ doyle barking ]
Seen too many men bit
by these mean bastards.
[ growls ]
Doyle.
[ whistles ] come on.
Sit.
[ exhales ] oh...
You, uh, mind if I have
a seat?
No. Be my guest.
Uh, miss riviera? Heh.
That's your name, right?
I need you to stay
right here, ma'am.
Can't have you
sneaking around.
[ chuckles ]
You know, this sofa's not
very comfortable.
Ah, maybe it's
your posture.
Your posture
is very important.
No, it's this, uh,
castro convertible.
It's very uncomfortable.
It's kind of -- kind of lumpy.
You know, I just don't
understand it.
It looks like
such a nice sofa.
How much did you pay for
this sofa, miss riviera?
Maybe it's the padding.
Booyah!
Could be the padding.
Yeah.
Probably the padding.
Go on. Get it over with.
Hmm.
There's something lumpy
in here, mr. Brogan.
You know, it's a good thing
I found this.
It's gonna make your sofa so
much more comfortable to sit on.
Sh-e-e-e-it.
Mr. Brogan,
I do believe you're fucked.
Royally.
Sh-e-e-e-it.
Baby...
Baby?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
This will be the best night
of my life.
Best night of my life.
I just -- I -- you know,
I've been waiting around
all day long --
I know. I know.
I just want to know
if we're gonna spend
Any time at all
together today.
I know.
Could you just talk
to me?
Talk to me, okay?
We haven't been talking.
This is our last night --
No. No, no, no.
It's not our last night.
It's my last night.
Not your last night.
You got all kinds of nights.
You got nights with your
girlfriends...
Okay.
Going out clubbing...
Sitting at bars...
"you and me" equals "our."
Getting drinks bought for you
by lawyers.
This is our last night.
You can sit at home watching
movies with your mother.
You got all kinds
of nights.
Look, I don't understand what
you're not understanding here.
Hey, you know what?
I can't do this right now, okay?
Babe, I need you
to just be quiet.
Please just be quiet.
I know, but we haven't talked
about this at all.
You know, lately you can't even
look at me in the eye.
I have to go.
Meet us at the place
in chinatown.
Where are you going?
I've got to see
my father tonight.
You know?
Do -- do me a favor, and wear
that silver dress tonight, okay?
You want me to?
Yeah...Yeah.
That's how I want to
remember you.
[ door closes ]
Mmm, very nice.
Very nice.
Hello, beautiful lady.
Beautiful baby.
You look like halle berry.
They tell you this?
Come back.
I make you half-black,
half-russian baby.
So many beautiful woman.
I love this neighborhood.
How much is rent?
You can't afford it.
Trust me.
What are you doing here?
Something is wrong?
No, I'm having the time
of my life.
What do you think,
you dumb shit?
Uncle nikolai wants me
talking with you.
Wants to make sure
you come to club tonight.
You know what? You're like
the third person in two
days that's said that to me.
What the fuck is going on?
What does he really want?
I don't know.
You come all the way
up here just to tell
me you don't know?
You never heard
of a telephone?
But you do not answer
my calls,
And uncle wants to make sure
That you're tonight
at the bridge.
I'll be there!
For christ's sake. Tell him.
Tell him I'm --
I'm bringing some friends.
I'm bringing naturelle.
Monty.
Wait, monty. Please.
Why you bring her?
Why wouldn't I?
We have this discussion
once before, no?
You get very mad at me.
Oh, you know what?
Will you stop with that already?
I already told you --
it wasn't her.
How you know this?
Why would she?
Maybe her aunt is illegal alien.
You know, these mexicans...
Hey, hey,
she's puerto rican.
They jump the border...
That makes her a citizen
of the United States.
That's more
than I can say for you.
Maybe the feds,
they -- they bust --
The feds. You know,
you're fucking cracking up.
Filling my head with this shit.
You're crazy.
You ask her?
No, I didn't ask her.
Listen.
Before you leave...
You should know.
I'll see you down there.
[ engine turns over ]
[ indistinct conversations ]
Monty: those guys coming back
in here yet?
James: not much.
Well, you know --
little by little.
It was hard on those guys.
I went to elementary school
with that guy nick.
You remember -- nicky?
Oh, nick. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Good kid.
Place looks good, though.
Hmm.
Want to take
your coat off?
Um, no.
I was feeling a little cold.
Hmm.
Oh.
That's a hell of a steak.
Only the best for you, sweetie.
I'll send you cookies
every month.
Peanut butter, right?
That's it.
I, uh...
I talked to sal.
Oh, dad, come on.
Oh, I'll see if he can help
with the --
Dad, the guy's been out
of the picture for 20 years.
He still knows people.
Look, that's not the point.
I-I don't want you
to get involved, okay?
I mean it.
I'm -- I'm gonna be all right.
You know, you'll still be
a young man when you get out.
I know you don't think
about it,
But don't start
any trouble in there.
Keep your head down.
Dad, don't worry
about me, please.
This should never
have happened.
You could've been --
you wanted money,
You could've done anything --
anything you wanted --
Doctor, lawyer.
Don't lay that on me.
That's all I'm saying.
I mean, when sal and his crew
were squeezing you
For the payments,
I didn't hear you wishing I was
a law school student then.
Not one word from you
back then.
Where'd you think that money was
coming from -- donald trump?
That was a mistake.
Well, let's just
forget it, then.
There were lots
of mistakes.
I should've stopped drinking
when your mother passed.
Oh, please.
Please don't do this.
11-year-old boy with a
dead mother and a drunk father.
Jesus, pop.
You know.
I got no one to blame
but myself.
Oh, stop. Stop.
It wasn't you, pop.
I'm gonna take a leak.
[ door opens, closes ]
Yeah, fuck you, too.
Fuck me? Fuck you.
Fuck you and this whole city
and everyone in it.
No, no, no, no, no.
Fuck the panhandlers
grubbing for money,
Smiling at me behind my back.
Fuck the squeegee men
Dirtying up the clean
windshield of my car.
Get a fucking job.
Fuck the sikhs
and the pakistanis
Bombing down the avenues
in decrepit cabs,
Curry steaming out their pores,
stinking up my day.
Terrorists in fucking training.
Slow the fuck down!
...Getting one
of those operations
That elongate your penis.
Fuck the chelsea boys
With their waxed chests
and pumped-up biceps,
Going down on each other
in my parks and on my piers,
Jiggling their dicks
on my channel 35!
Fuck the korean grocers
With their pyramids
of overpriced fruit
And their tulips and roses
wrapped in plastic.
Ten years in the country,
still no speakee english.
Fuck the russians
in brighton beach.
Mobster thugs
sitting in cafes,
Sipping tea
in little glasses,
Sugar cubes
between their teeth,
Wheelin' and dealin'
and schemin'.
Go back where you
fucking came from.
Fuck the black-hatted
hasidim
Strolling up and down
47th street
In their dirty gabardine
with their dandruff,
Selling south african
apartheid diamonds.
Come on.
Your wife deserves this.
Fuck the wall street
brokers.
Self-styled masters
of the universe.
Michael douglas-gordon gekko
wannabe motherfuckers
Figuring out new ways
to rob hardworking people blind.
Send those enron assholes
to jail for fucking life.
You think bush and cheney
didn't know about that shit?
Give me a fucking break.
[ indistinct conversations ]
Worldcom.
Fuck the puerto ricans.
Twenty to a car,
swelling up the welfare rolls.
Worst fucking parade
in the city.
And don't even get me started
on the dominicans,
'cause they make
the puerto ricans look good.
Who's this fuckin' guy?!
Get the fuck outta here!
Fuck the bensonhurst italians
with their pomaded hair,
Their nylon warm-up suits,
their st. Anthony medallions,
Swinging their jason giambi
Louisville slugger
baseball bats
Trying to audition
for "the sopranos."
Fuckin' crack
your fuckin' head open!
Bensonhurst!
Taxi! Taxi!
Fuck the upper east side wives
with their hermes scarves
Taxi!
And their $50
balducci artichoke.
Taxi!
Overfed faces
getting pulled and lifted
And stretched all taut
and shiny.
You're not fooling anybody,
sweetheart.
Taxi!
Fuck the uptown brothers.
They never pass the ball,
They don't want to
play defense,
They take five steps
on every layup to the hoop,
And then they want to
turn around
And blame everything
on the white man.
We not giving it up!
Slavery ended 137 years ago.
Move the fuck on.
Fuck the corrupt cops with
their anus-violating plungers
And their 41 shots,
Standing behind a blue wall
of silence.
You betray our trust!
Fuck the priests
who put their hands
Down some
innocent child's pants.
Fuck the church that protects
them, delivering us into evil.
And while you're at it,
fuck j.C.
He got off easy --
A day on the cross,
a weekend in hell,
And all the hallelujahs of the
legioned angels for eternity.
Try seven years
in fucking otisville, j.
Fuck osama bin laden,
al qaeda,
And backward-ass
cave-dwelling
Fundamentalist assholes
everywhere.
On the names of
innocent thousands murdered,
I pray you spend the rest
of eternity with your 72 whores
Roasting in a jet-fuel fire
in hell.
You towel-headed camel jockeys
can kiss my royal irish ass.
"I notice how many
of what I once thought
"were evidences of repression,
Sexual or otherwise..."
fuck jacob elinsky.
Whining malcontent.
Fuck francis xavier slaughtery,
my best friend,
Judging me while he stares
at my girlfriend's ass.
Fuck naturelle riviera.
I gave her my trust,
and she stabbed me in the back.
Sold me up the river.
Fucking bitch.
Fuck my father
with his endless grief,
Standing behind that bar,
sipping on club soda,
Selling whiskey to firemen
and cheering the bronx bombers.
All: let's go, yankees!
Fuck this whole city
and everyone in it,
From the row houses
of astoria
To the penthouses
on park avenue,
From the projects in the bronx
to the lofts in soho,
From the tenements
in alphabet city
To the brownstones
in park slope
To the split-levels
in staten island,
Let an earthquake crumble it,
let the fires rage,
Let it burn to fucking ash,
and then let the waters rise
And submerge this whole
rat-infested place.
[ horns blaring ]
No.
No. Fuck you,
montgomery brogan.
You had it all,
And you threw it away,
you dumb fuck!
What do you think
of naturelle?
She's a good girl.
Your mother would've liked her.
Yeah, but you trust her?
Do I trust her?
Mm-hmm.
Why do I have to trust her?
You think I can trust her?
Where you going with this?
Oh, I don't know.
People are...
Saying weird things.
I'm hearing stuff around,
Like maybe she was the one
that made the phone call on me.
Why would she do a thing
like that?
Maybe they got to her,
you know?
It happens. They find something,
put the screws on you.
The girl loves you, monty.
I can't believe
she would betray you.
I don't know.
I mean, everything's gotten
so strange, pop.
You know, I-I look at
these people around me,
And I..I'm thinking,
"these are my friends?
I don't even know
these people."
You know, and --
and naturelle, even.
Do I --
do I really know her?
I don't know.
It's all...
The only people I trust
are you, jacob, and frank --
The guys I grew up with.
I miss those boys.
Yeah, I know.
I'm -- I'm supposed to be
meeting them.
They're waiting for me.
I-I ought to get going.
What about your food?
I can't.
Okay.
I'll, uh, see you
in the morning.
No. No. Why?
I -- I'm gonna take the bus
up there.
Oh, forget about the bus.
I'll drive you.
Take half as long.
Take this.
They'll let you keep it.
When you was a little kid,
You used to sleep
in that fireman's helmet.
You wanted to be
just like your daddy.
I ever tell you about the fights
we had naming you?
Yeah. You wanted to
name me james.
James brogan jr. --
good, strong name.
Nah. Your mother thought
it was too boring for you.
She liked
montgomery clift.
Loved him.
"place in the sun" --
her favorite movie.
I kept saying,
"montgomery clift --
"look what happened
to that poor fuck.
Died way too young.
Bad luck."
[ exhales deeply ]
Bad luck.
I'm gonna go, okay?
I'll see you soon, pop.
[ bell jingles ]
Monty...
[ indistinct conversations ]
[ door closes ]
Francis: he'll be working
for me. I'll have his job.
Listen, I got to go.
Talk to you tomorrow.
[ knock on door ]
Cocksucker.
How you doing, bro?
Hey.
[ laughing ] hey.
[ laughs ]
Good to see you.
How you doing?
Good.
Good. Come on in.
All right.
Want a beer?
Yeah.
Cool.
[ bottles rattling ]
[ caps falling ]
There you go.
Thanks.
Cheers.
Jesus christ.
Yeah.
Yeah, the new york times says
the air's bad down here.
Oh, yeah?
Well, fuck the times.
I read the post.
E.P.A. Says it's fine.
Somebody's lying.
[ laughs ]
Yeah.
You gonna move?
Fuck that, man.
As much good money as I pay
for this place?
Hell, no.
Tell you what.
Bin laden can drop another one
right next door. I ain't moving.
[ sighs ]
What do we say to him?
Don't say nothing.
He's going to hell
for seven years.
What am I gonna do,
wish him luck?
Just get him drunk.
Make sure he has
one last good night.
That's it.
So you're up for this?
Yeah.
I don't even know
why he invited me.
What are you
talking about, man?
You know, we hardly ever see
each other anymore.
You know, you and I are
his friends from the past.
Oh, yeah.
Like his friends from the
present have done him much good.
[ sighs ] I just...
I just can't believe
he's going away for seven years.
Someone turns him in
and...
Oh, don't feed me
that shit.
What shit?
Come on, jake.
Don't feed me that bullshit.
Yeah, he got caught.
But hello --
monty's a fucking drug dealer.
Shit.
What, are you -- you driving
a vintage super "b"?
No.
No. He is.
Yeah, paid for by the misery
of other people.
He got caught.
He's gonna get locked up.
And I'll tell you
something else.
You two are my best friends
in the whole world,
And I love him like a brother,
but he fucking deserves it.
He deserves it.
What's he planning on doing
with doyle?
How the fuck
should I know?
[ chuckles ]
I don't know.
Maybe...Leave him
with naturelle or something.
They should at least let him
take doyle with him.
What?
Just let him take doyle
with him.
He wouldn't be so lonely.
You can't take a fucking dog
to the hoosegow, jake.
I'm just saying it'd be
kind of nice if he could.
[ chuckles ]
All right.
Yeah, it'd be nice.
Monty's tough.
I think he'll be okay.
If it were me,
I...I'd never last a day,
But...Monty,
he's different.
Oh, yeah?
You believe that?
Yeah.
You don't fucking get it,
do you?
What don't I get?
You want the simple
version, jake?
Guys who look like monty don't
do well in prison, all right?
Man, he's got three choices,
and none of them are good.
One, he can run.
Two, catch the bullet train.
Bullet train?
I'm not saying
what he's gonna do.
I'm saying
what his choices are.
His third choice is he goes
to prison, that's it.
Yeah, and that's
what he's gonna do.
He'll go and I'll see him
when he gets out.
Maybe.
I'll tell you what.
After tonight,
it's bye-bye, monty.
What does that mean?
Man, if he runs, he's gone.
He ain't coming home.
If he pulls the trigger,
they close the casket.
He's gone.
They lock him away, he's gone.
You'll never see him again.
I'll see him again.
No, you won't.
No, I'll visit him
up there
oh, bullshit.
And I'll see him
when he gets out.
Come on. Don't fuck with --
you know what?
This is such horseshit.
This is so much like you, jake.
You're not gonna see him --
like me?
Yeah, it's...Exactly.
What's -- why --
you'll never see him again.
You think you're gonna
kick back with some beers,
Reminisce -- old times --
you're still gonna be friends?
It's over after tonight, jake.
Wake the fuck up.
[ footsteps approaching ]
Let her go.
That's a good-looking girl
you got there.
Them spanish broads.
[ chuckles ]
Ooh.
That's a scary look.
Yikes.
You see the look
he gave me?
[ chuckles ]
Naturelle riviera --
what a name.
You see the rack on that girl?
[ exhales deeply ]
You know what?
Take another angle, man.
You can't fucking touch her.
No. No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
You're missing the point.
She touched you.
You're lying.
Am I?
Yeah.
Oh, that's sweet.
You really trust her.
[ chuckles ]
All I know is
she's walking away.
Yeah. We just signed
her release.
Probably having
a big party tonight
Over at jimmy's bronx cafe.
Sure. Why not?
Big celebration.
She got that whole fancy
apartment to herself now.
What? You thought she was
with you for your looks?
Sh-e-e-e-it.
Girl saw a pot of honey,
and she licked it clean.
Yeah.
She's a real smart girl.
Now, you,
on the other hand...
You're supposed to be smart.
Got yourself a scholarship
to a fancy private school, hmm?
Not bad for a punk
from bay ridge.
Yeah, but then you go
and get yourself thrown out
For dealing weed
to some rich kids.
What up with that?
You know what happens to
pretty boys like you in prison?
Ooh.
They gonna love you.
Yeah, maybe.
But then again...Maybe not.
"jeez, your honor, you know,
what can I say?
"I messed up.
"you know, my mother died.
"I-I was so worried
about my father.
"I needed to help him out.
"my head was a little
turned around.
"I got hooked in
with the wrong people,
"and I made a big mistake.
"I really did,
but...It was my first time.
I'm sorry, and it will never,
ever happen again."
Time served. Probation.
You don't read the papers much,
do you, smart guy?
In new york,
We've got a wonderful thing
called the rockefeller laws.
Let me educate you.
You had a kilo in your sofa.
That kind of weight makes it
an a-1 felony.
15 years to life minimum
for first offense.
Now, with that much spread
in the sentencing guidelines,
The judges take their cues
from the prosecutors.
So if mr. Prosecutor's wife
busted his chops that morning,
You're fucked.
You're gone for good.
If you get lucky --
really lucky --
Now, let's say he got
some good trim the night before.
Maybe he'll plead you off
to an a-2.
But that's still three to eight
for first time -- minimum.
How much of that stretch
you pull
Is all up to the mood
of the prosecutor,
And he's gonna ask us,
"did he play ball?"
So...
Why don't you tell us
about your friend nikolai?
Let us make it easy
on you.
Can I ask you one question?
[ laughing ] sure.
When you have your dick
in his mouth,
Does he just keep talking
like that?
'cause it seems to me
he just never shuts up,
And I'm --
I'm just curious --
Does that --
does that get annoying?
You know, you're fucking a guy
in the mouth,
And he just won't
shut up.
[ laughing ]
Look here,
you vanilla motherfucker.
When you're upstate
taking it in the culo
By a bunch of guys
calling you shirley,
You'll only have yourself
and governor rockefeller
To thank for the privilege.
Let's get the hell out
of here.
Tell the u.S. Attorney
we got a hard-ass.
You need a girlfriend.
I need a girlfriend?
Yeah.
[ laughing ]
wait a minute.
When was the last time
you had a girlfriend?
All right? When was
the last time you got laid?
I've got prospects.
[ laughs ]
Yeah, you got prospects.
I do.
You know what?
You're in the 62nd percentile
is what you are.
What is that?
62nd percentile?
[ laughing ] yeah.
That's you.
That's where you rate.
All the bachelors in new york,
we're all competing
For the same women --
well, the straight bachelors.
And I'm in
the 62nd percentile?
Yes, sir.
So in other words,
I'm better than 62%
of the new york bachelors.
You're rated higher
than them, yeah.
But worse than what,
38%?
37. No 100 percentile.
How'd you come up with 62?
There's a whole science
to figuring it out.
There's a science
to figuring it out?
That sounds
very scientific.
And if I may inquire,
what's your rating?
Funny you should ask.
Hmm.
Because I happen to fall
right in the 99 percentile.
[ chuckles ]
of course.
Who came up
with the ratings?
I did.
You came up
with the ratings?
Mm-hmm.
And you get a 99?
That's very interesting.
Yeah?
What are these, uh,
based on?
It's just a system.
I mean, that's your rating.
I mean, I'm not saying
you're a bad person, jake.
No, you're just saying
I'm a bad bachelor.
No. No.
You're -- you're a better
than an average bachelor.
What -- what are
the criteria?
First, money.
You have none.
Trust funds don't count
for shit
Because it's a red flag
that says,
"mommy and daddy could turn off
the cash flow one day."
So that right there keeps you
out of the top 10%.
10% of the...Gold diggers?
10% period.
Two...
You got chronic bad breath.
No offense,
But most women won't sleep
with a guy with stank breath,
So...
Fuck you.
You don't have to get
so annoyed, all right?
I am annoyed.
What puts you
in the 99th percentile?
That's what I'm wondering.
Okay.
Well, first of all,
I, um...
What?
Besides your salary
and all the money you make.
All right.
I happen to be blessed
with a very big dick.
[ laughs ]
Genetics, man.
Doesn't dyeing your hair
drop you down a few places?
Nope. Not at all.
Only bothers women
if it bothers me.
Going gray
does bother you.
No, it doesn't.
Of course it does.
If it didn't bother you,
you wouldn't smear that goop
All over your scalp
10 billion times a day.
Hey, it's a non-issue,
jake.
Well, are table manners
an issue?
See that -- that silver thing
to the left of your plate?
That's called a fork.
Mm-hmm.
And when people eat rice,
they use chopsticks or a fork.
Yeah, and grown people
don't eat...Fried rice
With their bare hands.
[ laughs ]
You don't know
how to behave.
You're busting my balls
on the way I eat?
You spend the whole week
Figuring out how to defraud
foreign governments --
Whatever you do -- and then
you -- you get out of there
And you go out
to the strange world
Outside your office
called reality...
And you don't know
how to behave.
[ belches ]
Oh, yeah?
I rest my case.
You gonna tell me
about reality?
Jacob, you're a rich jewish kid
from the upper east side
Who's ashamed of his wealth.
[ belches ]
You walk around unhappy 24-7
Trying to make up for the fact
that you were born privileged.
Fuck that.
You know what?
That's just some knee-jerk
liberalism bullshit, man.
You call that reality?
[ indistinct conversations ]
So what's monty?
Let's see.
Monty's going to prison.
He's a doughnut --
big, fat zero.
Yo.
Let's not go to practice.
Just today.
So don't go.
Let's go to my house.
[ laughs ]
Come on, nat.
Let's go.
My mother won't be home
till late, either.
And there's food.
Good, 'cause I ain't got
no money.
Vito's home.
So?
What's that?
Nothing.
I don't care.
You don't care, nat?
What do you mean now?
Yeah, right.
You know
you likededed him forever.
I never likededed him.
You're always trying to
hook us up
Because you want me to be
your sister-in-law,
But it ain't never
happening.
Yeah, that would be nice.
I wouldn't mind.
But don't front
like you don't likededed him.
Nat, please, okay?
Every day you come
to my house --
"vito, walk me home" --
Every day?
What kind of bullshit is that?
Anyway, he's always with
that girl.
What's up, simon?
Monty, how you doing?
Good, good.
Good to see you, man.
Good to see you.
Yeah.
Who's that?
It's a -- it's a new guy.
He's golden. He's good.
Now, you know what I told you
about that.
He's big. Big.
It's like, "beep, beep" --
Back up your truck, man.
You know what I'm saying?
All right, simon. I'll handle
my business, all right?
Just trying to help.
All right.
Take it easy.
When did he break up
with her?
Like a month ago.
But she don't stop.
She calls the house,
she calls, she hangs up.
Please. Please.
Did he break up with her,
or she broke up with him?
He needs somebody good.
He broke up
with her, though,
Or she broke up with him?
Excuse me.
Why doesn't he --
excuse me.
You got a light?
What?
Can I borrow your lighter
for a second?
[ children shouting ]
Thanks a lot.
What's he doing?
He's loco.
Yo, I've met you before,
haven't I?
You do look familiar to me.
How do I know you?
Yeah. You were in
my brother's class.
Pete.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I know who you are.
Yo, nat, come on.
Let's go.
We got practice.
I'll catch up.
Yeah, all right.
Whatever.
You stupid.
What do you got
practice for?
Basketball.
Seriously? You play?
Come on.
What are you, a guard?
Three spot.
You play small forward?
No shit?
That means you're strong
and quick.
I play the one -- point.
You know, you skip too many
of these things,
They'll give you the boot --
for real.
I just want to finish
my cigarette.
Funny. You don't --
I don't know.
I wouldn't have made you
for a ballplayer, you know?
You look more like a...
Like a...A runner,
like a track star.
Where you from?
No, I mean --
you -- you from uptown?
U.F.A.?
You on a scholarship?
What, I can't be
from riverdale?
You can be
from wherever you want.
Just...Curious.
I didn't mean nothing.
I was just...
You know, I-I was
on scholarship, too.
It's a good thing.
You -- you're lucky.
What -- what --
what's your name?
Nat? Natalie?
Naturelle.
Naturelle?
Are you serious?
Naturelle.
Wow. I like that name.
How old are you?
18.
Are you 18?
Why?
'cause it's not every day
I meet a girl as pretty as you
who plays the three spot.
That's...That's deadly.
How old are you?
I'm old enough
to have to ask.
You're too old to be
hanging out on the playground.
[ laughs ]
I wasn't hanging out.
I was...
I was passing by.
What if I was 17?
It might shorten
the conversation a little.
But you're not.
You're 18,
so we got no problem.
What do you say I come
and see you play sometime?
Seriously.
I'd like to.
Maybe.
Maybe?
Okay.
I'll be the one right behind
the bench yelling,
"get back on 'd'!"
[ laughs ]
See ya.
[ children shouting,
chains squeaking ]
Hey.
Come out here
and meet somebody.
Who's that?
She's just the girl
for you.
[ indistinct conversations ]
Hey, jody.
You back there?
Hey, baby.
Hey, sweetie.
How you doing?
Hi.
Is this your little brother,
frank? He's a cutie.
Don't bother with me.
I'm in the 62nd percentile.
Oh. That's probably because
you don't work on wall street.
The scale is skewed
to the money thing.
Everybody knows
about this.
Everybody knows.
Anybody at this bar.
[ exhales deeply ]
You see that ass?
She's beautiful.
Mm-hmm.
Man.
One of the guys
at school --
This, uh, biology teacher,
terry --
Mm-hmm.
Did you ever meet terry?
No, I don't think so.
Anyway, he, uh, he --
he really likes this girl.
Like a student?
A student.
[ laughs ]
yeah.
A junior.
Oh, man.
I mean, the girl's 16,
17, maybe.
I don't know.
Uh, she's not
really pretty,
Um...Not in the, uh,
classical sense,
But she...
I don't know. I don't know.
She's -- she's got something.
You know.
Mm-hmm.
And I told him. I...
[ exhales deeply ]
I told terry, you know, to just
forget about it, you know?
He's kind of obsessing,
And it's kind of scary
the way he talks about it.
Yeah.
But he's like...
"five years from now,
"she'll almost be out
of college.
"I mean, I'll be 36.
"you know, and...
You know?
Nothing wrong with that,
you know?"
You haven't fucked
her yet, huh? Have you?
No, I'm sorry. Were you
listening to what I just said?
No, I haven't fucked her.
Of course...
That's good, because, man,
big mistake.
Well, I...
I mean, I'm not a pervert.
You know what a man
should never ask
In a victoria's secret
shop, jake?
What?
"does this come
in children's sizes?"
Think about that.
What's that
supposed to mean?
It's literal.
It's a joke.
It's literal?
You know what? Why do we
always have to do this?
Why can't we just sit down
And, you know,
just shut the fuck up,
Have a beer,
have a drink?
What's the matter with you?
Francis xavier slaughtery.
Hey, baby.
How are you, naturelle?
Hey.
Nice to see you.
You too.
Hi.
How you doing, jake?
[ laughs ] nat.
[ laughs ]
You look fantastic.
There you go.
Thank you.
What are you boys up to?
Frank's just flirting
with the bartender.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
What's the verdict?
Guilty of looking good.
Oh, she's just tits,
francis.
Oh, yeah?
Did you see her ass?
The girl's got a fine ass.
She's oozing sex appeal.
Oh, she's oozing something.
[ laughs ]
See, that right there --
that is so typical.
That's what I'm
talking about, jake.
Why is it that a woman walks
in the room with great tits,
Every other woman in the joint
says that she's a slut?
Why is that?
I have great tits.
I'm not a slut.
Says you.
Another thing --
Hey!
Listen to this.
When I call a girl and I say,
"hey, we're gonna meet
For a dinner
at this particular place,"
Why can't I get off the phone
for a half an hour?
That's a sickness.
You guys have a sickness.
And -- and tell me this.
Please explain this to me.
Why is it that women feel
the need to cry
After having great sex?
Hmm?
Oh.
Yeah. Why is that?
[ laughs ]
what is up with that,
all right?
[ laughing ]
oh, my god.
What?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Well, it's a -- no,
it's a joy thing, it's not --
Oh, please.
Get the --
[ laughing ]
You're just a sad fuck,
francis.
Looks like you've been,
uh, demoted
From the 99th percentile
right there.
Yeah. Thanks, jake.
You should've been here
earlier.
You missed a great story
about jake's imaginary friend.
Okay.
So, where's your man?
Not like he's ever on time.
Better be tomorrow.
How's his dad doing?
He looks like he's aged 20 years
in the past couple months.
That's too bad.
Come on. Come on.
We got to keep this upbeat,
Make sure he has
a good night tonight.
[ sighs ] all right.
Why don't you give us
some more sex tips?
That'll cheer things up.
[ laughs ]
touche.
Where's the
little girls' room?
Thank you.
I know she cries
after having sex with him.
I'd bet good money
on that shit.
You'd like to know,
wouldn't you?
Set 'em up
for the dead-end kids.
Hey.
You been waiting long?
No.
We got here early.
Yeah. Naturelle?
Bathroom.
Hey.
These are on me.
Cheers.
Thank you, jody.
Thank you.
You guys ought to come by sunday
for my birthday party.
Yeah.
Thanks, jody.
You don't have to come.
I was just --
I was just saying.
No, thanks.
Thank you.
Fuck Sunday.
Hey.
[ siren wailing in distance ]
[ slow-tempo music plays ]
[ indistinct conversations ]
Whole city came out
to say goodbye.
You got a lot
of young fans.
Yeah.
I think we're
the oldest people here.
"we"?
[ laughs ]
[ indistinct conversations
continue ]
This is my guy.
How you doing, big man?
Mr. Man --
the man's arrived!
Coming and going
at the same time.
Seven years, man --
that shit ain't no joke.
Man, that's nervous, man.
That's the word.
Damn, you all right?
I'm trying not to think
about it, you know?
What -- what is this?
What -- what's going on here?
That's the legendary
dj dusk, man.
That's my man
from fort greene.
He's nice.
17 years old, man.
17?
Motherfucker's 17!
But he gets the girls
jumping, man.
And don't worry
about the crowd.
V.I.P.'s set up for y'all.
Don't worry about that.
These are my people here --
these guys here.
Do you want us
to come in here?
No, man, you're going
through the back, and
the door'll be open for you.
Don't worry about that.
Thank you.
Hey, listen up,
don't lose your temper
Until it's time
to lose your temper,
You hear me?
Take care of yourself.
I'll catch you
on the other side.
I'll see you
when I see you.
Hey, elinsky!
Mr. Elinsky!
Oh, my god!
What are you doing here?
Oh, my god.
I-I didn't know that you
ever left the school.
I thought that you had,
like, like a bed
Down in the boiler room
or something.
Um...
Mary d'annunzio.
Mary "b-minus" d'annunzio,
that's me.
Uh...
I-I'm kidding.
It's not a big deal.
No, it's okay.
I -- I'm here with friends,
So I have to go.
That guy who came
to class today?
He knows people, right?
I mean, so, do you think
he could get us in?
No, I don't --
I don't think --
you know, they're not
letting anyone in right now.
They say it's already
too crowded,
But I have to get in there --
I mean, I have to.
You're a fan of dusk?
Yeah, s-sure.
He's the absolute truth,
right?
I mean, he is so truth.
I can't believe
that you're into dusk.
I mean, no offense,
but, like,
I thought that you'd be
more into show tunes
Or barry manilow
or something.
No, I think -- I think dusk
is very good.
Actually I -- I mean,
I prefer his earlier work.
Hey, jake!
His earlier work?
Jake!
Yeah?
What are you doing?
I'm...
Come on. I got this guy,
he's holding the door.
We're together.
Let's go.
You're the guy
with the dog, right?
You again. Yeah.
Isn't it past your bedtime?
Oh, no. I'm with jake.
We're -- we're lovers.
Lovers? Really?
She's kidding.
Well, come on in.
There's plenty of room
for lovers.
I'm here with three friends.
Can -- can they come, too?
Girls?
No.
Mary, please.
Are you outta your mind?
We can't take a bunch of guys
in. Let's go, let's go.
She can't go in there.
No, it's good, it's good.
Monty...
What's up? These two.
Yeah, all right.
[ up-tempo hip-hop plays ]
[ indistinct conversations ]
Truth.
You know, I've seen pictures
of this room.
Like, daft punk
was in here.
So, um, who are you?
Are you someone famous?
Hey, d'annunzio,
what do you say
We give it a rest
with the questions?
Have a little champagne.
Okay.
Who's that?
One of jake's students.
What?
Enjoy.
Champagne
for my real friends...
And real pain
for my sham friends.
Cheers.       Cheers.
Cheers.                  Cheers.
[ glasses clink ]
Did you like that?
Yep.
Does anyone
want to go dance?
Come on, dance with me.
Go ahead.
No, go do it.
I'll catch up with you.
You sure?
Yeah.
Hey, daphne,
you got any whiskey?
What kind do you want?
Mccallen '18.
I'll go see
if we have some upstairs.
Hold up.
I'll come with you.
Back in a flash.
I can't believe you brought
my student in here.
Oh, come on.
Come on, she's cute.
Uh...
She's cute, she is.
She talks
a little bit too much,
But she's -- she's cute.
You're gonna get me fired.
You realize that?
Look, she's gonna tell her
friends, and then, you know,
They're gonna tell
their friends,
And they just keep talking.
What are they gonna say?
They're gonna say you met her
at a club,
You ran into her,
you talked a little bit.
Seriously, I mean, you haven't
done anything wrong yet.
What do you mean "yet"?
She's hot.
She's all over you.
I mean, she'd hop on you
in a second.
Monty...
She's 17, all right?
She's my student.
I can't, you know,
just touch her --
No, not now, but, you know,
in, like, seven months,
she'll be grad--
She'll be the age naturelle was
when I met her.
Like I said, not yet,
you know?
Okay!
Okay. Look, jake, jake,
I'm kidding.
Well, you know --
no, no, I'm giving you
a hard time.
You're smart.
You're way too smart
for that shit.
Really, you -- you've always
been smart about that stuff.
I -- I respect that.
I-I really do, I do.
Here, another sip.
I tell ya, one more of these,
and I'm, uh...
Yeah, I'm pissed.
Hey, listen, listen.
Make me a toast.
You want me to make you
a toast?
Yeah, come on.
I -- I'm not gonna see you
for a long time.
I want to have a nice memory.
Say something nice.
Okay.
Um...
Jesus.
Jake, relax.
Don't -- here, um,
here's to doyle.
To doyle.
All right.
Your dog now.
No.
Yeah.
[ laughs ]
He loves you.
Yeah?
He loves you, really, and --
and he needs a home
Yeah, I don't know.
I don't know.
'cause I'm going away.
I mean, you've seen the size
of my apartment, right?
So what?
Doyle's a tough dog.
He's seen worse, you know.
He'll learn to live
in a small space.
He'll survive.
Yeah, but what about nat?
No, no, she's -- she's moving in
with her mother.
The woman fucking hates him,
And doyle detests frank,
And my father's allergic,
so...
Saving him --
saving him --
I swear to god, the best thing
I ever did in my life
Was save that little
son of a bitch
'cause every day
that he's had since then,
That's because of me.
You know what?
Will you take him home?
Will you give him a home
while I'm gone?
I'd be honored.
Yeah?
Yeah.
[ rock music plays ]
Hoo!
This joint is jumping, boy.
There's a smorgasbord of girlies
here tonight.
And you're the talent scout,
huh?
You bet.
How you guys doing?
Good.
Hoo.
So who's that little tart
with you, jake?
My student.
Hot student.
What?
[ laughs ] no!
Not the student?
"terry's friend" --
the student?
You know what?
Remind me never to
tell you anything.
Okay, listen.
Leave him alone.
This is the only honest man
in the room.
He's doing noble work.
All right.
Party begins
without me?!
Yeah, it started without you,
you fat russian fuck.
Fat ukrainian fuck.
Yeah, is there --
there's a difference?
Monty, my friend,
you here long?
Not long.
You open shampanskoe
without me.
Hey, the clock's ticking,
kostya.
I don't have all the time
in the world.
Hello, frank.
How you doing,
kostadin?
Kostya, please --
kostya.
How you doing,
brother?
I am good.
I am better when our friend
comes back to us, no?
Jason, yes?
Jacob.
My shampanskoe, you like?
It's okay.
[ sighs deeply ]
Monty, I have beautiful woman,
very nice.
Yeah, well, I'm not really
in the mood for that.
I've got a nice girl.
I know, I know.
Tonight is special night.
Last night as free man.
I pick her out special
just for you.
The last girl you picked out
special for me had three teeth,
All in the back.
[ laughter ]
Funny you should say that.
[ continues laughing ]
Why? Why is it funny
I should say that?
What you say, it was funny.
Kostya, you can't --
when you --
It's an expression.
If you say that --
It's a, uh, euphemism,
right?
Can you explain this?
You're the english teacher.
Uh...
I think what he means, kostya,
is that when you say,
"funny you should say that,"
That means that it reminds you
of a funny story.
Exactly.
No.
No, no.
It was funny what you say --
"funny you should say that."
It still makes
no fucking sense.
This is what I deal with.
This is what I was
talking about.
I'm with you.
See? Perfectly clear.
Come.
You see her.
I don't think so.
Naturelle, she's dancing
right out here.
We go quick.
You must see this bitch.
Why don't you just find some
nice girls for my friends here?
They're on their own.
Frank?
Nah, I'm good, good.
I'm fine.
Let's just go down.
Come with me.
I'm good.
No, no, no. Forget that.
I gotta talk to you for, like,
five minutes.
All right.
You want me to stay here?
Yeah, someone's gotta look out
for naturelle
And, you know, your --
your field trip.
Should I tell nat that you're
having sex with prostitutes?
No, don't say this.
Tell her whatever you want.
Just don't go away, all right?
Hang out a minute.
We'll go uptown and get doyle.
So, what time
you wanna hook up?
I get off at 4:00.
Are we going
in the private room?
Of course,
the private room.
I'm sorry, monty.
I gotta talk to frank
for five minutes.
Just --
I'll meet you down there.
After girl, uncle nikolai
wants talk with you.
I know, I know, kostya.
Give me five minutes.
Remember,
they're waiting.
I know they're waiting!
Give me five fucking minutes!
Okay.
[ music continues ]
[ cheering ]
She looks good in silver,
huh?
Yeah.
You know, naturelle --
I've told you this, right?
She's the only girl I've ever
kept fantasizing about
After I slept with her.
Is that normal?
That's a pretty good kind
of normal.
Hey, fellas.
Tomorrow, huh?
That's right.
Nothing but a catnap.
Stay cool, brother.
Fuck.
How you doing, brother?
You all right?
Six months, you know.
Come on, now.
Six months
before I got pinched,
I was gonna come to you
with the loot --
Put me in some stocks,
put me in some mutuals.
Don't do this.
I'm gonna kick back,
watch my coin multiply.
We're gonna get rich
together.
You know, monty,
you shouldn't talk like this.
I just thought -- I thought,
"no, you know,
I can take out a little more
to live on, a little more."
I got greedy, greedy.
I just fucked myself.
Man, you're gonna wrap
yourself around in a twist,
You keep thinking
about this shit.
That's all I can do.
That's all I can do
is think about it.
I'm not gonna make it,
frank.
Yes, you will.
There's a thousand guys up there
who are harder than me.
I mean, in a -- in a room,
Some junkie
doesn't want to pay me,
And kostya behind me,
I'm pretty scary.
Up there, I'm a skinny white boy
with no friends.
Those guys are gonna use me up
and end me.
No, they won't, man.
You know why? Because you're
smarter than all of them.
You're gonna get up there,
You're gonna keep your eyes open
and your mouth shut.
You're gonna know the names,
the whole scenario.
You're gonna have the place
wired in a week.
The place is overcrowded.
They got bunk beds lined up
in the gymnasium
To handle the overflow.
I'm going in a room
with 200 other guys, frank.
So picture this --
first night, lights out.
Guards are moving out
of the space,
Looking back over their
shoulders, laughing at me,
"you are miles from home."
Door closes, boom --
I'm on the floor,
I got some big guy's knee
in my back.
I can give it a little go,
but there will be
too many of them.
Someone takes a pipe out
from under a mattress,
Starts beating me
in the face --
Not to hurt me, just to knock
all my teeth out
So I can give him head
all night,
And they don't have to worry
about me biting.
Let's say I make it through
7 years
Minus 84 days
for good behavior.
W-what then?
What kind of skills
do I have?
I can't get a job
in the straight world.
I can't go back
to doing this.
It's 15 years to life
for a second pinch.
I mean, I --
I'm gonna be a 38-year-old
punked-out ex-con
With government-issue
dentures.
38 is still young.
All right, you're gonna get out,
and you and me,
We're gonna start something
up -- you know, a fucking bar.
I mean, we're two irish kids
from brooklyn.
Where the fuck would we be
without a bar, right?
How can we not have a bar?
Come on, we have free hot dogs
on "Monday night football,"
You know?
We got an old jukebox
in the corner.
Green beer
on st. Patty's day.
Come on!
Fuck green beer, frank.
You've been working 15 years
to get away from green beer.
God, I hate this shit, too.
I'm just saying we got options,
all right?
I appreciate the thought.
I don't see it, man.
Seven years, you're gonna be
running your own show.
I don't see you
working with me.
We've known each other
since we were 3.
Have I ever broken a promise
to you, huh?
Have I ever once broken
a promise to you?
Have I ever said I'm gonna be
somewhere and not shown up?
No.
I'm gonna be there when you
get out, you hear me?
I'm gonna fucking be there.
I know you will,
But you're not gonna be
there tomorrow,
And it's all about
tomorrow.
Listen, I got one idea,
One way I might buy myself
a little room to breathe,
But I need a big favor
from you.
Cool.
[ music continues ]
[ up-tempo music plays ]
might have been lost
for trying
we have been left outside
looking at passersby
emotion blows strong...
but it's all right
if you still belong
[ saxophone solo ]
Jake the snake.
What are you doing?
Don't panic.
Nobody here gives a shit.
I give a shit.
I give a shit!
[ chuckles ]
You know what happens
if someone sees me?
Beg your pardon,
mr. Elinsky.
Are you drunk?
Yeah.
And I had some "e" earlier.
I didn't need to know that.
You know, naturelle
is cool as shit.
She knows everyone
who works here,
And I love that name,
right?
You know,
100% "naturelle."
All "naturelle" flavors.
And what's up with
her boyfriend, monty?
It's like
he owns this place.
Mary...
Do you think it
would be possible
To avoid talking about this
at school...
I mean, t-this whole night?
Do you think
it would be possible
For you to give me an "a"
for this semester?
Tell me you're joking.
I'm joking.
That's what I love about you,
elinsky.
What?
Huh?
What's what you love
about me?
Never mind.
Hey, do you think I'm weird?
No, I don't think
you're weird.
Are you allowed
to stay out this late...
You know,
on a school night?
Do you think my mother
gives a shit?
She's probably at her
boyfriend's, anyway.
I need to sleep.
Nope. Can't sleep yet.
Dusk is turning it on.
Hey...
Is there a bathroom
in here?
Is there?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Where is it?
It's, um...
Right up the stairs.
Back there.
[ instrumental music,
indistinct conversations
continue ]
[ knocking ]
You need to pee?
No.
[ breathing heavily ]
[ sighs ]
but it's all right
if you still belong
Hey.
Can I ask you a favor?
Mm-hmm.
Keep an eye on monty tonight,
would you?
Try to stick with him.
What's the matter?
He's just acting...
Really strange.
He's going to prison
in a couple hours.
How do you want him to act?
I want him to act
like he's scared.
Well, he is scared,
naturelle.
Believe me, he's scared.
I just don't want him
to hurt himself.
So will you watch him
for me?
I don't think
he wants me here.
Why? Why wouldn't he
want you here?
You see the way
he looks at me lately?
[ sighs ] it's like
he doesn't trust me.
What reason does he have
not to trust you?
I'm gonna go up top,
francis.
So when you see him,
just --
Cool.
I got it.
Hey.
Are you all right?
How could he do this, huh?
Just throw it all away?
I'm his oldest friend.
What'd I do to stop it?
What'd I say to him?
Nothing.
Not a word.
You know, when he
started selling weed to
the kids at coventry,
I didn't say shit.
Everybody's talking about
buying from monty,
You know,
the whole school,
And I knew they were gonna
nail him, I -- I knew it.
I didn't say a word.
Fucking last 10 years,
I've been watching him
Get deeper and deeper in
with these friends of his,
These fucks who you wouldn't
want petting doyle.
And did I say,
"hey, careful, monty,
You know,
you better cool out, man"?
I didn't say shit.
I just sat there and watched
him ruin his life.
And you did, too, all right?
We both did.
We all did.
Monty never listens.
Uh-huh.
You know how stubborn he is,
okay?
I told monty he should quit
a hundred times.
Did you? Was that before
or after you moved into
his apartment, huh?
Look, come on, of all nights,
please not tonight.
Just don't start.
Who paid for the apartment,
naturelle?
I need a drink.
[ indistinct conversations ]
[ knocks ]
j.D., shot.
Was that before
or after he gave you
that platinum necklace?
Do you want to watch
your mouth?
Who paid for the cartier
diamond earrings...
This silver dress
you're wearing?
Paid in full by the addictions
of other people.
Back up.
That's what I'm saying.
You two fly down to san juan,
first class all the way.
What do you think
paid for puerto rico?
You've never been to p--
listen to me.
You've never been to p.R.
In your life before monty.
You told him to quit?
The hell you did,
naturelle.
Back up.
You knew the deal
the minute you met him.
Come on.
You never had a real job
in your whole life.
You've been living
off the fat of the land.
And you never said
a goddamn word.
Who are you to get
all righteous with me?
Huh?
Did you disown him?
You're his best friend,
and you never said a thing.
But this is my fault?
I'm the evil one?
I never took his money.
Never once, not a red --
How long have you been
saving this, huh?
I came over here to talk
to my friend francis.
One minute ago,
you were my friend.
Are you drunk?
Tell me you've been
drinking too much,
You don't know
what you're saying.
You're fucking drunk.
I'm irish.
I can't get drunk,
all right?
I know exactly
what I'm saying.
Seven years from now,
I'll be at the prison gate.
You'll be married to monty.
Right or wrong?
What is wrong with you?
You want me to be
the bad guy?
Fine, I'm the bad guy.
Are you happy now?
[ indistinct conversation ]
[ sighs ]
God, francis.
[ glasses clinking ]
All I'm saying...
Is you knew
where he hid the money.
[ clinking continues ]
You knew where he hid
the drugs, didn't you?
What the hell
are you saying?
are you saying
right now, francis?
You know exactly
what I'm saying.
I told monty
when he first met you,
But he wouldn't listen
to me.
I told him,
"naturelle riviera...
She ain't nothin'
but a spic skank skeezer."
Nat.
[ sighs ]
[ indistinct conversations ]
I've been looking
all over for you.
Bartender: another one?
Here you go.
Is she all right?
[ breathing heavily ]
[ bottle clinks ]
Can we get out of here?
Nope. We gotta wait
for monty.
I kissed her.
You what?
My student, I --
I kissed her.
Who you trying to be --
r. Kelly?
[ indistinct conversations ]
I kissed my 17-year-old
high school student.
Jake...
Have a drink.
Shut the fuck up.
Excuse me. Could I --
could I have a water?
Fuck that.
Hit him.
Sure.
Okay.
[ sighs ]
I don't want to drink
anymore, frank.
Give him the whiskey.
Shut up.
Drink it.
[ rock music plays in distance ]
[ door closes ]
Montgomery, how's the party?
Nice. Thanks
for setting it up.
The first time
I went to prison...
I was 14 years old.
Skinny little boy...
Very afraid.
By the time I came out,
I had a beard.
I was grown man.
I went back
to my hometown.
I found my mother.
I kissed her.
And she screamed.
She didn't recognize me.
[ music continues ]
[ inhales ]
I have been in three
different prisons,
montgomery.
Three different countries.
And you know
what I learned?
I learned prison
is a bad place to be.
Seven years is a long time.
Some men would do anything
To avoid seven years
in prison.
Your father
is a hardworking man.
Where's his bar?
Staten island?
2192 bay street?
He drives in from
bay ridge --
A 1986 jeep grand wagoneer.
Should I tell you
how many miles
he has on the car?
[ speaks russian ]
Your father...
I like your father...
A hardworking man.
[ inhales deeply ]
He's had bad luck.
Everyone in the neighborhood
loved your mother.
Da?
Yeah.
Everyone said
she was a beautiful woman.
I want to help your father.
I could use a man like that,
a hardworking man,
A man I could trust.
I could take care
of your father.
Do you understand
what I mean, montgomery?
You don't have to do this.
You don't --
I never said anything
to anybody, okay?
Leave my father out of it.
I asked you a question,
montgomery.
Yeah. I understand
exactly what you mean.
I have a good job
for your father.
We'll help him
with the money he owes.
No, thank you.
[ music continues ]
[ sighs ]
Good weapon.
Accurate.
And reliable.
No jams.
Have you ever fired
a gun?
At someone, I mean.
No.
It's a toy for you.
Not toy, a prop.
A prop for you, like an actor.
Am I wrong?
With the gun,
you feel more...Dangerous.
I wouldn't know.
It's not mine.
[ gun cocks ]
I didn't say anything.
I never said anything,
nikolai.
I swear to god.
They came after me
to get to you.
I know that.
You know that.
They tried.
I never said anything.
I believe you,
montgomery.
[ gun uncocks ]
This is my advice to you --
When you get there,
figure it out who's who.
Find the man
nobody's protecting --
A man without friends --
And beat him
until his eyes bleed.
Let them think
you are a little bit crazy,
But respectful, too.
Respectful of the right men.
You are a good-looking boy.
It won't be easy for you.
But remember, I was 14
when I first went.
[ speaks russian ]
I tattooed "survive"
on my hand
The night before
I went away to prison.
And I did.
[ inhales ]
We do what we have to do
to survive.
[ speaking russian ]
Ugh!
Uhh!
Uhhh!
Monty, please!
Monty!
Now we have
this other problem.
How many people knew
you kept the stuff
inside the sofa, huh?
Your girlfriend
and kostya. Nobody else.
Get him up.
Ugh!
Kostya ratted you out,
little brother.
He made the call
And stole seven years
from your life.
They put the clamps on him.
And instead of being a man
about it,
He sold you out!
Kostya: do not listen
to them!
It's not true.
You know how to use it?
Yeah, I know how to use it.
Good. This man does not
deserve to live.
Kostya:
please. Don't do this.
He betrayed you.
He betrayed me.
No, please.
He stole from you.
He stole seven years
from you.
Monty, please!
End him.
Please.
No, no, no.
No, don't do this!
Shut up!
No!
Don't talk!
You motherfucker.
They're lying.
Why'd you do it?!
Why did you do it?!
You let me think
it was her?!
Why'd you tell me
Don't do this.
it was her?!
Kill this cockroach!
Why?!
No, no, no, no, monty!
No!
Why?! Why?!
Please!
Why did you tell me
it was her?!
Do it!
I had no choice!
I had no choice, monty!
Why?!
Please.
Why?! Why?!
[ music continues ]
[ groaning ]
I had no choice.
You told me
to trust this man,
I trusted this man.
Now I'm gone seven.
Clean up
your own fucking mess.
Be careful.
You do whatever you want
with him.
When I walk out this door,
I'm done.
I'm out
and my father's out.
You are being foolish.
You gonna let me go
or not?
Remember what I told you.
A man...With no friends.
No, monty, please.
Monty, come on.
Believe me. Please.
You were my friend.
[ man speaking russian ]
Please, monty, I'm sorry.
Don't leave me.
Come on.
You are missing your party.
Please.
No!
[ music continues ]
[ groaning ]
You know what time it is?
Eh?
Do you know what time
it is?
Late at night.
No, it's early.
You up for a little more
still?
Yeah.
Yeah. Definitely.
Hey.
[ keys jingling ]
Come here.
[ sighs deeply ]
Hey, there's jake.
Remember jake?
Yeah. Go see jake.
[ slow music plays ]
Hey, what time is it?
I still got a couple
of hours.
I'm sorry for everything
I've been putting you
through, naturelle.
I've been confused.
I've been...
Thinking that you...
It doesn't matter.
Yeah. It matters to me.
I don't want you to hate me
when I'm gone.
I could never hate you,
montgomery.
I love you.
Hey, stay with me.
I got one last thing
I gotta do.
Don't go.
I'll be back.
[ inhales ]
[ exhales ]
[ horn blows ]
Monty: wouldn't that
be the life, huh?
Jake: yeah.
Working a tugboat,
Be out on the river
every morning.
Yeah. It'd be nice.
It'd be nice.
What time you got?
Quarter past 6:00.
All right.
Come on.
[ birds chirping ]
Ready for mr. Doyle?
Yeah.
The leash is yours.
I need you to make me ugly.
I can't go in there
looking like this.
I already told you.
It's all about the first day.
If they get one look at me
looking like this,
I'll be finished.
Come on. This is --
you said anything.
You just said
you'd do anything.
This is what I need.
What are you thinking?
I'm gonna give you
a black eye,
And nobody's gonna mess
with you? Come on.
I need a lot more
than a black eye, pal.
Would you fucking
help me out here?
I need you
to really fuck me up.
I can't do it.
[ footsteps departing ]
I think you can.
I'm not gonna hit you,
monty.
You know what?
I think you want to
a little bit.
What?
You think I deserve it
a little bit.
I think you have
for years.
I'm not doing it.
You've been giving me that
look like, you know,
You want to smack
some sense into me.
Well, this is your chance.
I need it, frank.
This is your favor --
"make me ugly"?!
What the -- where the hell
is this coming from, man?!
It's bullshit!
Don't pussy out on me,
frank.
I need this from you.
Now, I'm not --
I'm not gonna fight back.
I'm not gonna be --
I'm not gonna kick you --
What the -- what the fuck
do you want from me, man?!
This is insane!
Shut up!
Nobody's talking to you!
I mean it!
Stay out of it!
All right, enough!
This is bullshit!
I'm gonna go
get some breakfast.
I'm gonna forget this shit.
No breakfast.
Hey!
Listen to me.
Don't do this, monty.
What is all this bullshit
you've been feeding me?
"I'm gonna be there
for you, monty"?
I'm here for you, man.
"I'll be there
when you walk out."
Frank...
He doesn't know
what he's doing.
I think this whole situation's
convenient for you.
You know what?
That's what I think.
What do you mean
"convenient"?
You're gonna send me away,
say, "bye, monty,"
So you can take care
of naturelle for me.
Is that
what this is about?
I would never fucking cross
the line with her, man!
Oh, bullshit!
You're full of shit!
Frank, he doesn't mean it.
You think I don't see
the way you look at her,
at her titties, at her ass?
Come on, you asshole.
You've been wanting
to fuck her for years.
Don't fucking do this,
man!
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Stop it!
Aah!
[ doyle barking ]
Don't do this!
Do it!
No!
Do it,
you fucking pussy!
Do it!
[ barking ]
Aah! Aah!
[ crying ]
no!
Stop! Frank, stop!
[ coughing ]
You're gonna kill him!
Frank.
Stop!
Frank!
Aaahhhh!
[ sobbing ]
Frank...Frank...
[ crying ]
I'm sorry!
Come on.
That's enough. Stop.
[ wings fluttering ]
[ birds chirping ]
[ chirping continues ]
[ fluttering continues ]
[ barking ]
[ sniffling ]
Oh, fuck.
[ coughing ]
[ spits ]
[ barking ]
Oh, my god.
Monty! Oh, my god!
It's all right.
Just get me inside.
Get me inside.
Of course I will.
Oh.
Oh, my god, baby.
Oh, my god.
Oh, god, monty,
let me take you
to the hospital.
Why'd you stay with me
all this time?
You should have left
a long time ago.
Stop talking like that.
I'll wait for you.
As long as it takes.
[ crying ]
Don't cry, baby.
I'm such an idiot.
Oh.
Naturelle, I blew it.
I really blew it.
[ crying continues ]
[ knock on door ]
Who's that?
Who did this to you?
I gotta go.
Let him take you
to the hospital, baby.
It's okay.
Oh, god.
How did this happen?
I don't know.
He just showed up like this.
[ sighs ]
monty...
He's a mess.
God, look at him.
Oh, god.
These people are hooligans.
I'll take him
to the hospital.
Say goodbye here, pop.
You don't trust
my driving?
I can't do it this way.
You just gotta let me
walk away, pop.
Please. It's easier.
Yeah. Easier?
My god,
you don't understand.
Let me drive you there.
I need to know where it is
for visits, you know?
O-okay, buddy?
Help me out.
Help me out?
Okay.
Give me the bag.
No hospital, pop.
No hospital.
Let's go.
[ door opens ]
I gotta go.
Wait one second.
Wait, wait, wait.
[ ice cubes rattling ]
No, no.
I don't want you coming up
there to visit me.
No.
I want you to be happy,
So I want you to forget
about me and live your life.
Mnh...
[ crying ]
[ door closes ]
I figure we take
the henry hudson
To the sprainbrook parkway,
Then to the taconic.
That should get us there.
Easy drive to otisville.
Ow.
Aw, jesus,
look what they did to you.
I tell you what, monty,
it's gonna be okay.
It looks bad, I know it.
But, you know,
when the swelling goes down,
It's gonna be okay.
Yeah.
Them hooligans sure give you
a licking, though, huh?
How many were there?
I don't know, pop.
There was a bunch of 'em.
You get some good shots in?
Yeah, I got
some good shots in.
Ah, give it a month.
You'll be better looking
than ever.
Hey, pop...
You were right.
It wasn't her.
It wasn't naturelle.
Of course it wasn't
naturelle.
[ engine turns over ]
[ horn blows ]
[ slow music plays ]
Cool dog.
[ music continues ]
Give me the word,
and I'll take a left turn.
Left turn to where?
Take the gw bridge
and go west.
Get you stitched up
somewhere and keep going.
Find a nice little town.
On the way, stop in chicago
for a cubs game.
You always told me
you wanted to see
wrigley field.
Dad...
I'm saying
that if you want it...
If that's what you want,
I'll do it.
No, they'd take your bar.
My bar.
Jesus. My bar.
They can take my bar
to hell and back.
You think my bar is more
important to me than you,
My only child?
Give me the word,
and we'll go.
They'll find me.
They'll find me
sooner or later.
You know
how they find people?
They find them
when they come home.
People run away,
but they usually come back.
That's when they get caught.
So you go...
And you never come back.
You never come home.
We'll drive.
We'll keep driving.
Head out to the middle
of nowhere.
Take that road
as far as it takes us.
You've never been west
of philly, have you?
This is a beautiful
country, monty.
It's beautiful out there.
Looks like
a different world --
Mountains, hills,
cows, farms,
And white churches.
I drove out west
with your mother one time
Before you was born.
Brooklyn to the pacific
in three days.
Just enough money for gas,
sandwiches, and coffee,
But we made it.
Every man, woman,
and child alive
Should see the desert
one time before they die.
[ bird squawks ]
Nothing at all
for miles around,
Nothing but sand and rocks
and cactus and blue sky.
Not a soul in sight.
No sirens, no car alarms,
nobody honking at you,
No madman cursing
or pissing on the streets.
You find the silence
out there.
You find the peace.
You can find god.
ye'll take the high road
and I'll take the low road
and I'll be in scotland
afore ye
but me and my true love
will never meet again
on the bonnie, bonnie banks
of loch lomond
So, we drive west.
Keep driving till we find
a nice little town.
These towns
out in the desert --
You know why they got there?
People wanted to get away
from somewhere else.
The desert's
for starting over.
Find a bar,
and I'll buy us drinks.
[ indistinct conversations ]
Two.
I haven't had a drink
in two years,
But I'll have one with you.
One last whiskey
with my boy.
Take our time with it --
Taste the barley,
let it linger.
[ laughing ]
And then I'll go.
I want you to keep that.
I'll hold it for you.
I'll tell you,
"don't ever write me.
Don't ever come visit."
I'll tell you, "I believe
in god's kingdom,
"and I believe
I'll be with you again
and your mother,
But not in this lifetime."
[ birds chirping ]
[ slow music plays ]
[ engine turns over ]
You get a job somewhere...
A job that pays cash,
A boss who doesn't
ask questions.
And you make a new life
and you never come back.
Monty, people like you.
It's a gift.
You make friends
wherever you go.
How you fellas doin'?
Two beers.
You're gonna work hard.
You're gonna keep
your head down
and your mouth shut.
You're gonna make yourself
a new home out there.
Here you go, james.
Thanks a lot.
You're a new yorker.
That will never change.
You got new york
in your bones.
Spend the rest of your life
out west,
But you're still
a new yorker.
You'll miss your friends,
you'll miss your dog,
But you're strong.
You got your mother's
backbone in you.
You're strong like she was.
Hey.
You find the right people,
And you get yourself
papers.
Why don't you go ahead
and have a seat?
A driver's license.
What's your name?
Uh, james.
James. Not from around here,
are you?
No, I'm from out west.
Well, let's go ahead
and get your picture.
Be still.
Give me a smile. Okay.
Why don't you give me
a bigger smile, james?
Come on, big, bigger.
Okay.
You forget your old life.
You can't come back.
You can't call.
You can't write.
You never look back.
You make a new life
for yourself,
And you live it.
You hear me?
You live your life the way
it should have been.
And maybe...
This is dangerous,
But maybe after
a couple of years,
You send word
to naturelle.
[ laughs ]
Mmm. Oh.
[ laughing ]
4...
Both: 3...2...1.
Happy new year.
Mmm.
Feel that right there.
Your mother's a lunatic.
[ laughs ]
Hurry up.
I need company.
[ bell ringing,
whistle blowing ]
You get yourself
a new family,
And you raise them right,
you hear me?
Give them a good life,
monty.
Give them what they need.
You have a son.
Maybe you name him james.
It's a good, strong name.
And maybe one day,
years from now,
Long after
I'm dead and gone,
Reunited with
your dear mother,
You gather
your whole family together
And tell them the truth,
Who you are
and where you come from.
We were in new york
together.
You tell them
the whole story.
I was arrested.
And then you ask them
If they know how lucky
they are to be there.
All of you...
It all came so close
to never happening.
...Came so close
This life came so close
to never happening.
[ man vocalizing ]
[ introduction
to bruce springsteen's
"the fuse" plays ]
down at the courthouse,
they're ringin' the flag down
down
long black line of cars
snakin' slow through town
town
red sheets
snappin' on the line
line
with this ring,
will you be mine?
the fuse is burning
shut out the lights
come on,
let me do you right
trees on fire
with the first fall's frost
long black line
in front of holy cross
blood moon risin' in a sky
of black dust
dust
tell me, baby,
who do you trust?
the fuse is burning
shut out the lights
come on,
let me do you right
tires on the highway hissin',
something's coming
you can feel the wires
in the treetops hummin'
devil's on the horizon line
your kiss and I'm alive
a quiet afternoon,
an empty house
house
on the edge of bed,
you slip off your blouse
the room is burning
with the noon sun
sun, sun
your bittersweet taste
on my tongue
tongue
the fuse is burning
shut out the lights
come on,
let me do you right
the fuse is burning
shut out the lights
come on,
let me do you right
the fuse is burning
[ dog barking ]