[WHEEZING]
[MATCH STRIKES]
[WHEEZING CONTINUES]
[SHOUTING IN DISTANCE]
[HORSES GALLOPING IN DISTANCE]
[DOGS BARKING]
[GUNS COCK]
WOMAN [WHISPERING]:
Dan...
Maybe it's the wind.
[MAN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE]
[CATTLE MOOING]
[HORSES NEIGHING]
No!
Stop!
Please! Stop!
[GRUNTS]
MAN:
Tucker!
You have a week, Evans.
Then we burn the house.
William?
Hey! William!
[HORSES NEIGHING]
Out. Out!
William!
God damn it,
William! William!
Goddamn it!
Put that down!
Come here!
Let go!
It's the last feed we got!
[CATTLE MOOING]
[MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE]
I'll take care of this.
No, you won't.
Herd's over the ridge
by now.
You go get cleaned up.
[SIGHS]
You lied to me, Dan.
You told me we made
payments to Hollander.
We did...some.
How do you think
we bought feed, Alice?
Three months water?
Medicine for Mark?
I had a choice between our
family and paying it down.
We're supposed to make
decisions together.
Would you have made it
any different?
Alice, we can't
make it rain together.
Or turn the dust
into grass.
Can't stop Hollander from selling
our land to the railroad, either.
It's too bad the doctors at
Essex saved so much of my leg.
I read that the pension act
pays by the pound now.
[CHUCKLES]
Stop looking at me like that.
You gonna tell the marshal
what those men did?
WILLIAM:
Marshal ain't doing shit.
William.
First thing, Mark,
I'm gonna take you boys, and
we're gonna round up the herd,
and then I'm goin' into town.
What are you gonna do in town?
I'm gonna tell Hollander
to make this right.
I'm gonna tell him...
to pay for a new barn.
Maybe we should just shoot
him like Will says.
Coach is headed
for Bisbee, Boss.
Girded with iron,
Pinks on top,
double shotguns,
and a Gatling.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
[MEN CHATTERING]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[HORSE GRUNTS]
You shoulda let me save the feed.
[COW MOOING]
You gonna hock that?
Someday, William...
you walk in my shoes,
you might understand.
I ain't ever walking
in your shoes.
MARK:
Tracks over here.
[COW MOANS]
[GUNSHOTS]
Here we go.
Kenny, here we go.
Here they come.
[GUNSHOTS]
Yah!
Pull that way!
Now that one!
[MEN SHOUTING]
Use the gun.
Don't let 'em get it.
Aah!
Mark, stay near.
Mark!
Yah! Yah!
Goddamn!
Giddyap!
Yah!
Get down. Now!
Look out!
Here I come!
[GATLING GUN FIRING]
[MOOING]
Yah! Yah!
Knock on 'em, Nonnie. Knock on 'em.
Keep 'em goin'.
Pull up. Pull up.
Pull up!
[COCKS GUN]
[SHELLS CLATTER]
Morning, Pinkerton.
Name's Charlie Prince.
I expect you heard
of me.
[GRUNTS]
Well, I heard of a...
balled-up whore named...
Charlie Princess.
That you, missy?
[GRUNTS]
I hate Pinkertons.
Byron McElroy.
When did your hair
turn all gray, Byron?
[COUGHS]
Go to hell, Ben Wade.
Well, would you look
at all this?
Y'all spared no expense
this time, Byron.
I gotta say, though,
it's probably cheaper
just to let me rob
the damn thing.
If you're gonna kill me,
just as soon get to it.
I ain't gonna kill you.
Not like this.
Won't change a thing,
lettin' me live.
I'll come for you.
[COUGHING]
I'd be disappointed
if you didn't.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
MAN: She's lit!
[FUSE CRACKLING]
MAN #2:
She's lit!
[WHISTLES]
All right, boys.
There you go.
It's full.
All right,
there you go.
Come on, give me one.
One more.
I'll ask you
to put down the money.
You step back!
You men step back!
All of you step back right
now, or this man dies!
Not a smart move,
friend.
Shit.
He's fast.
Well, Tommy...
it seems that
there was a Pinkerton...
inside that coach
that wasn't quite dead yet.
Now, I know Charlie
told you, because...
we done got but a few rules
in this outfit.
And this is what happens
when you put us all at risk.
Mark, look at me.
Look at me.
Keep lookin' at me.
Back up quietly.
Back-- William!
William, look at me.
Back up.
[ROCKS FALLING]
William, look at me.
[WHISTLES]
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Morning.
Those are my cattle.
I want 'em back.
[CHUCKLES]
Careful, rancher, that's Ben
Wade you're talking to.
Well, I need 'em back.
They're all I got.
I don't need your cattle.
But I will be needi''
them horses.
So you don't go doing
nothing...foolish.
Campos.
You'll find them
on the road to Bisbee.
Boys.
[WATCH TICKING]
They're probably just running
late, Mr. Butterfield.
Pinkertons don't run late.
That's why they're paid
$18 a day.
[DISTANT SHOUTS]
[GRUNTING]
Get me on my feet.
I think you're
in pretty bad shape, mister.
You should--
Just get me on my damn feet.
[GROANING]
Mark, William,
get me some of them boards.
Can I help you?
I think maybe...
a coach headed for here
got itself held up
in the canyon
about 10 miles back...
God damn it.
...by Mr. Ben Wade himself.
How did you know
it was Wade?
It's been him the last
21 times, Marshal.
I saw a Mexican sharpshooter
and an Apache.
God damn it. Jesus Christ.
And I've been told--
Did you see
The Hand of God?
What's that?
His pistol.
Why the hell didn't
you do something?
They had a lot
of weapons, mister...
and they were
shootin' bullets.
Let's go.
We're wasting time.
Where you from, anyway?
Tom Conrad bought
a thousand head in Mexico.
Hired us to drive 'em in.
Let's go.
Come on, boys.
Something's going on
with the railroad man.
Ma'am? Some whiskey
for my friends.
Let's go.
Huh?
The bar's closed.
Already?
[WHISKEY POURING]
[POURING]
Here's to the four
we lost in battle.
And here's
to the boss,
who...
had to say good-bye
to Tommy Darden today.
And that's too bad.
Proverbs 13:3.
"He that keepeth his mouth,
"keepeth his life.
"He that opens
his lips too wide
shall bring on
his own destruction."
Amen.
Tommy was weak.
Tommy was stupid.
Tommy is dead.
I'd drink to that.
Sutherland.
Jorgensen.
Campos.
Jackson.
Kinter.
Marshal's only half stupid.
He's gonna be back soon.
They're going
across the border.
I won't be far.
I'll wait for you.
All right, Charlie.
I've seen you
someplace before.
Have you?
You ever work for a blind
Irishman in Leadville?
I was a singer.
The best time
I ever had
in my whole life.
What made you quit?
Got to coughing.
Doctor said I should find
a drier climate.
You know, I spent more money in
that joint than I could tell you.
Do you remember a girl?
Her name was Velvet.
Nobody forgets Velvet.
You look kinda skinny.
I feel skinny.
That's all right.
I don't mind skinny girls.
Long as they got green eyes
to make up for it.
Have you got green eyes?
That's all right.
They don't have
to be green.
Do you think they lied?
Do you think they stole
our horses?
They don't need
our shit horses.
Watch your mouth.
I'll take him into town
on my own.
You boys go round up
the herd.
Don't push them too hard.
I can't afford any more dropping.
Mister, we're gonna have
to lift you up
to get you on top
of that horse.
Here comes the Cavalry.
Do as I said.
Is he from the coach?
Only one who made it.
Mr. McElroy,
can you hear me?
It was Ben Wade.
Mr. McElroy,
can you hear me?
Mr. Mc--
This man needs attention.
You see which way
he rode, Evans?
Looked like they
were headed to Bisbee.
MAN [IN DISTANCE]:
Hey! Yah!
Hey!
You know...
there's a little town
just south of the border...
pretty little pueblucho
down by the river.
Folks would pay good money
to hear a white woman sing.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah.
Imagine me shinning
on down to Mexico
with Ben Wade on my arm.
I'm not wanted
in Mexico.
Jump out that back window
with me now.
You're crazy.
You the doctor?
Yes.
Coach got held up.
Get him on the table.
[SIGHS]
What's his name?
Byron McElroy.
He's a bounty hunter under
contract with the Pinkertons.
DOCTOR: You've lost a lot
of blood, Mr. McElroy.
That bullet's still
in there.
Well, get it out.
All right.
[MOANS]
Now, what I'm about to do is gonna
hurt like a son of a bitch.
Ain't the first time
I been shot.
Hold him, please.
Don't touch me.
DOCTOR:
All right.
[EXHALES]
[SQUELCHING]
[GROANING]
[EXHALES]
What the fuck kind of
doctor are you, anyway?
It's nice to have a conversation
with a patient for a change.
[CHUCKLES]
MAN: You see
anything down there?
[MAN WHISTLES]
Marshal.
Wade's horse.
Take the back.
We'll take the front.
What the hell
are they looking for?
Ben Wade.
He held up
the payroll coach.
I want to talk,
Mr. Hollander.
Ben Wade in Bisbee.
Shit.
We're movin' up.
Mr. Hollander?
Tucker, go on
to the saloon.
You got no right
to do what you done.
You hear me?
That's my land.
Come next week
it's not, Evans.
You borrowed
a good deal of money
and I got rights
to recompense.
But you dammed up my creek.
You shut off my water.
How'd you expect me to pay
off my debts if you can't--
Before the water
touches your land,
it resides and flows
on mine.
And as such, I can do with
it as I fuckin' please.
Go home and pack up.
Can you--
Can you just
let me get to spring?
I can turn the corner.
Sometimes a man has to be big
enough to see how small he is.
Railroad's coming, Dan.
Your land's worth more
with you off it.
[CHUCKLES]
[COCKS RIFLE]
Hollander!
[SIGHS]
You look a little
bent, rancher.
You come to wake
some snakes?
WOMAN:
Dan, would you like a drink?
No, thanks.
You got your horses back,
didn't you?
And your cattle?
Yeah, I got
my horses back.
But you killed
two of my herd.
Well, they died
for a good cause.
You know...
them beeves of yours,
they wouldn't even
have fed a hungry dog.
I tell you what.
[COINS SLIDING]
That should cover it.
How much you get
for a day's work?
$2 when I hire out.
Well, there are $2
for a half a day.
[COINS CLATTER]
You took up
my boys' time, too.
You're right, I did.
[COINS CLINKING]
[COINS SLIDING]
Anything else you wanna
get paid for, Dan?
You can give me
$5 extra.
And what's that for?
For making me nervous.
[WOOD CREAKING]
Hands up, Ben Wade.
Boss! Boss!
Hey, Boss!
Gimme your hands,
Mr. Wade.
Tucker, take his gun.
TUCKER: Gimme that.
Ben Wade...
captured in Bisbee.
Be careful
with that thing.
That gun's got
a curse on it.
[CHUCKLES]
Laugh while you can.
Crawley, go get the wagon.
Make sure every weapon we got
is shoot-ready.
I'll meet you out front
of the office.
We gotta get him
outta here.
Sure thing.
I think we should
shoot him right now.
Hmm?
Put a bullet right
in his noggin.
Do that...everybody
in this shit-piss
little town
will be dead by morning.
22 robberies.
Over $400,000
in losses.
More in delays.
The Southern Pacific
will have Ben Wade convicted
in a federal court.
Hanged in public.
An example made.
And we will pay
to make it happen.
Y'all notice he didn't mention
any of the lives I've taken.
MARSHAL:
I need three more men.
You can have Tucker.
Good.
I'm coming.
You only need one.
MARSHAL: You're
wounded, Mr. McElroy.
I rode in here.
Sure as hell can ride out.
He goes,
Potter's coming.
What?
[SCOFFS]
Doc can't shoot shit.
DAN: I was best
shot in my regiment.
I'll come...
for $200.
You fight for the North
or the South?
North.
We're Southern
in name,
but Chicago owned.
Fine. $200.
MARSHAL:
Let's go.
Thank you.
Thank me when it's done.
MAN:
What's goin' on?
DRIVER:
Whoa! Whoa!
This town's gonna burn!
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
Let's get him, Mark!
Cover me!
[MEN SHOUTING]
MAN:
Shoot!
Get him!
Get in the coach.
God damn it.
Evans, Crawley, Tucker,
you need to mount up now.
Head for Evans Ranch.
I'll meet you there
with the coach.
How long does he have
to be here?
An hour...
to make sure his outfit
takes the bait.
[LOUD CLATTER]
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[CATTLE MOOING]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
Hello, there!
Evans! Can you give me
a hand with this?
Whatever your wife's
cooking in there,
it smells good,
Evans.
[COCKS GUN]
Let's go.
Good driving, Marshal.
Remind me not to play poker
in this town.
All right, Marshal.
Give us a count.
One, two, three.
Yah!
Whoa.
Good luck.
You're gonna check
on my family
when you come back, right?
First thing.
Let's go.
Hyah!
Ma'am.
Byron...
what an unpleasant surprise.
What happens if they
catch the wagon?
Well...
you saw where his man was.
He still gotta go
fetch the outfit.
Marshal's got a fast rig.
They should reach
the fort before dawn.
His gang can't do anything in
front of the whole 6th Cavalry.
Did you have something
to do with that?
I hope you're proud
of yourself.
Just doin' my job, Doc.
Thanks, son.
We always wait to say grace.
We don't presume to teach
other people manners.
Aren't we supposed to say
grace for murderers, too?
Grace is
for everyone, dear.
Then why don't we say it?
Mark.
MCELROY:
I'd like to hear it.
God our Father,
Lord, and Savior,
thank You for Your
love and favor.
Please bless this drink
and food, we pray.
Bless all who shares
with us today.
Amen.
If my pa wants to,
he could shoot you dead.
He can shoot a jackrabbit
at 50 yards.
[CHUCKLES]
Shooting an animal's
a lot different
than, uh,
shooting a man, son.
WADE:
No, it isn't.
Not in my opinion.
We could ask Byron here.
Now, Byron, he's killed
dozens of people:
men and women
and children,
miners, Apache.
Not a soul taken
didn't deserve what it got.
Every way of man is right
in his own eyes, Byron.
The Lord ponders the heart.
Proverbs 21.
Dan.
WADE: You eat more when you're
nervous, Mr. Butterfield?
Oh, why, thank you, Dan.
That would be pleasant
and kind of you.
Much appreciated.
You can cut
that up for me.
Oh, can you cut
the fat off there?
I don't particularly
like the fat at all.
[MUTTERING]
I-I just--
And the--
And the gristle.
I don't like
the gristle.
You mind if I ask you how you got
that hitch in your step, Dan?
BYRON: Don't tell him nothing,
Mr. Evans.
Where were you stationed?
Second Company
Sharpshooters
out of Lynnfield,
Massachusetts.
My father was defending
the U.S. capitol
in the District
of Columbia.
Is that so?
Well, Dan,
tell me the story
of how you lost your leg.
Did it get shot off,
cut off?
The Indians steal it?
[GUNSHOTS]
There's something moving
out there in the grass.
There ain't nothing.
MAN [IN DISTANCE]:
I think I saw something over the ridge.
What if they caught
the coach already?
What if they already know
it's Crawley inside?
You ever been
to San Francisco?
If it's all right
by you, Mr. Wade,
I'd rather we not talk.
So you've never been
to San Francisco.
No.
I knew a girl there.
She was the daughter
of a sea captain.
She had the most
beautiful green eyes,
about the greenest eyes
I ever saw.
Like yours.
And I'd stare deep
into them.
They'd just change
color in front of me.
All the colors
of the sea.
What did you say
your name was again?
Alice?
Alice.
For God's sake.
He's killed more men
than the drought.
He's not what I expected.
He's--
He's dangerous.
Dangerous is what
he is, Alice.
I don't want you or the
boys talking to him.
You can change
your mind, Dan.
No one will
think less of you.
No one can think less of me.
Six months from now,
everything's
going to be green.
The cows are
going to be fat.
We might even see
the steam
from the train
coming over the ridge.
We'll be all right.
But we won't make it
through the next six days
if I don't do this.
[KNOCKING]
Sorry, Dan.
McElroy says
five minutes.
You think
he's too much for me?
He's a killer, Daniel.
Then someone ought
to have the decency
to bring him to justice.
[SCOFFS]
What are you thinking?
I'm not out there alone,
you know.
Have a little faith in me.
Ben Wade has a gang,
and they're out there
tonight somewhere.
If I don't go, we got
to pack up and leave,
and God knows where,
without a prayer,
dirt-poor.
Now I'm tired, Alice.
I am tired of watching
my boys go hungry.
I'm tired of the way
that they look at me.
that you don't.
I've been standing
on one leg
for three damn years,
waiting for God
to do me a favor.
And He ain't listening.
[KNOCKING]
BUTTERFIELD:
Mr. Evans.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
This is my horse now.
Come on over here.
Come on.
Don't you
be any trouble, Mark.
Yes, sir.
All right.
William.
I want to come
with you.
Well, you can't.
I could help.
You're 14 years old.
Look, I can ride faster
and shoot better
than any one of them.
The Pinkerton's hurt,
Potter's no good,
that railroad man's
dead weight,
and that other bastard--
William.
I don't have time
to argue.
I need you here.
That's that.
So, boys,
where are we headed?
Ain't none of your business
where we're headed, Wade.
You're a prisoner.
You don't speak,
you don't piss,
you don't goddamn breathe
unless we say so.
You understand that?
We're taking you
to Contention.
Putting you on the 3:10 to Yuma
day after tomorrow.
You shouldn't have
told him that.
Relax, friend.
Now if we get separated,
I know where to meet up.
I'd like to thank you
for your hospitality, ma'am.
Hope I can send your
husband back all right.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
[COUGHING]
What did Ben Wade mean
about sending Pa
back all right?
Was he saying
he was gonna kill him?
WILLIAM: Ben Wade don't
have to lift a finger.
His gang will do it for him.
Your father can
take care of himself.
Shh.
So...
were you conscripted into
Lincoln's army, Mr. Evans,
or did you volunteer?
Neither.
Maybe both.
What does that mean?
Means I was a volunteer
in the Massachusetts
State Guard.
Then, in '62,
the federal government
was running low on men,
so they called in
the state militias
to protect Washington.
And that's
when you got hurt.
What are you doing
out here, Dan?
You got a family
to protect.
You're not a lawman.
You don't work
for the railroad
like Mr. Shiny Shoes
over there.
You're not a Pinkerton.
Maybe I don't like the idea
of men like you
on the loose.
It's man's nature
to take what he wants, Dan.
That's how we're born.
Well, I make an honest living.
It might be honest,
but I don't think
it's much of a living.
You must be hurting bad
for money to take this job.
Go to sleep.
I imagine debt puts
a lot of pressure
on a marriage.
You imagine?
What would you know
about marriage?
We can't all be
cutthroats and thieves.
I know if I was lucky enough
to have a wife like Alice,
I'd treat her a whole lot
better than you do, Dan.
I'd feed her better,
buy her pretty dresses,
wouldn't make her
work so hard.
Yeah, I'll bet Alice
was a real pretty girl
before she married you.
Shut up about my wife.
You shut up about her.
You say one more word,
and I'll cut you down
right here.
Right here.
I like this side
of you, Dan.
Mr. Evans.
Okay.
It's my watch now.
♪ [MAN SINGING IN DISTANCE]
♪ They're gonna hang me in the mornin' ♪
♪ Before the night is done ♪
♪ I'll never see the sun ♪
I suppose it's too much
to ask for a little quiet.
Huh.
The way I figured it
is I'd be asleep
in my own bed right now
if it weren't for you.
So if I got to be up,
well, then, you're damn well
gonna be up with me, too,
Ben Wade.
♪ They're gonna hang me in the mornin' ♪
♪ Before the night is done ♪
♪ Hang me in the mornin' ♪
[COCKS]
♪ I'll never see the sun ♪
[CHOKING]
[POUNDING]
Son of a bitch!
Enough.
Heh heh heh.
Enough!
That's enough, McElroy.
[CHUCKLING]
We have to bury him.
Take the time
to dig one grave,
might as well dig one
for yourself.
Let's go.
Mount up.
♪ Gonna hang me in the mornin' ♪
[CHUCKLING]
♪ I'll never see the sun ♪
Yah!
Yah! Yah!
[GUNSHOT]
Don't you worry there, Boss.
We're gonna get you
outta there in a second.
Charlie!
Wait! Wait!
Sutherland.
Jackson.
No.
[FIRE ERUPTS]
Don't do this.
Where is he?
Open the door.
Let me outta here, Goddamn it.
Where did they take him?
I don't know.
Mister...
you better tell me...
where they took him...
or you will burn.
[COUGHING]
Contention.
All right?
They're going to Contention.
They're gonna put him on the
3:10 to Yuma Prison tomorrow.
Let me outta here!
[SCREAMING]
Contention is...
80 miles back
the other way.
We'd have to about kill
our horses.
So we'll buy new ones.
Charlie...
it's his own fault
he got caught.
He made a mistake.
You think you could do a
better job leading this crew?
Maybe.
[COCKS GUN]
You forgotten
what he done for us.
We're going
to Contention.
Can't say
I didn't warn you.
There's a shortcut
we could take.
Shortcut?
Through the pass.
Takes you right through
to Contention.
Why didn't you say
something before?
That's Apache country.
BUTTERFIELD: I thought the
government gave them land.
These are the ones
refused to go.
I wouldn't take
that pass.
Oh, you'd like us
to take the long way?
That's right.
And let your boys catch us?
Mr. Butterfield,
the Apache that live
in that pass
are the ones
that stayed to fight.
They enjoy killing.
You ain't gonna make it.
We'll take our chances.
Something on your mind, Dan?
Why'd you kill Tucker?
Why not me?
Or Butterfield?
Well, Tucker took
my horse.
Did you like him, Dan?
No.
He told me
he burnt down your barn.
He was an asshole...
but wishing him dead
and killing him
are two different things.
Your conscience
is sensitive, Dan.
I don't think it's
my favorite part of you.
Button it up, Mr. Wade.
You wanna talk to somebody,
talk to me.
I don't like talking
to you, Byron.
Not when I have the gun.
No, that ain't it.
I just don't find you
that interesting.
[CHUCKLES]
Laugh it up, Doc,
till he guts you
like a fish.
Byron's like a song
with one note.
You ever read another book
in your life, Byron,
besides the Bible?
No need.
Byron acts pious.
Few years ago,
when he was under
contract to Central,
I seen him and a bunch
of other Pinks
mow down 32 Apache women
and children.
BYRON:
Renegades...
gunning down railroad men
and their families.
Picking 'em off the road
one by one.
Scalping 'em.
There was young ones
running around
crying and screaming.
No more than
three years old.
And his boys shot 'em all
then pushed 'em into a ditch.
Some of them
was still crying.
But I guess Byron figured
that Jesus wouldn't mind.
Apparently Jesus
don't like the Apache.
Keep on talking...
all the way to Yuma,
right up them steps,
to the rope,
straight to Hell.
Day I die, Byron,
I'm getting sprung
from Hell.
I might feel the same,
if I come from the seed
of a drunk gravedigger
and the rancid womb
of a whore.
Drop it, Dan Evans.
Drop it.
Toss that
to the ground, Doc.
Mr. Butterfield.
Now I believe, Dan,
you're carrying
a pistol as well.
I'd appreciate it
if you take that out
and drop it
on the ground.
Thank you.
Now, I always
liked you, Byron.
[GRUNTS]
But you never knew
when to shut up.
Even bad men
love their mamas.
[THUD]
Now I think it's time
for everybody to go home.
Don't you move,
Mr. Wade.
Let go of that shotgun.
William...
what the hell
are you doing here?
Now, I don't think
you gonna shoot a man
you admire in the back
of the head, boy.
Dan, tell your boy
it's over.
You think you can keep
your gun on him, William?
I'm doing a damn sight
better than you did.
You ever been
to Dodge City?
No.
Stop talking to him.
The way you're shuffling
those cards,
I took you for a pro.
I practice a lot.
I can tell.
You ever been
to Dodge?
Yes, indeed.
Meanest, most beautiful
dirty city there ever was.
Saloon was just overflowing
with cattle drivers,
and road agents,
prospectors, gunslingers,
gamblers, and women.
Women who'll do things to you
you'll never forget.
They'll give you a disease
Money in your pocket
in Dodge City,
you can have everything
a man ever wished for.
Everything a man
comes to need.
I got there on my own as a boy
not much bigger than you.
And how many men you killed
since then, Wade?
How many families
you destroyed?
Quite a few.
Is it true
that you dynamited
a wagon full of prospectors
in the Western Territories
last spring?
No, that's a lie.
It was a train full.
Well, Dan...
[SIGHS]
I gotta take a piss.
You know, I thought
he was gonna shoot me
back at the ravine.
I really thought
he was gonna do it.
You know, there's
a wildness in his eyes.
It reminds me of--
He's gonna be nothing like you, Wade.
William's got a head start
on the path of decency.
Yeah, that's why
I don't mess around
with doing
anything good, Dan.
You do one good deed
for somebody...
I imagine
it's habit-forming.
Something decent.
See that grateful look
in their eyes,
imagine it makes you feel
like Christ Hisself.
All right, I had enough
of this, Wade.
Come on, let's go.
Shh.
[GUNSHOTS]
[GRUNTS]
William!
There's three of 'em.
Yours?
If they were mine,
you'd be dead.
Give me that gun, Wade.
Wade?
Wade!
[BULLETS WHIZZING]
[GUNSHOT]
I told you not to come
this way.
It was McElroy's decision.
I told you
there'd be trouble.
Give me the keys
to the handcuffs.
DOC:
Easy...
Easy now.
Where is he?
He's gone.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
He took the horses with him.
I found this in the grass.
What's the quickest way
out of the pass?
He'll be looking for help
getting his cuffs off.
We're going after him?
Well, there ain't no reward
for getting him halfway
to that train, is there?
[DISTANT EXPLOSION]
[MEN CHATTERING IN DISTANCE]
[EXPLOSION]
[MEN AND WOMEN CHATTERING IN CHINESE]
[DISTANT EXPLOSION]
I got to be honest
with y'all.
I like some of their food.
As for wanting
$40 a month now
like them Irish up north--
[WOMAN SPEAKING CHINESE]
Goddamn Coolies.
They'll work just fine with
my left boot up their ass.
Well, if could teach
a monkey to lay track--
Well, what we need
is some Negroes
brung in here,
Mr. Boles.
Show these Chinamen
what real work is.
[CHITTERING]
Holy Christ.
Who's that?
That's him.
You, help me
with the handcuffs.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
Break the chain.
Use the hammer.
[GUNSHOTS]
MAN: I got five guns on
you out here, Ben Wade!
Best come on out!
Our horses.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[PLUNGER WHIRRING]
What in the hell's
going on here?
Mr. Butterfield,
all finished in Bisbee?
Mr. Boles.
Better hurry. We're making the last
blasts through the mountains this week.
That's my prisoner.
I'm taking him
to Contention,
putting him on
the prison train to Yuma.
What prisoner?
Come now, Mr. Boles,
that's Ben Wade
you have there.
Ben Wade gunned down
my kid brother
in front of me
six years ago in Abilene.
Your brother was a lyin',
bilkin' card sharp.
That is, if he's
the asshole I remember.
Could, of course, been some other
asshole I killed that I forgot about.
[PLUNGER WHIRRS]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
[STIFLED GROAN]
You can't do that.
That's immoral.
[PLUNGER WHIRRS]
[ELECTRICITY STOPS]
Moral ain't got
a damn thing to do with it.
I was expecting to collect
a $200 reward for that man.
I'm delivering him
to Contention.
I need that money.
Need it bad enough
to die?
Well, at least let us
take our horses.
I got no problem
with that...
as long as you
ride away, mister.
Nice knowing you, Dan.
Yah!
Did you see me get that one
with the shovel?
[GUNSHOTS]
[GRUNTS]
Doc.
Doc!
[GUNSHOTS]
Dan!
[HORSES NEIGHING]
Goddamn it!
Did we make it?
Did we get away?
Yeah, Doc.
We did.
Thanks to you.
We need a place
to lay low.
Keep him outta sight
till the train comes.
There's a hotel up here.
I'll check us in.
You ride around back.
All right.
Follow me.
Hello, gentlemen.
Hey, William, you go keep
a watch at the railhead.
If you see them coming--
I'll let you know.
And William?
There's a Can-Can on the hour
if you're interested.
It's the bridal suite.
Hope you don't mind.
It's all they had.
Well, well.
That looks like
rain clouds over Bisbee.
You still need
that $200, Dan?
Shut up.
Mr. Evans, you continue
to give me great confidence.
DAN:
Well, it ain't 3:10 yet.
I'm gonna go see
about the marshal.
Come on, move.
Let's go.
We're looking for a group
escorting an outlaw
by the name of Ben Wade.
Yeah, we been chasing him
through these tunnels.
Who are you?
What's it to you?
Ben Wade killed
my brother.
Then your brother
must be famous.
You boys some kind
of posse?
I hate posses.
[TICKING]
[HORSE NEIGHS IN DISTANCE]
So this is
the bridal suite.
Now, I wonder
how many brides
have taken in this view.
[CHUCKLING]
What are you gonna do
with your $200 now, Dan?
Now that the rains
are coming?
[SIGHS]
I owe people money, Wade.
That drought left me
in the hole.
Well, what do you think
about double that amount?
You could pay your debts,
buy a hundred more cows,
build a new barn.
How you reckon
I'm gonna do that?
Just lay down your gun
and let me walk out the door.
It's worth $400 to me.
Is that what you reckon
my price is?
No.
No, I reckon
it's a thousand.
$1,000.
Now, there's 10 times
that amount
in Butterfield's coach.
Oh, yeah?
You want my cut, Dan?
[CHUCKLES]
It's all yours.
Isn't that kind of reckless
of you, Wade?
Seeing as, uh...
you're so sure that, uh,
your crew's coming
to get you?
Oh, they're coming, Dan.
Sure as God's vengeance,
they're coming.
But I just like
to do things easy.
Imagine what you could do
with a thousand dollars, Dan.
You could hire
a couple of ranch hands.
Your boys could go to school,
grow up smart.
What about Alice?
She would be
the proud wife
of a bona fide
Arizona rancher.
All you got to do
is say yes.
[LAUGHS]
Well...
would you give me
a bank note, Wade?
Or maybe you'd be kind enough
to make a deposit for me.
Cash.
Well, you--
you tell me, Wade.
How would I account for--
for that amount of money?
And what would I tell people
when I spend it?
That, uh--
That you got the jump on me,
you escaped,
and somehow I got a fortune?
Hmm?
[LAUGHING]
No. How dumb do you think
people are?
Nobody needs to know.
You know what?
Would you do me a favor?
Don't talk to me for a while.
You mean we're still
not friends?
No.
No, we're not.
[CHUCKLES]
Come five minutes to three,
we're gonna be a hell of a
lot closer than you think.
♪ They're gonna hang me ♪
♪ In the mornin' ♪
♪ Before the night is done ♪
♪ They're gonna hang me ♪
♪ In the mornin' ♪
♪ I'll never see the sun ♪
[TICKING]
[KNOCKING]
Who is it?
It's me, Dan.
I brought help.
You been gone a long time,
Mr. Butterfield.
How do I know somebody ain't
got a gun on you out there?
[METAL SLIDING]
Dan, this is
Marshal Will Doane.
Marshal.
Mr. Evans.
Two of my finest men:
Harvey Pell...
Sam Fuller.
I'm sorry about
all that, Marshal.
I really am grateful for the help.
Don't mention it.
So you fellas really gonna
help put me on this train?
It may not seem
like it, Mr. Wade,
but we got law and order
in this town,
just like any other.
Well, that's very reassuring, Marshal.
How much is Butterfield
paying you?
That's none of your business.
You gonna come with us?
Oh, I'll be walking
with you...
every step of the way.
You have my word
on that, Dan.
So there's five of us.
Five is good.
[WADE CHUCKLING]
It ain't enough.
It ain't nearly enough.
[KNOCKING]
Pa!
That's my boy.
They're coming.
They're coming this way.
I seen 'em.
Where?
About a mile out. Same way we come.
How many are there?
Seven. Eight.
Which is it, boy?
Seven or eight?
Seven.
Yah! Yah!
Folks, sorry to bother you,
but I'm gonna need you all
to move outside
as quickly as possible.
That's it, folks.
Thank you very much.
That's it.
Move along, folks.
Move along.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
MAN:
Come on, now!
MAN #2:
Hey! Get out of my way!
Right there.
[RAPPING ON DOOR]
[MEN LAUGHING]
There sure are
a lot of 'em.
FULLER: I didn't figure on
it being the whole gang.
Boss.
Boss?
Boss, you in there?
What do you want me
to tell him?
You tell him you'll write him
a letter every day from Yuma.
You be careful, Wade.
Charlie. Boys.
MEN: Boss. Hey, Boss.
Yeah.
Charlie, why don't you
take the boys
down to the saloon
and buy 'em a drink.
You okay?
Oh, I'm fine.
I'm just sittin' up here
with my four new friends.
Hey...
that's enough.
Thank you, Charlie.
Boys.
Listen up!
That's Ben Wade
they have up there.
Ben...Wade!
Now...
the Railroad intends...
to put him on
the 3:10 to Yuma...
and hang him.
What's he doing?
We will give you
200 cash dollars
to any man who shoots
any one of his captors.
MAN: How much?
200 cash dollars
guaranteed!
$200 guaranteed!
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Right here. You got me.
Hand it over.
I'll tell you now,
mister.
I'll take 200.
Give me the money.
Well, you gotta
shoot 'em first.
There's gotta be 30, 40
more guns out there now.
Oh, to hell with this.
Now just a minute, Marshal.
Look, look.
If it's a fair fight,
well, sure.
I'd stay for that.
A fair fight, that--
That's a man's duty,
but...
there's only five
of us.
I'm sorry, mister,
but I'm not gonna
die here today.
And neither are my men.
Marshal...
forgot this.
Marshal--
Marshal!
Marshal, what's the--
[SIGHS]
Now, you see, Dan...
generally, pretty much
everyone wants to live.
I'll double your money.
Let's go, boys.
Please. Do you wanna see us
shot down in the street?
This thing happened
in Bisbee.
That means
Butterfield, too.
Why bring your troubles
to Contention?
We've got families.
Every one of us is a family man.
I'm a family man, too.
He's gonna walk out
on you.
Then you best get out
like the rest of us.
WADE: He's gonna
comeback up here,
and he's gonna
walk out on you.
Now what you gotta figure
is why you and your boy
are gonna die.
Because Butterfield's railroad
lost some money?
[GUNSHOTS]
Is that all of 'em?
MAN: Get inside!
MAN #2: Get a doctor!
Almost.
Your move, General.
What do you
expect him to say?
I expect him to say
something that makes sense.
Something that might
save the two of you.
Take a look, Dan.
What's the matter?
You don't wanna see?
I'll see 'em soon enough.
What about you, kid?
You wanna look?
You stay away from
the window, William.
WADE:
Go on, take a look.
Animals, all of 'em.
Campos, stand there.
Jackson, back door.
They're gonna kill you
and your father, William.
They're gonna laugh
while they do it.
I think you know that.
Call 'em off.
Why should I?
Because you're not
all bad.
Yes, I am.
You saved us
from those Indians.
I saved myself.
You got us
through the tunnels.
You helped us
get away.
If I'd had a gun
in them tunnels,
I would have
used it on you.
I don't believe you.
Kid, I wouldn't last
five minutes
leading an outfit
like that
if I wasn't
as rotten as hell.
[WATCH TICKING]
[CONTINUES TICKING]
Dan?
I can't do it, Dan.
And if I can't do it,
you shouldn't do it, either.
They say discretion
is the better part of valor.
BUTTERFIELD: If you think
you have an obligation to me
or to the Railroad,
I assure you you do not.
I'm releasing you.
It's just you left, Dan.
Just you and your boy.
Maybe he's right, Pa.
Maybe we should go home.
Well, what did Doc Potter
give his life for, William?
And McElroy?
WADE:
Little red ants on a hill.
BUTTERFIELD: I'll pay you the 200,
Dan, right now,
and you can walk away.
You know,
this whole ride,
that's been
nagging on me.
That's what the government
gave me for my leg.
$198.36.
And the funny thing
is that...
when you think about it,
which I have been lately,
was they weren't paying me
to walk away.
They were paying me
so they could walk away.
Don't muddy the past
and the present, Dan.
No, no, no, Wade.
I'm seeing the world
the way it is.
If you take him to the train,
Pa, I'm going with you.
No, Mr. Butterfield's
gonna take you home.
No, I'm not going anywhere with him.
Yes, you are.
I'm staying here
with you.
You're gonna hold up
in a room across the hall.
You're gonna wait
until we leave.
I'll get him to Bisbee, Dan.
I promise you.
Oh, you're gonna promise me a lot
more than that, Butterfield.
I want guarantees
that Hollander
and his boys
will never set foot
on my land again,
and that my water's
gonna flow.
And I expect you
to hand my wife
1,000 cash dollars
when you see her.
You got money to spare.
I can deliver that.
Just get him on the train.
You heard him?
I heard him.
William, I want you to give
this back to your mother.
I want you to tell her that it
helped me find what was right.
Pa...
I can't.
I can't just leave you.
I'm gonna be a day
behind you, William.
Unless something happens,
and if it does,
I need a man at the ranch
to run things,
protect our family, and I
know that you can do that
because you've become
a fine man, William.
You've become a fine man.
You got all
the best parts of me.
What few there are.
And you just remember
that your old man
walked Ben Wade
to that station
when nobody else would.
[DOOR OPENS]
[WATCH TICKING]
You know,
squeezing that watch
won't stop time.
Don't get so scared.
You might back a bad move.
You ever read the Bible, Dan?
I read it one time.
I was eight years old.
My daddy just got hisself
killed over a shot of whiskey,
and my mama said, "We're going
back East to start over."
So she gave me a Bible,
sat me down in the train
station, told me to read it.
She was gonna get
our tickets.
Well, I did what she said.
I read that Bible
from cover to cover.
It took me three days.
She never came back.
[CHURCH BELL TOLLS]
[BELL TOLLS]
It's time.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[LATCH CLICKS]
It's a half mile to the
station from here, Dan.
I guess we're walking.
There he is!
Go and flush him out!
Let's get to it!
Lucky.
Dan.
Thanks.
Move!
[GUNSHOTS]
Come on!
Might not get a chance to use
those Scofields, Charlie.
Perhaps you
can explain to me
the next portion
of your plan, Dan.
MAN:
I think I got him!
Hey.
Hey!
Not the black hat!
The rancher,
you dumb-shits!
The rancher!
The ranch--
Charlie!
Get back!
Get back! Get back!
Boss.
Boss!
Let's go.
The white door.
Move it!
[HORSE NEIGHS]
All right.
I ain't doing this
no more, Dan.
[DOOR OPENS]
I'm getting you
on that train, Wade.
Your son went back!
The boy's gone, hero.
Ain't nobody watching
no more.
You still got
that one good leg.
Why don't you use it
to get on home?
Charlie!
Charlie Prince!
Yeah, Boss!
Hold your fire.
I'm walking out.
CHARLIE: Hold your fire!
I ain't never been
no hero, Wade.
The only battle I seen,
we was in retreat.
My foot got shot off
by one of my own men.
You try telling
that story to your boy.
See how he looks
at you then.
CHARLIE:
Boss! Boss!
Okay, Dan.
Son.
They're on the roofs!
Boss!
Boss! Drop!
Can you make this?
Yeah.
Come on.
Come on!
Go! Run!
Spread out!
[GUNSHOTS]
What time is it?
About 10 past 3.
Where's the 3:10
to Yuma?
Running late,
I suppose.
How late?
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Beats me.
Gets here
when it gets here.
Goddamn trains.
Never can rely on 'em, huh?
MAN:
By the window!
[MOOING]
[GUNSHOTS]
You know...
[PANTING]
I ain't stubborn.
Excuse me?
You said I was stubborn
for keeping my family
on a dying ranch.
It's my son Mark.
The young one?
He got tuberculosis
when we was 2.
The doctor said he'd die
if he didn't
have a dry climate, so--
Why are you telling me this?
I don't know.
I guess I just...
wanted you to know
that I ain't stubborn is all.
[CATTLE MOOING]
WADE: Well,
as long as we're
making confessions--
DAN:
Yeah?
I've been
to Yuma Prison before.
Twice.
Escaped twice, too.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
[BELL TOLLING]
First car, sliding door.
They'll be coming!
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Yeah.
I got a prisoner
to go to Yuma!
Well, you did it, Dan.
No!
[GUNSHOTS]
Pa.
For a one-leg rancher...
he's one tough son of a bitch.
Yeah.
You done it, Pa.
You done it.
You got him on the train.
Pa.
[TRAIN WHISTLE TOOTS]
[WHISTLES]