One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
I'm sorry.
# Come a little bit closer #
# Hear what I have to say #
# Just like children sleeping #
# We could dream this night away #
# But there's a full moon rising #
# Let's go dancing in the light #
# We know where the music's playing #
# Let's go out and feel the night ##
Don't worry.
Hey...
...you're all right.
You're all right.
I promise.
Why didn't you let her come?
Do you blame her...
...for what happened?
No.
Because she blames herself.
It was no one's fault.
You still love her, right?
Of course I do.
You should tell her.
It's okay. It's okay.
You're safe.
They can't hear us.
It worked.
You just need to rest now.
Where are they?
I'll find them.
No, she was with me. She was with me, and...
...and then I had to go
and do laundry, and...
...he was with you. How did he...
Rockets.
- So he'd still be there.
- I'm sure he is.
He knows to wait for you. And she is...
...she's smart. She'll have found a place.
They know what to do.
It's a boy.
I could've carried him.
He was so heavy, wasn't he?
I can still...
...I can still feel the weight in my arms.
Small, but...
...so heavy.
And my hands were free.
I was carrying the bag,
but my hands were free.
You have to stop.
So, I could've carried him.
I should've carried him.
Who are we...
...if we can't protect them?
Who are we?
You have to protect them.
Promise me...
...you will protect them.
Dad!