Bio readouts are all in the green.
Looks like she's alive.
Well, there goes
our salvage, guys.
How are we today?
Ohh. Terrible.
Well, better than
yesterday, at least.
Where am I?
You're safe.
You're at Gateway Station.
Been here a couple of days.
You were pretty groggy at first,
but now you're okay.
Oh, looks like
you've got a visitor.
Jonesy. Come here.
Hey, come here.
How are you, you stupid cat?
How are you?
Where have you been?
Guess you two have met, huh?
I'm Burke. Carter Burke.
I work for the company, but don't let that fool you.
I'm really an okay guy.
I'm glad to see you're
feeling a little better.
They tell me that all the weakness
and disorientation should pass soon.
That's just natural side effects of such an
unusually long hypersleep, or something like that.
What do you mean?
How long was I out there?
Inhalation Therapy, report to-
Has no one discussed
this with you yet?
No.
But, I mean...
I don't... recognize
this place.
No, I know. Uh-
Okay. It's just that, uh,
this might be a shock to you.
It's long-
How long?
Please.
57 years.
What?
That's the thing. You were
out there for 57 years.
What happened was you had drifted
right through the core systems.
And it's really
just blind luck...
that a deep-salvage team
found you when they did.
It's one in a thousand, really.
I think you're damn lucky to be alive, kiddo.
You could be floating out there forever.
You-You okay?
Uhh-
Uuh!
You okay?
Oh-h-h! Oh, God!
Nurse! Please!
God!
Someone get in here now!
Now!
- Hold!
- Please.
Hold on!
Kill me!
No!
Uh!
Bad dreams again? You want
something to help you sleep?
No.
I've slept enough.
Jonesy.
Come here.
Shh.
It's all right.
It's all right now.
It's over.
Dr Hirsch, 334. Dr. Hirsch, 334.
Hi. Sorry I'm late. I've been
running behind all morning.
Is there any word
about my daughter?
Uh... I really think we should
worry about the hearing now.
'Cause we don't have a lot of time, okay?
I read your deposition, and it's great.
If you just stick to that, I think we'll be fine.
The thing to remember is,
there're gonna be a lot
of heavyweights in there.
You've got feds and Interstellar
Commerce Commission,
Colonial Administration,
insurance company guys-
Do you have any news
about my daughter?
Well, we did come up with some information.
Why don't we sit down?
I was hoping to wait
until after the inquest.
Um-
"Amanda Ripley-McClaren" -
married name, I guess-
"Age 66."
And that was at
the time of her death,
which was two years ago.
I'm real sorry.
Amy.
She was cremated and interred at Westlake
Repository, Little Chute, Wisconsin.
No children. I checked.
I promised her... that I'd
be home for her birthday.
Her 11th birthday.
I'djust like to go, uh-
back to this point about
the override destruct order.
Is it in the file?
I don't understand this.
We have been here
for three and a half hours.
Now, how many different ways do you
want me to tell the same story?
Look at it from our
perspective, please.
Please?
Now, you freely admit to
detonating the engines of,
and thereby destroying,
an M-class starsreighter,
a rather expensive piece
of hardware.
Forty-two million
in adjusted dollars.
That's minus payload,
of course.
The lifeboat's flight recorder corroborates
some elements of your account,
in that, for reasons unknown, the
Nostromo set down on LV-426,
an unsurveyed planet at that time,
that it resumed its course...
and was subsequently set for self-destruct
by you for reasons unknown.
Not for reasons unknown.
I told you.
We set down there on company orders to get
this thing, which destroyed my crew...
and your expensive ship.
The analysis team, which went over the
lifeboat centimeter by centimeter,
found no physical evidence
of the creature you describe.
Good! That's because I blew it
out of the goddamn air lock,
like I said.
Are there any species like this
hostile organism on LV-426?
No. It's a rock.
No indigenous life.
Did I.Q.'s just drop sharply
while I was away?
Ma'am, I already said
it was not indigenous.
It was a derelict spacecraft.
It was an alien ship.
It was not from there. Do you get it?
We homed in on its beacon.
And found something
never recorded once...
in over 300 surveyed worlds.
- "A creature that gestates inside
a living human host." - Yes.
These are your words. "And has
concentrated acid for blood."
That's right.
Look. I can see
where this is going,
but I'm telling you
that those things exist.
- Thank you, Officer Ripley. That will be all.
- Please. You're not listening to me.
Kane, the crew member-
Kane, who went into that ship, said
he saw thousands of eggs there.
Thousands. Thank you.
That will be all.
Goddamn it, that's not all!
Because if one of those things gets
down here, then that will be all!
Then all of this-this bullshit
that you think is so important-
You can just kiss
all of that good-bye!
It is the finding
of this court of inquiry that...
Warrant Officer E. Ripley,
NOC14472,
has acted with
questionable judgment...
and is unfit to hold an I.C.C. license
as a commercial flight officer.
Said license is hereby
suspended indefinitely.
Now, no criminal charges will be
filed against you at this time,
and you are released
on your own recognizance...
for a six-month period
ofpsychometric probation,
to include monthly review
by an I.C.C. psychiatric technician.
These proceedings are closed.
That could have been better.
Look, I think the-Ripley?
Van Leuwen.
Why don't you
just check out LV-426?
Because I don't have to. There have
been people there for over 20 years,
and they never complained about any hostile organism.
What do you mean? What people?
Terraformers.
Planet engineers.
They go in, set up these big atmosphere
processors to make the air breathable.
Takes decades.
It's what we call
a "Shake 'N Bake" colony.
How many are there?
How many colonists?
I don't know-60, maybe 70 families.
Do you mind?
Families.
Jesus.
I'll be down in maintenance, okay?
Al!
What?
Hey, Al.
What? Remember you sent
some wildcatters...
out to the middle of nowhere last
week, out past the Ilium Range?
- Yeah, what?
- One of them's on the horn, a mom-and-pop survey team.
He says he's onto something. He wants
to know if his claim will be honored.
Why wouldn't his claim
be honored?
Well, because you sent them to that particular
middle-of-nowhere on company orders, maybe.
I don't know. Christ! Some honch
in a cushy office on Earth...
says, "Go look at
a grid reference."
We look. They don't say
why, and I don't ask.
I don't ask, because it takes two weeks to get
an answer out here, and the answer is always-
"Don't ask."
So what do l tell this guy?
Tell him as far as I'm concerned,
if he finds something, it is his.
Lydecker?
What?
You kids know you're not
supposed to be on this level!
Go on!
Get outta here!
Do too. You go in places we can't fit.
So? That's why I'm the best.
Knock it off! I catch either of you playing
in the air ducts again, l'll tan your hides.
Mom, all the kids play-
Wait a minute. Annie, come and
have a look at this, will ya?
Folks, we have
scored big this time.
What is it, Dad?
I'm not sure.
Let's see if we can't get a closer look at this
thing, maybe through that crack there on the side.
- Shouldn't we call in?
- Let's wait till we know what to call it in as.
That's about as close
as we can get.
Should we take a look inside?
You two stay inside. I mean it.
We'll be right back.
Okay.
Bye.
Huh?
Timmy, they've been gone
a long time.
It'll be okay, Newt.
Dad knows what he's doing.
Mayday, Mayday! This is Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner calling!
This is Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner!
Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner calling!
Hiya, Ripley.
This is Lieutenant Gorman...
of the Colonial
Marine Corps-
Ripley, we have to talk.
We've lost contact
with the colony on LV-426.
I don't believe this.
You guys throw me at the wolves, and
now you want me to go back out there?
Forget it.
It's not my problem.
Can I finish? No.
There's no way.
Ripley, you wouldn't be
going in with the troops.
I can guarantee your safety.
These Colonial Marines
are very tough hombres.
They're packing
state-of-the-art firepower.
There's nothing
they can't handle.
- Lieutenant, am I right?
- That's true.
We've been trained to deal
with situations like this.
Then you don't need me.
I'm not a soldier.
Yeah, but we don't know exactly
what's going on out there.
It mayjust be a downed
transmitter, okay?
But if it's not, I would like
you there as an adviser,
and that's all.
What's your interest in all this?
Why are you going?
Corporation cofinanced
that colony,
along with
Colonial Administration.
We're getting into a lot of terraforming now.
"Building Better Worlds"-
Yeah, yeah.
I saw the commercial.
Look, I don't have time for this.
I've got to get to work.
Oh, right. I heard you're
working the cargo docks.
That's right.
Running loaders and forklifts,
that sort of thing? Yeah. So?
Nothing. I think it's great
that you're keeping busy.
And I know it's the only
thing that you could get.
There's nothing wrong with it.
What would you say if I told you
I could get you reinstated...
as a flight officer?
The company's already agreed to
pick up your contract. If I go.
Yeah, if you go.
Come on.
That's a second chance, kiddo.
I think, personally, for you, it would
be the best thing in the world...
to get out there and face this
thing, get back on the horse.
Spare me, Burke. I've had my
psych evaluation this month.
Yeah, I know. I've read it. You wake up every night.
Your sheets are soaking with sweat-
I said no, and I mean it!
Now, please leave.
I am not going back.
And I am-I would not be
any good to you if I did.
Okay. Shh.
Would you do me a favor?
Just think about it.
Thanks for the coffee.
Oh!
Hello.
Ripley.
You okay? Just tell
me one thing, Burke.
You're going out there
to destroy them, right?
Not to study, not to bring back,
but to wipe them out.
That's the plan.
You have my word on it.
All right. I'm in.
I think that-
And you, you little shithead,
you're staying here.
Mmm.
They ain't payin' us
enough for this, man.
Not enough to have to wake
up to your face, Drake.
What?
Is that a joke?
Oh, I wish it were.
Hey, Hicks. Man, you look
just like I feel.
All right, sweethearts.
What are you waiting for?
Breakfast in bed? Another
glorious day in the corps.
A day in the Marine Corps
is like a day on the farm-
every meal's a banquet, every paycheck
a fortune, every formation a parade.
I love the corps!
Christ!
Man, this floor is freezing!
What do you want me to do? Fetch your slippers for ya?
Gee, would you, sir? I'd like that.
Look into my eye.
Fall in, people.
Come on. Let's go.
I hate this job.
Crowe, Wierzbowski. Come on. On your feet.
We got some slack coming, right?
You had three weeks on your back, Frost.
What do you want?
I'm talking about breathing,
not this frozen shit.
Yeah, Top. How 'bout it?
All right. First assembly's
in 15, people. Shag it.
Hey, mira.
Who's Snow White?
She's supposed to be
some kind of consultant.
Apparently,
she saw an alien once.
Whoopee-fuckin'-do!
Hey, I'm impressed.
IQue bonita!
Hey, Vasquez. Have you ever
been mistaken for a man?
No. Have you?
Ha, ha! Oh, Vasquez.
You're just too bad.
Uhh!
Hey, Top, what's the op?
It's a rescue mission.
You'll love it.
There's some juicy colonists' daughters
we have to rescue from their virginity.
Dumb-ass colonists.
What's this crap supposed to be?
Vasquez.
Corn bread, I think. It's
good for you, boy. Eat it.
Hey, sure wouldn't mind getting some
more of that Arcturian poontang.
- Remember that time?
- Yeah. Except the one that you had was male.
Doesn't matter
when it's Arcturian.
Hey, Bishop, man. Do the thing
with the knife. Oh, please.
Oh, come on. Yeah.
All right! Yeah.
- I don't want to see that, man.
- Come on, man. All right. All right.
Hey, what are you doing, man?
What are you doing?
Come on. Quit messing around, Drake.
Hudson, shut up!
- Bishop, hey, man.
- Do it, Bishop!
Hey! Not me, man! Quit messing around!
Yeah, you! Don't move.
Trust me.
Aah!
All right. Knock it off,
knock it off.
Thank you.
There you go, short shit.
Enjoy your meal.
That wasn't funny, man.
Lieutenant Gorman? Mr. Burke?
Yeah, thanks.
Looks like the new lieutenant's too
good to eat with the rest of us grunts.
Boy's definitely got
a corncob up his ass.
Thought you never miss, Bishop.
You never said anything about an
android being on board. Why not?
It never-
never occurred to me.
It's just common practice. We
always have a synthetic on board.
I prefer the term
"artificial person" myself.
Right.
- Is there a problem?
- I'm sorry.
I don't know why
I didn't even-
Ripley's last trip out, the syn-the
artificial person malfunctioned.
- Malfunctioned?
- There were problems and a few deaths were involved.
I'm shocked.
Was it an older model?
The Hyperdyne Systems
1 20-A2.
That explains it then. The A2s
always were a bit twitchy.
That could never happen now
with our behavioral inhibitors.
It is impossible for me to harm, or by omission
ofaction, allow to be harmed, a human being.
- You sure you don't want some?
You just stay away from me,
Bishop. You got that straight?
Guess she don't like
the corn bread, either.
Squad, ten-hut! Officer on deck!
As you were.
Quickly, quickly.
Settle down.
All right.
Listen up!
Morning, marines. l'm sorry we didn't have time
to brief you people before we left Gateway-
Sir?
What is it, Hicks?
Hudson, sir.
He's Hicks.
What's the question?
Is this gonna be a stand-up
fight, sir, or another bug hunt?
All we know is that there's still
no contact with the colony...
and that a xenomorph
may be involved.
Excuse me, sir. A what?
A xenomorph.
It's a bug hunt.
- What exactly are we dealing with here?
- Ripley.
I'll tell you what I know.
We set down
on LV-426.
One ofour crew members was brought back on
board with something attached to his face,
some kind of parasite.
We tried to get it off.
It wouldn't come off.
Later, it seemed to come off
by itselfand die.
Kane seemed fine.
We were all having dinner,
and, um,
it must have laid something inside
his throat, some sort of embryo.
He started-Um, he-
Look, man.
I only need to know one
thing-where they are.
Yo, Vasquez. Kick ass.
Anytime, anywhere.
Right, right. Somebody said "alien." She thought
they said "illegal alien" and signed up.
Fuck you, man.
Anytime, anywhere.
Are you finished?
I hope you're right.
I really do.
Yeah, okay, right.
Thank you, Ripley.
We also have Ripley's report on disk.
I suggest you study it.
Because just one of those things managed to
wipe out my entire crew in less than 24 hours.
And if the colonists have found that
ship, then there's no telling...
how many of them
have been exposed.
Do you understand?
Anyway, we have it on disk,
so you better look at it.
Any questions?
What is it, Private?
How do I get out of this
chickenshit outfit?
You secure that shit, Hudson.
All right.
Now listen up.
I want this thing
to go smooth...
and by the numbers.
I want D.C.S. and tactical
database assimilation by 0830.
Ordinance loading, weapons strip
and drop-ship prep details...
will have seven hours.
Oh, come on.
Now, move it, people!
All right, sweethearts. You heard
the man, and you know the drill.
Assholes and elbows! Hudson, come here.
Come here.
I don't care if you are short, Hudson.
Get it done.
Hey, Sarge. You'll get lip
cancer smoking those.
Corporal, I want this
loading lock sealed. Now!
How many more you got, Spunkmeyer?
Last one.
Good. Take it away.
Clear behind.
Did you check number three?
Let me see that.
Hi. I feel like kind of a fifth wheel around here.
Is there anything I can do?
I don't know. Is there
anything you can do?
Well, I can drive that loader.
I have a Class 2 rating.
Be my guest.
Where you want it?
Bay 12, please.
All right, sweethearts. We're a team,
and there's nothing to worry about.
We come here, and we gonna
conquer, and we gonna kick some.
Is that understood? That's what we
gonna do, sweethearts. Yes, sir.
We are going to go and get some.
Hey.
All right, people!
On the ready line!
Are you lean? Are you mean?
Yeah! Yeah!
What are you? What are you?
Lean and mean!
Hudson! Get on the
ready line, marine!
Get some today!
Get on the ready line!
Yo! Move it out! Move
it out, goddamn it!
Get hot! One, two, three!
Get out, get out, get out!
Move it out, move it out, move it out!
Absolutely badasses.
Let's pack 'em in.
Get in there!
All right! Move it!
Let's go, let's go!
One, two, three,
four, five, six!
All right. I want combat seating.
You know your places.
Get those weapons stowed.
Let's go.
Come on.
Settle down, people.
Lock 'em in, Hudson.
Ready to get it on?
You know it!
Okay, Bishop, let's go.
Roger.
I'm ready, man.
- Ready to get it on!
- Go!
Stand by. Cross-locking now.
Prelaunch autocycle engaged.
Primary couplers released.
Hit the internals.
Shit, man. Confirm cross-lock
and drop stations secured.
Affirmative.
All drop stations secured.
Stand by. Ten seconds.
Stand by to initiate release sequencer...
on my mark.
- Five, four, three,
- We're on an express elevator to hell, going down.
Two, one, mark.
Woo-hoo!
- Switch to D.C.S. ranging.
- 240, nominal to profile.
We're in the pipe,
five by five.
We're picking up
some hull ionization.
Got it.
Rough air ahead.
We're in for some chop.
How many drops is this
for you, Lieutenant?
Thirty-eight.
Simulated.
How many combat drops?
Uh, two...
including this one.
- Shit.
- Oh, man!
Range 014.
Turning on final.
And I'm telling you, I got a
bad feeling about this drop.
You always say that, Frost. You always say,
"I got a bad feeling about this drop."
Okay, okay.
When we get back without you,
I'll call your folks.
All right.
Let's see what we can see.
Everybody online.
Looking good.
Drake, check your camera. There
seems to be a malfunction.
That's better.
Pan it around a bit.
- Good.
- I'm ready, man. Check it out.
I am the ultimate badass.
Yeah. That's right.
State-of-the-badass art. You do not want
to fuck with me. Who here's runnin'?
Check it out.
Hey, Ripley, don't worry.
Me and my squad of ultimate
badasses will protect you.
Hey!
That's right.
Check it out.
Independently targeting
particle-beam phalanx.
Fry halfa city with this puppy.
We got tactical smart missiles,
phase-plasma pulse rifles,
R.P.G.'s.
- We got sonic, electronic ball breakers!
- - Whoo!
We got nukes, we got knives,
sharp sticks-
Knock it off, Hudson.
All right, gear up.
Two minutes, people.
Get hot.
Somebody wake up Hicks.
Coming around for a 709er.
Terminal guidance locked in.
Where's the damn beacon?
Oh, I see it.
That's the atmosphere processor?
Yep, that's it.
Remarkable piece of machinery.
Completely automated.
You know, we manufacture
those, by the way.
Okay, Ferro. Take us in low
over the main colony complex.
Storm shutters are sealed.
There's no visible activity.
All right. Hold at 40.
Roger.
Give me a slow circle of the complex.
Structure seems intact.
They still have power.
Okay, Ferro. Set down
on the landing grid.
Immediate dust off on my
clear, then stay on station.
Down and clear.
Ten seconds, people.
Look sharp.
All right. I want a nice,
clean dispersal this time.
Let's go!
Move it out!
Head 'em up!
First squad up on line. Hicks, get
yours in accord and watch the rear.
Vasquez, take point.
Let's move!
Move up.
Hudson, run a bypass.
Second squad, move up.
Flanking positions.
Second squad on line.
You set?
Go on.
Second team, move inside.
Hicks, take the upper level.
Sir, you copying this? Looks
like hits from small-arms fire.
Uh, we got some
explosives damage.
It's probably seismic
survey charges.
Are you reading this?
Keep it tight, people.
All right. Hicks, Hudson,
use your motion trackers.
Nothing.
Not a goddamn thing.
Quarter and search by twos.
Okay. Dietrich,
Frost, you're up.
It's right in there.
Now!
- Haah! Uh-
- Good one, Hudson!
Uh, sir, uh, we have a negative situation here.
Uh, movin' on, sir
Wait. Wait,
tell him to-
Hicks, back up.
Pan right.
- There.
- You seeing this all right?
Looks melted. Somebody must have
bagged one of Ripley's bad guys here.
Acid for blood.
If you like that,
you're gonna love this.
Quit screwing around.
Second squad,
what's your status?
Uh, we just finished our sweep.
Nobody's home.
Roger.
Sir, this place is dead.
Whatever happened here,
I think we missed it.
All right. The area's secured. Let's go in
and see what their computer can tell us.
- Wait a minute. It's not secure.
- The area's secured, Ripley.
First team,
head for operations.
Hudson, see if you can get their C.P.U.
on line. Affirmative.
Hicks, meet me at the south lock.
We're coming in. Roger.
He's comin' in.
I feel safer already.
Pendejo jerk-off.
Sir, we got the C.P.U. on line.
No problem.
Good. Stand by
in Operations.
Okay, let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Sir, they sealed off
this wing at both ends,
welded the doors and blocked off
the stairs with heavy equipment.
Mm-hmm. But it looks like
the barricade didn't hold.
Any bodies?
No, sir.
Last stand.
Must have been
a hell ofa fight.
Yeah, looks that way.
All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able to cut through
the medlab to Operations.
Lieutenant.
Gorman.
Are those the same ones that-
Careful, Burke.
Looks like love
at first sight to me.
Oh, he likes you, Burke.
Two are alive.
The rest are dead.
"Surgically removed
before embryo implantation.
Subject Marachek, John J.,
died during the procedure."
They killed him taking it off.
Yo, Hicks.
I think we got something here.
Behind us.
One of us?
Apone, where are your people?
Anybody in "D" block?
Ah, that's a negative.
We're all in Operations.
Talk to me, Frosty.
Let's keep moving, baby.
It's moving.
Which way?
It's coming straight for us.
Straight up.
Fuck!
Hold up.
Ripley.
Hey. Shh.
It's all right.
It's all right. Come on.
Just grab her, Corporal.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
We won't hurt you.
Shh. It's all right.
It's okay.
Come on out. Come on.
- Easy. Easy.
- I got her.
Ow! Damn!
Watch her! She's under the grille!
Don't let her go.
Frost, get your light up here.
Where'd she go?
Shine the light.
Here. Here.
There she is.
Keep back. Keep back.
Don't scare her.
Grab her, man. We're gonna lose her.
Damn it!
Kick it out!
Wait.
It's okay.
It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
See?
- Wait.
- No, you don't.
It's okay. You're gonna
be all right now.
Shh.
Easy. Easy.
It's gonna be okay.
It's all right.
You're gonna be okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
What's her name again?
Rebecca.
Now think, Rebecca.
Concentrate.
Just start at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
Now, look, Rebecca,
you have to try and help-
Gorman, give it a rest,
why don't you?
Total brain lock.
Physically, she's okay.
Borderline malnutrition, but I don't
think there's any permanent damage.
Come on.
We're wasting our time.
Try this.
It's a little hot chocolate.
There you go.
Whoop.
That good, huh?
Uh-oh. I made
a clean spot here.
Now I've done it. Guess l'll
have to do the whole thing.
Hard to believe there's a
little girl under all this.
And a pretty one too.
You don't talk much, do you?
Smoking or nonsmoking?
Just tell me what
you're scanning for, Private.
P.D.T.s.
What?
Personal data transmitters.
Every colonist had one
surgically implanted.
If they're within 20 klicks,
we'll read it out here.
So far, zippo.
I don't know how you
managed to stay alive,
but you're one
brave kid, Rebecca.
N-Newt.
- What'd you say?
- Newt.
My name's Newt.
Nobody calls me Rebecca
except my brother.
Newt?
I like that.
I'm Ripley.
It's nice to meet you.
And who is this, hmm?
Casey.
Hello, Casey.
What about your brother?
What's his name?
Timmy.
Is Timmy around here too?
Maybe hiding like you were?
Any sisters?
Mom and dad?
Newt, look at me.
Where are they?
They're dead, all right?
Can I go now?
I'm sorry, Newt.
Don't you think you'd
be safer here with us?
These people are here
to protect you.
They're soldiers.
It won't make any difference.
Need anything else?
Hello, Bishop. Do you
need anything else?
No.
That's a nice pet
you got there, Bishop.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yo! Stop your grinnin'
and drop your linen! Found 'em.
They alive?
Unknown,
but it looks like all of them.
Over at the processing station,
Sublevel 3,
under the main cooling towers.
Looks like
a goddamn town meeting.
Let's saddle up, Apone.
Aye, sir.
All right. Let's go, people. They
ain't payin' us by the hour.
Let's go.
Head 'em out!
Okay, Frost, you're driving.
It's okay. Don't worry.
It'll be okay.
I want a straight "V" deployment,
second team on left flank.
Advance on axial 664.
Tracker on line.
Set the "V" gain
to filter R.F. ambient.
Hudson, tracker on line.
Left and right, little buddy.
Forty meters in, bearing 221,
there should be a stairwell.
Check. Got it.
You want Sublevel 3.
Let's go, people.
Hudson, you got the point.
Hicks, watch our tails.
Nice and easy.
Check those corners.
Watch your spacing. All right.
You heard the man.
Don't bunch up.
Stay loose.
Uh, your transmission's
showing a lot ofbreakup.
Probably getting some
interference from the structure.
Use those lights.
Next one down,
and proceed on a 216.
Uh, roger. That's a 216.
I'm not making that out
too well. What is it, Hudson?
You tell me, man.
I only work here.
What is that?
I don't know.
Proceed inside.
Watch your fire
and check your targets.
Remember we're looking
for civvies in here.
Easy.
Tighten it up, Frost.
We're getting a little thin.
Nice and easy.
Looks like some sort
of secreted resin.
Yeah, but secreted from what?
Nobody touch nothing.
Busy little creatures, huh?
Hot as hell in here.
Yeah, man, but it's a dry heat.
Knock it off, Hudson.
Lieutenant, what do
those pulse rifles fire?
Ten millimeter
explosive-tip caseless.
Standard light
armor-piercing round.
Why? Well, look
where your team is.
They're right under the
primary heat exchangers.
So?
So if they fire their weapons in there,
won't they rupture the cooling system?
- Ho, ho, ho. Yeah. She's absolutely right.
- So? So what?
Look. This whole station is
basically a big fusion reactor.
Right?
So you're talking about a thermonuclear
explosion, and adios, muchachos.
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit!
Look.
Uh... Apone.
Look. We can't have
any firing in there.
I, uh, I want you to collect
magazines from everybody.
- Is he fuckin' crazy?
- What the hell are we supposed to use, man, harsh language?
- Flame units only. I want rifles slung.
- Sir, I-
Just do it, Sergeant.
And no grenades.
All right, sweethearts. You heard the man.
Pull 'em out. Come on. Let's have 'em.
Come on, Vasquez.
Clear and lock.
Damn!
You too. Give it up, Ski.
Come on. Let's go.
Crowe, I want it now.
Give it up.
Right on, Vas.
Let's go, marine.
Give it up.
Frost, you got the duty.
Open that bag.
- Thanks a lot, Sarge.
- Hicks, cover our ass.
Head 'em out, people.
I like to keep this handy...
for close encounters.
I heard that.
Any movement?
Nothing. Zip.
Holy shit.
Newt, go sit up front.
Go on! Now!
Steady, people.
Let's finish our sweep.
We're still marines,
and we got a job to do.
Keep it moving. Easy.
- Help!
- What?
Top, get over here. We got a live one!
You're gonna be all right.
Please... k-kill me.
Just stay calm.
We're gonna get you outta here.
It's gonna be all right. Give me a hand.
We gotta get her outta here.
- What is it, Dietrich?
- Convulsion!
Dietrich, get back!
Get back!
- No!
- Frost, flamethrower. Kill it!
Get back!
Flamethrower! Move!
Movement!
- What's the position?
- I can't lock in!
Talk to me, Hudson!
Multiple signals.
They're closing.
Go to infrared, people.
Look sharp!
What's happening, Apone?
Can't see anything in here.
Pull your team out, Gorman.
I got signals. I got readings
in front and behind.
Where, man?
I don't see shit.
He's right.
There's nothing back here.
Look, I'm telling you. There's
something moving, and it ain't us!
- Oh, shit.
- Tracker's off scale, man.
They're all
around us, man! Jesus!
Maybe they don't show up
on infrared at all.
Frost!
Come on!
Jesus Christ, Apone!
What is going on?
Wierzbowski and Crowe are down!
Dietrich, Crowe! Sound off! Frost!
Dietrich, Frost, off the board!
Frost!
Wierzbowski?
Let's rock!
Who's firing?
Goddamn it!
Yeah!
- I ordered to hold fire.
- They're coming out of the walls!
They're coming out of the goddamn walls!
Let's book!
On the right, man.
Uh, Apone,
I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with the incinerators-
Vasquez, Drake, hold
your fire, goddamn it!
Apone, are you copying me?
I want you to lay down suppressing fire...
with the incinerators and fall
back by squads to the A.P.C.
Over. Say again, all
after "incinerator."
I said I want you to lay down a suppressing
fire with the incinerators and fall back...
- by squads to the A.P.C.
- Over.
Hey!
- Sarge! Sarge!
- Apone.
Talk to me. Apone?
Copy! Copy!
Talk to me, Apone.
He's gone!
Get them out of there!
Shut up!
Do it now! Hicks, whoever's
left, get-Shut up!
Just shut up!
Goddamn it!
It's coming out of the goddamn walls!
Where's Apone? Where's Apone?
The sarge is gone!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Let's move it!
Let's go, marine!
Hudson? Vasquez?
Hudson, look out!
Get it!
Watch it!
Hicks. Come on. Behind you!
Fall back!
- I told them to fall back.
- Fall back, goddamn it, now!
- They're cut off!
- Hudson, move your ass!
- Do something!
- Let's go, marine!
Fuck!
Come on. Keep moving, baby.
Hold on, Newt.
Ripley, what the hell
are you doing?
Turn around!
That's an order!
Get offme, damn it!
Goddamn it, that's an order!
You had your chance, Gorman.
Come on!
Come on. Let's move it!
Let's go! Let's go!
It's blocked, man.
We gotta go around!
- Open the door! Hicks!
- Drake, we are leaving!
Get them, man!
Run for it!
Shit!
- Go! Go!
- Come on, man! Come on!
Drake, come on!
No!
- Fire in the hole!
- He's gone!
Put it out! Put it out!
Go! Go!
- Come on. Put it out!
- Drake's coming, man!
Drake! No, he's not! He's gone!
Forget him!
He's gone!
They're in the goddamn door!
Eat this!
Ripley!
Go, go, go!
It's all right!
We're clear!
Ripley, you've blown
the transaxle!
You're just grinding metal!
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
Ease down. Ease down.
You okay?
L'm all right.
Hudson.
Get away from me, man!
Lieutenant. What
happened to Gorman?
I don't know.
Maybe a concussion.
But he's alive.
He's dead!
Wake up, pendejo, and then
I'm gonna kill you!
Back off.
Right now.
Fuck! Somebody get
me a first aid kit.
Hey. Hey, look.
The sarge and Dietrich
aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low,
but they ain't dead.
- Then we go back in there and get them.
- Fuck that!
We don't leave our people behind—
I ain't going back in there.
You can't help them!
You can't. Right now they're being
cocooned just like the others.
Oh, dear Lord Jesus, this ain't
happenin', man. Damn it.
This can't be happenin', man.
This isn't happenin'!
All right. We got
seven canisters of CN-20.
I say we roll them in there and
nerve gas the whole fucking nest.
That's worth a try, but we don't
even know if it's gonna affect them.
Let's just bug out and call it even. Okay?
What are we talking about this for?
I say we take off and nuke
the entire site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Fuckin' "A"! Hold on.
Hold on one second.
This installation has a substantial
dollar value attached to it.
They can bill me.
Okay, look. This is an emotional
moment for all of us, okay?
I know that. But let's not
make snap judgments, please.
This is clearly-clearly an important
species we're dealing with,
and I don't think that you or
I or anybody has the right...
- to arbitrarily exterminate them.
- Wrong.
Yeah. Watch us.
Maybe you haven't been
keeping up on current events,
but we just got
our asses kicked, pal!
Look. I'm not blind
to what's going on,
but I cannot authorize
that kind of action.
I'm sorry.
Well, I believe
Corporal Hicks...
has authority here.
Corporal Hicks is-
This operation is under
military jurisdiction,
and Hicks is next
in chain of command.
Am I right, Corporal?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah. Look, Ripley.
Yes.
This is a multimillion-dollar
installation, okay?
He can't make
that kind of decision.
He's just a grunt.
Uh, no offense.
None taken. Ferro, do you copy?
Standing by.
Prep for dust off. We're
gonna need immediate evac.
Roger. On our way.
I say we take off, nuke the site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Let's do it.
Let's go. Pick it up, Hudson.
Pick it up, baby.
All right.
Set him down here.
Move it, Spunkmeyer.
We're rolling.
Hold on a second.
There's something-
Just get up here.
I'm in. Ramp closing.
Spunkmeyer.
Goddamn it.
Well, where the fuck-
Run!
Well, that's great.
That's just fuckin' great, man.
Now what the fuck
are we supposed to do?
We're in some
real pretty shit now, man!
Are you finished?
You all right?
I guess we're not gonna
be leaving now, right?
I'm sorry, Newt.
You don't have to be sorry. It
wasn't your fault. That's it, man.
Game over, man!
Game over!
What the fuck are we gonna do now?
What are we gonna do?
Maybe we could build a fire. Sing a couple
of songs, huh? Why don't we try that?
We'd better get back
'cause it'll be dark soon,
and they mostly
come at night, mostly.
That's everything, right? All right.
This is absolutely everything...
that we could salvage
out of the A.P.C. wreckage.
We got four pulse rifles
with about 50 rounds each.
That ain't so good.
We got, uh,
1 5 of these M-40 grenades.
Don't touch that.
Dangerous, honey. Is that
the only flamethrower?
Yeah. It's only half full,
but it's functional.
Got another one, it's damaged—
I don't know about that one.
But the good news-we got
four of these robot sentries,
with display
and scanners intact.
They really kick ass.
I think they'll come in handy.
How long after we're declared
overdue can we expect a rescue?
Seventeen days.
Seventeen days?
Hey, man, I don't wanna rain on your
parade, but we're not gonna last 17 hours.
Those things are gonna come in here like they did before.
They're gonna come in here-
Hudson! Hudson! They're gonna come
in here and they're gonna get us!
This little girl
survived longer than that...
with no weapons
and no training.
Right?
Why don't you
put her in charge?
You'd better just start dealing
with it, Hudson. Listen to me.
Hudson, just deal with it
because we need you.
And I'm sick of your bullshit.
Now, I want you to get on a terminal and
call up some kind of floor plan file.
Do you understand? Construction blueprints.
I don't care.
Anything that shows the layout of this place.
Are you listening?
Yeah.
I need to see air ducts.
I need to see electrical
access tunnels, subbasements,
every possible way
into this complex.
- We don't have much time.
- Okay.
Okay, I'm on it.
Hudson!
Just relax.
I'll be in medlab. I'll check on
Gorman, continue my analysis.
Fine.
You do that.
So this service tunnel must be how
they're moving back and forth.
That's right. It moves from
the processing station...
right into the sublevel here.
Come down on that.
Okay, come over.
Hold. Go back. Okay, punch
that in right there.
No. It's back here.
Okay.
Well, there's a pressure
door at this end.
Couldn't we put one of the remote sentry
units in the tunnel and then seal that door?
Yeah, that'll work, but we gotta figure
on them getting into the complex.
That's right, so we repair the
barricades at these two intersections.
Right. And weld plate
steel over these ducts...
here and here and here.
That way they can only come at
us from these two corridors.
All right. Then we put the other
sentry units here and here, right?
Right.
Outstanding.
Now all we need
is a deck of cards.
All right, people. Let's
move like we got a purpose.
Affirmative.
Do your thing, baby. Come on, Vasquez.
Let's get the hell outta here.
Hudson here. "A" and "B"
sentries are in place and keyed.
Roger. Stand by. Arming now.
Test it, Hudson.
Do it!
Fire in the hole!
Okay, great. Let's get
the hell outta here!
We're sealing the tunnel.
Come on, baby.
For what it's worth.
Here. I want you
to put this on.
- What's it for?
- It's a locator.
Then I can find you anywhere
in the complex on this.
It's just a precaution. Thanks.
Doesn't mean we're
engaged or anything.
All right, what's next?
Last stop.
Get in.
Scoot down.
That's good.
Now, you lie here and have a nap.
You're very tired.
I don't want to.
I have scary dreams.
Well, I bet Casey doesn't
have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
Nope. Nothing bad
in there.
See? Maybe you could
just try to be like her, hmm?
Ripley, she doesn't
have bad dreams...
because she's just
a piece of plastic.
Right.
I'm sorry, Newt.
There.
My mommy always said
there were no monsters-
no real ones-
but there are.
Yes, there are, aren't there?
Why do they tell
little kids that?
Most of the time it's true.
Did one of those things
grow inside her?
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
Isn't that how babies come?
I mean, people babies?
They grow inside you.
Oh, that's very different.
Did you ever have a baby?
Yes, I did.
I had a little girl.
Where is she?
She's gone.
You mean dead.
Here.
Take this.
For luck.
There's that.
Don't go, please.
Newt, I'm gonna be
right in the next room.
And you see that camera
right up there?
I can see you
right through that camera,
all the time
to see if you're safe.
I'm not gonna leave you, Newt.
I mean that.
That's a promise.
You promise?
I cross my heart.
- And hope to die?
- And hope to die.
Now go to sleep,
and don't dream.
Sneak.
The molecular acid oxidizes after the
creature's death, completely neutralizing it.
Bishop, you know, that's very interesting, but
it doesn't really get us anywhere, does it?
I'm trying to figure out
what we're dealing with here.
Let's go through it again.
They grab the colonists,
they move them over there...
and they immobilize them
to be hosts for more of these.
Which would mean that there would have
to be a lot of these parasites, right?
One for each colonist.
That's over 100, at least.
Yes. Τhat follows.
But each one of these things
comes from an egg, right?
So who's laying these eggs?
I'm not sure.
It must be something
we haven't seen yet.
Hey, maybe it's like
an ant hive.
Bees, man.
Bees have hives.
You know what I mean. There's, like,
one female that runs the whole show.
Yes, the queen.
Ueah, the mama.
She's badass, man.
I mean, big.
These things ain't ants, estúpido.
I know that.
Bishop, I want these specimens destroyed
as soon as you're finished with them.
- Is that clear?
- Mr. Burke gave instructions...
that they were to be kept alive in
stasis for return to the company labs.
He was very specific about it.
Look. Those two specimens are worth millions
to the bio-weapons division, right?
Now, if you're smart, we can
both come out of this heroes,
and we will be set up for life.
You're crazy, Burke.
Do you know that?
Do you really think you can get a dangerous
organism like that past I.C.C. quarantine?
How can they impound it if
they don't know about it?
But they will know about it,
Burke, from me.
Just like they'll know that you were
responsible for the deaths of 157 colonists.
Wait a second. You sent
them to that ship.
You're wrong. I just
checked the colony log.
Directive dated 6-1 2-79,
signed Burke, Carter J.
You sent them out there,
and you didn't even warn them.
Why didn't you warn them, Burke?
Okay, look.
What if that ship didn't even exist?
Do you ever think about that?
I didn't know. So now if I went and made
a major security situation out of it,
everybody steps in, administration steps in,
and there's no exclusive rights for anybody.
Nobody wins. So I made a
decision, and it was wrong.
It was a bad call, Ripley.
It was a bad call.
Bad call?
Right.
These people are dead, Burke!
Don't you have any idea
what you've done here?
I'm gonna make sure that they nail
you right to the wall for this!
You're not gonna sleaze
your way out of this one.
Right to the wall.
Ripley. I-
You know, I expected
more from you.
I thought you'd be
smarter than this.
Well, I'm happy
to disappoint you.
What is it? What's going on?
They're coming.
Where?
In the tunnel.
Here we go. "A" and "B" gun tracking far end.
Multiple targets.
Those ammo counters go.
"B" gun's down 50%..
Man, it's a shooting gallery
down there.
Sixty rounds left on "B."
Forty. Twenty. Ten.
"B" gun's dry.
Twenty on "A."
Ten. Five.
That's it.
Jesus, they were
wall-to-wall in there.
They're at the pressure door.
Man, listen to that.
Bishop here. I'm afraid
I have some bad news.
Well, that's a switch.
It's very pretty, Bishop,
but what are we looking for?
That's it.
Emergency venting.
Oh, that's beautiful, man. Oh,
man, that-that just beats it all.
How long till it blows?
Four hours.
With a blast radius
of 30 kilometers,
equal to about 40 megatons.
We got problems. I don't believe this.
I don't fucking believe this.
Vasquez, close the shutters.
Why can't we shut it
down from here?
I'm sorry. The crash
caused too much damage.
An overload is inevitable
at this point.
Oh, man, and I was
getting short.
Four more weeks and out. Now
l'm gonna buy it on this rock.
It ain't half fair, man.
Hudson, give us a break!
Four more weeks. Oh, man.
We've got to get the other
drop ship from the Sulaco.
I mean, there must be some way
of bringing it down on remote.
How? The transmitter was on the A.P.C.
It's wasted.
I don't care how, but we'd better think of something.
We'd better think of a way.
Think of what? We're fucked!
We're doomed! Shut up!
Shut up! What about
the colony transmitters?
The uplink tower down at the other end.
Why can't we use that?
No, I checked. The hardware in
between here and there was damaged.
We can't align the dish.
Well, somebody's gonna
have to go out there,
take a portable terminal, go out
there and patch in manually.
Oh, yeah, sure. With those things running around?
You can count me out.
Guess we can just count you
out of everything. I'll go.
That's right, man.
Why don't you go, man?
I'll go.
What?
I'll go. I mean, I'm the only one qualified
to remote pilot the ship anyway.
Yeah, right, man. Bishop should go.
Good idea.
Believe me, I'd prefer not to.
I may be synthetic,
but I'm not stupid.
How long?
This conduit runs almost to the
uplink assembly-1 80 meters.
Say 40 minutes to crawl
down there-Right.
An hour to patch in
and align the antenna.
Thirty minutes
to prep the ship,
and about 50 minutes flight time.
It's gonna be close.
Good luck.
See you soon.
Watch your fingers.
Vaya con Dios, man.
This is unbelievable.
Twenty meters and closing.
Fifteen.
How many?
Can't tell. Lots.
"D" gun's down 50%..
"C" gun's right behind it.
Stopping them.
It ain't stopping them.
- 150 rounds on "D."
Come on. Come on, baby.
Hundred rounds.
Come on! Come on!
"D" gun's down to 20.
Ten.
Damn it!
Wait! They're retreating.
The guns stopped them.
You're right.
Next time they walk
right up and knock.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
They're probably looking
for other ways to get in.
That'll take 'em a while.
Maybe we got 'em demoralized.
Shut up!
I want you two
walking perimeter.
Move!
Hey, listen.
We're all
in strung-out shape,
but stay frosty and alert.
We can't afford to let
one of those bastards in here.
All right.
Vámonos.
How long's it been
since you got any sleep?
Twenty-four hours?
Hicks, I'm not gonna end
up like those others.
You'll take care
of it, won't you?
If it comes to that,
I'll do us both.
Listen, let's just make sure
it doesn't come to that.
All right?
All right.
Hey, I want to introduce you
to a personal friend of mine.
This is an M-41A
pulse rifle, 10 millimeter,
with an over-and-under 30 millimeter
pump-action grenade launcher.
Feel the weight.
Okay, what do I do?
Okay, pull it in tight here.
Right.
Uh-huh. Lean into it. Mm-hmm.
All right.
Now, it will kick some.
All right. When the counter
reads zero here, you-
I press this up?
That's right.
Get another one in quick.
Slap it in hard.
Right. And you're ready
to rock and roll.
What's this? That's
the grenade launcher.
I don't think you
want to mess with that.
You started this.
Show me everything.
I can handle myself.
Yeah, I noticed.
How do you feel?
All right, I guess.
One hell of a hangover.
Look, Ripley, I just
want-Forget it.
Excuse me.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
It's okay. It's okay.
Newt, wake up.
Wha-
Be quiet.
We're in trouble.
No!
Move, Newt!
Hey!
Help! Help!
Hicks!
Somebody!
Say again, Bishop.
You've got it into auto-refuel
mode, and it's sequencing right?
That's right.
Okay, good. Stay on it.
Get back to me when you've
activated the launch cycle.
Roger.
He's at the uplink tower.
Good.
Terrific.
- Hicks! Hicks! Hicks!
- Help!
- Help! Help!
- Hicks, help us!
- Break the glass! Break it. Break it.
- Yes.
I'll try.
Ripley, I'm scared.
Me too.
Stay here.
It's the medlab. Hudson!
Vasquez, meet me in medlab.
We got a fire.
We're on our way.
They're coming, Newt.
Shoot it out!
- Hudson!
- Jesus.
Christ, kid, look out!
Fucking die.
Over there! Ready?
Yeah! Yeah!
Now!
Hudson?
Yeah. All clear.
Nailed the other one.
Lt's history, man.
Jesus.
Burke-
It was Burke.
I say we grease this rat-fuck
son of a bitch right now.
Just doesn't make
any goddamn sense.
He figured that he could get an
alien back through quarantine...
if one of us
was impregnated-
whatever you call it-
and then frozen
for the trip home.
Nobody would know about the
embryos we were carrying-
me and Newt.
Wait a minute, now.
We'd all know.
Yes. The only way
he could do it...
is if he sabotaged certain
freezers on the way home.
Namely yours.
Then he could jettison the bodies
and make up any story he liked.
Fuck! He's dead.
You're dog meat, pal.
This is so nuts.
I mean, listen-
Listen to what you're saying.
It's paranoid delusion.
It's really sad.
It's pathetic.
You know, Burke, I don't know
which species is worse.
You don't see them fucking each other
over for a goddamn percentage.
All right.
We waste him. No offense.
No! He's gotta go back-
They cut the power. What do
you mean, they cut the power?
How could they cut the power, man?
They're animals.
I want you two with trackers,
checking the corridors! Move!
Gorman, watch Burke!
I got him.
Newt, stay close.
I'll go this side.
You do that, man.
- Anything?
- There's something.
It's inside the complex.
You're just reading me.
No, no, it ain't you.
They're inside-inside the perimeter.
They're in here.
Hudson, stay cool!
Vasquez?
Hudson may be right.
- Get back, both of you!
- The signal's weird.
Must be some interference
or something.
There's movement
all over the place!
Get back to Operations.
It's game time.
Newt.
Seal the door.
Hurry!
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Get back!
Work fast.
Cover your eyes, Newt.
Don't look at the light.
Movement. Signal's clean.
Range, 20 meters.
They found a way in,
something we missed.
We didn't miss anything.
Eighteen.
Seventeen meters.
Something under the floor, not in the plans.
I don't know.
- Fifteen meters.
- Ripley!
- Definitely inside the barricades.
- Let's go.
Thirteen meters. That's
right outside the door.
Hicks, Vasquez, get back!
This is a big fucking signal.
- How you doing, Vasquez? Talk to me.
- Almost there.
That's it.
Twelve meters. Eleven.
- Ten.
- Then they're right on us.
- Nine meters.
- Remember-short, controlled bursts.
Eight meters.
Seven.
- Six.
- It can't be. That's inside the room.
- It's reading right, man. Look!
- Well, you're not reading it right.
Five meters, man.
Four. What the hell?
Oh, my God. Oh, sh-
Give me the light.
There they go!
Over there! Get them!
Come on! Get them!
Do something, Gorman!
Get them! Look out! There's more of them!
There's more of them!
Medical! Get to Medical!
Do it! Now!
Hudson, look out!
Look out!
Now!
Burke!
Open this door!
Burke! Open it!
Go! Fall back!
Go!
- Die, motherfucker!
- Burke!
Hudson! Hudson!
Motherfucker! Come on! Come on!
Come and get it, baby! Come on!
I don't got all day! Come on! Come on!
Come on, you bastard!
- Come on! You too!
- Oh, you want some of this?
Fuck you!
Fuck you! Hicks!
Hudson!
Come on.
Let's go!
It's locked!
- Got it! Let's go! Let's go!
- Go! Go!
- Move, Gorman!
- Seal it!
Burke! Goddamn you!
Open this door!
Get back!
- Hurry up.
- Gorman, get out of the way!
Ripley, this way!
What-
Wait. Get behind me.
Whatever you're gonna do,
do it fast!
Hicks! Go! Come on. Let's go.
Move!
Which way is it to the landing
field from here? This way.
Go right.
This way. This way.
- Which way?
- Straight ahead and left.
Bishop, do you read me?
Come in. Over.
The ship is on its way.
E.T.A., 16 minutes.
Stand by there.
We're on our way.
- Which way now?
- That way.
No, wait. This way.
You sure?
Vasquez, move!
Right up here. It's just up here.
Hicks!
We're almost there.
Newt, wait! Newt!
Vasquez!
Go!
Oh, no!
Newt.
Up there. There's a shortcut
across the roof.
Hicks.
You always were
an asshole, Gorman.
Newt! God!
Ripley!
Newt!
Hicks! Hicks, get her!
Hurry!
- Hold on, Newt!
- I'm slipping!
- Don't let go.
- Ripley!
- Hold on. Gotcha!
- Help!
I gotcha.
Newt!
No!
Come on.
We can find her with this.
- Stay where you are, Newt.
- Ripley!
We're coming.
Ripley!
This way.
She's close.
Newt!
Ripley!
Where are you?
Can you hear me?
Newt!
Here!
I'm here!
Where?
Newt, are you okay?
We'll have to cut it.
Climb down, honey.
We've gotta cut through.
Newt?
Now, don't move.
Stay very still.
Okay.
We're almost there.
Hang in there, okay?
Hicks. Hurry.
I know.
I know!
I mean it!
Newt? Newt,
just stay still.
Almost there.
No!
Newt!
No! No!
No! No! No!
Let's go.
No! No!
They don't kill you!
They-They don't kill you!
They-
She's alive!
All right. I believe you.
She's alive.
We've got to go. Now!
Go!
Get it off!
Hicks.
Here.
Go.
Come on.
You can make it.
Bishop, how much time?
Plenty.
Twenty-six minutes.
We're not leaving.
We're not?
Ripley-I don't wanna hear about it, Bishop.
She's alive. There's still time.
In 19 minutes, this area is gonna be a
cloud of vapor the size of Nebraska.
Hicks, don't let him leave.
We ain't going anywhere.
See you, Hicks.
Dwayne.
It's Dwayne.
Ellen.
Don't be gone long, Ellen.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have 15 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have 14 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Oh.
- Ripley! Ripley!
- Newt.
Grab on to me!
Hold on!
Let's go!
Behind us!
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have four minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Come on, goddamn it!
Hold on to me!
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have two minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
No.
Bishop, goddamn you!
Close your eyes, baby.
Look!
Come on! Come on!
Punch it, Bishop!
It's okay.
We're okay.
Hey.
We made it.
I knew you'd come.
He's gonna be all right.
He's just out.
I had to give him another shot
for the pain.
We need a stretcher
to carry him up to Medical.
Okay.
I'm sorry if I scared you. That
platform wasjust becoming too unstable.
I had to circle and hope that things
didn't get too rough to take you off.
Bishop, you did okay.
- I did?
- Oh, yeah.
Go! Move!
No! Here! Here!
Run!
Here!
Get away from her, you bitch!
Come on! Come on!
Ripley!
Bishop!
Mommy.
Oh, God!
Not bad for a h-human.
Are we gonna sleep
all the way home?
All the way home.
Can I dream?
Yes, honey.
I think we both can.
Sleep tight.
Affirmative.