[Shutter Whirring]
I need a father who's a role model,
not some horny geek boy...
who's going to spray his shorts whenever
I bring a girlfriend home from school.
What a lame-o.
Someone really should just put him
out of his misery.
[Boy]
You want me to kill him for you?
Yeah. Would you?
[Shutter Whirring,
Clicking Off]
[Man Narrating]
My name is Lester Burnham.
This is my neighborhood.
This is my street.
This is my life.
I'm 42 years old.
In less than a year, l'll be dead.
[Alarm Ringing]
Of course,
I don't know that yet.
And in a way,
I'm dead already.
Look at me:
jerking off in the shower.
This will be the high point of my day.
It's all downhill from here.
That's my wife, Carolyn.
See the way the handle on those pruning
shears matches her gardening clogs?
- That's not an accident.
- [Dog Barking]
[Man]
Hush, Bitsy!
- Hush. What is wrong with you?
- That's our next-door neighbor, Jim.
- And that's his lover, Jim.
- [Both Arguing]
- You spoil her.
Bitsy, no bark. Come inside now.
- Me?
- Come on. Yes. Inside.
- [Carolyn] Good morning, Jim!
Good morning, Carolyn.
I love your tie!
That color!
I just love your roses. How do you
get them to flourish like this?
Well, l'll tell you:
eggshells and Miracle-Gro.
- I've never heard that.
- Man, I get exhausted just watching her.
She wasn't always like this.
She used to be happy.
We used to be happy.
My daughter Jane.
Only child.
- Janie's a pretty typical teenager:
- [Computer Beeps]
angry, insecure, confused.
I wish I could tell her that's all going
to pass, but I don't want to lie to her.
[Horn Honking]
Jane, honey, are you trying
to look unattractive?
- Yes.
- Congratulations.
You've succeeded admirably.
Lester, could you make me
a little later, please,
because I'm not quite late enough.
[Mutters, Indistinct]
Nice going, Dad.
[Lester Narrating] Both my wife and
daughter think I'm this gigantic loser.
And they're right.
I have lost something.
I'm not exactly sure
what it is,
but I know
I didn't always feel this...
sedated.
But you know what?
It's never too late
to get it back.
Hello. This is Lester Burnham
from Media Monthly magazine.
I'm calling
for Mr. Tamblin, please.
Well, we're all under
a deadline here. You see,
there's some basic information...
about your product launch
that isn't even covered
in your press release, and I'd...
Yeah, c...
can I ask you a question?
Who is Tamblin? Does he exist?
'Cause he doesn't ever seem to come in.
Yeah. Okay.
l'll leave my number.
It's 555-0199.
Lester Burnham.
Thank you!
Hey, Les.
You got a minute?
For you, Brad,
I got five!
So, yeah, I'm sure you can understand
our need to cut corners around here.
Oh, sure.
Times are tight.
You got to free up some cash.
You got to spend money to make money.
- Right?
- Exactly.
Like the time that Mr. Flournoy
used the company MasterCard
to pay for that hooker,
and she used the card numbers
and stayed at the St. Regis for,
what was it, three months?
- That's unsubstantiated gossip.
- That's $50,000.
That's somebody's salary.
That's somebody who's going
to get fired because Craig
has to pay women to fuck him!
Jesus!
I mean, calm down.
Nobody's getting fired yet.
- [Scoffs]
- That's why we're having everyone...
write out a job description mapping
out in detail how they contribute.
That way management
can assess who's valuable...
And who's expendable.
It's just business.
I've been writing
for this magazine for 14 years.
- You've been here how long?
A whole month?
- I'm one of the good guys, Les.
I'm trying to level with you.
This is your one chance
to save your job.
[Carolyn] There is no decision.
You just write the damn thing.
- [Lester] You don't think
it's weird and kind of fascist?
- Possibly.
- But you don't want to be unemployed.
- All right.
Let's just all sell our souls
and work for Satan 'cause
it's more convenient that way.
Oh, could you be a little bit
more dramatic, please, huh?
So, we finally
got new neighbors.
You know, if the Lomans
had let me represent them
instead of the Real Estate King,
that house would never
have sat on the market for six months.
Well, they were still mad at you
for cutting down their sycamore.
Their sycamore?
Come on.
A substantial portion of the root
structure was on our property.
You know that.
How can you call it their sycamore?
I wouldn't have the heart to just cut
down something if it wasn't partially
mine, which, of course, it was.
@@ [Stereo: Instrumental]
[Woman Singing]
@ Bali Ha'i @
@ They call you @@
- @@ [Continues, Indistinct]
- Mom, do we always have to listen
to this elevator music?
No. No, we don't.
And as soon you've prepared a nutritious
yet savory meal that I'm about to eat,
you can listen
to whatever you like.
So, Janie, how was school?
It was okay.
Just okay?
No, Dad.
It was spectacular.
Well, you want to know
how things went in my job today?
They've hired
this efficiency expert,
this really friendly guy
named Brad...
How perfect is that?
And he's basically there
to make it seem they're justified...
in firing somebody,
because they couldn't just come
out and say that, could they?
No, no. That would just be too honest.
So they've asked us...
[Chuckling] You couldn't
possibly care less, could you?
What do you expect?
You can't all of a sudden be my best
friend just because you had a bad day.
I mean, hello, you've barely even
spoken to me for months.
Oh, what?
You're "Mother of the Year"?
- [Muttering]
You treat her like an employee.
- What?
[Shouts]
What?
I'm going
to get some ice cream.
Janie...
I'm sorry I haven't
been more available.
I'm just... I...
You know, you don't always
have to wait for me to come to you.
Oh, great.
So now it's my fault?
I didn't say that.
It's nobody's fault. It...
Janie, what happened?
We used to be pals.
[Inaudible]
[Water Running]
@@ [Humming]
@@ [Stops Humming]
[Grunts]
[Exhales Forcefully]
I will sell this house today.
[Coughing]
Welcome.
I'm Carolyn Burnham.
This living room
is very dramatic.
Wait till you see
the native stone fireplace!
A simple cream could
really lighten things up.
You could even put in a skylight.
Well, why don't we
go into the kitchen?
It's a dream come true
for any cook.
Just filled
with positive energy, huh?
And you'll be surprised
how much a ceiling fan can
cut down on your energy costs.
You know, you could have some fun
backyard get-togethers out here.
The ad said this pool was lagoon-like.
There's nothing lagoon-like about it.
Except for maybe the bugs.
There aren't even any plants out here.
What do you call this?
Is this not a plant?
If you have a problem with the plants, I
can always call my landscape architect.
- Solved.
- I mean, I think "lagoon,"
I think waterfall, tropical.
This is a cement hole.
Uh...
I have some tiki torches
in the garage.
[Crying]
Shut up! Stop it!
You weak... You baby!
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up!
[Gasping]
- [Crowd Cheering]
- [Drums Beating Rhythmically]
[Players Shouting
To Each Other]
[Crowd Cheering]
Who are you looking for?
My parents are coming tonight.
They're trying to, you know,
take an active interest in me.
Gross. I hate it
when my mom does that.
They're such assholes. Why can't
they just have their own lives?
[Girls Screeching]
[Lester]
What makes you sure she wants us
to be there? Did she ask us to come?
Of course not. She doesn't want us
to know how important this is to her.
But she's been practicing
for weeks.
l'll bet she's going to
resent it, and I'm missing
the James Bond marathon on T.N.T.
Lester, this is important.
I'm sensing a real distance
growing between you and Jane.
"Growing"?
She hates me.
- She's just willful.
- She hates you too.
[All Shouting]
[Girls Cheering]
- Excuse me. Sorry. I'm sorry.
- Pardon me.
- [Buzzer Sounding]
- Hi! Patty!
[Announcer Over P.A.]
Now, for your halftime entertainment,
Rockwell High's award-winning
Dancing Spartanettes!
We can leave
right after this, right?
@@ [Band Playing "On Broadway"]
[Audience Clapping In Tune]
[Ambient Noise Fades]
@@ ["On Broadway" Finishes]
[Crowd Cheering]
Shit. They're still here.
Janie!
Hey, I really enjoyed that.
- Congratulations, honey. You were great.
- I didn't win anything.
- Hi. I'm Lester, Janie's dad.
- Oh, hi.
This is my friend,
Angela Hayes.
Okay. Good to meet you.
You were also good tonight,
very... precise.
- Thanks.
- Nice to meet you, Angela.
Honey... [Grunts]
I am so proud of you.
You know, I watched you very closely.
You didn't screw up once.
Okay, uh, we have to go.
- So what are you girls doing now?
- Dad.
- We're going out for pizza.
- Really? Do you need a ride?
We can give you a ride.
- I have a car.
You want to come with us?
- Thanks, but I have a car.
You have a car.
That's great. That's great.
Janie's thinking about
getting a car, too, soon, aren't you?
Dad, Mom's waiting for you.
Well, it was very nice
meeting you, Angela.
Any friend of Janie's...
is a... friend of mine.
[Exhales]
Well... l'll be
seeing you around, then.
Could he be any more...
pathetic?
I think he's sweet.
And I think he and your mother
have not had sex in a long time.
[Lester Narrating]
It's the weirdest thing.
I feel like I've been in a coma
for about 20 years...
and I'm just now waking up.
Spec-tacular.
@@ [Radio: Rock]
I'm so sorry
my dad was weird tonight.
That's okay.
I'm used to guys
drooling over me.
It started
when I was about 12.
I'd go to dinner
with my parents.
Every Thursday night: Red Lobster.
[Chuckles]
Every guy there would stare at me
when I walked in.
And I knew
what they were thinking,
just like I knew guys at school thought
about me when they jerked off.
- Vomit.
- No. I liked it.
I still like it. If people I don't even
know look at me and want to fuck me,
it means I really have a shot
at being a model.
Which is great,
because there's nothing worse in life
than being ordinary.
I really think
it'll happen for you.
I know.
Because everything that was meant
to happen, does... eventually.
Asshole.
[Shower Running]
[Phone Ringing]
[Angela]
Hello? Hello?
- [Clanking]
- [Phone Beeps Off]
[Phone Rings]
- Hello?
- Why'd you call me?
I didn't.
Well, my phone just rang and
I answered it, and somebody hung up.
- And I star-69ed,
and I called you back.
- Well, I was in the shower.
Oh, gross!
[Woman]
Ricky! Breakfast!
Be right there.
- Mom.
- Hello.
I don't eat bacon, remember?
I'm sorry.
I must've forgotten.
What's new in the world, Dad?
This country
is going straight to hell.
[Doorbell Ringing]
- Are you expecting anyone?
- No.
No.
- Hi.
- Welcome to the neighborhood.
- It's just a little something
from our garden.
- Except for the pasta.
- We got that at Fallaci's.
- Right. It's unbelievably fresh.
You just... You drop it
in the water, and it's done.
Jim Olmeyer. Two doors down.
Welcome to the neighborhood.
Colonel Frank Fitts,
U.S. Marine Corps.
- It's nice to meet you.
This is my partner...
- Jim Berkley, but call me J.B.
Let's cut to chase, okay?
What are you guys selling?
- [Chuckles] We...
- Nothing. We just wanted to
say hi to our new neighbors.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You said you're
partners, so what's your business?
Well... he is a tax attorney.
And he's an anesthesiologist.
@@ [Frank Humming]
How come these faggots
always have to rub it in your face?
How can they
be so shameless?
- @@ [Resumes Humming]
- That's the whole thing, Dad.
They don't feel that's anything
to be ashamed of.
Well, it is.
- Yeah, you're right.
- Don't placate me
like I'm your mother, boy.
Forgive me, sir,
for speaking so bluntly,
but those fags make me want
to puke my fucking guts out.
Well, me too, son.
Yeah. Me too.
@@ [Frank Resumes Humming]
[Angela] I'm serious. He just
pulled down his pants and yanked it out.
- You know, like,
"Say hello to Mr. Happy."
- Gross!
- It wasn't gross. It was kind of cool.
- So did you do it with him?
Of course. He's a really
well-known photographer.
He shoots for Elle on,
like, a regular basis.
- It would've been majorly stupid
of me to turn him down.
- You are a total prostitute.
Hey, that's how
things really are.
You just don't know because you're
this pampered little suburban chick.
So are you. You've only been
in Seventeen once, and you looked fat.
So stop acting like you're
goddamn Christy Turlington!
Cunt!
I am so sick of people
taking their insecurities out on me.
- Oh, my God. That's the pervert
who filmed me last night.
- Him?
Jane. No way.
He's a total lunatic.
- Do you know him?
- Yeah.
We were on the same lunch shift
when I was in ninth grade,
and he would always save
the most random, weird things.
And then one day,
he was just, like, gone.
And then Connie Cardullo told me
that his parents had to put him
in a mental institution.
Why? What did he do?
What do you mean?
Well, they can't put you away
just for saying weird things.
You total slut.
You've got a crush on him.
- What? Please!
- You are defending him. You love him.
- You want to have, like,
10,000 of his babies.
- Shut up.
Hi. My name's Ricky.
I just moved next door to you.
I know.
I kind of remember this creepy incident
where you were filming me last night?
- I didn't mean to scare you.
I just think you're interesting.
- Thanks.
But I really don't need to have some
psycho obsessing about me right now.
I'm not obsessing.
I'm just curious.
What a freak.
And why does he dress
like a Bible salesman?
He's, like, so confident.
That can't be real.
I don't believe him.
I mean, he didn't even,
like, look at me once.
@@ [Bugle: "Reveille"]
- How'd you get in the Army?
- Sergeant, I got three reasons
for being in the Army.
First, I'm patriotic. Second, I love
my country. And third, they nailed me.
[Laughs]
[TV Chatter Continues]
[Lock Rattling]
[Door Closes]
Hey.
- What's going on here?
- Bend all the way down.
Here comes the Bull of the Woods.
I'm sorry. What?
Mom, nobody said anything.
Oh. I'm sorry.
@@ [Latin Beat]
Everyone here is with their spouse
or significant other.
- How would it look
if I showed up with no one?
- You always end up ignoring me.
Now, listen to me.
This is an important business function.
As you know, my business
is selling an image,
and part of my job
is to live that image.
Honey, do me a favor and say
whatever you want to say
and spare me the propaganda.
All right.
Hi, Shirley!
Listen. Just do me a favor.
Act happy tonight.
- [High Voice] I am happy, honey!
- You're not... Oh, that's Buddy!
- Buddy! Buddy! Hi!
- Hi.
Good to see you again.
- It's so good to see you too, Catherine.
- Carolyn.
Oh, Carolyn! Of course.
How are you?
- Very well, thank you. Hello, Christy.
- Hello.
- My husband, Lester.
- It's a pleasure.
Oh, we've met before,
actually. This thing last year.
Christmas at the Sheraton.
Oh, yeah!
Oh, it's okay.
I wouldn't remember me either.
Honey, don't be weird.
- All right, honey. I won't be weird.
- Okay.
l'll be whatever
you want me to be.
Well, oka...
- We have a very healthy relationship.
- I see.
[Sighs]
Well, I don't know about you guys,
but I need a drink.
Ohh.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Put a little more in there, cowboy.
[Carolyn, Buddy
Shrieking With Laughter]
[Groaning]
Excuse me. Don't you live on Robin Hood
Trail? The house with the red door?
- Yeah.
- I'm Ricky Fitts.
I just moved in the house next to you.
Oh. Hi, Ricky Fitts.
I'm Lester Burnham.
Hi, Lester Burnham.
- Do you party?
- Excuse me?
Do you get high?
You know, I probably wouldn't
even tell you this if I weren't
a little tipsy, but...
I'm in complete awe of you.
I mean, your firm...
is hands-down the Rolls-Royce
of local real estate firms,
and your personal
sales record is...
[Clicks Tongue, Sighs]
It's very intimidating.
You know, I'd love to sit down
with you and just pick your brain,
- [Chuckles]
- If you'd ever be willing.
You know, I suppose technically
I'm the competition,
but I mean, hey,
I don't flatter myself...
that I'm even
in the same league as you.
I don't.
I'd love to.
- Really?
- Absolutely.
Call my secretary.
Have her schedule a lunch.
l'll do that.
Thank you.
[Lester] Did you ever see that movie
where the body is walking around...
carrying its own head, and then
the head goes down on that babe?
- [Both Laughing]
- [Ricky] Re-Animator.
[Both Continue Laughing]
- [Both Stop Laughing]
- Look.
I'm not paying you to do whatever
it is you're doing out here.
Fine. So don't pay me.
Excuse me?
I quit, so you don't have
to pay me. Now leave me alone.
Asshole.
I think you just
became my personal hero.
Doesn't that make you nervous,
just quitting your job like that?
Well, I guess when
you're all of, what, 16...
Eighteen. I just do
these gigs as a cover.
I have other sources of income.
But my dad interferes less
in my life when I pretend...
to be an upstanding young citizen
with a respectable job.
[Carolyn]
Lester?
- What are you doing?
- Honey, this is... Ricky Fitts.
[Wheezing Laugh]
This is Ricky Fitts.
[Continues Laughing Hysterically]
I'm Ricky Fitts. I just moved
into the house next to you.
I go to school
with your daughter.
- With Jane?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Jane.
Hi. I'm ready to go.
l'll meet you out front.
- [Whimpering Laugh]
Oh, I'm in trouble.
- [Chuckles]
Nice meeting you, Ricky.
Thanks for the thing.
Anytime. Lester?
If you want any more,
you know where I live.
[Laughs]
- @@ [On TV]
- [Door Closes]
Oh, shit. They're home. Quick.
Let's go up to my room.
I should say hi
to your dad.
I don't want to be rude.
Nice suit.
You're looking good,
Mr. Burnham.
Last time I saw you,
you looked kind of wound up.
Ooh, is that root beer?
I love root beer,
don't you?
- Hey.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi.
- Remember Angela?
Yes, of course.
I forgot to tell you. She's going
to spend the night. Is that okay?
[Coughing, Choking]
- [Jane] Sorry about my dad.
- [Angela]
Don't be. I think it's funny.
Yeah, to you he's just another guy
who wants to jump your bones.
But to me, he's just...
too embarrassing to live.
Well, your mom's the one
who's embarrassing. What a phony.
- But your dad's actually kind of cute.
- Shut up.
[Angela] He is. If he just
worked out a little, he'd be hot.
- Shut up!
- Come on.
Like you've never sneaked a peek
at him in his underwear?
I bet he's got a big dick.
[Jane Laughing]
You are so grossing me out right now.
[Angela] If he built up his chest
and arms, I would totally fuck him.
- @ La, la, la, la, la, la @
- I would. I would suck
your dad's big fat dick,
and then I'd fuck him until
his eyes rolled back in his head.
- [Rattling]
- Jane, shh. What was that noise?
- I swear I heard something.
- Yeah.
That was the sound of you
being a huge, disgusting pig.
- No, I'm serious.
- [Rattling]
See?
- Oh, my God. Jane.
- What is it?
It's that psycho next door.
Jane, what if he worships you?
What if he's got a shrine
with pictures of you surrounded
by dead people's heads and stuff?
Shit. I bet
he's filming us right now.
Really?
[Clattering]
Welcome to
America's Weirdest Home Videos.
- [Knocking]
- [Frank] Ricky?
Coming, Dad.
You know I don't like
locked doors in my house, boy.
- I'm sorry.
I must've locked it by accident.
- Mm.
[Ricky]
So what's up?
I... I need a urine sample.
Wow.
It's been six months already.
Can I give it to you in the morning?
I just took a whiz.
Yeah. I suppose.
Y-You know...
Well, good night, son.
[Water Dripping]
I've been waiting for you.
You've been working out,
haven't you?
I can tell.
I was hoping you could
give me a bath.
I'm very, very dirty.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
- You were masturbating.
- [Whispers] I was not.
Yes, you were.
Oh, all right.
So shoot me. I was whacking off.
That's right. I was choking
the bishop, chafing the carrot.
You know, saying "hi"
to my monster.
That's disgusting.
Well, excuse me, but some of us still
have blood pumping through our veins.
- So do I.
- Really?
Well, I'm the only one who seems
to be doing anything about it.
[Grunts]
Lester, I refuse to live like this!
This is not a marriage.
This hasn't been
a marriage for years,
but you were happy as long
as I kept my mouth shut.
Well, guess what.
I've changed.
And the new me whacks off
when he feels horny...
'cause you're obviously not going
to help me out in that department.
I see. You think you're the
only one who's sexually frustrated.
I'm not? Well, then,
come on, baby. I'm ready.
Don't you mess
with me, mister.
I will divorce you so fast,
it'll make your head spin.
On what grounds?
I'm not a drunk.
I don't fuck other women.
I don't mistreat you.
I've never hit you.
I don't even try to touch you,
since you made it so abundantly clear...
just how unnecessary
you consider me to be!
But... I did support you
when you got your license.
And some people might think that
entitles me to half of what's yours.
Oh!
So, turn out the light
when you come back to bed, okay?
[Lester Narrating] It's a great thing
when you realize you still have...
the ability
to surprise yourself.
Makes you wonder what else you can do
that you've forgotten about.
Hey, guys.
Lester. I didn't know you ran.
- I just started.
- Good for you.
I figured you guys might be
able to give me some pointers.
I need to shape up, fast.
Are you looking to just lose weight,
or do you want to have...
increased strength
and flexibility as well?
I... I want
to look good naked.
[Squeaking]
Oh, what is this?
Fuckin' gay pride parade?
Hey! Yo, Ricky.
[Panting]
My entire life is passing
before my eyes, and those two
have barely broken a sweat.
Sorry. Hi. Lester Burnham.
I live next door. We haven't met.
Colonel Frank Fitts,
U.S. Marine Corps.
Oh, whoa. Well.
Welcome to the neighborhood, sir.
Ricky, uh...
I was thinking about the, uh...
I was gonna... The movie we talked about.
- Re-Animator.
- Yeah!
You want to borrow it?
Okay. It's up in my room. Come on.
- Can you hold this for a sec?
- Sure.
I don't think my dad would try
to come in while someone else
is here, but you never know.
- What is this?
- Urine.
I have to take a drug test every
six months just to make sure I'm clean.
Are you kidding?
You just smoked with me last night.
It's not mine.
One of my clients is a nurse
in a pediatrician's office.
Cut her a deal,
she keeps me in clean piss.
You like Pink Floyd?
I like a lot of music.
Man, I haven't listened
to this album in years.
How much do you want?
I don't know. It's been a while.
Um, how much is an ounce?
This is totally decent,
and it's 300.
Wow!
This shit is
top of the line.
It's called G-13. It's genetically
engineered by the U.S. government.
It's extremely potent, but
a completely mellow high. No paranoia.
Is that what we smoked
last night?
This is all I ever smoke.
- How much?
- Two grand.
Jesus!
Things have changed since 1973.
- You don't have to pay now.
I know you're good for it.
- Thanks.
There's a card in there
with my beeper number.
Beep me anytime, day or night.
And I only accept cash.
Now I know how you can afford
all this equipment.
God. When I was your age,
I flipped burgers all summer
just to buy an eight-track.
- That sucks.
- No, actually it was great.
All I did was party
and get laid.
I had my whole life
ahead of me.
My dad thinks I pay for all
this with catering jobs.
Never underestimate
the power of denial.
@@ [Humming]
- @@ [Music Playing, Faint]
- [Sniffing]
@ There must be some way
out of here @
@ Said the joker
to the thief @
@ There's too much confusion @
- @ I can't get no relief @
- What the hell do you
think you're doing?
- Uh-oh. Mom's mad.
- @@ [Continues]
Bench presses.
I'm going to whale on my pecks,
and then I'm going to do my back.
I see you're smoking pot now.
I... I'm so glad.
I think using illegal
psychotropic substances...
is a very positive example
to set for our daughter.
You're one to talk, you bloodless,
money-grubbing freak.
Uh... Lester!
You have such hostility in you.
Do you mind? I'm trying to work
out here. Unless... you want to spot me.
Lester, you will not
get away with this.
- You can be sure of that.
- @ There are many here among us @
- That's... what...
- @ Who feel that life is but a joke @@
you... think.
"My job consists of
basically masking...
"my contempt for
the assholes in charge...
"and at least once a day
retiring to the men's room...
"so I can jerk off...
"while I fantasize
about a life...
that doesn't so closely
resemble hell."
Well, you obviously have no interest
in saving yourself.
Brad, for 14 years, I've been a whore
for the advertising industry.
The only way I could save myself now
is if I start firebombing.
Whatever. Management wants you
gone by the end of the day.
Just what sort of severance package
is management prepared to offer me,
considering the information
I have about our editorial director...
buying pussy
with company money?
Which I think
would interest the I.R.S.,
since it technically
constitutes fraud.
And I'm sure that some of our
advertisers and rival publications...
might like to know about it as well,
not to mention... Craig's wife.
- What do you want?
- One year's salary with benefits.
That's not going to happen.
What do you say I throw in a little
sexual harassment charge to boot?
[Laughing]
Against who?
[Laughs]
Against you.
Can you prove that you
didn't offer to save my job...
if I let you blow me?
Man... you are
one twisted fuck.
Nope. I'm just
an ordinary guy...
with nothing to lose.
Yeah.
- Carolyn.
- Buddy.
- I am so sorry to have kept you waiting.
- Oh. [Chuckles]
Christy left for New York
this morning.
Let's just say things were
a little... hectic around the house.
- What's she doing in New York?
- She's moving there.
Yes, we are splitting up.
Buddy. I'm so sorry.
Yes. According to her, I'm...
too focused on my career.
- [Scoffs]
- As if being driven to succeed is...
some sort of a character flaw.
[Chuckling]
Well, she certainly did
take advantage of the lifestyle
my success afforded her.
Ooh! Ha. Wow.
[Chuckles]
- Ah, it's for the best.
- Mm-hmm.
When I saw you two at the party the
other night, you seemed perfectly happy.
Well, call me crazy,
but it is my philosophy
that in order to be successful,
one must project
an image of success...
at all times.
What are you doing?
- I was filming this dead bird.
- Why?
Because it's beautiful.
I think maybe you forgot
your medication today, mental boy.
[Ricky]
Hi, Jane.
I want you to stop filming me.
Okay.
Well, whatever. This is boring.
Let's go.
- Do you need a ride?
- Are you crazy?
I don't want to end up hacked to pieces
in a Dumpster somewhere.
It's okay. L'll walk.
But thanks.
He doesn't want to go anyway.
Let's go.
- Come on, Jane.
- I think I'm going to walk too.
What?
Jane, that's, like,
almost a mile.
[Screaming, Grunting]
[Laughing, Grunting]
Oh, God!
- [Grunting]
- I love it! Oh! Oh!
- You like getting nailed by the King?
- Oh, yes, I love it!
- Fuck me, Your Majesty! Aah!
- Ohh!
- Who's the King?
- Oh! You are!
[Both Grunting Loudly]
@@ [Car Stereo:
"American Woman"]
@@ [Humming Opening Melody
In High Voice]
[Singing Along]
@ American woman @
@ Stay away from me @
@ Mama, let me be @
@ Don't come knockin'
around my door @
@ I don't wanna see
your face no more @
@ I got better things to do @
@ Than spend my life
growin' old with you @
@ Now, woman @
@ Said stay away @
[Woman Over Speaker]
Smile. You're at Mr. Smiley's.
- @@ [Volume Decreases]
- What?
Would you like to try
our new bacon and egg fajita
for $1.29 for a limited time only?
Uh, no, but thank you.
I'd like the Big Barn Burger,
Smiley Fries and an orange soda.
Please drive up to the window.
Thank you.
Smile. You're at Mr. Smiley's.
That'll be 4.98, please.
@ Mama, let me be @@
- Would you like some Smiley sauce?
- No, no...
Actually, I'd like
to fill out an application.
- There's no jobs for manager.
It's just for counter.
- Good.
I'm looking for the least possible
amount of responsibility.
I don't think
you'd fit in here.
I have fast food experience.
[Laughs]
Yeah, like 20 years ago.
I'm sure there've been amazing
technological advances in the industry,
but surely you must have
some sort of training program.
It seems unfair to presume
I won't be able to learn.
- That was exactly what I needed...
- Mm.
the "royal treatment,"
so to speak.
[Chuckling]
I was so stressed out. Ah!
- Ah! Ah.
- Mm.
[Both Laughing]
Know what I do
when I feel like that?
What?
- I fire a gun.
- Really?
Oh, yeah. I go to this
little firing range downtown,
and I... just pop off
a few rounds.
- I've never fired a gun before.
- Well, you've gotta try it.
Nothing makes you feel
more powerful.
Well...
almost nothing.
- So, do you like your new house?
- I like it.
The people who used to live
there fed these stray cats,
so they were always around,
and it drove
my mother nuts.
And then she cut down
their tree.
Is that a funeral?
Yeah. Have you ever
known anybody who died?
No. Have you?
No.
But I did see this homeless woman
who froze to death once...
just laying there
on the sidewalk.
She looked really sad.
I got that homeless woman
on videotape.
Why would you film that?
- Because it was amazing.
- What's amazing about it?
When you see something like that,
it's like God is looking right at you,
just for a second,
and if you're careful,
you can look right back.
And what do you see?
Beauty.
[Clock Ticking]
Mom, I want you
to meet somebody.
- Mom.
- Yes?
I want you to meet somebody.
This is Jane.
- Hi.
- Oh, my.
I apologize for the way
things look around here.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Ricky]
This is where my dad hides out.
[Jane]
I take it he's got a thing for guns.
You gotta see
this one thing.
My dad would kill me
if he knew I was in here.
Did you steal his keys?
No. One of my clients
is a locksmith.
He was short on cash one night,
so I let him pay me in trade.
Turn it over.
Oh, my God.
It's, like, official state china
of the Third Reich.
There's a whole subculture
of people who collect this Nazi shit.
But my dad just has
this one thing.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
No, you're scared of me.
No, I'm not.
You want to see the most beautiful thing
I've ever filmed?
It was one of those days...
where it's a minute
away from snowing,
and there was this electricity
in the air.
You can almost hear it.
Right?
And this bag was just...
dancing with me,
like a little kid
begging me to play with it,
for 15 minutes.
That's the day I realized
that there was this...
entire life behind things...
and this incredibly
benevolent force...
that wanted me to know that there
was no reason to be afraid...
ever.
Video's a poor excuse, I know,
but it helps me remember.
I need to remember.
Sometimes there's so much...
beauty...
in the world.
I feel like
I can't take it...
and my heart...
is just going to...
cave in.
Oh, my God.
What time is it?
@@ [Lounge]
- Sorry I'm late.
- No, that's quite all right, dear.
Your father and I were
just discussing his day at work.
Why don't you tell
our daughter about it, honey?
- Janie, today I quit my job.
- [Laughing]
Then I told my boss to go fuck
himself, and then I blackmailed
him for almost $60,000.
- Pass the asparagus.
- Your father seems to think...
this kind of behavior
is something to be proud of.
And your mother seems to prefer
that I go through life
like a fucking prisoner...
while she keeps my dick
in a Mason jar under the sink.
How dare you speak to me
that way in front of her?
And I marvel that you can be
so contemptuous of me...
on the same day
that you lose your job!
I didn't lose it. It's not like,
"Whoops, where did my job go?"
I quit!
Pass the asparagus.
Oh, oh, oh! And I want to thank you for
putting me under the added pressure...
of being the sole
breadwinner now.
- I already have a job.
- No, no!
Don't give a second thought
as to who's going to pay the mortgage.
We'll leave it up to Carolyn.
"You're going to take care
of everything now, Carolyn?"
"Yes. I don't mind."
"Everything? You don't mind having
the sole responsibility?
Your husband feels he can just
quit his job, and you don't..."
Will someone please pass me
the fucking asparagus?
- I'm not going to be a part of this.
- Sit down!
@ And I'm irresponsibly mad @
@ For you @
@ Go on and call me @
@ Unpredictable @
@ Tell me that I'm impractical @
@ Rainbows
I'm inclined to pursue @
I am sick and tired of being treated
like I don't exist.
You two do whatever you want
to do whenever you want to do it,
and I don't complain.
- All I want...
- Oh, you don't complain?
Oh, please! Excuse me!
I must be psychotic then!
If you don't complain, what is this?
Yeah, let's bring in the laugh meter
and see how loud it gets on that one.
@ Mad for you @@
Don't interrupt me, honey.
@@ [Lush Instrumental]
And another thing.
From now on, we're going
to alternate our dinner music,
because, frankly...
and I don't think I'm alone here...
I am really tired
of this Lawrence Welk shit.
@ A bright, shiny world @
[Knock At Door]
- Go away.
- [Carolyn] Please.
Please let me in.
Look, I wish that you hadn't witnessed
that awful scene tonight,
but in a way, I'm glad.
Why? So I could see
what freaks you and Dad really are?
Me?
Tsk. God.
- Oh, Christ. Mom.
- [Sobbing]
No, I'm glad because, uh...
because you're old enough now to learn
the most important lesson in life:
You cannot count
on anyone except yourself.
[Sighs]
You cannot count on
anyone except yourself.
You know, it's sad but true,
and the sooner you learn it,
the better.
Look, Mom, I really don't feel like
having a Kodak moment here.
- [Gasps]
- You ungrateful little brat!
Just look at everything
you have!
When I was your age,
I lived in a duplex!
We didn't even have
our own house.
- [Door Slams Open]
- You little bastard!
Dad, no, I just...
How did you get in there?
How? How?
Come on! Get up!
Come on!
Get up!
Fight back,
you little pussy!
- No, sir, I won't fight you.
- How?
- How did you get in there?
- I picked the lock, sir.
What were you looking for, huh?
Money? Are you on dope again?
No, sir. I wanted to show
my girlfriend your Nazi plate.
A girlfriend?
Yes, sir. She lives next door.
[Panting]
Her name's Jane.
[Coughing]
[Panting]
This is for
your own good, boy.
You have no respect for other
people's things and for authority...
Yes, sir. I'm sorry.
Can't just go around doing
whatever you feel like.
You can't.
There are rules in life.
Yes, sir.
You need structure, yeah.
You need...
- [Together] Discipline.
- Yes, sir. Thank you
for trying to teach me.
Don't give up on me, Dad.
Oh, Ricky.
You stay out of there.
[Grunts]
[Gasps, Groans]
[Whimpers]
[Shells Clanking Onto Floor]
- Whoo!
- I gotta say, Mrs. Burnham,
when you first came here, I thought you
would be hopeless, but you're a natural.
Well, all I know is
I love shooting this gun.
[Singing Along With Radio]
@ Don't tell me not to fly
I've simply got to @
@ If someone takes a spill
it's me and not you @
@ Don't bring around the cloud
to rain on my parade @
@ I'm gonna march
my band out @
@ l'll beat my drum @
@ And if I'm found out @
@ Your turn at bat, sir @
- @ Hey @
- @ At least I didn't fake it @
@ Hat, sir, so what
I didn't make it @
@ Nobody @
@ I said nobody @
@ Had better rain @
@ On my @
@ Parade @
@ Yeah @@
[Stomps]
[Yells]
[Sighs]
[Fingernails Tapping]
What?
Uh, whose car is that
out front?
Mine. 1970 Pontiac Firebird,
the car I've always wanted,
and now I have it.
- I rule!
- Uh-huh. Where's the Camry?
I traded it in.
- Shouldn't you have consulted me first?
- Hm, let me think.
No. You never drove it.
Have you done something different?
You look great.
[Sighs]
Where's Jane?
Jane not home.
We have...
the whole house...
to ourselves.
Christ, Carolyn.
When did you become so...
joyless?
Joyless?
I am not joyless.
There happens to be
a lot about me...
that you don't know,
Mr. Smarty Man.
There's plenty of joy
in my life.
Whatever happened to that girl...
who used to fake seizures
at frat parties when she got bored?
Who used to run up to the roof
of our first apartment building...
to flash
the traffic helicopters?
- [Chuckles]
- Have you totally forgotten about her?
Because I haven't.
[Sighs]
Lester, you're going
to spill beer on the couch.
So what?
It's just a couch.
This is a $4,000 sofa,
upholstered in Italian silk.
This is not just a couch.
It's just... a... couch!
This isn't life!
This is just stuff,
and it's become more important
to you than living.
Well, honey,
that's just nuts.
I'm only trying to help you!
[Sighs]
Don't.
[Ricky]
Why?
It's weird watching myself.
I don't like how I look.
I can't believe you don't know
how beautiful you are.
Look. I'm not going
to sit here for that shit.
Ha! How does it feel now?
Fine.
You don't feel naked?
I am naked.
You know what I mean.
So tell me about
being in the hospital.
When I was 15,
my dad caught me smoking dope.
He totally freaked and decided
to send me to military school.
I told you this whole thing
about structure and discipline, right?
Of course,
I got kicked out.
Dad and I had
this huge fight.
He hit me.
And the next day at school,
some kid made a crack about my haircut,
and I just snapped.
I wanted to kill him.
I would've... killed him...
if they hadn't pulled me off.
That's when my dad
put me in the hospital.
They drugged me up and left me
in there for two years.
Wow.
- You must really hate him.
- [Lighter Clicking]
[Whispers]
No.
He's not a bad man.
Well, you'd better believe I'd hate my
dad if he did something like that to me.
Wait.
I already do hate my dad.
Why?
He's a total asshole;
he's got this crush on my friend Angela,
and it's disgusting.
- You'd rather he had the crush on you.
- [Chuckles]
- Gross. No.
- [Chuckling]
But it'd be nice if I was anywhere near
as important to him as she is.
I know you think my dad's harmless,
but you're wrong.
He's doing massive
psychological damage to me.
How?
Well, now I, too,
need structure,
a little fucking discipline.
I'm serious, though.
How could he not
be damaging me?
I need a father
who's a role model,
not some horny geek boy
who's going to spray his shorts...
whenever I bring a girlfriend
home from school.
What a lame-o.
Someone really should just...
put him out of his misery.
Want me to kill him for you?
Yeah. Would you?
It'll cost you.
I've been baby-sitting
since I was about ten.
I've got almost $3,000.
Of course I was saving it up
for a boob job.
But...
[Laughing]
[Both Laughing]
You know, that's not
a very nice thing to do...
hiring someone
to kill your dad.
Well, I guess I'm not
a very nice girl then, am I?
You know I'm not serious, right?
Of course.
You know how lucky we are
to have found each other?
[Lester Narrating]
Remember those posters that said...
"Today is the first day
of the rest of your life"?
Well, that's true
with every day except one...
the day you die.
@ I've looked under chairs @
@ I've looked under tables @
@ I've tried to find the key
to 50 million fables @
@ They call me the Seeker @
@ I've been searching
low and high @
- @@ [Whistling Melody]
- @ I won't get to get what I'm after @
@ Till the day I die @
@@ [Whistling Continues]
@ I asked Bobby Dylan
I asked the Beatles @@
Jane, hurry up.
I've got a very important
appointment.
- Is it okay if Angela
sleeps over tonight?
- She's always welcome.
I thought you two had a fight. I haven't
seen her around here in a while.
[Door Opens, Closes]
What?
I've been too embarrassed
to bring her over,
because of you and that way
that you behave.
- What are you talking about?
I've barely even spoken to her.
- Dad!
You stare at her all the time
like you're drunk!
- It's disgusting!
- You better watch yourself,
or you're going to turn into
a real bitch just like your mother!
[Whispers]
Oh, fuck.
You ready to go?
Oh, I-I don't need a ride.
I'm going with Jane
and her mom.
[Carolyn]
Oh, morning!
[Lester]
Yo, Ricky!
- How's it going?
- Pretty decent, Mr. Burnham.
[Whispers]
Hey. Wait.
[Man] I need that Super Smiley
with cheese ASAP!
- You need more than that,
my little hombre.
- May I take your order?
- [Carolyn Over Speaker]
Oh, yeah! What's good here?
- [Buddy] Nothing.
Oh, well, then I guess
we'll just have to be bad, won't we?
[Laughs]
l'll have a Double Smiley sandwich,
- Curly fries and a vanilla shake.
- [Buddy] Make that two.
[Woman] That'll be 7.98. Please
drive up to the window. Thank you.
I think we deserve a little junk food
after the workout we had this morning.
[Both Laughing]
- Did you know that?
- Thank you. I'm flattered.
Smile!
You're at Mr. Smiley's!
Would you like to try our new beef
and cheese pot pie on a stick?
Just $1.99 for
a limited time only.
- We were just at a seminar.
Buddy, this is my...
- Her husband.
We've met before,
but something tells me...
you're going
to remember me this time.
[Woman]
Whoa!
You are so busted.
This really doesn't concern you.
Well, actually,
Janine is senior drive-thru manager,
so you are on her turf.
- [Sighs]
- So, this makes sense.
- Oh, Lester...
- Honey, it's okay.
I want you to be happy.
Would you like Smiley Sauce with that?
- Lester, just stop it!
- No, no.
You...
don't get to tell me
what to do...
ever again.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Sighs]
- I'm sorry.
- [Fingers Tapping]
I guess we should
cool it for a while.
I'm facing a potentially
very expensive divorce.
No, no,
I understand completely.
It's...
"In order to be successful,
one must project an image
of success at all times."
[Ignition Starting]
Stop it. Stop it.
[Yelling]
@ Oh, oh, whoa @
- @ There she stood in the street @
- [Exhales]
@ Smiling from her head
to her feet @
@ I said
Hey, what is this @
@ Now, baby, maybe @
@ Maybe she's in need
of a kiss @
- @ I said, Hey, what's your name @@
- Shit.
[Beeper Beeping]
I have to run next door.
Jane left her geometry book in my bag,
and she needs it to do her homework.
So you and psycho boy are fucking on,
like, a regular basis now, right?
No.
Come on. You can tell me.
Does he have a big dick?
I'm not going to talk about his dick
with you, okay? It's not like that.
Not like what?
Doesn't he have one?
Why don't you want
to talk about it?
- I tell you every detail
about every guy that I fuck.
- Yeah.
Maybe you shouldn't, all right?
Maybe I really don't want
to hear about all that.
So now that you have a boyfriend,
you're, like, above it?
We got to get you
a real man.
- You got any papers?
- Yeah, in the cigar box
right over there.
Put up a fight, dude. You are such a
pushover. "No, I can't, really. Okay."
You should learn
to roll a joint.
[Car Door Closes]
Oh! Hi.
- [Jane] Where's Mom?
- Don't know.
- Hi, Mr. Burnham.
- Hi.
Wow, look at you.
Have you been working out?
- Some.
- [Sighs]
You can really tell.
Look at those arms.
You like... muscles?
[Laughs] I should probably
go see what Jane's up to.
Where did you get that?
- From my job.
- Don't lie to me.
Now, I saw you with him.
You were watching me?
What does he make you do?
Oh.
[Laughing]
Dad, you don't really think
me and Mr. Burnham...
Don't you laugh at me!
I will not sit back and watch
my only son become a cocksucker!
Jesus, what is it with you?
[Groans]
I swear to God...
l'll throw you out of this house
and never look at you again!
- You mean that.
- You're damn straight I do!
I'd rather you were dead
than be a fuckin' faggot!
[Sighs]
You're right.
- I suck dick for money.
- Boy, don't start.
- Two thousand dollars. I'm that good.
- Get out!
You should see me fuck. I'm the
best piece of ass in three states.
Damn it, get out!
I don't ever want to see you again.
[Sobs]
What a sad...
old man you are.
Get out.
[Sobbing]
[Muttering]
Mom... I'm leaving.
Okay.
Wear a raincoat.
I wish things would have
been better for you.
Take care of Dad.
[Man On Audiotape]
...disinvesting problems of power...
and removing their ability
to make us afraid.
This is the secret
to "Me-Centered Living."
Only by taking
full responsibility...
for your actions
and their solutions...
will you ever break free
from the constant cycle of victimhood.
You are only a victim if you choose
to be a victim. We all have the power...
[Jane] I don't think
we can be friends anymore!
[Angela]
You're too uptight about sex.
Just don't fuck my dad,
all right?
- Please?
- Why not?
- [Knock At Door]
- [Sighs] Dad, leave us alone!
It's me.
- If I had to leave tonight,
would you come with me?
- What?
If I had to go to New York to live,
tonight, would you come with me?
Yes.
You guys can't be serious. You're just
a kid, and he's, like, a mental case.
- You'll end up living
in a box on the street.
- I'm no more a kid than you are.
- We can use my plastic surgery money.
- We won't have to.
I have over $40,000. I know people
in the city that can help us get set up.
- What, other drug dealers?
- Yes.
- You'd be out of your mind
to go with him.
- Why do you even care?
- Because you're my friend.
- She's not your friend.
She's someone you use
to feel better about yourself.
- Go fuck yourself, psycho!
- Hey, shut up, bitch!
- Jane, he's a freak!
- Well, then so am I!
We'll always be freaks,
and we'll never be like other people!
And you'll never be a freak
'cause you're just... too perfect!
Yeah, well,
at least I'm not ugly.
Yes, you are.
And you're boring,
and you're totally ordinary,
and you know it.
You two deserve each other.
[Sobbing]
[Lester Breathing Heavily]
Jesus, man,
you're soaked.
You want me to get Ricky?
He's in Jane's room.
Are you okay?
Where's your wife?
Uh, I don't know.
Probably out fucking that dorky
Prince of Real Estate asshole.
And you know what?
I don't care.
Your wife is
with another man, and...
you don't care?
Nope.
Our marriage is just for show.
A commercial
for how normal we are...
when we're anything but.
Jesus, man,
you are shaking.
We really ought to get you
out of these clothes.
Yeah.
It's okay.
I... am...
You just tell me what you need.
- It's okay.
- [Sobbing Quietly]
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm sorry.
Y-You got the wrong idea.
[Man On Audiotape]
"I refuse to be a victim."
When this becomes your mantra,
constantly reinforcing
your new non...
I refuse to be a victim!
[Sighs]
@@ [Slow Rock Intro]
@ Old man lying
by the side of the road @
@ With the lorries rolling by @
@ Blue moon sinking
from the weight of the load @
- I hope you don't mind
if I play the stereo.
- @@ [Continues]
Not at all.
Bad night?
Not really bad, just...
strange.
Believe me, it couldn't possibly be
any stranger than mine.
@ It's only castles burning @
@ Find someone who's turning @
- @ And you will come around @
- Jane and I had a fight.
It was about you.
She's mad at me because...
I said I think you're sexy.
Do you want a sip?
Sure.
@ "Come on down
to the river of sight @
@ And you can really understand" @
@ Red lights flashing through
the window in the rain @
@ Can you hear
the sirens moan @
@ White cane lying
in the gutter in the lane @
- @ And you're walking home alone @
- [Grunts]
@ Don't let it
bring you down @
@ It's only castles burning @
- @ Find someone who's turning @
- So.
- @ And you will come around @
- You gonna tell me?
What do you want?
- I don't know.
- @ Don't let it bring you down @
- You... don't know?
- @ It's only castles burning @
- What do you want?
- @ Find someone who's turning @
- Are you kidding?
- @ And you will come around @
I want you.
I've wanted you since
the first moment I saw you.
You are the most beautiful thing
I have ever seen.
@ And the buildings
scrape the sky @
@ Cold wind ripping
down the valley at dawn @
- You don't think I'm ordinary?
- @ And the morning paper flies @
@ Dead man lying @
- You couldn't be ordinary if you tried.
- @ By the side of the road @
@ Don't let it
bring you down @
- Thank you.
- @ It's only castles burning @
- I don't think there's anything
worse than being ordinary.
- @ Find someone who's turning @
@ And you will come around @
@ Don't let it
bring you down @
@ And you will come around @
@ Don't let it
bring you down @
bring you down @@
I refuse to be a victim.
Lester,
I have something
I have to say to you.
[Heavy Breathing]
Are you scared?
I don't get scared.
My parents will try
to find me.
Mine won't.
This is my first time.
You're kidding.
I'm sorry.
I still want to do it.
I just... thought
I should tell you...
in case you wondered why I...
I wasn't... better.
What's wrong?
I thought you said
I was beautiful.
You are beautiful.
You are so... beautiful.
And I would be a very...
lucky man.
I feel so stupid.
Don't.
- Shh.
- I'm sorry. [Sobbing]
You have nothing
to be sorry about.
It's okay.
Everything's okay.
Wow, I was starving.
- Do you want me
to make you another one?
- No, no, no. I'm fine.
You sure?
I'm still a little weirded out,
but I feel better. Thanks.
- How's Jane?
- What do you mean?
I mean,
how's her life?
Is she happy?
Is she miserable?
I'd really like to know, and she'd die
before she'd ever tell me about it.
[Sighs]
She's, uh...
She's really happy.
She thinks she's in love.
[Scoffs]
Good for her.
How are you?
It's been a long time
since anybody asked me that.
I'm great.
I've gotta go to the bathroom.
Man, oh man.
Man, oh man, oh man.
[Gunshot]
[Jane Shudders]
Oh, my God.
Wow.
[Lester Narrating] I had always
heard your entire life flashes...
in front of your eyes
the second before you die.
First of all,
that one second...
isn't a second at all.
It stretches on forever,
like an ocean of time.
For me, it was
lying on my back...
at Boy Scout camp,
watching falling stars.
[Gunshot]
And yellow leaves
from the maple trees...
that lined our street.
[Gunshot]
Or my grandmother's hands
and the way her skin...
seemed like paper.
[Distant Gunshot]
And the first time
I saw my cousin Tony's...
brand-new Firebird.
[Panting]
And Janie.
[Gasps, Sobs]
[Panting]
[Grunts, Sobs]
[Wailing]
And... Carolyn.
I guess I could be pretty pissed off
about what happened to me,
but it's hard to stay mad when
there's so much beauty in the world.
Sometimes I feel like I'm seeing
it all at once and it's too much.
My heart fills up like a balloon
that's about to burst.
And then I remember
to relax...
and stop trying
to hold on to it.
And then it flows
through me like rain,
and I can't feel anything
but gratitude...
for every single moment...
of my stupid little life.
You have no idea what
I'm talking about, I'm sure.
But don't worry.
You will someday.
@ Ahhh, ahh @
@ Because the world is round @
@ It turns me on @
@ Because @
@ The world @
@ Is round @
@ Ahhh @
@ Ahh @
@ Because the wind is high @
@ It blows my mind @
@ Because @
@ The wind @
@ Is high @
@ Ahhh, ahh @
@ Love is old, Love is new @
@ Love is all, Love is you @
@ Because the sky is blue @
@ It makes me cry @
@ Because @
@ The sky @
@ Is blue @
@ Ahhh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh @
@ Ahhh, ahh, ahh @
@ Ah, ah, ah @
@ Ahhh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh @
@ Ahh, ah, ah, ah @
@ Ahhh @
@ Ahhh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh @
@ Ahhh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh @
@ Ahhh @@
www.moviesubtitles.org