'Lord...'
'If atonement for my
sins is what You seek...'
'...take my life.'
'But...'
'...this boy should live.'
'He should live for his mother
who is waiting for him.'
'He should live to ascend
the throne Mahishmati.'
'Mahendra Baahubali should live.'
"Sacrifices..."
"and martyrs..."
"is what this story
has been weaved from."
"For ages..."
"it's been raging..."
"the flames of retribution!"
"Is death the bearer
of that great soul..."
"one that the universe describes."
"Did our benefactor
descend from the skies..."
"one whose feet the earth kisses."
"Is destiny..."
"capable of..."
"creating that compassionate one?"
"The blood that boils..."
"and gushes through the veins..."
"is Shivam."
'The war with the Kalakeyas was over.'
'In warfare Baahubali
and Bhallaldev...'
'...were on equal footing in
their bravery and boldness.'
'But because of the
way Baahubali saved people,
the balance tipped in his favour.'
'So Queen Mother announced him
as the crown prince.'
'The entire kingdom
started celebrating.'
'Anticipating the coronation day,
people awaited the occasion.'
'Meanwhile a celebration to exhibit
the destruction of evil took place.'
'It was commemorated
only once in 26 years.'
'To ensure prosperity it is
customary for the daughter-in-law...'
'...of the royal
family to go barefoot...'
'...to Lord Shiva's temple
is situated in a jungle...'
'...30 miles from the royal fort...'
'...carrying a pot of
hot coal on her head...'
'...to destroy a demon's effigy...'
'...without faltering a single step.'
Long live, Queen Mother
Shivgami Devi.
Long live our beloved
Queen Shivgami Devi.
Long live Queen Mother Shivgami Devi.
Attack!
- Kattappa.
- Mother.
Escort everyone to a safe place.
But how can I abandon you?
It is my order, Kattappa.
Your wish is my command.
Soldiers, rush the people
to safe grounds.
Without faltering a single step.
"Your glory spreads far and wide."
"Long live Baahubali!"
"You're dearer to us than our lives."
"Everyone's going to sing..."
"and keep singing, in your praise!"
"He's like..."
"an immovable mountain."
"Such a strong feeling of love."
"Such a strong bond."
"When one breathes,
the other feels alive."
"Bounded by the same bond."
"His stride's like the wind..."
"or like the raging fire."
"When he walks, the earth quivers."
"Such is Baahubali's might."
"Even death doesn't scare him..."
"because he's always
risking his life."
"For his mother's sake..."
"he can even lay down
his life in an instant."
"He's like..."
"an immovable mountain."
"like a bright shining star."
"He's like..."
"an immovable mountain."
"Your glory spreads far and wide."
"Long live Baahubali!"
"You're dearer to
us... than our lives."
"Your glory spreads far and wide."
"Long live Baahubali!"
"You're dearer to us than our lives."
"Everyone's going to sing..."
"and keep singing,
in your praise!"Baahubali!
Baahubali! Baahubali! Baahubali!
"Queen Mother!"
"Shivgami!"
Bhalla?
Have you ever thought of...
or wanted to kill your mother?
I wanted to do so.
Instead of nursing only you...
when you were a newborn...
she also nursed Baahubali.
That was the 1st time...
I wanted to kill her.
When she was sharing
the jewellery, fame...
rights, everything with him...
I wanted to kill her.
Now...
When she is bequeathing
the throne to him...
this hand is
trembling to strangle her.
Bhalla?
Shall we kill her?
You are talking
in a drunken stupor, father.
Your mother's watchdog is coming.
Hey! Bloody dog!
- My lord?
- What is your latest bark?
Her Majesty has decided
to crown Baahubali as king...
on forthcoming
'Vijaydashmi' festival.
Queen Mother wanted you to be
the 1st recipient of this news.
History repeats itself!
The throne meant for me
was given to my younger brother!
And now the throne meant for my son is
being bequeathed to my brother's son!
Should my son, grandson,
great-grandson also...
toil for generations?
Dog, answer!
Why was I not crowned as king then?
Was it because I am disabled?
So what if one hand
is incapacitated...
isn't my other iron
fist enough to rule our kingdom?
Kingship was denounced to you not
because of the disability of your hand...
but because of your
dysfunctional brain.
Command me, my lord.
Dog! Are you not
aware your razor tongue...
can be sliced into
2 for your insolence against a royal?
Forgive me, my lord.
The brain that wishes to
kill a beloved wife...
what else can it be
but deformed and devious?!
- Did you overhear?
- No, my lord.
Since I am a 'dog'...
I sniffed it!
She is the princess
of Pataliputra, Varuni.
In the entire country,
she is the most beautiful it seems.
But her eyes look lifeless.
She is not the right
choice for Baahubali.
- Look for another bride.
- Sure, Your Majesty.
Please keep this in mind, astrologer.
She will not only be
Baahubali's wife...
nut also the queen of this kingdom.
There should be no reason
to point a figure at her.
Mother, did you send for me?
Baahu, you must take
a tour of our kingdom.
As you wish, mother
Queen Mother, with the coronation
just around the corner...
taking a tour now
is not a good idea.
Even deities from our temples...
are taken on a procession.
Do you know why, minister?
So they can envision the gladness and
sadness of our subjects in person.
Baahu, only when the future king
steps outside the palace walls...
he can understand
the trials of his people.
- Yes, mother.
- Let Kattappa accompany you.
As you wish.
Mother, why take this old man along?
He will again bore me with the
same old stories.
Bear with him for one last time.
By the time you return...
I will find you a princess...
to narrate enchanting fairy tales!
- He is the thief.
- No, sir... I haven't done anything.
He has committed the theft.
Punish him.
Uncle, even at this
age you are so energetic?
You seem surprised about this.
The way I wielded a sword
when I was your age...
you know chaste maidens
would be dumbfounded?!
You are such a bragger, uncle.
Pindari (Bandits).
They don't just plunder
the entire kingdom.
In fact killing
people is their pastime.
I brought these wild elephants
specially for you to play with.
On the banks of
the river Pranahita...
is the Spring palace
I am building for you.
Do you like it, Bhalla?
I had this bow made in such a way
it can kill a target 50 miles away.
Mother...?
After giving the
throne to my brother...
are you compensating me
with these gifts?
Your son is not so petty to lament
about not being crowned as king, mother.
Queen Mother Shivgami Devi's
command will be complied.
Do not offer these gifts
and degrade their value.
- Taste this sweet, uncle.
- Thank you, dear.
Sir, who are you?
Good lord!
He is showing off like a hero?
Bandits...!
These are soldiers
in disguise to nab them.
We do not have
to strain ourselves.
She brandishes the sword
as fast as lightning.
Wonder who she...
By the way...
our hero seems to be
missing in action?
- My lord.
- Two of you go that side.
- Two this side.
- Yes, my lord.
10 of you stay right here.
Baahuu...!
Baahu, throw me the weapon.
Baahu...?
What nonsense!
You are distracted, Baahu.
You chopped off a tree?
You know I escaped death
by a hair's breadth!
I might have died, you know?
I feel like I can
do anything for her.
Anything? Does it mean you can kill?
That too, kill me?!
Wretched fellow! I took such
good care of you in your childhood.
You must do much more
to unite us, uncle.
- Madhav.
- Your Highness.
Trace their hideout.
- We must retrieve the stolen goods.
- Yes, Your Highness.
Tie all of them.
I will not let anyone escape.
Tie all of them properly.
Long live, Your Highness!
- You were a godsend.
- Thank you.
Saved us at the right time.
May you always be blessed.
You two seem fit as a fiddle.
Are you not ashamed
to hide behind women?
Forgive me, Your Highness.
My nephew is a bit of a numbskull.
He is not adept at any job.
- He was driven out of his house.
- What...?
- Your family threw you out?
- Yes, Your Highness.
You seem to be so compassionate.
If you can kindly
teach him some skill...
we will be grateful to you
until our last breath.
So be it.
He has a robust appearance.
If you train him in sword fighting
he can at least become a guard.
I will teach him that.
Grateful, sir.
Truly grateful, Your Highness.
Hey! Look over there.
'Full moon night is fast approaching.'
'We must pray to
Lord Krishna.'
'My queen,
it is purely a ladies' festival.'
'You perform it as you deem fit.'
Princess...
In our entire kingdom
no one can beat you in archery.
But still why are you not satisfied?
Not enough, Prime minister.
You cannot string 2 arrows
from 1 bow, Your Highness.
Prime minister, anything
is possible for my sister.
Try again, Devsena.
Move aside.
Instead of getting
your young sister married...
you are teaching her
all this like she is a boy.
Absolutely right, Your Majesty.
Will you choose from
the proposals in hand?
Or should I get you married
to my brother Kumar Varma?
Imbecile! Come along, I will show
our weapons to you.
This is a mace.
You won't be able to lift it.
This is a spear.
You won't be able to throw it.
This is a sword.
Come, I will teach you
how to wield it.
Tell me, what do you excel in?
Quite a few, my lord.
Outdoor games like 'Stick and stone',
Hide and seek.
'Tip-Cat'.
What about hopscotch?
I've watched from far.
But the girls don't let me play.
I will teach you
how to wield a sword.
Watch and learn.
You should hold like this.
- Lift it high.
- On!
Then one swift blow.
Try your hand.
Look how he's holding the sword.
You won't be able to do it, nephew.
Idiot! Let me show you once more.
Hold it like this.
Lift it above your head.
Like this.
Strike.
- What a blow, my lord.
- Did I?!
Of course, you.
Who else, my lord?
I did it.
Struck like a thunderbolt.
'Fantastic!'
Elephant's might.
Lion's roar.
Cheetah's speed.
Vulture's sight.
I can see the entire jungle
in you, my lord.
My lord?
- I like you.
- Grateful.
'I will teach you also
to wield the sword.'
Why this drama for a princess
of such a small kingdom?
Reveal your identity and they
will get you two married immediately.
What is this drama for?
A 60-year-old man wants
to know what love is.
How do I enlighten him?
Don't simply let
your tongue run, Baahu.
Describe love to me and if I still...
don't understand, then ridicule me.
Look at those 2 partridges on...
that branch in this
cold wintry night.
The moon shining
in her full glory...
having their fill of the moonlight
scattered on the silken petals down there.
Watching them caress and feed
each other with affection.
What do you feel, uncle?
Having lived on this earth
for all these years...
I've never enjoyed them
anywhere, anytime.
If we catch these two,
marinate with salt and pepper...
roast them on a slow fire
simmer and eat them.
Sheer heaven!
What is wrong with you?
- You excelled this morning.
- My lord?
Princess Devsena is
coming to see you.
Welcome, Devsena.
If you should meet me
at this time of the night...
there must be a special reason.
Kumar...
I was unable to watch
your brave feat in the morning.
Please demonstrate now.
- Where can I get a log of wood now?
- It is right there.
Look at that.
It's hidden there.
You found it, huh?
Good you found this...
but where is my sword?
Over there.
Move a few steps back.
Go ahead.
Stop... stop, my lord.
If a brave warrior like you...
repeats the same feat at night...
it is considered a bad omen.
Are you not aware of this?
Why not?
I forgot.
You reminded me
at the right time.
- We intend to go hunting tomorrow.
- Why?
Wild pigs are ruining our field...
- Pigs disgust me.
- Not pigs.
- Wild boars.
- That too.
Farmers complained that these
boars are ravaging the fields.
Bring him also.
- Uncle!
- Well, even a rat will make him scurry.
Why do you want to
take him along?
How will he learn
if he is always in the kitchen?
If he accompanies us
only then we will know...
how useful he can be.
Bring him along.
Look there!
Wild boar.
- Why do you fall over me?
- You killed it.
Blue arrow.
Blue arrow is Kumar Varma's.
Kumar Varma killed
the wild boar, bravo!
Again it is Kumar Varma.
Wild boar.
How huge it is!
- Looks like a horse.
- Shut up!
Brilliant!
You were too good!
Varma's arrow is like
Lord Rama's arrow.
Long live Kumar Varma!
Long live Kumar Varma.
Amazing!
Kumar Varma's bravery
unsurpassed glory!
Single-handedly he killed
a sounder of boars!
Long live the brave Kumar Varma.
Long live the brave Kumar...
Stop with the flattery.
Yes, lord.
Devsena, we must preserve
these arrows in the royal museum.
It will motivate
the future generations.
I had my doubts...
since I set
my eyes on you your acting skill.
And his extra meekness.
- Me?
Doesn't look like that.
What did you say your name was?
Shi-Shivu.
Shivu.
Held her!
This hand is adept at wielding
a sword in the battlefield.
I would know a warrior's hand.
Uncle, she is saying something.
What are you saying?
He is a simpleton!
Let me be the judge of that.
Bring Bahadur.
What is this, Your Highness?
A man who cannot even lift
a twig to brush his teeth...
what can he do with a huge spear?
Why are you doing this?
B... bull!
The bull is charging
Towards this coward.
My nephew will die.
My nephew has been killed.
What injustice meted out to a boy...
who has not yet seen
the flush of youth!
Is it a fracture?
It is over, chapter closed!
Who will marry him hereafter?
Which girl will be ready
to fall in love with him?
- Who is that big-hearted princess?
- Stop it!
Bring the chariot.
'What will I do now?'
'Oh Lord! Lord! Lord Shiva!'
The angel who promised to help
has broken his arm.
- Lord!
- Can you get up?
Imbecile! Can you not hear him?
Get up!
Adjust the pillow.
- Give him this brew at once.
- Sir.
If he sleeps well tonight,
he will be right as rain.
Writhing in agony like this
how can you expect him to sleep?
Oh Lord! Lord Shiva!
- Uncle...
- What? Lullaby?
You want someone
to sing you a lullaby?
Where will I find someone
to sing you a lullaby now? Who?
Do you know how to sing a lullaby?
- You do not?
- No.
- What about you?
- I cannot.
Neither can you?
What do I do?
Princess!
Do you sing?
Ever since my nephew
broke his arm...
I do not know what I am blabbering.
'Oh Lord... Lord Shiva!'
'What will I do now?
I will have to sing!'
"Where's the mother
that sings lullabies?"
"Where's the father
that showers love and care?"
"He's naïve and unaware of the world."
"Who will comfort him?"
"Lord Shiva..."
"Where's the mother
that sings lullabies?"
"Where's the father
that showers love and care?"
"He's naïve and unaware of the world."
"Who will comfort him?"
Your Highness, you are
still in your hunting attire.
Come, it is time for our prayer.
"Oh enchanting Lord."
"Nandlala Kanhaiyya."
"Don't tease me, oh Lord."
"Don't try your tricks on me."
"I will go tell your mother Yashodha."
"Sleep, oh Lord..."
"Don't peek secretly..."
"Don't try to touch
me with your sights."
"Sleep, oh Lord..."
"When I heard the mesmerizing
tune of your flute..."
felt drawn towards you,
oh tormentor."
"Why do I sing Your song?"
"I'm Yours now."
"I've fallen for you."
"Oh Lord, what has happened."
"How could I be so crazy..."
"to let you face a charging bull?"
"It's completely my fault."
"Sleep, oh Lord..."
- "Kanha..."
- Oh enchanting Lord."
"Kanha...
- Nandlala Kanhaiyya."
- "Kanha...
- Oh enchanting Lord."
- "Nandlala Kanhaiyya.
- Kanha..."
"Kanha..."
"Radha's beloved."
"Sleep, oh Lord..."
Baahubali and Kattappa are
in Kuntal kingdom now.
Staying in the palace...
Baahubali is pretending
to be a blockhead, my lord.
Why should he pretend?
That is what he is!
Why is he doing so?
Baahubali may be
in love with Devsena...
the princess of Kuntal kingdom.
This is her portrait, my lord.
He gets to sit on the throne
and marry such a beauty!
Devsena should belong
only to me, father.
How is it possible?
- If my mother gives her word?
- How can she promise you will marry...
the beauty your brother
is in love with?
She is unaware of the fact that
my brother is interested in her.
I intend on making the 1st move.
That's why.
Bhalla...?
Mother?
Neither did you come for breakfast
nor attend court like you do.
- Why, Bhalla?
- Nothing, mother.
I didn't feel like coming.
I know what is happening,
Queen Mother.
What is the issue?
Architectural imbalance?
- Architectural imbalance?
- Yes, Your Majesty.
The south east corner has
become heavy suddenly.
- Do you want to see?
- What are you saying?
Bhalla...?
I am telling you now.
Show me.
The most beautiful lady
who even puts beauty to shame!
- Who is she?
- Princess of Kuntal kingdom.
Her name is Devsena.
The moment he saw
the painting by an artist...
north corner
gained favor in his heart.
Are you so besotted
with this princess, Bhalla?
Yes, mother.
I want her as my wife.
What is this, Your Highness?
You are asking
as if she is a toy.
How is it possible?
Why not?
He sacrificed the throne
of this kingdom flippantly.
So large-hearted is my son.
If I cannot fulfill
such a small wish of his...
how can I call myself a mother?
Bhalla...
Devsena will be your wife.
I give you my word.
Prime minister.
One ornament is not worn again
for a whole year...
send caskets with varied
jewelry as gifts to Devsena.
- As you command, Your Majesty.
- Dandnayak.
Send clothes spun in gold to the royal
family of Kuntal kingdom. As you command.
Royal sword of Bhalla.
Minister...?
Make Devsena tie
a knot to this sword...
and let the alliance be finalized.
Make arrangements for my
daughter-in-law to be welcomed...
with royal fanfare
amidst pomp and splendor.
'Blessings to King Jaysena
of Kuntal kingdom.'
'Shivgami,
Queen Mother of Mahishmati...
'...the 'Ultimate Utopia',
writes herewith:'
'Like Cupid in form,
like the demigods in nature...'
'Only the bravest of
the brave for my son...'
'I have chosen your sister
Devsena as his life partner.'
'Send your sister Devsena as
our daughter-in-law to our kingdom.'
'By the time you return...'
'...I will find you a princess
to narrate enchanting fairy tales!'
You have chosen the same girl
Baahubali is in love with.
'Yours truly,
Queen Mother Shivgami Devi.'
To seek alliance with
Mahishmati kingdom...
when so many powerful empires
are waiting in line so eagerly.
But Queen Mother's compassionate gaze
has fallen on your small territory.
Princess is indeed fortunate.
Look at the trousseau Queen Mother
has sent to fix this alliance.
You would have never set eyes upon...
such wealth and
valuables in your life.
Is it just you and
your Queen Mother?
Or is everyone in
your kingdom like this?
Looking at these riches...
you may wag
your tail like a dog.
This is equivalent to
dust under my feet!
- Devsena...!
- Minister!
If your prince had even
an ounce of this arrogance...
I would have been glad
he is also a man!
Someone as brainless as him,
not just me...
even the dogs in my kingdom
will not marry such a wimp!
- Devsena...?
- Bravo, Your Highness!
Your Majesty,
at least can you persuade...
It is her decision, Prime minister.
You send a befitting reply, Devsena.
Write this down.
To Shivgami Devi, Queen Mother
of Mahishmati kingdom...
'I, princess Devsena
of Kuntal kingdom...'
'...write this with utmost humility.'
'Without appraising me of your
son's appearance and character...'
'...you send me these gifts and
expect me to think high of him.'
'I realize he is a spineless warrior
who hides behind a woman.'
Along with the trousseau
you have given me so graciously...
I am sending you my sword.
Bedeck your son with gold
and precious jewelry.
'Ensure he ties the knot to my sword.'
'Send him to Kuntal kingdom.'
'I will take good care of him.'
With utmost humility, Devsena.
- Prime minister...!
- Queen Mother...?
Ask our army commander to prepare
for war against Kuntal kingdom.
Shivgami...!
You don't need a divine weapon
to kill a bird.
I heard Baahubali is somewhere
around Kuntal kingdom.
If you send word to him, he will crush
that kingdom to pieces single-handedly.
And bring
Devsena as his prisoner.
I stretched out my hand
seeking amity...
they seem to want enmity.
Ask Baahubali to bring Devsena
as captive to Mahishmati.
Send word to him
as Queen Mother's command.
As you order, Queen Mother.
If she could reject such a worthy
alliance in an outburst of rage...
do you understand
how much she loves me?
But, my lord, the princess seems to be
singing love songs for that blockhead...
is what I heard from
my grapevine in the harem.
- That blockhead?
- Yes, my lord.
I will have him
trampled under elephants.
Baahu, a piece of good news
and an equal piece of bad news.
- Which do I tell you first?
- Tell me both.
I'll decide which is good or bad.
Queen Mother has sent word
asking Devsena to marry you.
My mother knows what I want.
But the princess however...
has rejected the proposal angrily.
This is also good news.
How is it good?
Having fallen in
love with this 'me'...
- she would have rejected that 'me'!
- Oh.
Uncle.
Weapon.
You imbecile!
A man who scurried like a cat
is prowling like a tiger today.
- Where are you going?
- To the princess's chamber.
What audacity!
You want to meet Devsena
at this time of night?
Why?
This kingdom is in peril, Kumar Varma.
- Listen to me.
- You dare call me by my name!
I don't have time to explain.
Move aside.
How can you brush me aside?!
Don't stand there dazed, Kumar Varma.
They are Pindaris (Bandits).
Sound the alarm.
Look! Shiva.
They are attacking.
Kumar Varma.
Time offers every spineless man an
opportunity to become a brave warrior.
This is your opportunity.
God creates life.
The physician saves it.
One who protects that life...
is a true warrior!
Princess...
Not 2, but 4.
Turn the wrist facing outward.
Shoot.
Wait.
Who are you?
This isn't the right time
for explanations, let's go.
'We are all mere cowherds, sir.'
'How can we fight?'
'If you fight intelligently even
a blade of grass will be an arrow!'
'Your army lacks adequate strength.'
'Your kingdom needs
every helping hand.'
- 'Are you ready?
- Yes, we are.'
Demonstrate your strength.
Godspeed.
Praise be to Goddess Bhavani.
Climb up.
Fix the hooks below.
Sadhaka!
Not knowing your real identity...
I spoke out of turn.
I kicked you on your chest.
Only when you kicked me...
I realized how strong you are!
This is not blood, my friend.
It is a mark of victory.
Pronouncing you as a warrior
and not a coward.
You saved us like God
from an unexpected peril.
Who are you?
Where are you from?
Don't bother about who we are,
Your Majesty.
We came believing
only you can help us.
This brave warrior
needs help from me...
He is... in love with
a girl from your kingdom.
Is that so?
Who is that lucky maiden?
She is...
Your... princess.
What more joy can one ask for?
'What is the message, brave heart?'
What is it?
Queen Mother Shivgami has ordered me
to bring you back to our land as captive.
Treachery.
Princess,
you have misunderstood...
We hailed you as a godsend
and savior just a while ago.
Now you want to take
me as your prisoner.
Who are you?
Even a sweet will taste bitter
when you are angry, Princess!
Just answer my query.
Who are you?
After this anger dissipates...
Crown prince of
Mahishmati kingdom.
Queen Mother's Shivgami's beloved son.
Bravest of braves,
achieved the impossible...
by defeating
the invincible Kalakeyas.
Amarendra Baahubali.
With kith and kin embraces will do,
respect is unnecessary, Your Majesty.
Queen Mother asked for Devsena's
hand for this brave warrior?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Queen Mother is unaware
Baahubali loves your sister.
Because you rejected her son
she asked him to make you a prisoner.
My mother will never
go wrong, Devsena.
In whatever she does, a deep
inner meaning is bound to be hidden.
This is an error based on confusion,
not born out of contempt.
Come with me as my prisoner.
You are the brave warrior
who won over my heart.
If you ask me to
come as your attendant...
I will gladly do so
till the jaws of death.
But disrobing me of my dignity
not even one step as your captive...
will I accompany you.
From this instant...
till death separates us...
I am yours, Devsena.
'I swear based on the Dharma
my mother has instilled in me.'
'I will not let your chastity and
respect be tarnished in any way.'
'Give me your hand.'
We are sending our kingdom's light
with you, Your Highness.
Don't worry,
now she's my responsibility.
Princess, you are not hurt, I hope.
Your thoughts are flitting elsewhere.
"Oh King of Kings."
"The bravest of all."
"Don't ever leave my sights."
"I am all yours."
"So what are you waiting for?"
"Take me with you."
"Hold my hands."
"We must stride together."
"Devsena is all yours."
"I want to live and
die in your arms... forever."
"Even I cannot live... without you."
"When our hearts
united... conveys the waves."
"And I heard... the sky
sing songs of our love."
"Your love is like a dream."
"May this dream never break."
"Devsena is your prisoner."
"Oh King of Kings."
"The bravest of all."
"Don't ever leave my sights."
"I am all yours."
"So what are you waiting for?"
"Take me with you."
"Hold my hands."
"We must stride together."
"Devsena is all yours."
Do not worry about anything,
Princess.
Our Queen Mother will take care
of you as her own daughter.
Mahishmati.
Royal Court, attention!
I ridiculed your decision
and insulted you.
I replied arrogantly and hurt you.
Can you forgive my temerity,
Queen Mother?
For this Shivgami's daughter-in-law...
a little bit of temerity
is appealing indeed.
Come and stand next
to your future husband.
Whether my selection is
the perfect choice or not...
let the people
of Mahishmati decide.
Devsena...?
What are you doing?
I am doing exactly as you said.
I chose you as bride
for my son Bhallaldev.
What are you saying, Queen Mother?
The man I fell in love with
and you wished me to marry...
is Baahubali.
What is happening here?
Please forgive me, Queen Mother.
I made a huge blunder.
The son you had referred to
in your royal message...
I mistook it to be Baahubali.
I am responsible for all this chaos.
Her Highness is not to blame.
Kattappa.
No point in dissecting the past.
We need to focus
only on our future.
Queen Mother...
Baahu.
I have given my word to your
brother that he will marry Devsena.
Stop it.
Who are you to give your word
for my marriage without my consent?
Do you not know a princess has
the right to choose her husband?
Are you not aware of that courtesy?
What audacity to raise...
your voice in front of Shivgami?
Dandnayak.
Tie this boorish girl
and make her kneel.
As you command, Queen Mother.
A hand laid on Devsena
is equal to anyone...
touching Baahubali's sword.
Mother.
I have given my word to Devsena
to protect her dignity.
Your Highness, are you
confronting our Queen Mother?
You are the one who once said
even Lord Shiva can make a mistake...
but our Queen Mother's
words can never go wrong.
'For a word given in good faith.'
'For upholding justice.'
'To protect the code of Dharma
oppose whoever the offender is.'
'Even if it is God, do not be afraid.'
'That is the Law of Dharma.'
'Righteousness of
the warrior clan.'
Promising your son blindly
not knowing a woman's heart is wrong.
What you did was wrong, mother.
What Shivgami did was wrong?
You killed your mother
when you entered this world.
Yet she nursed you,
was that wrong?
She brought you up like her own child,
What is wrong to declare
you the crown prince?
Was it wrong for her
to crown you as king?
What is wrong?
Did you see that, Shivgami?
Your sacrifice has been called...
a wrong deed by him.
You must honor your promise.
But is it alright if
your mother breaks her promise?
So your mother's promise
has no value or respect?
No need.
Our pearls of wisdom
are falling into deaf ears.
I realize that now.
Amarendra Baahubali...!
You have 2 choices
laid before you.
Do you want to rule as the king of
Mahishmati, which is a slice of paradise?
Or do you wish to marry
this manipulator Devsena?
Aspiring for the throne
if I break my promise to her...
it will be a disgrace
to the way you raised me.
I cannot break my promise.
So be it.
On the forthcoming Vijaydashmi
festival, at same auspicious hour...
Bhallaldev will ascend
the throne of Mahishmati.
Under the supervision
of commander Baahubali...
the grand coronation
ceremony will be performed.
Queen Mother, kindly reconsider.
This is my command.
Carte blanche.
To the east of Mahishmati
is the Udayagiri range.
Malava islands to its west.
Many vassal kingdoms like Kuntal
are situated in the north.
Vast extensive Katkari forest
and Kalakeya forest in the south...
are the boundaries of...
this glorious Mahishmati
kingdom of which Bhallaldev...
will be the sole sovereign.
"May Mahishmati
always be indestructible..."
"through passage
of time indisputable."
"May all its endeavours
be victorious..."
"until the sun,
moon, stars shine glorious."
Cavalry of Mahishmati.
Attention.
Salute the king.
"Impenetrable,
fortified in every form."
"Formidable even to enemies fearsome."
"May warfare tactics core
be the military forms 4."
To receive His Majesty,
the elephantry pays tribute.
"Parade a march of victory."
Fencers.
"May the battlefield
display in history."
"Mahishmati's greatness and glory."
"Let the flag exemplify
with this emblem sky high."
"A golden throne
flanked by horses two."
"Imprinting the glory
of Mahishmati true."
Under the tutelage
of Karikal Kattappa...
exclusive troop...
salute the king at his feet.
Pay obeisance.
I, Bhallaldev, son of
Bijjaldev and Shivgami Devi...
take the noble
responsibility of ruling...
this vast empire Mahishmati.
I hereby promise to fend and defend
my kingdom with Lord as witness.
Emperor Bhallaldev.
Long live... long live!
Long live!
Emperor Bhallaldev.
I, Amarendra Baahubali.
I, Amarendra Baahubali...
will protect the
people of Mahishmati.
Their health,
wealth, mortality and dignity.
As supreme commander of
King Bhallaldev's armed forces.
I will be alert every single minute
while I discharge my duty.
I will not even hesitate
to sacrifice my life.
I take this oath of allegiance with
Queen Mother Shivgami Devi as witness.
Baahubali, long live!
Mahishmati.
From my earliest memories...
I have always longed for you.
Even in my dreams and sleep...
I placed you on my head.
After all these years.
After all these ploys.
Though in the palm of my hand,
I cannot clasp you!
Why are you evading me?
When I gave you pride of place...
why did you prefer Baahubali to me?
Bhalla.
Now you are the king.
Order Baahubali to be killed.
No one can oppose you.
Close his chapter.
I have the authority...
only to command.
The power to execute...
is still with Queen Mother.
I must change that.
Change Shivgami?
The sun cannot rise
in the west, Bhalla.
The sun will never rise in the west.
But I shall bury it in the east.
Shivgami, you nursed a snake
and nurtured it on your lap.
It is now baring its fangs.
In another few days
it will bite you.
You never valued my words.
I am the cause for your mother
and you drifting apart.
I feel distressed by that burden.
My mother's anger will last
only till we give her a grandson.
"In the mother's womb
rests baby Nandlala."
Place these offerings here.
The rest over there.
"Offer a veil to mother Yashoda.
Come over Nand and offer her gifts."
Worried your mother
has not come as yet?
She will definitely attend.
I know for sure.
Kattappa...?
Your Highness.
You have not brought
any gift for me?
I am a slave who
is not even privileged...
to wish you wholeheartedly.
What gift can I offer?
If I ask you for something
you can do, will you comply?
My pleasure.
According to our custom
after birth...
the baby should be held
1st by his grandfather.
To live a long happy life.
My father is not alive,
neither is his father.
Will you do us the honor, Kattappa?
For a slave who has no right
to even stand near you...
you have elevated me
to a father's position.
I will hold your baby
not only in my hand...
but carry him over my head.
Welcome Queen Mother Shivgami Devi!
Mother...?
You are bearing the heir
of Mahishmati kingdom.
Take all precautions.
You lost the privilege to
address her as 'mother'.
Her graceful presence here
is only as Queen Mother.
Am I late?
For the cub born to
this tigress.
For the little tiger.
Kumar hunted and killed
this tiger by himself you know?
Really, Kumar...?
If a hand wields
Baahubali's sword...
if Baahubali's words
are deep seated in any heart...
even a new born baby
can kill a tiger!
Welcome King Bhallaldev.
Attention!
I will give you a special gift
which no one else can offer.
What gift is that, Your Majesty?
A pregnant woman about to deliver
does not desire riches or possessions.
She wants only her husband's embrace.
Baahu.
In performing your official duties,
you are forgetting Devsena.
Therefore I am relieving
you of your duty...
and transferring it to Setupaty.
Your ordinance, Your Majesty.
Baahu...?
When such a drama is being
enacted in front of you...
are you watching
like a statue, Queen Mother?
Devsena...?
You have not understood
our customs as yet.
The power to decide who is
conferred which designation...
lies on the king entirely.
Lame excuses.
Queen Mother...?
Compared to a villain's violence a
good man's silence shatters a kingdom.
'Are you unaware of that?'
How can this title
from a brave warrior...
be thrown to a dog?
- How can you be quiet?
- Devsena...!
All our guests came
laden with gifts.
You have not given me any gift.
Will you give me what I ask?
You must occupy
Mahishmati's throne.
That is my wish.
Not just mine.
People of our kingdom
wish the same too.
It's said that a Warrior's duty
is to fulfill people's wishes.
Then do so.
Mother...?
Salutations, Your Highness.
Time for the king to arrive now.
Whoever it may be...
go through the next line.
You can enter.
It is alright.
You go ahead.
'Come.'
'Come forward'.
'So many are waiting behind you.'
'Everyone should step forward. Quick.'
You will be next.
Arrest her.
'Devsena,
wife of Baahubali is accused of...'
'...chopping the commander
Setupaty's fingers.'
'With Queen Mother Shivgami
Devi's permission...'
'Under the jurisprudence of King Bhallaldev,
the interrogation will commence now.'
Go ahead.
Is there anything you wish
to speak, Devsena?
Without a fair trial
you have already handcuffed me.
You have already charged me
guilty of the crime.
- Is this what you call 'justice'?
- You are guilty until proven innocent.
This is the law of Mahishmati.
Even barbarians will not
frame a law like this.
Throw your code of laws
into the fire.
Toss your covenants into the sea,
bury your treatise..
Deep into the ground.
Irony is this kingdom is named
Mahishmati, meaning 'Ultimate Utopia.'
Devsena...!
About our great, renowned kingdom...
if you utter another
blasphemous word...
Fame is never measured
by gigantic thrones...
and golden statues, Queen Mother.
Only through compassion.
No one here has
big hearts or open minds.
Shameful!
You heard her, Your Majesty?
If she can deride us
right in front of you...
in your absence imagine
how low she would have stooped.
Think about it, Your Highness.
Baahubali...!
Baahubali is here.
What happened?
Tell me, Setupaty.
The temple was
thronging with devotees.
Devsena also arrived.
You were about to arrive...
Since you was
about to arrive, I told her...
I told her to enter
through another line.
Baahu, what is this?
You are intimidating the victim.
The truth will not be disclosed
if asked politely, Your Majesty.
You are crossing your limit,
Baahubali.
When this court chained
a woman in her final trimester...
this court already
crossed its limit, mother.
Be it a pregnant woman,
tottering old hag, you or me...
rules of interrogation
are the same.
Do you know what happened?
What happened, Devsena?
He asked the women to form
a separate line inside the temple.
Then he made a pass at them.
- He was about to grope me too.
- 'She is lying.'
- I chopped his fingers.
- You did wrong, Devsena.
If one lays a hand on any woman,
you should not chop his fingers.
You should chop his head!
'Our Mahishmati kingdom
is indestructible."
"Through passage of time,
indisputable."
"With the sun, moon, stars glorious
aligned triumphant, always victorious."
Baahubali...!
What audacity!
How dare you insult my court?
Since Setupaty was guilty,
he was perturbed and panic-stricken.
Because Devsena spoke the truth
she stood absolutely fearless.
His guilt has been proved,
he was beheaded!
Baahubali...?
As you claimed
Setupaty might even be guilty.
Who should interrogate
and pass the verdict?
You or the king?
Or are you thinking
you are the king?
During the baby shower, your wife
wanted you to be crowned king.
Did you choose the wrong way to act
as king to make her wish come true?
Mother?
Ignoring my repeated
warnings your wife maligned...
Mahishmati's constitution.
She scorned our
governing law scriptures.
She uttered in many a word.
You proved with your sword.
Both your deeds tantamount
to royal treachery.
- Prime minister.
- Queen Mother.
What is the punishment
to be meted out to them?
If any member of the royal family
violates Mahishmati's laws...
they should be banished
from the palace.
Mete out the punishment.
I want both of you
this instant, right now...
walk out of our royal palace
with just the clothes you are wearing.
On one hand is the law you trust, on
the other hand is 'Dharma' you taught.
Between the two
this sword you gave me...
made me choose
the path of righteousness.
Even if I am banished
under reproach...
I will serve and sacrifice
my life for Mahishmati.
"Does the sun..."
"ever leave the skies."
I shall take leave, mother.
"Does the lamp..."
"ever burn without the wick?"
"Does the sun..."
"ever leave the skies."
"Does the lamp..."
"ever burn without the wick?"
"This is unfair."
"Every eye is filled with tears."
"You left us."
"How can we live?"
"You're our benefactor."
"You're our support."
"You're our entire world."
"You are our sun..."
"and the stars."
"Glory to you... Glory to you..."
"Lord, always help us when in need."
Stop crying.
God is leaving the temple and
stepping out to live with us.
Let's celebrate.
"You're that stream."
"Wherever you shall set foot..."
"turns into paradise for us."
"No one can understand
your divine play."
"You're the strength of the weak."
As long as he is alive...
he will always be considered as king.
"Those under you refuge,
need not fear anyone."
"Every inch of our
body is filled with joy."
"Swaying like the branches."
How are you able to sleep?
He is rebelling and
renouncing kingship.
He claims he can solve
any problem all by himself.
"You don't need a king he says!"
He is conspiring something.
I am scared.
"You're the one..."
"who quenches our thirst..."
"Like the clouds."
"You're that stream of nectar."
"Glory to you... Glory to you..."
"Lord, always help us in need."
Bhalla, what are you doing
at this hour of night here?
Why is he here?
Forgive us, Your Majesty.
He escaped today.
Tomorrow if you do not place
his head in my hand...
Whose head?
I will chop your head and
place it in your hand.
- Go.
- Bhalla.
My lord.
Bhalla, whose head?
Who else?
Baahubali, of course!
You usurped his throne,
exiled him stooping down
further you want to kill him.
Also his wife.
- And her unborn baby too.
- Bhalla.
If you oppose me, I will disregard
the fact you are my father!
I overheard.
I know about my son very well.
If he makes up his mind...
he has to achieve it.
- We must inform Baahubali at once.
- Will he believe us?
Baahubali doesn't
understand craftiness.
He will never believe that
his brother can stoop so low.
I can see only one way out now.
What is that?
- That is also only in your hands.
- In my hands?
Bhallaldev...
needs to die!
Do not say 'no', Kumar Varma.
For Baahubali's sake.
For Devsena.
For the unborn baby in her womb.
Kill my son Bhallaldev.
'Kumar Varma.'
'Time offers every spineless man an
opportunity to become a brave warrior.'
'This is your opportunity.'
Are you totally in the dark
of what is happening, Kumar Varma?
Sacrificial offering
is being performed!
To get Baahubali's death warrant signed
and sealed by Shivgami's own hands.
A great sacrificial offering.
In that ritual, you are
a small piece of wood.
Look, Shivgami.
Baahubali gave his dagger to
his trusted aide, Kumar Varma.
Told him about the secret passage
to the royal palace.
He has sent him to
kill the king at midnight.
Kumar Varma and his men...
killed all our bodyguards.
'They slit king Bhallaldev's face.'
After all this has happened
we should not wait even for a minute.
Baahubali needs to die.
Why are you still
introspecting, Shivgami?
Discharge your duty
as the Queen Mother.
'Do not fall prey to
your maternal sentiments.'
Bhallaldev is not only your son,
he is also the ruler of this kingdom.
Whoever tries to kill the king...
he has to be sentenced to death.
If Baahubali is sentenced to death...
our people will revolt.
Our court will split into factions.
Civil war is not good for the kingdom.
If that is the case, do you intend
forgiving him even after all this treason?
Baahubali's death is certain.
But his blood stains should not
smear the hands of the king.
History should not defame the king
for murdering his brother.
Then...
what is your plan?
Kattappa.
Your ancestors have pledged
their allegiance Mahishmati.
They have promised to obey
every command by the king.
Do you adhere to that oath?
No doubt indeed.
Your wish is my command.
Kill Baahubali.
What are you saying?
'Why?'
'Do as you are being told.'
Queen Mother?
Mother...?
Is this happening
with your consent?
I beg of you.
Ask the king to
take back his command.
Even integrity can
take a backseat.
Baahubali has no
mean bone in his body.
The son you raised.
He grew up drinking your milk.
'Your teachings run in his blood,
Mother.'
Baahubali has to die.
I won't be able to do it.
I cannot do it.
As punishment for my refusal...
please sever my head.
Will you kill him?
Or shall I finish this task?
No, Queen Mother.
Your hands should not be
stained by that sin.
'I will kill him.'
Can we trust this dog, Bhalla?
Our prince is so perturbed.
Everything will be fine.
Kattappa is being punished
for royal treason.
Did you see him?
Hey! Do you know what you are saying?
Devsena, uncle is in danger.
I have to leave now.
He has promised to hold
our baby in his hands.
Please escort him
back here safe and sound.
Baahubali! Run!
Who was it, uncle?
Baahu?
Baahu...
Massacre them.
Baahu, leave me here.
Pay heed to my words, Baahu.
Life of this slave is not
more precious than yours.
Leave me.
You go.
Leave me here, Baahu
Listen to me.
Leave me here.
Don't risk your life...
Try to understand.
Leave me here to die.
Even I want to abandon you, old man.
You have promised to hold
my baby in your hands first.
My wife made me promise I
will bring you back safe and sound.
Therefore uncle...
Keep quiet for a while...
and let me continue with my work.
'Oh God! How do I convince you?'
I beg of you.
Go away.
Leave me here and go away, Baahu.
Are you scared for Baahubali?
As long as you are by my side no man
has been born as yet to kill me, uncle.
Uncle?
Uncle...
Royal command.
King's order to kill you.
Baahu...
Baahu, forgive me.
Take care of my mother.
Long live Mahishmati!
I suspected you unnecessarily,
Kattappa.
You are my dog, indeed.
Baahubali.
Amarendra Baahubali.
'I, Amarendra Baahubali...'
'...will protect the
people of Mahishmati.'
'Their health,
wealth, mortality, dignity.'
'I will protect them all.'
'With Queen Mother
Shivgami Devi as witness.'
'I take this oath of allegiance.'
Queen Mother.
Foolish mother.
I deceived her, making her think
you planned to kill me.
I made her sign and seal
your death warrant.
'And you took your
oath swearing on her?!'
'Assure us our God
is safe and sound.'
'Queen Mother.'
'What happened to Baahubali?'
Blood of Baahubali.
Can we wash away this sin
from our hands in this birth, mother?
Kattappa!
You were wrong, Shivgami!
A grave mistake.
You lost your temper on Baahubali
rather too rashly.
You were blind to the injustice
of your own blood behind your back.
'Queen Mother.'
'Foolish mother.'
'I deceived her, making her think
you planned to kill me.'
'I made her sign and seal
your death warrant.'
When he breathed his last...
he did not think of
his wife or unborn child.
Do you know the last words he uttered?
'Take care of my mother.'
"Oh, the light of my life..."
"I am your mother."
"Let me hide you in my arms..."
"Oh Baahubali."
"When uncle Kattappa
is your protector..."
"and with your brother
Bhalla on your side."
"When you're in your mother's arms.."
"forget about the world..."
"And weave beautiful dreams."
"Oh Baahubali."
You gave me the honor
of being your father
and asked me to use my
hands to bless your child.
But with the same hands...
I killed your husband.
Strangle that tiny throat, Shivgami.
Or else that baby's
cry will soon rebel...
as a voice of inquiry against you.
Cross-examine you.
Roar in uproar.
Only if we stifle the
cry of this newborn...
all enemies of
Mahishmati will be annihilated.
Crush him.
Realizing the virtues
of Baahubali you have risen...
above the infinite sky.
Killing the son whom I nursed...
I have fallen
at your feet in disgrace.
Other than joining
him in his abode to...
wash his feet with
my tears of remorse...
how else can I repent?
What else can I do?
Mother...
If Baahubali is dead or not...
the people,
typical herd mentality...
are clamoring for
an official declaration.
They will believe it
only if you announce.
Go and announce.
I will handle this child.
Amarendra Baahubali is no more.
Now your new king is...
Mahendra Baahubali!
Mahendra Baahubali.
Long live!
Kattappa,
call for an urgent meeting...
of the council of ministers.
The guilty should be hanged
until death in public.
So be it, Mother.
Believing he had sinned...
you executed the death...
of Baahubali who was your breath,
me being a two-faced-beast...
how will I think
you will forgive me?
Would I not have taken
ample precautions?
Guards!
Kill Shivgami and
the baby in her hands.
Come with me, Queen Mother.
Devsena... Devsena...
Get up.
Listen to me.
Mother...
Saving my son...
is equal to giving
my husband back to me.
Mahendra, you must come back here.
I will be waiting for you.
Mahishmati kingdom
will be waiting for you.
Will you come back?
Your Majesty, she has escaped.
'Gaining full authority
as sole ruler of Mahishmati...'
'...Bhallaldev's atrocities
knew no bounds.'
'Due to his murderous
rage over Devsena...'
'...he reduced Kuntal
kingdom to cinders.'
In this world for
you to love or hate...
only I remain, Devsena.
'Everyone thought you were dead.'
'But your grandmother sacrificed
her life to save you.'
Your mother...
Your kingdom...
Waited for 25 long years.
Only for you, Mahendra.
Send word to our kingdom, grandfather.
Ask the young, grownups, old...
everyone to assemble before me.
Sword, Sabre,
stick, spear, scythe, sickle.
Tell them to bring
any weapon they can find.
Tell them, to eradicate the disease
defiling this kingdom...
Queen Mother Shivgami's grandson
and Amarendra Baahubali's heir...
Mahendra Baahubali is back.
They have 30000 warriors,
Your Majesty.
We do not even have
proper weapons.
Our hands are our weapons.
This life is our wild tempest.
Each one of us
is a powerful army.
Praise be to Mahishmati!
The golden statue.
The throne of Mahishmati, the
crown over my head.
And to rule as sole sovereign.
All along I assumed
only this gave me happiness.
But I was wrong.
This iron chain...
which made
Devsena feel hell on earth...
These shackles.
When I see Devsena is
not enslaved any longer...
the veins in my skull
are erupting to explode, father.
I want Devsena.
Your Majesty,
Kattappa has garnered support...
from people to revolt against us.
Kattappa?
Why should this slave dog
Kattappa revolt now?
Bhalla...?
Every single head there which
witnessed your death will roll.
Bhadra, I will pile...
all those heads and place
yours on top and cremate you.
With the anguished cries
of 10,000 families...
echoing as an auspicious tune...
I will bid you farewell.
DEATH TO THE ENEMY!
CHARGE!
ATTACK!
Attack!
He was in your womb
after all for 9 months only.
On the other hand...
you have been with me for 25 years.
So why did you leave me and
go as soon as he came back, Devsena?
"Dharti, earth for sustenance."
"Janani,
divine mother of benevolence."
"Avani, basis of existence."
Lift the drawbridge.
Release the arrows.
Wait, Mahendra.
The very thought of my mother being
his captive makes me burn in anger.
I do not care if I die,
do not stop me.
Was your mother's penance
all these decades to see you die?
It was to watch him die!
You are Amarendra Baahubali's son
whose radiant thoughts lit the darkness.
Think like your father.
Think like Baahubali.
'Push... help us Goddess Shakti.'
'Pull harder... with the grace
of our Goddess Shakti.'
'Push... help us Goddess Shakti.'
'Pull harder... with the grace
of our Goddess Shakti.'
- Who operates the drawbridge? Find them.
- What are you doing, Kattappa?
Your forefathers for generations
were servile to the king.
They earned unbounding good will.
You want to tarnish
their good reputation...
and go back on your word?
Do not succumb to this, Kattappa.
Set right your wrong-doing.
In the same way
you killed Baahubali...
close his son's chapter too.
Go, Kattappa.
Kill him.
25 years ago...
Queen Mother proclaimed
Mahendra Baahubali as our king.
Assuming he was no more...
all these years I have served a lie
discharging my duties duly.
Our truth has bounced back.
Kattappa never breaks
his promise, my lord.
Half the army of Bhallaldev
is inside the fort, Mahendra.
We must find a way
for our troops to enter.
I want a hammer, grandfather.
Shiva...
Light the fire, Avantika.
Hand me the staff, grandfather.
Go ahead, mother.
Before you circumambulate
Lord thrice...
to burn him alive and reduce him to
ashes, I will make him lie on this pyre.
Go ahead, Devsena.
Before you come back here I will
place your son's head in your hands.
Trial by fire.
Whoever completes it...
will never face defeat, my lord.
Create hurdles.
Stop Devsena.
'Before she circumambulates
the temple...'
set the bridge on fire.
Cover her. Protect her.
How dare you break my statue's head!
How dare you!
You came back when all along I
thought you were dead.
Mere words cannot express...
how joyous I felt.
My own hands did not slay him
gave me sleepless nights.
You are the splitting image of him!
You have come to grant
me my unfulfilled dream.
Now you have given me the chance to...
pluck your heart out.
How can I express my gratitude...
Mahendra Baahubali.
Hey! Kattappa...
Mahendra!
Listen...
Come with me.
We can both die together.
"The funeral pyre is lit..."
"Smoke fills the lungs. Nevertheless
there is a yearning in my heart."
'Bhallaldev's anguished cries
petrified of death...'
'...will echo around and far beyond
the walls of Mahishmati.'
"See who comes your way."
My first order with Queen Mother
Shivgami Devi as witness.
In our kingdom those who believe
in hard work and justice...
will walk
with their heads held high.
And if anyone thinks of
harming these good people...
whoever it may be, their severed
head will burn in the flames of hell.
This is my order.
This is my ordinance.
"River of Life..."
"When God supports
the vow taken by humans..."
"even the stars,
the earth and skies bow before him."
"When humans use
their faith as weapon..."
"even destiny accepts defeat."
But, grandfather...
will Mahendra Baahubali's son
be the heir to Mahishmati's throne?
God only knows!
How would I know what lies
in Lord Shiva's mind?