♪♪
Mmm.
I had the craziest dream last night.
I was dancing the white swan.
It was different choreography though.
It was more like the Bolshoi's.
It was the prologue...
when Rothbart casts his spell.
Look how pink. So pretty.
Pretty.
- You're in a good mood.
- Mm-hmm.
He promised to
feature me more this season.
Well, he certainly should.
You've been there long enough...
and you're the most dedicated
dancer in the company.
Up.
- What's that?
- What?
There.
Nothing.
Sure you don't want me
to come with you?
You sweet girl.
Southbound 1 train to South Ferry.
Next stop, 59th Street.
Did you see Beth today?
I can't believe she's back.
Of course she's back.
What? She can't take a hint? The company's
broke. No one comes to see her anymore.
Uh, nobody actually comes
to see ballet, full stop.
That's not true. I heard the Royal
had one of their best seasons yet.
He just needs to try something new.
That's all.
No. Someone new.
Like who?
Like someone who's
not approaching menopause.
It's sad.
What's sad?
Beth's such a beautiful dancer.
Yeah. So is my grandmother.
Well, Fonteyn danced into her 50s.
Yeah. We know.
Hey. Oh. Soloists?
Great.
I fuckin' missed my stop.
Had to hoof it all the way from 79th.
- Who's that?
- It’s that girl from San Francisco.
Eh?
♪♪
- ♪♪
- And up...
two, three, four.
Good. One.
♪♪
Two, three, four.
Up.
Beautiful as always, Nina.
Relax.
And one, and two...
and three, and four, and-
- ♪♪
- Stop, John. One second.
Okay. Take position.
- And one, and two-
- ♪ ♪
And three, and up.
One, and two, and three, and four.
- How are you?
- Good. Thank you.
♪♪
We all know the story.
Virginal girl, pure and sweet...
trapped in the body of a swan.
She desires freedom...
but only true love can break the spell.
Her wish is nearly granted...
in the form of a prince.
But before he can declare his love...
her lustful twin, the black swan...
tricks and seduces him.
Devastated...
the white swan leaps off a cliff...
killing herself...
and in death...
finds freedom.
♪♪
- Good morning, company.
- Good morning.
We open our season
with Swan Lake.
Done to death, I know...
but not like this.
We strip it down,
make it visceral and real.
A new production needs
a new Swan Queen.
A fresh face to present to the world.
But...
which of you can embody both swans?
The white and the black?
All the soloists I tapped...
go to your scheduled
rehearsals this afternoon.
And the girls I didn't tap...
meet me in
the principals' studio at 5:00.
Thank you.
All right. Let's go. Did we do left side?
- Yes, mistress.
- Let's hit it one more time.
♪♪
Fuck! Fuck!
What?
♪♪
If I was only casting the white swan,
she'd be yours.
But I'm not.
Maestro.
Odile's coda, please.
Now show me your black swan, Nina.
♪♪
Not so controlled. Seduce us.
Not just the prince, but the court,
the audience, the entire world. Come on!
Your fouetteés are like a spider
spinning a web. Attack it!
Attack it! Come on!
♪♪
Well, good of you to join us.
- Sorry.
- Girls, this is Lily...
straight off the plane
from San Francisco.
- She's filling Rebecca's old spot.
- Hey.
- Get warmed up.
- No, it's okay. I’m good.
Should I go again?
No. Thanks, Nina. I've seen enough.
Okay. Veronica.
The white swan variation.
Come on, come on, come on, please.
All right. Maestro.
Two, three-
So how'd it go?
You were late,
so I called Susie in the office.
An audition. I can't believe
he just sprang that on you.
So?
It was fine.
Just fine? Oh.
Oh, sweetheart.
Oh. Oh, you tell me about it.
I know, Susie,
but he just can't expect these girls...
to come back from a break
and dance like Beth Maclntyre.
It’s completely unrealistic.
I mean, they can do the work,
but they don't have Beth's magic.
She's miserable, and it's-
- Ow.
- Nina? Everything all right?
I’m fine!
Oh. Shh.
Almost done.
You're working yourself too hard.
We all have off days.
If that girl hadn't barged in-
I’m sure she didn't mean to.
Remember when you first started?
If I hadn't taken you to each of your
classes, you would have been completely lost.
I’m gonna talk to him tomorrow.
I’m gonna tell him I finished it.
You don't need to lie.
It won't convince him one way or the other.
Oh, sweetheart.
I know it's disappointing.
And when you start getting older,
there's all this-
ridiculous pressure.
God knows, I understand.
But it's all right.
No matter what.
You'll probably get to dance
the pas de quatre again.
That's such a wonderful part.
♪♪
Or maybe he'll make you a big swan.
Either way, you'll shine.
I know.
Everything will be better
in the morning.
It always is.
♪♪
Sweet girl.
Ciao.
- Yes, Nina?
- Do you have a minute?
- If now's not a good time, I can-
- Now is perfect.
So?
Um-
I just wanted to tell you that...
I practiced the coda last night,
and... I finished.
I thought you should know.
Okay, Nina, listen. Honestly,
I don't care about your technique.
- You should know that by now.
- Yeah, but yesterday-
No. Anyway,
I’ve already chosen Veronica.
So-
Sorry.
Okay. Thank you.
That's it? You're not gonna try
and change my mind?
You must have thought it was possible.
Otherwise, what are you
doing here all dolled up?
I came to ask for the part.
Well...
the truth is...
when I look at you...
all I see is the white swan.
Yes, you're beautiful, fearful, fragile.
Ideal casting.
But the black swan?
It’s a hard fucking job to dance both.
I can dance the black swan too.
Really?
In four years, every time you dance...
I see you obsess getting
each and every move perfectly right...
but I never see you lose yourself.
Ever.
All that discipline for what?
- I just want to be perfect.
- You what?
I want to be perfect.
Perfection is not just about control.
It’s also about letting go.
Surprise yourself,
so you can surprise the audience.
Transcendence.
And very few have it in them.
I think I do have it in-
You bit me?
I can-I can't believe you bit me.
I’m sorry.
Now, that fucking hurt.
- You were great.
- Thanks.
Yeah. Really. No.
Yeah.
What? Why is she always staring at me?
She's obsessed with you.
Hey. It’s been posted.
Hey. It’s up.
Veronica.
Congratulations.
Hey!
Why would you say that? Hmm?
Your idea of some sick joke?
What?
Fuck you.
Oh, my goodness!
Hey, Nina. Congratulations.
Congratulations.
Oh, Nina. Congratulations.
You were so beautiful at the audition.
I knew you were gonna get it.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations.
- Hello?
- Hi.
- What is it? What's wrong?
- I’m fine.
- Um-
- What is it?
He picked me, Mommy.
- Did you hear me?
- For Swan Lake?
- I’m gonna be the new Swan Queen.
- Oh, my God!
Well, um-
- I'll be home soon. I just wanted to let you know.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- Oh! Please-
Mom?
Mom, are you in your room?
Nina. Are you home?
Nina, when you get out,
I’m in the kitchen.
Come on, sweetie.
My daughter, the Swan Queen.
It’s our favorite.
Vanilla with strawberry filling.
Oh, Mom, not too big.
Oh, that's way, way too much.
It’s a celebration. It’s just this once.
Mom, my stomach's still in knots.
Fine.
Fine. Then it's garbage.
No. Mom, don't. I’m sorry.
I’m just-
I’m just so proud of you.
That looks so yummy.
Mmm.
- ♪♪
- Smoother.
♪♪
Okay, okay. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, Nina.
It’s very nice.
But I knew the white swan
wouldn't be a problem.
The real work will be
your metamorphosis into her evil twin.
And I know I saw
a flash of her yesterday.
So, get ready to give me
more of that bite.
Up...
and-
All right.
Excellent.
That evil force is pulling you,
that you can't escape...
that's just like-
out of your control.
So you're-You sense it,
you get aware of it more-
It’s taking me. It’s taking me.
A little bit more desperate.
Right. And you can maybe go up a little bit
and then come down and then-
That's it.
♪♪
Three, four.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Step and a step. And-
Watch the way she moves.
Imprecise, but...
effortless.
She's not faking it.
Gorgeous.
- Okay. That's beautiful.
- Sorry.
We'll start again from the beginning.
Okay.
Sorry.
Welcome to the principals' room.
You room with Beth from now on,
so be considerate.
Thanks, Susie.
Those are for you, from Mr. Leroy.
They're beautiful.
♪♪
- Come on.
- I’ll be back in a second.
Let me come back to you, please.
Okay.
Let's go.
♪♪
Ready to be thrown to the wolves?
We need their cash,
so, please, don't forget to smile.
- Ladies and gentlemen, please,
may I have your attention? - ♪ ♪
- Shh, shh.
- Good evening.
Let me make this
very important announcement.
You all have had the chance
and the privilege...
to be enchanted, transported...
and even sometimes devastated by the
performances of this true artist of our company.
She's been a crucial inspiration
to my work...
a role model to all dancers,
and even more than that...
a deeply appreciated
presence on our stage.
You all know who I’m talking about.
Ladies and gentlemen, Beth Maclntyre.
But as we all know,
every great career has to come to an end.
Beth is retiring at the end of the season.
She will be giving
her farewell performance as Melpomene...
the role she originated
in my first ballet.
My little princess.
We honor you. You will be greatly missed
and never forgotten.
But, as we bid adieu to one star...
we welcome another.
We are opening our season
with my new version of Swan Lake.
Taking the role of our new Swan Queen...
the exquisite Nina Sayers.
- You'll soon have-
- Sorry.
The pleasure of seeing her perform,
but right now, please...
let's raise a glass to all of us-
to Beth, to Nina...
to beauty.
Just a second.
Come on. I’m about to burst.
Hey. It’s you.
I don't think we ever officially met.
I’m Lily.
Hi. Nina.
Yes. Our new Swan Queen.
- Here. Hold this?
- Yeah. Sure.
Oh, you must be so excited.
Oh. Are you freaking out?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Oh. Oh, it's okay.
Oh, I'd be losing my mind.
Well, I should get back.
No. No, no. Come on. Stay.
Keep me company.
Excuse me.
♪♪
There you are. Come on.
Hey. They tried to eat you alive,
but here you are.
- You did well.
- Really?
Mm-hmm.
- Where are you going?
- Upper West Side.
Stop at my place for a drink.
It’s on the way.
Thomas. You need to
say hello to Karen Halloway.
A minute more of ass kissing,
I’ll be back. Wait for me here. All right?
Hello, Karen!
Beth.
I’m so sorry to hear
you're leaving the company.
Oh.
What'd you do to get this role?
Huh?
He always said you were
such a frigid little girl.
What did you do
to make him change his mind?
- Did you suck his cock?
- Not all of us have to.
You fucking whore.
You're a fucking little whore.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's going on here?
Hey. Hey.
- I need to talk to you.
- I think you're drunk.
- You should go home.
No! Don't you do that.
Don't you dismiss me like that.
Beth.
My little princess,
please, hold it together.
- I’m coming by later.
- Come on.
I have something for you.
It’s a token of my appreciation.
- Right.
- You make the most of it, Nina.
Don't worry. It’s typical.
♪♪
Please.
I thought it would be good to talk
about the role. Ground us a little.
Yeah.
I don't want there to be
any boundaries between us.
- No. Me neither.
- Good.
So...
you got a boyfriend?
No.
And you had many in the past?
A few, but no one serious.
You're not a virgin, are you?
No.
Ah. So there's nothing
to be embarrassed about.
And you enjoy making love?
Excuse me?
Oh, come on. Sex.
Do you enjoy it?
Well, we need to be able
to talk about this.
I got a little homework
assignment for you.
Go home and touch yourself.
Live a little.
Well, it's late.
Lots of work tomorrow.
The doorman will find a cab for you.
♪♪
Sounds like quite an evening.
I wish I could have been there.
- You know I asked.
- I know you did. Susie told me.
- Guess he wanted you all to himself.
- That's not why.
I don't blame him.
Hmm.
- Where'd you get these?
- They're fake.
Fooled me.
I can do it.
He must have been by your side all night.
Showing you off.
- Oh, Nina.
- It’s just a rash.
Just a rash? What are you talking about?
It was worse a few days ago.
It’s fine already.
- You've been scratching yourself again.
- No, I haven't. Mom.
I thought you'd outgrown
this disgusting habit.
Jesus Christ.
I thought you were done with this, Nina.
Shrugs. You'll keep wearing the shrugs.
Sit down.
- I have been.
- You have the white one and the pink one...
and that'll hide it.
And then-And then I’ll dig out that-that
expensive cover-up. We still have some.
No one will see it.
Mom, please.
It’s the role, isn't it?
It’s all this pressure.
I- I knew it'd be too much. I knew it.
- Ow.
- Oh.
Are you all right? You all right?
It'll be all right.
♪♪
Très bien, Veronica.
What happened?
Beth's in the hospital.
- She had an accident.
- Oh, no.
- Beth?
- She's really hurt.
What happened?
She walked into the street
and got hit by a car.
And you know what?
I’m almost sure she did it on purpose.
How do you know?
Because everything Beth does
comes from within...
from some dark impulse.
I guess that's what makes her
so thrilling to watch.
So dangerous.
Even perfect at times.
But also so damn destructive.
Was it right after we saw her?
Oh, no. Wait, wait, wait.
This has nothing to do with you.
It’s not your problem,
so don't let yourself be distracted.
This is your moment, Nina.
Don't let it go.
What are you doing?
Nina?
Sweetie, are you ready for me?
And-
Come on. Forget about control, Nina.
I want to see passion.
Come on.
Reach.
More! You're stiff.
Stiff like a dead corpse. Let it go.
Let it go. Let it go.
And again.
It feels like you have, uh-
your diaphragm is in
a bit of a... contraction.
Okay.
I want you to breathe into this hand.
Breathe into this hand.
Breathe in, breathe in,
breathe in. All the way.
Good. And exhale.
Oh.
Does it feel jammed in the front
every time you plié?
Sometimes. Not always.
- One more pull. Okay?
- Okay.
- Is that okay?
- Mm-hmm.
♪♪
David, can I ask you a question?
Honestly, would you fuck that girl?
No.
No one would.
Nina, your dancing is just as frigid-
Fuck!
Oh!
We're still working here, please.
Light. The lights!
Thank you.
Okay, guys, you can go.
Thanks for your patience.
Na-da-da-da-da. You stay.
You stay.
Have fun, you two.
Hey, oh.
Okay. Come here.
Come, come, come, come.
I’ll be the prince.
♪♪
Let it go. Let it go.
Feel my touch. Respond to it.
Come on.
Open your mouth.
Open it. Open it.
Open it.
That was me seducing you...
when it needs to be
the other way around.
Please.
Who is that?
Hey.
You okay?
You can't smoke in here.
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
So...
big day's getting closer and closer, huh?
Well, I can't wait.
I think you're gonna be amazing.
Thanks.
Come on.
So...
do you want to talk about it?
I just had a hard day.
Oh. Leroy playing
a little too rough for you?
Come on, Nina. He's a prick.
He's brilliant.
Sure. But it's not like
he's all warm and fuzzy.
Well, you don't know him.
Someone's hot for teacher.
Oh. Come on. It’s okay.
I don't blame you.
- I should go home.
- Oh, Nina, come on.
I’m just playing around.
Nina.
Sweetie?
What are you doing in there?
♪♪
Again.
- ♪♪
- Do you have any corrections?
Lily told me that she saw you crying-
that you were very upset
and that I should take it easy on you.
I didn't tell her that.
- Maybe you need a little break,
like a day or two. - Thomas-
- Or a month? What do you think?
- She shouldn't have said anything.
- No, you shouldn't be whining in the first place.
- I didn't!
You could be brilliant,
but you're a coward.
- I’m sorry.
- Now stop saying that!
That's exactly what I’m talking about!
Stop being so fucking weak!
- Again!
- ♪ ♪
Lily?
Oh, look who's decided to grace us
with her presence.
- I need to talk to you.
- Okay.
- Now!
- Oww!
Shut up. Come on.
What's up?
You told Thomas about last night?
Oh. Uh, yeah, I ran into him in the morning.
He said you guys were having some trouble.
Why would he talk to you?
Excuse me, Your Highness.
I told him you were working
your ass off and that you'll be great.
Well, you shouldn't have.
Okay.
Has he tried anything with you?
He has a reputation.
I have a right to be concerned, Nina.
You've been staying late
so many nights rehearsing.
I hope he isn't taking advantage.
That's all.
- He's not.
- Good.
I just don't want you to make
the same mistake I did.
Thanks.
Not like that. I just mean as far
as my career was concerned.
What career?
The one I gave up to have you.
You were 28.
So?
And only in the-
Only what?
- Nothing.
- What?
Nothing.
How's your skin?
It’s fine.
- Are we leaving it alone?
- Mm-hmm.
Let me see.
- Take off your shirt.
- No.
- Can I help you?
- Is Nina around?
Sorry. She's not here.
Who was that?
It was no one.
It was no one!
Hello?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I just came by to apologize. You're right. I
should have never spoken to him about you.
- Sweetheart?
- Give me a second.
- Your dinner.
- Mom, please!
Wow, she's a trip.
How do you know where I live?
I have my ways.
Jesus, relax.
I got it from Susie in the office.
I feel really shitty about what I did,
and I just want to make it up to you.
- So how about I take you out to dinner?
- I don't think-
Okay, that's fine.
What about, um, drinks?
Sweetie, you need to rest.
- Jesus.
- Wait.
What are you doing?
- Going out.
- What?
- Stairs.
- Nina!
You're on the stage tomorrow!
I can't believe he calls her that.
It’s so gross.
I think it's sweet.
"Little princess"?
He probably calls every girl that.
No way. That's just for Beth.
I bet he'll be calling you
"little princess" any day now.
I don't know about that.
Oh, sure, he will.
You just gotta let him lick your pussy.
Cheeseburger, extra bloody.
Mmm! Danke schön.
Let me know if that's
juicy enough for you.
Oh, I will.
You got enough... cheese?
No, but you do.
Enjoy.
Okay.
Mmm.
Wanna spruce up?
What? I carry a spare.
In case I wake up
somewhere unexpected.
So, how is he?
Thomas.
I wouldn't know.
- Oh, come on.
- I really don't want to talk about that.
Oh. Okay.
You really need to relax.
One for you, one for me.
Oh, and don't worry.
It’s pure. I promise. I brought it with me
straight from San Francisco.
What is it?
What, are you kidding?
You've never rolled?
Oh, it'll relax you.
It’ll loosen you up.
Let you see the night sky.
How long does it last?
Couple hours, tops.
It’s okay.
Okay.
♪♪
- I was-
- That's very sweet of you.
Will you bring the drinks?
Hey! Hi!
- I thought maybe you and I could use a couple drinks.
- I’m gonna head out.
So, this is Tom and this is Jerry.
- Actually, it's Andrew.
- Tom.
Hi. Um, I have to go.
Oh, no, come on, you can't go.
I just got us some drinks.
I shouldn't.
We're on the stage tomorrow.
So, what are you gonna do?
Go home to Mommy?
Hey. Come on. Live a little.
It’s just a couple hours, right?
Tops.
- Hey. There you go.
- Thank you.
- Cheers.
- You haven't told me who you are.
- Mmm. I’m a dancer.
No, I mean your name.
Oh. Uh, Nina.
- So, are you two sisters?
- No.
Yes. Blood sisters.
We dance in the same company.
Ah, ballerinas.
No wonder you two look alike.
You know, Tom and Jerry here
are gay lovers.
- Very funny.
- I like to amuse myself.
- I’ve never been to the ballet.
- Oh, really?
Oh, well, then you are definitely not gay.
- I mean, it's kind of boring though, isn't it?
- No, it's not.
No. You know what, it's just-
It’s not for everyone.
You guys should come sometime.
I can comp you tickets whenever you want.
- Yeah.
- Um-
Yeah, that would be... neat. Thanks.
Okay, well, I think
it is time for another round.
Bottoms up.
- Four, please.
- So, what are you guys working on now?
♪♪
I’m sorry.
- Uh, Swan Lake.
- Okay.
Yeah?
- You know it?
- No.
Not really. Heard of it.
What's it about?
Uh, it's about a girl
who gets turned into a swan...
and she needs love to break the spell.
Okay.
But her prince falls
for the wrong girl and-
so she kills herself.
So, a happy ending then.
It’s beautiful actually.
Like you.
Huh?
I said, you're beautiful.
That's funny?
Um, my hands are sweaty.
Hey.
Oh, hey.
It looks like someone might be rolling.
All right, come on. Come on.
It’s time to go dance.
♪♪
- ♪♪
- Sweet girl. Sweet girl. Sweet girl.
Hey! Nina!
♪♪
Hey, what the fuck?
Where you going?
Nina!
Where are you going?
Shh!
- Do you have any idea what time it is?
- Mm-hmm.
Uh, late.
Where have you been?
To the moon and back.
- You've been drinking.
- Ding-ding-ding-ding-ding!
- What else?
- Hmm?
What else have you been doing?
Oh. You want to know their names?
You need to sleep this off.
- There were two. There was Tom and there was Jerry.
- Be quiet, Nina!
And I fucked them both.
Shut your mouth!
- Don't come in here!
- What's this?
It’s called privacy!
I’m not 12 anymore!
- You're not my Nina right now.
- Leave me alone!
Shh.
Sweet girl.
Why didn't you wake me up?
I’m moving out.
♪♪
My music.
Thomas, I am so sorry.
- Keep on going.
- ♪ ♪
Go get warmed up.
♪♪
That was good.
Actually, really good.
Okay, let's take 10.
Hey.
Look, he just wanted to work it
and asked me to step in. Okay?
- I overslept.
- Oops.
Well, hey, at least
you had a good time, right?
- You put something in my drink.
- Yeah.
And then you just took off
in the morning?
- In the morning?
- Yeah. You slept over.
Um... no.
Unless your name is Tom,
and you got a dick.
But we-
But we what, Nina?
Wh-Did you have some sort
of lezzie wet dream about me?
- Stop.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! You did!
You fantasized about me!
- Shut up!
- Was I good?
♪♪
The final act!
Your final dance!
You tasted your dream, touched it...
only to have it crushed.
Your heart is broken!
Wounded!
Your life force fading.
The blood drips.
The black swan stole your love!
There's only one way to end the pain!
You're not fearful,
but filled with acceptance!
And you look down at Rothbart...
and then at the prince...
and then, yes, at the audience.
And then you jump!
Come on, go ahead. Jump.
You'll be fine. Jump!
♪♪
Okay, everybody gets a drink of water.
Then it's notes, hmm?
You lost weight.
Take off your shrug, please.
Okay.
Very good.
Face front. We're almost done.
And that's it.
Okay, you're done.
Thank you very much.
- Georgina?
- Yes.
I’m Lily.
Thomas said I should come.
Yes, we have to get you measured
for your Swan Queen costumes.
What's she doing here?
He made me your alternate.
Look, it's just in case.
- Thomas. Thomas!
- I don't want anybody-
- Thomas!
- Yes?
It can't be her. It can't be her.
Okay, why don't you just go?
I’ll catch up later.
- What's going on?
- Lily.
You made her my alternate?
Well, there's always an alternate.
- Lily is the best choice.
- No, but she wants my role.
- Every dancer in the world wants your role.
- No, this is different.
She's after me.
- She's trying to replace me.
- Nobody's after you.
No, please believe me.
Hey. Shh-shh-shh-shh.
I know it's been a struggle.
Yeah.
But you just had
a breakthrough this morning.
Tomorrow's yours.
Just give a great performance and you won't
have to worry about Lily or anybody else.
Now go home and rest.
From the vision again.
♪♪
What happened?
I’ve got a life.
Don't work too hard.
It’s your big day tomorrow.
Hey.
I’m still working in here.
Could you please
turn the lights back on?
Hello?
- What are you doing here?
- I’m so sorry.
I’m so sorry.
I know how it feels now.
She's trying to replace me.
What do I do?
You stole my things?
I was just trying to be perfect like you.
Perfect?
No, I’m not perfect.
I’m nothing.
Nothing!
Nothing! Nothing!
No!
- Nothing! Nothing!
- No!
Nothing! Nothing!
Sweet girl.
Mommy?
Sweet girl. Sweet girl.
- It’s my turn.
It’s my turn.
Stop!
What are you doing?
Sweetie?
Nina!
- Nina!
- Go away!
Open the door!
Go away!
Open the door, Nina!
Nina!
- Get out!
- What's wrong with you?
- You're sick!
- Get out! Get out!
Nina!
♪♪
Shh. It’s okay.
I’m here.
You were scratching all night.
Where's my clock?
- Don't worry about that.
- What time is it?
- Shh.
- My show is tonight.
- No, no, no.
- I have to-Ow.
No, don't worry. I called the theater,
and I told them you weren't feeling well.
- I have to go.
- No, no, lie down.
Let go of me.
You're staying in here
until you feel better.
Where is it?
This role's destroying you.
- Move.
- Nina.
- Move!
- What happened to my sweet girl, huh?
She's gone!
Ohh! Nina!
Oh, Nina! Oh, no! Please!
- You're not well!
- Let go of me!
- You can't handle this!
- I can't?
I’m the Swan Queen!
You're the one
who never left the corps.
Nina!
It’s Nina.
I have complete
confidence in you. Okay?
Stay focused, and you'll be fine.
This is your moment.
- What are you doing here?
- Nina?
- She was supposed to be sick!
- Wait, wait, wait. Give us a minute.
- Are you okay?
- I’m fine.
Uh, Nina-
- Nina.
- What?
I’ve already asked Lily.
Have you announced it?
After Beth, do you really
need another controversy?
I’m here, Thomas.
I’m doing it.
The only person
standing in your way is you.
It’s time to let her go.
Lose yourself.
White swan, entrance in 10.
♪♪
What are you doing?
You need to be upstage.
♪♪
Hey.
We sucked!
Okay, Nina.
♪♪
What the fuck?
- Are you okay?
- Nina, are you okay? What happened?
Can you tell me what the fuck happened?
- It wasn't my fault. He dropped me.
- It’s a fucking disaster!
Rough start, huh?
Must have been pretty humiliating.
- Ohh.
- Get out of my room.
See, I’m just-I’m worried
about the next act.
I’m just not sure you're feeling up to it.
Stop. Please stop.
How about...
I dance the black swan for you?
Leave me alone!
It’s my turn!
My turn! My turn!
Black swan, places in five.
♪♪
Wow!
Get back out there!
Come on! They want you-
Great job.
Fifteen to the last act.
♪♪
Hey!
You were amazing.
Seriously, I know that things got
a little messed up between us, but-
I mean, holy shit,
you completely blew me away!
O- Okay, well, I guess, um, that's it.
So I’ll-I’ll let you finish.
Meh.
♪♪
Oh! Can you hear them?
They love you!
My little princess,
I always knew you had it in you.
Come on. Let's take your bow.
Go get some help! Go get some help!
- What did you do? What did you do?
- ♪ ♪
- I felt it.
- What?
Perfect.
It was perfect.
♪♪