The world is full of complainers.
The fact is,
nothing comes with a guarantee.
And I don't care
if you're the Pope of Rome,
President of the United States,
or Man of the Year.
Something can all go wrong.
Go on ahead, you know, complain,
tell your problems to your neighbor,
ask for help and watch him fly.
Now, in Russia, they got it mapped out
so that everyone pulls for everyone else.
That's the theory, anyway.
But what I know about is Texas.
And down here, you're on your own.
Gave me a little pearl-handled .38
for our first anniversary.
Uh-huh.
Figure I better leave
before I use it on him.
I just don't know how you can stand him.
I'm only an employee.
I ain't married to him.
Yeah.
It's just...
I don't know.
Sometimes I think maybe
there's something wrong with him,
like maybe he's sick, mentally.
Or is it maybe me, do you think?
Listen, I...
I ain't a marriage counselor.
I don't know what goes on.
I don't wanna know.
But I like you.
I always liked you.
What are you gonna do in Houston?
Oh, I'll figure something out.
How come you offered
to drive me in this mess?
I told you, I like you.
I never knew that.
Well, now you do.
Hell.
Stop the car, Ray!
You know that car?
No.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
I just think maybe I'm making a mistake.
What was that back there?
Back where?
That sign.
I don't know.
Motel.
- Abby...
- Ray.
Do you remember what you said before?
Were you just being a gentleman?
Abby, I like you.
But it's no point starting anything now.
Yeah.
- I mean, I ain't a marriage counselor.
- Yeah.
What do you wanna do?
Hello.
Having a good time?
Who is this?
I don't know. Who's this?
You still there?
Yeah, I'm still here.
Ray?
Yeah.
Who was it?
Your husband.
Put your sweet lips
A little closer to the phone
And let's pretend that we're together...
I know where you can get those framed.
Why'd you take these?
What do you mean? Just doing my job.
You called me. I knew they were there.
Why'd you take them?
Well, I don't know.
Call it a fringe benefit.
How long you watch them?
Most the night.
They'd rest every few minutes,
then they'd get started again.
Hmm.
Quite something.
You know, in Greece,
they would cut off the head of the messenger
that brought the bad news.
Now that don't make much sense.
No.
Made them feel better.
Well, first off, Julian,
I don't know what the story is in Greece,
but in this state we got
very definite laws about that.
Second, I'm not a messenger.
I'm a private investigator.
And third and most important,
it ain't such bad news.
I mean, you thought he was colored.
You're always assuming the worst.
Anything else?
Mmm-hmm.
Don't come around here anymore.
If I need you,
I'll know what rock to turn over.
That's good, yeah.
Yeah.
"What rock to turn over."
That's very, very good.
You give me a call whenever
you want to cut off my head.
I can always crawl around without it.
Jeannie and the boys...
They'll be back after a spell.
Hopefully you will be, too.
Darn right.
Hold it, hold it.
You're sweet as a honey bee
But like a honey bee stings...
Where was I?
You were telling me
about the Ring of Fire.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right. Right, right.
Now, look, you've got
all these volcanoes, right?
And every time one goes pop,
you got the equivalent of what,
20, 30 megatons of TNT.
Meurice.
Yeah, I know, Marty. Pour them short.
Did Ray come in yet?
No, it's his night off.
Where was he last night?
How do I know where he was last night?
I don't know. Didn't he call?
Marty, this is an old friend of mine.
This is Debra.
Debra, this is Julian Marty.
There's a deuce in the corner needs help.
Right.
How long you know Meurice?
About ten years.
Ten years, huh?
What are you doing tonight?
Going out with Meurice.
Tell him you have a headache.
It'll pass.
We don't seem to be communicating...
Look, you wanna hustle me.
I don't wanna be hustled.
Oh, you don't?
It's as simple as that.
Oh, it's as simple as that.
Meurice,
I'm not here if Ray calls, okay?
Right.
Nice guy.
Not really.
What did you say your last name was?
There, Opal.
Ray?
Yeah.
Let's get out of here.
You get what you wanted?
Yeah. Let's get out of here.
Drive me to a motel?
You can stay at my place.
Drop you there.
Where are you going?
See a guy.
Ray, don't go to the bar.
I know him. It ain't a good idea.
I just gotta see a guy.
Sweet dreams of you
So it's a deal.
You and your colleagues find a way
to harness this vast, volcanic energy,
and I'll just sit back and watch
these shitkickers go broke.
Howdy, stranger.
Meurice.
Sorry about last night.
No sweat. Wasn't too busy.
You missed a good one, though.
This white guy walks in about 1:00 and
asks if we have a discount for alcoholics.
Well, I tell him to get lost,
but now Marty's sitting here,
and I can tell he's thinking that
maybe that ain't such a bad idea.
Marty.
Well, what?
What, what?
Am I fired? You wanna hit me, what?
I don't particularly wanna talk to you.
Well.
You're not gonna fire me,
I might as well quit.
Fine.
Suit yourself.
Having a good time?
I don't like this kind of talk.
What'd you come here for?
You owe me for two weeks.
No.
She's an expensive piece of ass,
but you get a refund if you tell me
who else she's been sluicing.
I want that money.
You got something to tell me, fine.
What are you,
a fucking marriage counselor?
What are you smiling at?
I'm funny, right? I'm an asshole?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
That's not what's funny.
What's funny is her.
What's funny is that
I had you two followed.
Because if it's not you
she's sleeping with, it's someone else.
And what's really gonna be funny
is when she gives you
that innocent look and says,
"I don't know
what you're talking about, Ray.
"I ain't done anything funny."
But the funniest thing to me right now
is that you think that
she came back here for you.
That's what's fucking funny!
Come on this property again,
I'll be forced to shoot you.
Fair notice.
Hey, Marty.
Marty, I thought you were dead.
You going home?
No.
I'm staying right here in hell.
That's kind of a bleak point
of view there, isn't it, Marty?
Meurice...
I don't want the asshole near my money.
And I don't want him in the bar.
We get a lot of assholes in here, Marty.
Hello?
Marty?
Who was it?
What?
- On the phone. Was it...
- Um...
Was it for you?
I don't know.
He didn't say anything.
How'd you know it was a he?
You got a girl?
Am I screwing something up by being here?
No.
Am I?
I can find a place tomorrow,
and I'll be out of your hair.
Well, if that's what you wanna do,
then you ought to do it.
You...
You want the bed or the couch?
Well...
Couch will be all right.
You can sleep on the bed if you want.
I'm not gonna put you out of your bed.
You wouldn't be putting me out.
I'll be all right here.
Okay.
Opal?
Lover boy better lock his door.
A lot of nuts out there.
Let's do it outside in nature, hmm?
Like to have seen his face
when he found the dead end.
Louie, Louie
Oh, my baby
Me gotta go, yeah
Louie, Louie
Hey, mister, how'd you break
your pussy finger?
I love it! I love it!
You come up here a lot?
Yeah?
Well, I'm sorry, sweetheart,
my date is here.
She saw me rolling a cigarette,
thought it was marijuana.
Thought I was a swinger, I guess.
Louie, Louie
Isn't that wild?
Stick your finger
up the wrong person's ass?
You know,
a friend of mine a while back
broke his hand and put it in a cast.
The very next day, he falls,
protects his bad hand
and he breaks his good one.
So he breaks that, too, you know.
So now he's got two busted flippers.
You know?
So I says to him, I said, "Creighton,"
I says, "I hope your wife
really loves you,
"'cause for the next five weeks,
"you can't even wipe
your own goddamn ass."
That's a test, ain't it?
A test of true love.
I got a job for you.
Well,
if the pay is right and it's legal,
I'll do it.
It's not strictly legal.
Well, if the pay's right,
I'll do it.
It's in reference
to that gentleman and my wife.
The more I think about it,
the more irritated I get.
Yeah? Well, could you tell me what it is
you want me to do, or is it a secret?
This is no joke.
You want me to kill them.
Well?
Well, what?
What do you think?
You're an idiot.
So this won't interest you, huh?
I didn't say that.
All I said was, "You're an idiot."
Hell, you been thinking about it
for so much, it's driving you simple.
I'll give you $10,000.
I'm supposed to do a murder,
no, two murders,
trust you not to go simple on me
and do something stupid.
I mean, really stupid.
Now, why should I trust you?
For the money.
Money.
Yeah.
That's a righteous amount of money.
In Russia,
they make only 50 cent a day.
I want you
to go fishing.
What?
Go down to Corpus for a few days,
get yourself noticed.
I'll give you a call when it's done.
You just find a way to cover that money.
I'll take care of the money.
You make sure those bodies aren't found.
There's a big incinerator behind my place.
So you want, like, a townhouse,
your own apartment.
Come. I show you around.
You sure this apartment
is vacant, Mrs. Estevez?
Oh, yes. Yes, yes.
I was just explaining to him
that he moved out yesterday.
Don't mind Mr. Garcia.
He used to be my brother-in-law.
Looks like the state legislature's
already in session.
Yeah, I thought this was where they met.
Listen, you're gonna help me
with a problem.
I am?
You're gonna keep an eye on Marty
and Ray, make sure nothing happens.
How about it, gentlemen?
Let's show our appreciation
for Lorraine up there,
a registered nurse from Bolton, Texas.
How about it, gentlemen? Yeah.
Thanks, Meurice.
Anytime.
Hey, you don't have to worry
about a thing for a while.
Marty went down to Corpus yesterday.
He's in the house.
What's the matter?
Could have sworn I heard something.
Door's locked. There's nothing there.
Well, I guess we wouldn't have heard
anything if it had been him.
He's real careful.
Fact is, he's anal, Ray.
Oh?
Uh-huh. He told me once himself.
He said to me,
"In here, Abby. In here, I'm anal."
Well, I'll be damned.
I couldn't believe it myself.
Me, on the other hand,
I got lots of personality.
Marty always said I had too much.
'Course, he was never big on personality.
He sent me to a psychiatrist once,
to see if he could calm me down some.
Yeah? And what happened?
Psychiatrist said I was the healthiest
person he ever met, so Marty fired him.
I don't think you can fire
a psychiatrist, exactly.
Well, I never saw him again,
I can tell you that much.
Mmm-hmm.
I said, "Marty, how come you're anal
"and I gotta go to the psychiatrist?"
What did he say?
Nothing.
He's like you. He doesn't say much.
Well, thanks.
Except when he doesn't say things,
they're usually nasty.
Mmm-hmm.
And when you don't, they're usually nice.
Do you ever get tired?
Hmm?
Oh, yeah. I guess.
Uh-huh.
Hello?
Marty?
Yeah.
Catch any fish?
What?
Did you catch any fish?
Yeah, yeah.
What kind of fish?
Listen, is it done?
Yes, sir. You owe me some money.
If you're fucking with me,
you'll regret it.
They look good.
Why, you want a couple?
Just the 10,000 will be fine.
You got something to show me first?
Dead?
So it would seem.
What did you do with the bodies?
It's taken care of.
Less you know about it, the better.
Jesus.
I don't believe it.
Oh...
I'm gonna be sick.
I'm gonna want that picture back.
You did say something about the money.
Yeah, money.
Something I gotta ask you, Marty.
I been very, very careful.
Have you been very, very careful?
Of course.
Nobody knows you hired me?
Don't be stupid.
I'm not about to tell anyone.
We have to learn to be discreet.
Trust each other.
For richer or poorer.
Don't say that.
Your marriages don't turn out so hot.
How did you cover the money?
It's been taken care of,
and the less you know about it, the better.
I made a call.
It'll be all right.
I must have gone mighty simple.
A murder like this, too risky.
Then you shouldn't have done it.
Can't have it both ways.
Count it...
And go.
No, I trust you.
Who looks stupid now?
Damn.
Marty.
What's the matter? You deaf?
Come on.
Marty, you home?
Marty?
What night is tonight, Diane?
What night is it?
Tuesday?
Tuesday night is ladies' night.
What?
All your drinks are free.
You're sweet as a honey bee
But like a honey bee stings
You've gone and left my heart in pain
All you left is our favorite song
The one we danced to all night long
It used to bring sweet memories
Of a tender love that used to be
Now it's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
It's the same, same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
I, oh, I
Sentimental fool am I
To hear an old love song and wanna cry
But the melody keeps haunting me
Reminding me how in love we used to be
I keep hearing the part
that used to touch our hearts
Saying together forever
Darling, breaking up never
It's the same old song
Ain't glad to hear it
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
It's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
We used to dance to the music...
...has increased over 80%
in the last three years.
And what's more, in two years' time,
we'll be experiencing
what's known as the Jupiter effect,
wherein all the planets
of the known universe will be lined up,
causing an incredible wave
of destructive power...
...in John 6:18,
the Lord out and tells us
that these are the signs
by which we shall know
that he is among us.
There are many good people
who disagree with me,
but it is my belief that
this Antichrist is alive today
and living in that ten-nation alliance
I spoke of earlier.
This is WKLJ through the night.
And I'm John Lievsay.
I'll be here with you
till 6:00 this morning,
when Mike Miller will be stepping in.
Here's a request we really had to dig for.
It's another song
from south of the border.
Yeah?
Abby, you all right?
Ray? What time is it?
I don't know.
It's early.
I love you.
You all right?
I don't know.
I better get off now.
Well, I'll see you.
And thanks, Ray.
Abby...
Hey, Ray.
Why didn't you get into bed?
I didn't think I could sleep.
Surprised you could.
You called me this morning.
Yeah.
I just wanted to let you know
that everything is all right.
I took care of everything.
Now all we have to do is keep our heads.
What do you mean?
I know about it, Abby.
I went to the bar last night.
What happened?
Was Meurice there?
Yeah.
He didn't see me, though.
Nobody saw me.
Is it cold in here?
Well, what happened?
I cleaned it all up.
But that ain't important.
What's important is what we do now.
I mean, we can't go around half-cocked.
What we need is time to think about this,
figure it out.
Anyway, we got some time now.
We gotta be smart.
Ray...
Abby, you should never point a gun
at anyone unless you mean to shoot him,
and if you shoot him,
you better make sure he's dead.
'Cause if he ain't dead,
he's gonna get up and try and kill you.
The only thing they taught us in
the service that's worth a God damn.
Where in the hell's my windbreaker?
Ray...
Just tell me what happened.
That ain't important.
What's important is that we did it.
That's the only thing that matters.
We both did it for each other.
That's what's important.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I mean, what are you talking about?
I haven't done anything funny.
What was that?
Ray, you're not even acting like yourself.
First you call me at 5:00 in the a.m.,
saying all kind of nice things on the phone,
and then you come charging in here,
scaring me half to death,
without even telling me
what I'm supposed to be scared of.
I mean, if you two had a fight
or something, I don't care.
Just as long as...
Pick it up.
What?
Well, that's him.
Who?
Marty.
What's going on with you two?
All right.
You can call him back, whoever it was.
I'll get out of your way.
You left your weapon behind.
Hi, Meurice, this is Helene,
Helene Trend, you know?
And I'm calling 'cause I wanna know
just what the hell that remark
you made about Sylvia is supposed to mean.
She said you're full of shit,
and frankly, I believe her.
And, hey, I love you, too, sure.
Anyway, you better call me soon,
'cause I'm going to South America
tonight, you know, Uruguay.
Listen, asshole, it's Marty.
I just got back from Corpus Christi,
and there's a lot of money missing
from the safe. A lot of money.
I'm not saying you took it, but the place
was your responsibility, Meurice,
and I told you to keep an eye
on your asshole friend.
Don't come to the bar tonight.
I got some...
Damn machine. What is this?
The bar is still gonna be closed tonight.
I got some other business to take care of,
but tomorrow I wanna have
a word with you and with Ray,
if you can find him.
I hope you're planning on leaving town.
You got a problem, Meurice?
No, but you do, cowboy.
Have you been to the bar?
Why?
You shouldn't have taken
the fucking money!
Look at me, man. Now, I'm serious.
You broke in the bar,
and you ripped off the fucking safe.
Abby warned me about you.
You know what your problem is?
You're too fucking obvious.
The only two people with the combination
are you and me, and Abby, maybe.
These fucking things
are nothing but coffin nails.
Hey, look, Ray, personally
I don't give a shit, you know.
Look, man, I know Marty's a hard-on,
but you gotta do something.
Say you're sorry, give the money back,
get the fuck out of here, or something.
Shit.
Hey, look, man, this is very humiliating,
preaching about this bullshit.
But I'm not laughing, Ray Bob,
so you know it's no fucking joke.
Damn.
Ray?
Lover boy ought to lock the door.
I love you.
That's a stupid thing to say, right?
I love you, too.
No.
You're just saying that
because you're scared.
You left your weapon behind.
He'll kill you, too.
Ray?
Where is everything?
In the trunk.
In the car.
You leaving?
Isn't that what you want?
You wanna come with me?
I gotta know what happened first.
What you wanna know?
You broke into the bar
and you wanted to get your money.
And you and Marty
had a fight or something.
Well, I don't know. Wasn't it you?
- Maybe a burglar broke in and then...
- With your gun.
Nobody broke in, Abby.
I'll tell you the truth.
Truth is that...
I been feeling sick
the last couple of days.
I can't sleep.
Can't eat.
When I try...
Ab.
Truth is...
He was alive when I buried him.
Yeah, yeah. Just a second.
Abby, what's the matter?
I think Marty's dead. Can I come in?
That's bullshit.
Marty called me after he was jacked up.
I don't know where Marty is,
but he's not dead.
Now, you relax, and I'll go find him.
And stay away from Ray.
The guy's gone nuts.
Turn it off.
Ray.
Just turn it off!
Why?
No curtains on the windows.
So?
I think someone's watching.
So what'll they see?
Just leave it off. He can see in.
You do anything, the neighbors will hear.
You...
Abby, I meant it.
When I called.
I love you, too.
But you're scared.
All right.
Now, you've got some
personal property of mine.
What did you do?
Now, I don't know what the hell
you two thought you was gonna pull off.
I'm not afraid of you, Marty.
Well, ma'am, if I see him,
I'll sure give him the message.
You're sweet as a honey bee
But like a honey bee stings
You've gone and left my heart in pain
All you left is our favorite song
The one we danced to all night long
It used to bring sweet memories
Of a tender love that used to be
Now it's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
It's the same, same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
And it breaks me up to hear it
I, oh, I
Sentimental fool am I
To hear an old love song and wanna cry
But the melody keeps haunting me
Reminding me how in love we used to be
I keep hearing the part
that used to touch our hearts
Saying together forever
Darling, breaking up never
It's the same old song
Ain't glad to hear it
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
It's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
We used to dance to the music
Make romance to the music
It's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
Now it's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
I, oh, I can't bear to hear it
It's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone
It's the same old song
But with a different meaning
since you've been gone