His name is Jan.
I do not know him.
He's from the rig.
You know we do not favour
matrimony with outsiders.
Can you even tell us what matrimony is?
It's when two people are joined in God.
Do you really believe you're capable...
...of bearing the responsibility
...not only for your own marriage in God,
...but also another's?
I know I am.
Can you think of anything of real value...
...that the outsiders have
brought with them?
Their music.
Out you go, Bess McNeill, and be seated.
Forgot my six-string razor,
...hit the sky
Halfway to Memphis...
...before I realized
Well, I rang the information...
...my axe was cold
They said she rides a train to Oriole
Now it's a mighty long way...
Bess.
Bess, come on.
Don't be silly.
He's late.
All right, but at least he's coming.
Get this on, then.
You're going to ruin your dress.
He's late.
You're being silly.
Come on.
Bess, get your clothes on.
Don't ruin it.
It's a good day.
Come on.
Bess, you're not supposed to see him.
You know that.
You're going to ruin your...
You're late!
Hey!
Break out the bottles!
Come on.
It's my wedding.
Will you please,
be upstanding for the bride?
The Lord's my Shepherd,
I'll not want;
He makes me come to God...
...in pastures green;
He leadeth me...
...as quiet waters lie...
As we stand in thy presence
today, in thy house,
We worship thee as the author...
...of every good and perfect gift.
Christ loved the church
and gave himself for her.
We should love Christ
and give ourselves to him.
If it is not too inappropriate...
...may I say that you, Bess,
...have shown that love and that
commitment in your own life.
It is not once or twice...
...that you have been in this building,
...giving your time
and effort to cleaning it.
I know that you have done that...
...not so as to be
well-thought-of here on earth
...but out of your love for God in heaven.
Great sermon, father.
Ring the bells, then.
Our church has no bells.
That's not too fun, is it?
This is Dodo.
The sister-in-law.
We haven't really met, have we?
No.
Well, everything happened so quickly.
What makes you say that?
I just mean...
Well, it did, didn't it?
Are you not happy for me?
Of course I am.
Come on, Terry.
Hey!
Get along, little doggies!
Bess.
"Dear Bess,
"I've known you for 6 years,
...and I can definitely say...
...you have the biggest heart...
...of anyone I've ever met."
"It wasn't easy for me here
when I married Sam,
...but you welcomed me instantly,
...and I won't ever forget that."
"Your generosity knows no bounds,
...like the time when you
lent jack a bike...
...because his was broken,
only it was mine,
...and I had to walk to work."
"I was furious with you then,
...but I regret that now,
...because it's your spirit."
"You'd give anything to anyone."
"When Sam died, I lost
a husband, and you a brother."
"We saw each other through that...
...and promised to look after one another."
"You are the reason..." sorry.
"I have stayed...
...when I almost gave up
in this cold place,
...and now your warmth
has embraced another outsider."
"His name is Jan,
...and I don't know
much about him,
...but I'll accept
his right to be here...
...because of you, Bess."
"If he doesn't take care of you...
...and give you
everything you need,
...I'll kill him."
"Thank you for all you've given me, Bess.
I love you very much."
Have me now?
Here?
Maybe you wanted something more romantic.
This is lovely.
You sure?
No.
Have me.
What do I do?
Ok?
You got blood on your dress.
Shall I go down and wait for you?
You ok?
Hi.
Take care of yourself.
Go get her now, Jan!
Go get her, Jan!
Every day I spend my time
Drinking wine, feeling fine
Waiting here to find the sign
That I can understand
yes, I am
In the days between the hours
Ivory towers,
...bloody flowers
Push their heads into the air
I don't care if I ever know
there I go
Don't push your love too far
Can't get this fucker open.
Shit.
What's so funny?
How could you take it?
How could you keep away from the boys?
I waited for you.
No.
Don't laugh.
Yeah.
But you must have been lonely.
Who did you talk to?
I thank you for the greatest gift of all:
the gift of love.
I thank you for Jan.
I'm so lucky to have been
given these gifts.
But remember to be a good girl, Bess,
...for you know I giveth
and I taketh away.
What?
I didn't mean it like that.
Yes. I'll be good.
I'll be really, really good.
Thank you.
What did you say?
Fly.
Away!
Hello, Jan.
Hello.
Bess.
Why don't you have any church bells?
We do not need bells in
our church to worship God.
I like church bells.
Let's put them back again.
Have fun.
But now, friends,
...things have become very different.
It hurts me to have to say it,
...but there appears to be
those in the church...
...who are prepared to
cling to the world...
...instead of fleeing from it.
But those to whom I refer...
...will know what I am speaking about.
It grieves my heart,
...and I know there are others...
...who feel just the same.
Amen.
Mr. Donald John Beaton,
will you rise and address the question?
Thank you, Lord, for this day
you have blessed us with.
It's stupid that only men
can talk in the service.
Hold your tongue, woman.
Lassie!
It's Lassie!
It is Lassie, I know it!
Lassie!
Oh, Lassie!
Lassie. Oh, Lassie.
Welcome home.
They're burying Anthony now.
Go and listen to the minister.
What?
Yeah.
You can do that if you want.
Men are allowed at funerals.
Go on.
Anthony Dodd Mantle, who has been one...
Anthony Dodd Mantle, you are a sinner...
...and you deserve your place in hell.
The minister said he would go to hell.
Did he say that?
Bloody cheerful.
Will Anthony go to hell.
Everyone knows that.
You do realize...
...that I will have to go back soon,
don't you?
You knew it all the time.
"Lord, we are unworthy of
the least of all thy mercies.
We thank thee for this food.
Pardon our sins for Jesus' sake.
Amen."
Amen.
When are you going back?
Didn't you know?
Jan's going to stay at home with me...
...quit the rig because we're so happy.
Bess, come on.
I wish I could.
I will not have that kind of
behaviour in my house!
I'm sorry, mother.
I'm sorry.
If you cannot control your moods,
...It's the hospital again
for you, my girl.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Why should you be any different?
Every woman around here
has to learn to be alone...
...when their man's away
at sea or on the oil rigs.
Even you can learn how to endure.
I don't even know who you are.
I don't know anything about you,
...and quite frankly...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to say this,
...but I don't trust you.
She's...
She's very susceptible.
And you could get her...
You could get her to do
anything you wanted.
No.
I don't think so.
How am I supposed to look out for her now?
What do you want to do?
Keep her here, locked up
for the rest of her life?
She hasn't got the strength.
She's stronger than you and me.
You don't understand, do you?
She's not right in the head.
Come on.
She just wants it all.
What's this?
What?
What's that?
It's a present.
Can I open it?
Yeah, sure.
Open it.
Nice colours, aren't they?
Very cheerful.
It's open.
We've been waiting for you, bud.
Hey.
Yeah. That's fine.
You want a little snort?
Look at you.
Bess!
No!
Come, come, come.
All right?
It's ok.
Watch your head!
Watch your head.
Ok?
It's just for a little.
I'll call you.
Jan!
No!
Bess!
You're going to be all right, dear.
Ok?
You're ok.
It's all right, darling.
It's all right.
It's ok.
It's all right, dear.
Let's give you one of these.
One of these down you.
Here we go.
Take one of these.
That's it.
Pop it in your mouth.
Swallow.
Who would be a poor man,
a beggar man, a thief?
If he had a rich man
in his hand?
And who would steal the candy
from a laughing baby's mouth?
If he could take it
from the money man?
Cross eyed Mary
a-goes jumping in again
She signs no contract
but she always
plays the game
She dines in Hampstead village...
You are guilty of selfishness, Bess.
You didn't even consider for one second...
...how painful it must have been for him.
You put your own feelings
before everyone else's.
I can't see that you love him
when you behave like that.
Now you must promise
to be a good girl, Bess.
I promise to be a good girl.
I'm sorry for the way I behaved, mother.
It's all right, Bessie.
Mother, would it be ok...
...if I came home for a bit
while Jan's away?
Of course it would, Bessie.
Ok.
You got it.
A little bit of this shit.
Oh, shit.
Nice.
You know, the waves are
getting pretty heavy.
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck's wrong with you?
Just pissed.
Just give me one.
Just wait.
Now, but you know, there's some nice...
Shit.
Sorry, guys.
Just throw the god-damn radio away.
You can't get anything in here anyhow.
You and your fucking radio.
Oh, God! Fuck.
Jeez!
Come on.
Dance! Dance!
Fire!
Wet towel!
Just... shit!
Hey!
Bueno!
Bueno! Bueno!
Didn't he say he'd call?
Do you want me to wait with you?
Yes, please.
Where the fuck is the second shift?
I got a phone call to make.
I got to go to the hospital.
Are you cold?
No.
No?
You're all right?
Don't wait too long, will you?
Oh, shit.
Pim, got to make a phone call.
Get out of here.
Hello?
Is Bess there?
One moment.
Bess.
Is that you, Bess?
Hi.
I'm sorry I couldn't get
to the phone earlier.
That's ok.
Don't you love me any more?
Of course I do.
Say so, then.
I'd made up my mind not to.
Everyone says that I love you too much...
...and if you found out...
...how much I loved you,
...you might get upset...
...because we're not together right now.
Bess, never stop saying you love me.
You hear?
Yes.
No matter what anybody says.
Say it, then.
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
I can hear you breathing.
Can you hear me?
What are you thinking?
That you're here.
And what are you doing?
I'm touching your arms...
...and your chest...
...and your tummy
and...
...your prick.
You're so huge.
Jan will be home in ten days for a week.
Pardon?
Pits.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Where's Jan?
I'm the only one back.
Hurt my wrist.
They sent me home.
He sends his love.
How long have you got off now?
Only three days.
Yeah.
You know me.
I'm back.
Sorry.
How long has she been asleep?
What's the matter with you?
Cat got your tongue?
Have you taken my calendar?
No, I have not.
What would I want with your calendar?
Don't be ridiculous.
You've taken it.
I have not taken it.
Yes, you have.
I don't know what you're talking about.
What calendar?
Where is it?
Bess, you've got to
stop all this, you know.
You've got to go on living
when he isn't here.
I mean, he's not dead.
You're not dead.
You know what I mean?
You've got to stop it.
It's all right.
It's nothing.
What's going on?
Go back to sleep.
It's all right.
Was that Bess?
No. It's ok.
It's all right.
Bit of hysterics.
No, no. It's all right.
I'll sort it out.
We're not to have this
carry on in the house.
I know. Just stay where you are.
Go back to sleep.
It's terrible.
Bess McNeill, for many years,
you've prayed for love.
Shall I take it away from you again?
Is that what you want?
Oh, no.
I'm still grateful for love.
What do you want, then?
I pray for Jan to come home.
He will be coming home in ten days.
You must learn to endure.
You know that.
I can't wait.
This is unlike you, Bess.
Out there, there are people
who need Jan and his work.
What about them?
They don't matter.
Nothing else matters.
I just want Jan home again.
I pray to you.
Please, won't you send him home?
Are you sure that's what you want?
Yes.
Ok.
Get her up.
Blow out!
Get away!
Terry!
Talk to me, will you?
Watch out!
Jan!
Go get... get a medic!
I don't know what kind of
condition he's in.
I think it's very serious, though.
I don't quite know.
It's Jan.
There's been an accident on the rig.
Jan, can you hear me?
What are you doing?
I'm holding your hand.
Don't touch me.
Don't touch me!
Jan, relax.
Just take...
Sit down here.
All right.
Deep breath.
Hello.
Talk to me, darling.
Talk to me.
Come on.
It's all right.
It's going to be all right.
They're going to operate straight away.
It will be a few hours,
...so I think we better wait...
Bess.
Bess, you can't go in there.
It's not allowed.
I want to be with him.
I know you do.
I know.
But come on. Come with me.
Come on.
No.
I want to see him all the time.
Bess, it's not a good idea.
Come on.
Bess.
Bess, please, you can't stay here.
It's just not possible.
Bess!
Can I have a word with you?
Stay there, all right?
Don't move.
I want you to pray with me.
But...
Please.
Dear god, we pray that you...
...will hold your hand
over Jan...
...and not let him die.
Amen.
Mrs. Nyman, will you please come with me?
Will he live?
We have stabilized your husband's
condition for the time being.
Will he live?
Yes.
Yes, Bess, he will live.
Your husband suffered
very serious injuries.
Life shouldn't always
be preserved at any cost.
What do you mean?
Well, the doctor means, Bess...
...that, sometimes...
...in some cases when
life isn't worth living,
...then it may
be better to die.
You don't know Jan, or you
could not say such a thing.
Your husband may never walk again.
We think he'll be completely paralysed.
But he'll live?
Yes.
He will live, it seems.
Father.
Are you there?
Are you still there?
Of course I am, Bess.
You know that.
What's happening?
You wanted Jan home.
I've changed my mind.
Why did I ask for that?
Because you're...
...a stupid little girl, Bess.
I had to test you.
Your love for Jan
has been put to the test.
Thank you...
...for not letting him die.
You're welcome, Bess.
He said "there is no reason
And the truth is plain to see"
But I wandered
through my playing cards
And would not let her be
One of 16 vestal virgins
Who were leaving
for the coast
And although
my eyes were open
They might just as well
have been closed
And so it was...
I would say to you...
...that if there is one of
these commandments...
...which you do not love
and do not obey,
...you have no place
at the Lord's table.
When did you get back?
I came back with Jan.
It's good to see you.
Surf's up!
Hi.
Hi, guys.
How you doing, buddy?
Well, fine.
How are you?
Ok.
Did you find anything?
Gas.
Nothing really.
Guess what, now.
We're heading up north.
Well, north, that's good.
That's where you always said the oil was.
What are you doing here, anyway?
We're meant to be out drilling.
I just felt like...
Putting my feet up for a while.
I didn't trust you
two guys out there alone.
Oh, my...
My arms aren't ok, so...
I'm not thirsty, anyway.
Bullshit!
Hey, come on.
Come on.
Oh, man, sorry.
Ok.
Thank you.
I'm not really supposed to
have any visitors, so...
We really don't have the time, either.
Ok.
You take care of yourself?
Take care.
Get well soon.
See you, guys.
Will you do something for me?
Yes.
The next time you come,
...could you wear something more...
More loose...
So I...
So I won't have to see your body.
Bess, you'll have to go now...
...because Jan needs to rest.
All right.
You shouldn't get him
too overemotional, you know.
It's not good for him.
I'm sorry.
You got to cheer him up.
Is he asleep now?
Well, he should be...
...the amount I've given him.
Would it be all right...
...If I went and had a look at him?
I love you, Jan.
I love you, too, Bess.
You are the love of my life.
Bess.
Where have you been?
I've been to the church.
What, at 2:00 in the morning?
I don't want you getting ill again...
...like you did when Sam died.
I said I've been to the church.
It has nothing to do with the church.
Did you hear what I said?
Did you?
I don't want you to get ill again.
Like you did when Sam died.
I've had a word with Dr. Richardson,
all right?
And he says he could see you tomorrow.
Can he?
Bess, would you like to come in?
Dodo said I had to come.
She has this idea about me treating you.
My predecessor admitted you
a few years ago.
Well, why did he do that?
I don't know.
No, nor do I.
You were upset because
your brother had died...
...and now you're upset
because your husband's ill.
Nothing unusual about that.
Am I not going to have some pills?
I'm probably not like your old doctor.
I don't think that people
should be given pills...
...just because they do
what's only natural.
Maybe showing what you feel
isn't the done thing...
...from where you come from,
...but it's certainly no disease.
What... happened on the rig...
...was my fault.
How come?
I prayed to God to send him home.
Well...
What powers you possess.
Do you really...
Do you really believe
that you possess such powers?
I know you people believe
a lot about yourselves.
Bess...
Perhaps you should do a bit of grieving...
...for yourself instead of him.
I think you should come and see me...
...now and again if you feel like it.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Well, things will pick up
once he gets home again.
Well, she's my woman of gold
Yes, she's not very old,
uh-huh, huh
Well, she's my woman of gold
Yes, she's not very old,
uh-huh, huh
I don't mean to be bold, uh
But, uh, may I hold your hand?
Well, she ain't no witch
and I love the way she twitch
uh-huh, huh
Well, she ain't no witch
and I love the way she twitch
uh-huh, huh...
Happy birthday to you
Squashed tomatoes and stew
You look like a monkey
and I thought it was you
Look at that.
Special.
Shall I open your present?
Yes.
Your presents.
Can you see all right?
What is it?
Wait and see.
I don't believe it.
Where did you get that?
I got it in a shop.
That is the stupidest thing I've ever seen.
Look, it's not doing anything now.
Ahem. All right, go on.
Well, go on.
That is just terrible.
That is daft, that is completely daft.
Happy birthday, Jan.
Thank you.
I'll see you later.
Do you like it?
Yes, it's...
It's... it's nice.
I'll give you your pill.
Ok?
One more drink.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Happy birthday.
I'm finished, Bess.
No.
You could take a lover...
...without anybody noticing...
...but you can't divorce me.
They'd never let you.
Bess.
No.
Is that what you think I want?
You cripple!
You must make up with him.
A husband and wife...
...have to be able to talk to each other.
He's the one who is helpless,
...and you're the one...
...who must show you're strong.
Go to him and tell him...
...you are sorry you were angry.
You have God.
You have the strength...
...your life in God has bestowed upon you,
...and that is a strength
he does not possess.
Oh, no.
Come on.
You're all right.
That's it.
It's all right.
All right, all right.
What's she thinking of...
Going off leaving you like this?
You must admit that she was...
She was happy when we got married.
She blossomed...
Didn't she?
I can't just lie here.
I can't even make love to her.
She's got to get out of here.
She's got to get on with life.
Help me set her free.
She'd do anything for you, Jan.
You know that.
She don't care... anything about herself...
...but she'd do anything for you...
just to see a smile on your face.
Do you understand me?
Yeah.
Right.
Thanks for telling me.
No trouble.
Do you want me to read to you?
Are you all right?
They took him back to the hospital.
Bess.
Bess, what is going on?
He went unconscious.
We had to bring him back here.
At home any more...
Not if you're going to go running off...
...and leaving him like that.
I'm sorry.
Well, it's just not good enough!
I'm not... I'm not even allowed
to kiss him any more.
Why don't you try listening to
what he says, Bess?
It's up to you.
He ain't got anyone else.
You could give him the will to live.
That's more than any doctor can do.
Bess?
I'm sorry.
No, it was my fault.
Come here.
Hi.
Love is a mighty power...
Isn't it?
If I die...
It will be because love
cannot keep me alive.
But I can hardly remember...
...what it's like to make love.
And if I forget that...
...then I'll die.
Remember when I phoned you from the rig?
We made love without being together.
Do you want me to talk
to you like that again?
I'd love to.
Bess.
I want you to find
a man to make love to...
...and then come back here
and tell me about it.
It will feel like you and me
being together again.
Now, that... that will keep me alive.
I can't.
This morning when I...
When I told you to get a lover,
It wasn't for your sake.
It was for my sake...
...because I don't want to die.
I'm afraid.
Do you understand?
Yes.
It will be you and me, Bess.
Do it for me.
I can't.
Please.
Bess?
Are you all right?
Sure?
Here you go.
Easy.
Suzanne takes you down...
...to her place near the river
You can hear the boats go by,
...you can spend the night, beside her.
And you know
that she's half crazy,
But that's why
you want to be there
and she feeds you
tea and oranges...
...that come all the way from China
And just when you mean
to tell her,
that you have no love
to give her
Then she gets you
on her wavelength
And she lets the river answer
That you've always been her lover
You certainly needed some shut-eye.
I put your rose in a vase.
Perked up a bit.
You should think of yourself a bit, too.
Go out.
Go dancing.
I've seen you dance.
You like to dance.
Where's Jan?
There's nothing you can do in here.
Don't let him die.
And why shouldn't I let him die?
I love him.
So you keep saying, but I don't see it.
There's nothing I can do.
There's nothing at all.
Prove to me that you love him...
...and then I'll let him live.
I've come to dance.
It's great. You're great.
Great movement...
But, maybe you could talk to me.
And love lies bleeding in my hand
Oh, it kills me to think
of you with another man
I was playing...
Bess, stop dancing.
Talk to me.
But my guitar couldn't hold you
So I split the band
Bess...
Talk to me.
Give me five minutes.
You can touch me now.
You can have me now.
Bess, listen to me.
We're not going to make love.
Now put your clothes back on.
Don't you want me?
Don't you like me?
You said that you liked me.
Yes, Bess, I like you.
Now put your clothes on.
But you don't understand.
I'll...
I'll be good to you, and...
I want us to make love.
Listen.
Bess...
If you want to talk to me...
...we can meet at the hospital.
Now just put your clothes on, Bess.
No...
Please.
I don't know what to do with you.
All right, now just put
your clothes on, Bess,
...and go home.
No.
I'm lying on my back, all naked.
And...
...he comes in, and he sees me.
And he kisses my breasts.
And he enters me...
And...
And he's making love to me...
Gently...
And...
He's coming.
It was Dr. Richardson.
Hi.
Hi, Bess.
Where are you going, then?
Jan, we're going to
take you off the respirator...
...for five minutes to exercise
your lungs a little bit...
...and see how you are,
...so just relax and take it easy.
Ok, start to breathe by yourself, now, Jan.
Just take very deep breaths.
Slowly.
That's it.
And again.
Very good.
Deep breaths.
Now, that's it.
Bess.
Yes?
What are you doing on this bus?
Which bus, Jan?
Come to me.
Come.
I'm here.
I'm here in the back.
Yes.
In the back of the bus.
Yeah.
Come.
Dodo.
Jan.
Go and get Dr. Richardson.
I'm going to put you back
on the respirator now, Jan.
Jan, can you hear me?
Are you awake?
Talk to me.
Hi, Bess.
I'd like to have a chat with you.
Bess.
This is my bus... My bus.
Forgive me, father.
I have sinned.
Mary Magdalene sinned,
...and she is among my dearly beloved.
I go to the back of the bus...
...and you're there.
And you're so huge...
...that you're almost
bursting out of your pants.
And I undo your fly...
...and I touch you.
I'm touching your prick.
Have you been in to see Jan?
How is he?
Better.
He's better?
Just a bit.
Hey, Bess, it looks like...
...your prayers have been answered.
We've been able to take
him off the respirator.
Good news, isn't it?
Do you think...
...that we turn to different people
...when we get close to the edge?
And that we...
...we turn bad when we're going to die?
You're not going to die.
I know you're not.
I promise you.
When are you
gonna come down?
When are you going to land?
I should have stayed
on the farm
I should have listened
to my old man?
You know you can't hold me forever
I didn't sign up with you
I'm not a present
for your friends to open
This boy's too young to be singing...
...the blues...
Look!
Here you go.
Hey, hey, girlies!
We found some shroomies!
Don't get your hopes up too high, will you?
Dr. Richardson says that
Jan could get worse again.
I'm the one who saved his life.
I can save it again.
Bess, what are you talking about?
I told Jan stories...
Stories about love.
That was almost like
being together, him and me.
You see, love can save Jan.
He must not forget about love.
He told me that.
He tells me what to do.
Bess, I'm glad that you listened to Jan,
...but don't let him gain
too much power over you.
Sickness is a mighty power.
I've saved Jan.
Don't talk like that.
It's stupid!
You always said that I wasn't stupid.
Well, you're stupid if you
say things like that.
Why are you saying I'm stupid now?
Because I can see
that you're disappearing...
...into a world
of make-believe,
...and it worries me.
I used to go mad...
...when people called you stupid,
But... you are stupid!
We're going to put
a drain in this afternoon.
It'll be much easier
to get through to him.
Don't worry.
It's a very minor operation.
Are you trying to make me feel guilty?
What makes you say that?
I think she's trying
to make me feel guilty.
Come here.
You look fucking awful.
Why do you dress like that?
You dress like a widow.
I'm not even dead yet.
Maybe you wish I was.
No.
No, no.
You haven't done what I asked you to do.
I have!
I asked you to be with a man.
I have done that.
You call that being with a man?
I call it a joke.
I love you.
I don't love some other man.
Prove it.
Bess, what is going on?
Are you sleeping with other men
to feed his sick fantasies?
He did get better.
No, he did not get better!
That's just the way it goes, Bess.
Sometimes he's better;
Sometimes he's worse.
It has nothing to do with what you're doing.
That's all in your mind.
He is my husband, and god has
said that I must honour him.
Well, if that's what
honouring is all about...
...then I must have something wrong.
Well, you don't come from
around here, do you?
No, and I'm glad I don't.
With locals talking.
It makes me sick.
But you live here,
and you go to the church.
Yes, but it don't mean I don't
look at things me own way.
Why don't you move, then?
Your husband's dead.
You know very well why I don't move.
I don't move because of you.
A woman has to choose for herself, Bess.
She has to have a mind of her own.
Now, what you're doing is making
things worse. It's nonsense.
His head's full of scars.
He's up to his eyeballs in drugs.
He doesn't know what he's saying.
And he doesn't know.
I'm sorry.
Am I going to go to hell?
Whom do you want to save...
yourself or Jan?
Bess.
It's been a long time... most unlike you.
I must warn you that
the Lord looks with anger...
...upon those who fail him.
You've got to lend me something to wear.
A good shot.
All right.
Hello.
Good shot.
How much, darling?
1, 2, 3, up.
Ok.
Good.
Thank you.
I can't hear the blood pressure.
The blood pressure.
We have a fibrillation.
Clear.
Still no change.
Ok.
Clear.
Clear again, please.
Go on.
Clear, please.
Yes!
Oh, yes!
All right.
Good work.
It's ok?
Hi, Bess.
Bess...
Bess, I think it's time
we had a little chat.
I love you no matter what is in your head.
So you didn't have to give Jan...
...electric shock treatment
when his heart stopped...
...in the operation yesterday?
No, we didn't.
It was a perfectly simple operation.
As you know.
Well...
I shouldn't have to say that.
You know that very well.
I want a word with Bess on her own.
Thank you, Dorothy.
I'm not going to ask you
what you've been getting up to...
...because I don't want
to hear you lie to me,
...but as long as you are
living under my roof,
...you are to behave
like a decent human being.
I have never lied to you.
Do you understand me?
Yes, mother.
This is very painful for me.
Your grandfather can no longer
hold his hand over you with the elders.
I don't think you realize what that means.
Have you any idea
what it's like to be cast out?
You will have nothing, Bess.
I've known strong men and women...
...wither away after being cast out.
Now, you are not strong.
You're a feeble girl.
It would kill you, Bess.
I've said enough.
Bess.
Can you come down a minute, love?
Dr. Richardson is here.
Hi, Bess.
Hello.
How are you?
Can we sit down?
Bess...
I think... I think you've got yourself...
...involved in something...
...which is out of your control.
Have I?
Come on, Bess.
You're not a kid any more.
Look, for Christ's sake,
...he's forcing you to get screwed...
...by every Tom, Dick, and Harry.
It's just not you.
I don't make love with them.
I make love with Jan...
...and I save him from dying.
Well, I'm sorry, but you know,
To me, he seems more
like a dirty old man...
...who wants to play the peeping Tom.
Sometimes...
I don't even have to tell him about it.
Jan and me...
We have a spiritual contact.
God gives everyone something to be good at.
I've always been stupid...
But I'm good at this.
God gives everyone a talent.
And what's Jan's talent?
He is...
He's a great lover.
Well, what's... what's mine, then?
I don't know.
Haven't you found it yet?
I see.
And what's your talent, then, Bess?
Because...
Surely it can't be being screwed...
...by men you've never seen before.
I can believe.
Are you angry now?
Yes, I am!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm angry...
...because you can't see that
he's messing you about.
He's the one who's sick.
Look, what he's doing to you is sick,
and it's getting sicker and sicker.
He's becoming more
and more of a danger to you
the more the fluid rises in his...
...listen to me, for god's sake!
Do you always get so involved...
...in your patients' problems,
Dr. Richardson?
Listen to me, Bess.
I care for you.
I love you, Bess.
You're very special.
Will you move your hands, please?
Certainly.
Dodo.
Will you show Dr. Richardson out, please?
What's going to happen now, Bess?
Has he told you any more...
...of the thoughts he's had?
Any more services for you to perform?
Don't come here again.
He has, has he?
And what's it going to be this time?
What are you going to give him
to slobber over this time?
Dear father, what's going on?
Father, where are you?
That boy scared me.
Hello.
Can you take me out to the ships?
Can't take you out there.
The other girls wouldn't like it.
But they can't do all the ships.
They don't have time.
Maybe not.
What about the big one?
I don't go out to that one any more.
Girls won't go aboard.
Well, then you can take me.
No harm done.
How are you feeling, Jan?
Well, I've felt better.
Yeah.
Unfortunately, the periods...
...in which we can get through to you...
...have lately become very rare.
I'll have to send you back to Glasgow...
...for a while, I'm afraid.
I don't want any more...
...operations.
Of course, it's entirely up to you,
...but...
I have to say that your
condition's unlikely to improve...
...without surgery.
Well, if you've made
your mind up on that point,
Maybe it's time to consider other matters.
I mean, we should start thinking
about other people than just you.
Bess.
I'm glad you understand
what I'm driving at.
Your... your condition's been-
it's been very hard on her.
And I can't judge why,
but she's suffering...
...from delusions regarding your condition.
I have to be blunt.
I don't think that
seeing you is good for her.
I guess not.
I am convinced that the best thing
...we can do for her right now...
is to admit her again.
Get her away?
Yes.
As far away as possible.
Think that's necessary?
Listen, if you don't want surgery,
...the indications are that we
will enter a prolonged period...
...in which you will be more and
more affected by your condition.
The poorlier you are, the more
detrimental your influence on Bess.
I've drawn up some papers giving
me the authority to detain her...
...under the provisions
of the mental health act.
I'll need your consent.
You're going to section Bess?
It's the only way I can get her treated.
Tell me, Dr. Richardson, does...
...does this mean I will
never see her again?
To be realistic, yes.
It's just there at the bottom.
You said you wanted to help her.
Come on, Jan.
If you've been bad
Lord, I bet you have
And you've not been hit
You've not been hit
by flying lead
You'd better
close your eyes
bow your head
Wait for the ricochet...
How do I get back?
I'll keep an eye out for you.
Hello.
What do you want?
I want that you do it
with the sailor and I watch.
Ok.
It's all right.
It's ok.
All right.
Come here, you.
No!
There we go, eh?
Yeah.
That's better.
Come on down.
Yeah.
You like it like this, eh?
Oh, please.
Can I go home now?
No. No.
Please, I don't want...
Stay still.
No.
Please.
No. No. Please.
Stay still, I said.
No.
Bitch!
I'm going to shoot you.
You will?
You think so?
You don't even know how to use that thing.
Nobody will believe a hooker!
Because there is only one thing for us,
...sinners that we are,
...to achieve perfection
in the eyes of God...
...through unconditional love...
...for the word that is written,
...through unconditional love for the law.
I don't understand what you're saying.
How can you love a word?
Love words.
You cannot be in love with a word.
You can love another human being.
That's perfection.
No woman speaks here.
Bess McNeill, the kirk session...
...has decided this day that henceforth,
...you shall no longer
have access to this kirk.
They who know you shall not know you.
Please, let me stay!
Please!
Be gone, Bess McNeill,
from the house of God.
Hello, Bess.
You're... you're coming with us.
We're going to Glasgow.
Bess, they're going to take you...
...back into hospital
just for a little bit.
It's for your own good.
I want to see Jan.
I want to see my husband.
I know, but not now, Bess.
It's for your own good, Bess.
Mother can't have me admitted.
Not now that I'm married.
Bess, it wasn't mother
that signed the paper.
It was Jan.
You liar!
Come along, Bess.
Jan!
Dodo, how can you do this?
You had a husband, too, once.
Your love could have saved him,
if only you'd tried!
Jan!
Ok, Bess.
Let's go.
Oh, fuck!
Ryan, she's not here!
Hello.
Who's a tart?
What are you doing?
Tart!
I can't open the door.
Mother?
Please.
Please, mother, open the door!
Please, open the door!
Mother!
I'll be good.
I'll be really, really good.
I'll be really good.
Oh, please, open.
Please go away.
Stop it!
Go away.
You just go away and leave me!
Who's a tart?
Away with you.
Stop all this racket
outside the house of God.
Come on!
On you go.
What's happened?
Bess.
Bess!
Bess, are you all right, love?
Bess, it's Dodo.
Oh, Bessie.
Jan is dying.
I wasn't to tell you.
No.
It's good you told me.
I know you love me.
I have to go.
Is there anything I can do for you?
Anything at all?
Yes.
I'd like you to go to Jan...
...and pray for him to be cured...
...and to rise from his bed and walk.
Will you take me to the big ship?
Again?
Are you sure?
Father, why aren't you with me?
I am with you, Bess.
What do you want from me?
Where were you?
Don't you think I have other people...
...who want to talk to me?
Well, of course.
I hadn't thought of that.
There's this silly
little thing called Bess...
...who keeps on wanting me
to talk to her,
...so my work's been piling up a bit.
But you're with me now?
Of course I am, Bess.
You know that.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Do you need me?
No. That's all right.
Stay there.
Bess asked me to pray.
For what?
For Jan's life.
For a miracle.
Yeah.
That would be a miracle.
Dear God,
I pray that Jan gets better,
That he rises from his bed and walks.
Sister McNeill here.
We'll make you better.
Where's Jan?
I'd like to see him.
No.
Not now, love.
You're going to have an operation now.
I want to see him.
Not now, love.
You need an operation.
No.
I've got to see Jan.
Please, Dodo.
All right.
All right. Stop.
She wants to see Jan.
I'm going to take her to see Jan.
Come on.
Out of the way, for God's sake.
Help me.
Come on.
Move, for Christ's sake!
All right.
There you go.
There you are.
You can see him now, can't you?
How is he...
How's he doing?
Is he not any better?
No.
No, he's not.
I thought he might be better now.
Maybe I was wrong after all.
Ok, let's get inside.
Here.
Take those.
Tape.
Ok, take care. Let's go.
1, 2, 3.
There we go.
It's all right, love.
Now, Bess, do you know me?
Yeah.
Pulse 90.
What happened?
Do you know?
No.
Pressure on 100.
Get the blood pressure.
100.
It will be all right, love.
It will be all right.
Can I have a look at her back?
There we go.
Ok.
Hand me the scissors.
Yes.
All right.
Mother.
Oh, mother.
Here she is.
Bessie.
Bess.
I'm sorry that I could not be good, mother.
That's all right, Bessie.
Your grandfather's
sorry he couldn't come.
Will you tell him that I love him?
I am glad that you came, mother.
Blood pressure.
It will be all right.
It's going down.
2 units now.
2 units immediately.
2 units.
Ok, we're just going to lower you down
a little bit now, all right, Bess?
There we go.
That was easy, wasn't it?
Going to be all right.
Dodo, hold me.
Here I am.
I'm holding.
It's all right, love.
I'm here. I'm here.
I'm afraid.
I know.
Jan?
Jan!
Now...
I'm frightened.
It's...
It's all wrong.
No pulse.
Bess?
Stand clear.
Stand clear!
Clear.
What?
It's going to be all right.
That's a good girl.
Come on.
Ok.
You can stop now.
What? What?
What do you mean?
She's gone, Dodo.
She's gone.
No.
Bess.
Bess, listen to me.
I'm sorry.
Dodo.
No!
Come on, Dodo.
Let's go!
Come on.
I'm sorry!
It's a god-awful small affair
To the girl with the mousy hair
But her mummy is yelling "No"
And her daddy has told her to go
But her friend is nowhere to be seen
Now she walks through her sunken dream
To the seat with the clearest view
And she's hooked to the silver screen
But the film is a saddening bore
'Cause she's lived it ten times or more
She could spit in the eyes of fools
As they ask her to focus on
Sailors fighting in the dance hall
Oh man!
Look at those cavemen go
It's the freakiest show
Take a look at the Lawman
Beating up the wrong guy
Oh man!
Wonder if he'll ever know
He's in the best selling show
Is there life on Mars?
You describe the deceased as
"an immature, unstable person,
...a person who, due to the
trauma of her husband's illness,
...gave way in obsessive fashion...
...to an exaggerated,
perverse form of sexuality."
Would you like to clarify
that to the inquiry?
That's what I wrote.
Yes.
That's what it says.
Can I have a glass of water, please?
Get Dr. Richardson a glass of water.
Thank you.
Listen, man, you had
the deceased in your care.
The court would like
to hear the medical facts.
If you'd... if you were to ask me again...
...to write... the conclusion, then...
...instead of writing "neurotic"...
...or, "psychotic," then I might...
...just, use a word like...
"Good."
Good?
Yes.
You wish the records of this court...
...to state that in your medical opinion,
...the deceased was suffering
from being "good"?
Perhaps this was
the psychological defect...
...that led to her death.
Is that what we shall write,
Dr. Richardson?
No.
Of course not.
Very well, then.
Perhaps we should stick to your
original statement then, doctor.
Yes.
I think that everything there is to say...
...about Bess McNeill
has been said already.
We have agreed to sanction her burial,
...but there can be no funeral service.
The fact that some of us
knew the deceased girl well...
...cannot be allowed to
influence the form of her burial.
Bess McNeill's funeral must be the same...
...as anyone else of her kind.
The body will be released by
the authorities sometime this week.
I've obtained permission from
the elders to bury Bess...
but... I cannot deviate from the principles
that apply to funerals here.
I must say about Bess what must be said.
Ok.
Come on.
Where's Jan?
Has he gone down there yet?
I don't know.
Have you seen Jan?
Bess McNeill, you are a sinner,
...and for your sins,
you are consigned to hell.
Not one of you has the right...
...to consign Bess to hell.
Terry, it's time.
Let's do it.
Get up, for Christ's sake.
Come on, man.
Come on.
Take good care of her.
Come on, Jan.
You got to let her go.
Bess!
Jan.
Jan, hey.
What?
What's the matter?
Come on.
I want to show you something.
You're not going to believe it.
What?
Come on.
Please.
Here.
Let's go.
Pim!
Pim, come on!
You're not going to believe it.
Hey, Pim, Come on.
Check this out.
Check this thing out, man.
You see anything?
There's nothing out there.
I've tried all the fucking ranges,
...and there's nothing there.
I just wanted to be sure.
Come on.