Oh...
Oh-ho.
Whoo.
Oh!
All right, Curly,
enough's enough.
You can't eat
the venetian blinds.
I just had them
installed on Wednesday.
Whoo.
Down the hatch.
Oh.
She's no good.
What can I say?
You're right.
When you're right,
you're right,
and you're right.
I'll pay you
the rest next week.
We only caught
60 ton of skipjack.
They don't pay
for skipjack
as they do albacore.
Forget it, Curly.
I was only
illustrating a point.
I don't want
your last dime.
Who do you think I am?
Thank you, Mr. Gittes.
Call me Jake.
Careful driving home,
Curl, huh?
A Mrs. Mulwray's
waiting for you
with Mr. Walsh
and Mr. Duffy.
[Door Opens]
Mrs. Mulwray,
may I present Mr. Gittes.
how do you do?
Mr. Gittes.
Now, uh, what seems
to be the problem?
My husband,
I believe, is seeing
another woman.
No. Really?
I'm afraid so.
I am sorry.
Mr. Gittes, please,
could we
discuss this alone?
I'm afraid not,
Mrs. Mulwray.
These are my operatives.
At some point,
they'll have to assist me.
I can't do
everything myself.
Of course not.
Now...
what makes you certain
that your husband is, uh...
involved with someone?
A wife can tell.
Mrs. Mulwray,
do you love your husband?
Yes, of course.
Then go home
and forget everything.
I'm sure he loves you, too,
Mrs. Mulwray.
Do you know the expression
"Let sleeping dogs lie"?
You're... you're
better off not knowing.
I have to know.
Very well.
What is your husband's
first name?
Hollis.
Hollis Mulwray.
Water and Power?
He's chief engineer.
Chief engineer?
Mrs. Mulwray, this...
this type of investigation
can be hard
on your pocketbook.
It takes time...
Money doesn't matter
to me, Mr. Gittes.
O.K., we'll, uh...
we'll see what we can do.
Gentlemen, today you
can walk out that door,
hop a streetcar,
and within 25 minutes
end up
in the Pacific Ocean.
You can swim
and fish in it,
but you can't drink it,
and you can't irrigate
an orange grove with it.
Now remember, we live
next door to the ocean,
but we also
live next to a desert.
Los Angeles
is a desert community.
Beneath this building,
beneath our streets
is a desert.
Without water, the dust
will rise and cover us
as though
we never existed.
Now, the Alto Vallejo
can save us from this,
and I respectfully suggest
that $8.5 million
is a fair price to pay
to keep the desert
from our streets
and not on top of them.
[Applause]
Mayor Bagby, let's hear from
all the departments again.
I suppose we'd better take
Water and Power first.
Mr. Mulwray?
In case you've forgotten,
gentlemen,
over 500 lives were lost
when the Van der Lip Dam
gave way.
Core samples have shown
that beneath this bedrock
is shale similar
to the permeable shale
in the Van der Lip
disaster.
It couldn't withstand
that kind of pressure.
Now you propose yet another
dirt-banked terminus dam
with slopes of 21/2 to 1,
112 feet high,
and a 12,000-acre
water surface.
Well, it won't hold.
I won't build it.
It's that simple.
I'm not going to make
the same mistake twice.
- Boo!
[Bleating]
Quiet! Quiet!
What the hell are you doing?
Get those goddamn things
out of here!
Where should I take them?
You don't have an answer
for that so quick, do you?
You steal water
from the valley,
ruin the grazing,
starve the livestock.
Who's paying you
to do that, Mr. Mulwray?
That's what
I want to know!
[Water Trickling]
[Music] I've flown
around the world [music]
[Music] In a plane [music]
[Music] I've settled
revolutions in Spain [music]
[Music] And the North Pole
I have charted [music]
[Music] Still I can't
get started [music]
[Music] With you [music]
[Music] On the golf course [music]
[Music] I'm under par [music]
[Music] Metro-Goldwyn [music]
[Music] Have asked me
to star... [music][music]
Jeez, he was there
all night.
That's right.
I had to go back
three times
to pick up
the watches.
Yesterday he went
to three reservoirs,
a men's room at
a Richfield gas station,
and the Pig 'n Whistle.
The guy's got water
on the brain.
So what do you got?
This?
They argued outside
the Pig 'n Whistle.
What about?
I don't know.
The traffic was loud.
I heard only
one thing, though...
uh, "apple core".
"Apple core"?
Yeah.
Walsh, is that what you spent
your day doing?
You tell me to take pictures,
I take pictures.
Let me explain
something to you, Walsh.
J.J. Gittes
and Associates.
This business requires
a certain amount
of finesse.
[Buzz]
What is it, Sophie?
Duffy's on the phone.
Duff, where are you?
I got it! He's found himself
some cute twist.
Slow down.
Where are you?
I'm at Glendale
and Douglas.
They're in Echo Park
in a rowboat. A rowboat!
O.K.
Echo Park.
Water again.
O.K., pal,
let's have us
a big smile.
You'll love it.
No mires para atras.
Cubrete los ojos.
Te gusta?
Estas bonita.
Oh, here. Let me...
[Crash]
When you get
so much publicity,
you got to get
blasé about it.
Let's face it, Jake,
you're practically
a movie star.
[Horn Honks]
Look at that, Barn.
Yeah, the heat's murder.
Sure is.
Fools' names
and fools' faces.
What's that, pal?
Nothing. You got
a hell of a way
to make a living.
Oh? What do you do
to make ends meet?
Mortgage department,
First National Bank.
Tell me,
did you foreclose
on many families
this week?
We don't publish
a record in the paper.
Neither do I.
No, your
press agent does it.
Who is this bimbo,
Barney?
Is he a regular
customer or what?
I make
an honest living.
People come to me when
they're desperate.
I don't kick families
out of their houses
like you bums
at the bank do.
Maybe you'd like
to go outside and discuss it.
What do you think?
I don't know how it got
in the newspaper.
It was so quick,
I didn't know it myself.
Make an honest
living.
Of course you do.
Anyway, this guy got tired
of screwing his wife...
An honest living,
understand?
Do what the Chinese do.
He says, "What's that?"
The Chinese
screw a little...
Duffy. Hey, Walsh!
Sophie, go to
the little girl's room, O.K.?
But, Mr. Gittes...
Sophie...
Yes, Mr. Gittes.
I want to tell you
a story.
There's this guy,
Walsh, understand?
He's tired of
screwing his wife.
Jake...
You're always
in such a hurry.
So his friend says,
"Do it like
the Chinese do."
How do the Chinese
do it?
The guy says,
"First they screw a little,
"then they stop
and read a little Confucius.
Then they screw a little more,
then stop again..."
Jake.
Walsh, just listen
to me for a second.
I mean,
you'll love this.
"Then they screw
a little more,
then they contemplate
the moon or something..."
Makes it more exciting.
Now the guy goes home
and starts screwing
his own wife.
He screws a little,
then stops.
He goes and reads
Life magazine,
then he returns
and starts screwing again.
He says, "Excuse me, honey,"
and smokes a cigarette.
Now his wife
is getting sore.
He comes back,
starts screwing again,
gets up to leave again.
She says,
"What's the matter?
You're screwing
just like a Chinaman!"
Jesus!
That Barney!
Mr. Gittes.
Yes.
Do you know me?
Well, uh...
I think
I would have remembered.
Have we ever met?
Well, no.
Never?
Never.
That's what I thought.
You see,
I'm Mrs. Evelyn Mulwray,
Mr. Mulwray's wife.
Not, uh...
that Mulwray?
Yes, Mr. Gittes,
that Mulwray.
And since
you agree with me
that we've
never met before,
you must also agree
that I've
never hired you,
certainly not to spy
on my husband.
I see you like
publicity, Mr. Gittes.
Well, you're
going to get it.
Wait a minute,
Mrs. Mulwray.
There's been some
misunderstanding here.
There's no point
in getting tough...
I don't get tough
with anyone, Mr. Gittes.
My lawyer does.
Uh, here's something
for you, Mr. Gittes.
Uh...
I suppose we'll be hearing
from your attorney.
Mr. Mulwray.
He's not in, Mr...
Gittes.
What is this
regarding?
It's
a personal matter.
Has he
been gone long?
Since lunch.
Gee whiz,
and I'm late.
He was expecting you?
15 minutes ago.
I'll just go in and wait.
Sir?
Is Mr. Yelburton
there?
He's still
in the building?
Very well.
Thank you.
Can I help you?
Russ Yelburton,
deputy chief of the department.
J.J. Gittes.
It's not a departmental matter,
Mr. Yelburton.
Would you care to wait
in my office?
Certainly.
We're nervous
around here
with all this business
in the papers
about Mr. Mulwray.
Uh, right this way.
After you've worked
with a man
for a certain
length of time,
you come to know
his habits, his values.
You come to know him.
Either he's the kind
who chases women or he isn't.
And Mulwray isn't?
He never even kids
about it.
Well, maybe he takes it
very seriously.
Uh, sit down.
Uh, no, thank you.
Do you know where
Mulwray's having lunch?
No, I'm sorry,
I don't.
Well, uh, tell him
I'll be back.
I will.
Do you mind
if I take your card?
In case
I need you again.
No, help yourself.
Mulvihill,
what are you doing here?
They shut my water off.
How'd you find out
about it?
You don't drink it.
You don't
take a bath in it.
They wrote you
a letter.
But then you'd have to
be able to read.
Relax, Mulvihill.
Glad to see you.
You know Claude
Mulvihill here?
I hope so.
He's working for us.
Doing what?
There have been
some threats
to blow up
the city reservoirs.
Any particular
reason?
It's this drought.
We rationed water in the valley.
The farmers
are desperate,
but the city
needs drinking water.
Well, you're in luck,
Mr. Yelburton.
How's that?
When Mulvihill
was sheriff of Ventura County,
the rum runners
landed tons of booze on the beach
and never lost
a drop.
He ought to hold on
to your water
for you.
[Ring]
J.J. Gittes
to see Mr. Mulwray.
Please.
You wait.
Oh.
Heh.
Bad for glass.
Yeah, sure.
Bad for the glass.
Mr. Gittes.
Actually, I came
to see your husband, Mrs. Mulwray.
Would you like
something to drink?
What are you having?
Iced tea.
That'll be fine,
thank you.
Two iced teas,
Khan, please?
Yes, ma'am.
My husband's
at the office.
Actually, he's not,
Mrs. Mulwray,
and he's checked out
of his apartment
at the El Macondo.
That's not
his apartment.
Anyway, I, uh...
The point is,
I'm not in business to be loved,
but I am in business.
Whoever set your husband up
set me up.
L.A.'s a small town.
People talk.
I don't want to become
a local joke.
Mr. Gittes, you've
talked me into it.
I'll drop the lawsuit.
What?
Let's drop
the whole thing.
Sugar, lemon, or both?
Both. Mrs. Mulwray,
I don't want to drop it.
I better talk
to your husband about this.
Why? What on earth for?
Hollis seems to think
you're an innocent man.
I've been accused
of a lot of things before,
Mrs. Mulwray,
but never that.
Look, somebody's gone
to a lot of trouble here,
and I intend to find out.
I'm not supposed to be caught
with my pants down.
Unless it's a problem,
I'll talk to your husband.
Why should it
be a problem?
May I speak frankly?
You may if you can,
Mr. Gittes.
Well, that little
girlfriend was pretty
in a cheap
sort of a way, of course.
She's disappeared.
Maybe they disappeared
together.
Suppose they did.
How does that
affect you?
It's nothing personal,
Mrs. Mulwray.
It's very personal.
It couldn't
be more personal.
Is this a business or
an obsession with you?
Let's look at it this way.
Now, this phony broad...
excuse the language...
she tells me she's you.
She hires me.
Whoever's behind it
has nothing against me.
They're after
your husband.
If I can see him,
I can help him.
Did you talk to him
this morning?
No, uh...
I went riding
rather early.
Looks like you went
quite a distance.
I was riding bareback.
You, um...
you might try
the Oak Pass
or the Stone Canyon
Reservoir.
Frequently Hollis
walks around them.
Otherwise, he'll
be home by 6:30.
I'll stop by.
Please call first.
Sorry, closed
to the public, sir.
Oh, uh, that's
all right, officer.
Russ Yelburton,
deputy chief
of the department.
Sorry, Mr. Yelburton.
Go on down.
That's O.K.
Gittes!
For Christ's sake.
Loach.
Get out before
he sees you.
What's going on here?
Loach!
Hello, Jake.
Lou. How are you?
Lousy cold
I can't seem to shake,
but otherwise,
uh, I'm O.K.
Yeah, summer colds
are the worst.
Yeah, they are.
There's no smoking...
That's all right, officer.
We'll make an exception.
I'll see he's careful
and doesn't burn himself.
Thanks, Lou.
How'd you get
past the guard?
To tell you the truth,
I lied a little.
You look like you've
done well by yourself.
I get by.
Sometimes
it takes a while
for a man
to find himself.
Maybe you have.
Yeah, going through
other people's dirty linen.
Yeah. Tell me,
you still putting
Chinamen in jail
for spitting
in the laundry?
You're a little
behind the times, Jake.
They use steam irons now,
and I'm out of Chinatown.
Since when?
Since I made lieutenant.
Congratulations.
Mmm. What are you
doing around here?
I'm looking
for somebody.
Who?
Hollis Mulwray.
You seen him?
Yeah.
I'd like
to talk to him.
You'd like
You're welcome to try.
There he is.
Looks like
he was washed down
the entire length
of the runoff channel.
Could he swim?
Of course.
Obviously the fall
must have knocked him unconscious.
Mrs. Mulwray,
this alleged affair your
husband was having...
the publicity...
didn't make him
morose or unhappy?
It didn't
make him happy.
There is no possibility
that he would have
taken his own life?
No.
Mrs. Mulwray...
Do you happen
to know the name
of the young lady
in question?
No.
Or where
she might be?
Certainly not.
You and your husband
never discussed her?
He...
We... we did.
He... he wouldn't
tell me her name.
We quarreled over her,
of course.
It came as a complete
surprise to me.
A complete surprise?
I thought you hired
a private investigator.
A... private investigator?
Mr. Gittes.
Oh...
Well, yes,
but I did that
because I thought
I would put an end
to a ridiculous rumor
that had no basis.
Uh-huh.
When did Mr. Gittes
inform you
that these rumors had
some foundation in fact?
Just before the story
broke in the papers, Lou.
You wouldn't
happen to know
where I could
find her?
No.
Or her name?
Of course not.
Will you need me
for anything else, lieutenant?
Oh, no,
Mrs. Mulwray.
If we need any
more information,
we'll be in touch.
Of course you have
my deepest sympathy.
I'll see her
to the car, Lou.
I'll be right back.
Jake, come on,
what's the story?
Take it easy, guys.
Let us get through.
We better do this
in a hurry.
Guys, give us
a little room.
You want a picture, guys?
Here it is.
- What?
- Hey!
Gittes.
Two Ts and an "E."
Thank you for...
going along
with me back there.
I just didn't want
to explain anything.
I'll send you
a check.
A check?
To make it official
that I've hired you.
[Coughing]
I'll get to it
this afternoon if I can.
Jake, what are you
doing here?
Nothing, Morty.
It's my lunch hour.
Thought I'd drop by
and see who
dropped dead lately.
Isn't this something?
Middle of a drought,
and the water
commissioner drowns.
Only in L.A.
Yeah. Looks
pretty banged up.
Well, that's
a long fall.
[Coughs]
So how are you
doing, Morty?
[Coughs]
Never better, except for
this darn cough.
You know me,
Jake.
Yeah.
[Announcer Calling
Horse Race On Radio]
Who you got there?
Leroy Shuhardt,
local drunk.
Used to hang around
Ferguson's Alley.
Quite a character.
Lately
he'd been living
in one of the downtown
storm drains.
Had a bureau dresser
down there and everything.
Yeah. He drowned, too.
Come again?
Yeah. Got drunk,
passed out
in the bottom of the riverbed.
The L.A. River?
Yeah. Right under
Hollenbeck Bridge.
What's wrong
with that?
Why, it's dry
as a bone, Morty.
It's not
completely dry.
Well, he ain't going to exactly
drown in a damp riverbed
no matter
how soused he is.
We got water
out of him.
He drowned.
Hello.
Howdy.
You were riding out here
the other day,
weren't you?
Speak English?
¿Habla ingles?
Si.
Uh, you were talking to a man
a few days ago.
He wore glasses?
Yes.
Uh, what did you
talk about,
do you mind
my asking?
The water.
What about
the water?
When it comes.
When it comes?
What did you
tell him?
It comes in different
parts of the river,
every night
a different part.
[Gunshots]
Son of a bitch!
Goddamn Florsheim shoe.
Hold it there,
kitty cat.
Hold it.
Hello, Claude.
Where'd you get the midget?
You're a very nosy fellow,
kitty cat, huh?
You know what happens
to nosy fellows?
Huh? No?
Want to guess?
O.K. They lose
their noses.
Uh!
Next time you lose
the whole thing.
Cut it off and feed it
to my goldfish.
Understand?
Understand, Gittes?
I understand.
All right.
So some contractor
wants to build a dam,
and he makes
a few payoffs.
So what? Think you
can nail Mulvihill?
He'll claim
you were trespassing.
Don't want Mulvihill.
I want the big boys that
are making the payoffs.
Then what?
Sue the shit
out of them.
Yeah?
Yeah.
[Intercom Buzzes]
What is it, Sophie?
A Miss Sessions
is calling.
Who?
Ida Sessions.
Don't know her.
Take a number.
Sue people like that,
they're liable
to be having dinner
with the judge
who's trying the suit.
[Intercom Buzzes]
I'm sorry.
Miss Sessions insists.
She says
you know her.
O.K.
Hello, Miss Sessions.
I don't believe
we've had the pleasure.
Oh, yes, we have.
Are you alone?
Isn't everyone?
Uh, what can I
do for you?
Well, I'm
a working girl.
I didn't come in
to see you on my own.
When did you come in?
I pretended to be
Mrs. Mulwray. Remember?
Shut the fuck up.
Beg your pardon?
Uh, yes, I remember.
Is something wrong?
No. I was just checking
some details
with my two associates.
Uh, go on.
I never expected
anything to happen
like what happened
to Mr. Mulwray.
If it ever comes out,
I want somebody to know
that I didn't know
what would happen.
I understand.
Who was your employer?
That could be helpful
to both of us.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
No.
Uh, what's your address?
Maybe we could
talk this over.
No, Mr. Gittes.
Just look in
the obituary column
of today's
L.A. Post-Record.
Obituary column?
You'll find one
of those people.
[Click]
Miss...
Sure.
How do you like
them apples?
Madam.
Thank you for coming.
Yes, sir?
Drink?
Tom Collins with lime,
not lemon, please.
Tom Collins
with lime.
I got your check
in the mail.
Yes. As I said,
I was very grateful.
Uh, Mrs. Mulwray,
I'm afraid that's not good enough.
How much
would you like?
Oh, stop it.
The money's fine.
It's generous,
but, uh...
I think you shortchanged me
on the story.
I have?
I think so.
Something besides the death
of your husband was bothering you.
You were upset,
but not that upset.
Mr. Gittes, don't
tell me how I feel.
Sorry.
Look, you sue me,
your husband dies,
you drop the lawsuit
like a hot potato...
All of it quicker
than the wind from a duck's ass.
Excuse me.
Then you ask me
to lie to the police.
It wasn't much
of a lie.
If your husband
was killed, it was.
This could look
like you paid me off
to withhold evidence.
But he wasn't
killed.
Mrs. Mulwray, I think
you're hiding something.
Well...
I suppose I am.
Actually, I knew
about the affair.
How did you find out?
My husband.
He told you?
And you weren't
the least bit upset?
I was grateful.
Mrs. Mulwray, you'll
have to explain that.
Why?
Look, I do
matrimonial work.
It's my metier.
When a wife says
she's happy
that her husband's
cheating on her,
it runs contrary
to my experience.
Unless what?
She was
cheating on him.
Were you?
I dislike
the word "cheat."
Did you
have affairs?
Mr. Gittes...
Did he know
about it?
I wouldn't tell him
every time I went
to bed with someone,
if that's
what you mean.
Anything else you want
to know about me?
Where were you
when your husband died?
I can't tell you.
You mean
you don't know?
I mean
I can't tell you.
You were seeing
someone, too.
For very long?
I don't see anyone for
very long, Mr. Gittes.
It's difficult for me.
Now, I think you know
all you need know
about me.
I didn't want publicity.
I didn't want to go
into any of this
then or now.
Is that all?
Oh, by the way,
what does this "C"
stand for?
Cu...
Uh, Cross.
That's your
maiden name?
Yes.
Why?
No reason.
You must've had
a reason to ask.
No. I'm just a snoop.
Oh, no. I have
my own car.
The Packard.
Wait a minute,
sonny.
I think you better
come with me.
But why?
There's nothing
more to say.
Will you get
my car, please?
O.K., go home.
But in case
you're interested,
your husband
was murdered.
Somebody's been dumping
thousands of tons of water
from the city's
reservoirs,
and we're supposed
to be in the middle of a drought.
He found out
and was killed.
A waterlogged drunk's
in the morgue...
Involuntary
manslaughter
if anybody wants
to take the trouble,
which they don't.
Half the city
is trying to cover it all up,
which is fine by me.
But, Mrs. Mulwray,
I goddamn near
lost my nose,
and I like it.
I like breathing
through it.
And I still think
that you're hiding something.
Mr. Gittes!
J.J. Gittes
to see Mr. Yelburton.
Mr. Yelburton will
be busy for some time.
Well, it's
my lunch hour.
I can wait.
He's liable to be
tied up indefinitely.
I take a long
lunch hour.
All day sometimes.
[Humming]
[Whistling]
Noah Cross worked
for the water department.
Yes... no.
Well, did he
or didn't he?
He owned it.
He owned
the water department?
Yes.
You mean, he owned
the entire water supply
for the city?
Yes.
How did they
get it away from him?
Mr. Mulwray felt
the public should own the water.
Mr. Mulwray?
I thought you said
Cross owned it.
Along with
Mr. Mulwray.
They were partners?
Yes. Yes,
they were partners.
[Humming]
[Scratching]
Mr. Yelburton
will see you now.
Mr. Gittes, sorry
to keep you waiting.
These staff meetings,
they just go on and on.
Yeah. Must be
especially tough
to take over
under these circumstances.
Oh, yes. Hollis was
the best department chief
the city's ever had.
My goodness,
what happened to your nose?
Cut myself shaving.
You ought
to be more careful.
That must
really smart.
Only when I breathe.
Only when you breathe.
Uh, don't tell me
you're still working for Mrs. Mulwray.
I never was.
I don't understand.
Neither do I,
actually.
You hired me,
or you hired
that chippy to hire me.
Mr. Gittes, you're not
making a bit of sense.
Well, let's
look at it this way...
Mulwray didn't want
to build a dam.
He had a reputation
that was hard
to get around.
You decided
to ruin it.
Then he found out
you were dumping water
at night.
Then he was, uh...
drowned.
Mr. Gittes, that's
an outrageous accusation.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Well, Whitey Mehrholtz
over at the Times will.
Dumping thousands
of gallons of water
down the toilet
during a drought...
That's, uh, news.
Mr. Gittes, uh...
we're...
we're not anxious
for this to get around,
but we have been
diverting a little water
to irrigate orange groves
in the northwest valley.
The farmers there
have no legal right to our water.
We've been helping
some of them out.
Naturally,
when you divert water,
there's
a little runoff.
Yeah.
A little runoff.
Where'd you say
those groves were?
In the northwest
valley.
That's like saying
they're in Arizona.
Mr. Gittes,
my field men are out.
I can't give you
the exact location.
You're a married man,
aren't you?
Yes.
Hard-working?
Wife? Kids?
Yes.
I don't want
to nail you.
I want to find out
who put you up to it.
I'll give you a few days
to think about it.
Call me. I can help.
Who knows?
Maybe we can put
the whole thing off
on a few big shots,
and you can stay
head of the department
for the next 20 years.
[Door Closes]
Drink?
No, thank you.
What is
your usual salary?
$35 a day,
plus 20
to my associates,
plus expenses,
plus a bonus
if I show results.
Whoever is behind
my husband's death,
why have they gone
to all of this trouble?
Money.
How they
planned to make it
out of
emptying reservoirs,
that I don't know.
I'll pay your salary
plus $5,000
if you find out
what happened to Hollis
and who is involved.
Sophie, draw up one of
our standard contracts for Mrs. Mulwray.
Yes, Mr. Gittes.
Tell me something, uh...
did you get married
before or after
Mulwray and your father
sold the water department?
Noah Cross is
your father, isn't he?
Yes, of course.
It was sometime after.
I was just out of grade school
when they did that.
Then you married
your father's business partner?
You've already got
one going, Mrs. Mulwray.
Oh.
Does, uh...
my talking about
your father upset you?
Why, no.
Yes. A little.
You see,
Hollis and my f-f...
my father had
a falling-out finally.
Over you or over
the water department?
Why should it
be over me?
Then it was over
the water department.
Yes. Hollis felt
that the water should
belong to the public,
and I don't think
my father felt that way.
Actually, it was over
the Van der Lip Dam.
You know,
the dam that broke.
Oh, yeah?
Yes. Hollis never
forgave him for it.
Never forgave him
for what?
For talking him
into building it.
They never spoke
from that time on.
You sure about that?
Of course
I'm sure.
Sign here.
The copy's
for you.
Mr. Gitts?
Gittes.
Oh.
How do you do?
You've got a nasty
reputation, Mr. Gitts.
I like that.
Thanks.
If you were
a bank president,
that would
be one thing,
but in your business,
it's admirable,
and it's
good advertising.
It doesn't hurt.
It's why you attracted
a client like my daughter.
Probably.
But I'm surprised you're
still working for her,
unless she's come up
with another husband.
No. She thinks the
last one was murdered.
Uh... how'd
she get that idea?
I think
I gave it to her.
I believe they
should be served with the head.
Fine. Long as you
don't serve chicken that way.
Ha ha ha ha.
Tell me,
what do
the police say?
They're calling it
an accident.
Who's the investigating
officer?
Lou Escobar.
He's a lieutenant.
Do you know him?
Oh, yeah.
Where from?
We used
to work together.
In Chinatown.
Would you call him
a capable man?
Very.
Honest?
As far as it goes.
He has to swim
in the same water we all do.
But you've no reason to think
he's bungled the case?
None.
That's too bad.
Too bad?
It disturbs me.
Makes me think you're taking
my daughter for a ride.
Financially speaking,
of course.
What are you
charging her?
My usual fee,
plus a bonus
if I get results.
Are you, uh,
sleeping with her?
You don't have to think about that
to remember, do you?
If you want an answer
to that question, Mr. Cross,
I'll put one
of my men on the job.
Good afternoon.
Mr. Gitts...
Gittes.
Gittes. You're dealing
with a disturbed woman
who just lost her husband.
I don't want her
taken advantage of.
Sit down.
What for?
You may think you know
what you're dealing with,
but believe me,
you don't.
Why is that funny?
It's what
the district attorney
used to tell me
in Chinatown.
Yeah? Was he right?
Exactly what
do you know about me?
Sit down.
Mainly
that you're rich
and too respectable
to want your name in the newspapers.
Of course
I'm respectable.
I'm old.
Politicians, ugly
buildings, and whores
all get respectable
if they last long enough.
I'll double
whatever your fee is
and pay you $10,000
if you find
Hollis' girlfriend.
Girlfriend?
Disappeared,
hasn't she?
Yeah.
Wouldn't it be useful
to talk to her?
Maybe.
If Mulwray was murdered,
she'd be one of the last
to have seen him alive.
When's the last time
you saw Mulwray?
Sheriff's gold posse.
Bunch of damn fools.
They paid $5,000 apiece towards
the sheriff's re-election.
I let them practice up
out here.
Yeah.
Do you remember the last
time you saw Mulwray?
At my age,
you tend to forget.
Five days ago outside
the Pig 'n Whistle,
and you had one hell
of an argument.
I got the pictures
in my office
if that'll
help you remember.
What was
the argument about?
My daughter.
What about her?
Just find the girl,
Mr. Gitts.
I happen to know
Hollis was... fond of her.
I'd like
to help her if I can.
I had no idea
you and Hollis
were that fond of one another.
Hollis Mulwray
made this city,
and he made me
a fortune.
We were a lot closer
than Evelyn realized.
If you
want to hire me,
I still have to know
what the argument
was about.
My daughter's
a very jealous woman.
I didn't want her
to find out about the girl.
How did you
find out?
I still got a few teeth
left in my head
and a few friends
in town.
O.K.
I'll, uh...
I'll have my secretary
draw up the papers.
Tell me, uh...
are you frightened
for the girl
or what Evelyn
might do to her?
Just find the girl.
I'll look into it
as soon as I've checked out
some orange groves.
Orange groves?
We'll be in touch,
Mr. Cross.
I'm a little lost.
Could you tell me
where the plat books for
the northwest valley are?
Part of it's
in Ventura County.
We don't have
Ventura County
in our
Hall of Records.
I'll settle
for Los Angeles County.
Row 23, Section "C."
Weasel.
Say, uh... sonny,
uh...
why do they have
all those names
pasted in
the plat books?
Land sales
out of escrow
are recorded
within the week.
Then these
are all new owners?
That's right.
Well, that means
most of the valley's sold
in the last few months.
If that's
what it says.
Can I check one
of these volumes out?
Sir, this is not
a lending library.
It's
the Hall of Records.
Oh. How about
a ruler?
A ruler?
Yeah.
The print's real fine.
I left my glasses home.
I'd like to be able
to read across.
Why, thank you.
[Coughs]
[Gunshot]
Hold it right there!
All right.
Quit it now!
Search the man.
See if he's armed.
I said see if he's armed,
not empty his pockets!
Search him.
He ain't armed.
Who you with,
the water department
or the real estate office?
Get away from me!
Come near me
with that again,
you'll need
a pair of them.
Pick on somebody
your own size.
Cut that out! Give the man
a chance to say something!
The name's Gittes.
I'm a private
investigator.
I'm not with
either one of them.
What you doing
out here, mister?
A client hired me to see
if the water department
was irrigating your land.
Irrigating my land?
The water department's
sending you people
to blow up
my water tanks.
They put poison
down three of my wells.
Who'd hire you
for a thing like that?
Mrs. Evelyn Mulwray.
Mulwray's the one
who's done it to us.
Mulwray's dead.
You don't know what
you're talking about,
you dumb Okie.
Well, uh, that's that.
What's going on?
You didn't look too good,
so we thought we better
call your employer.
Thanks for coming.
That dam's a con job.
What dam?
The one
your husband opposed.
They're conning L.A.
Into building it,
but the water's
not going to L.A.
It's coming right here.
To the valley?
Everything you see.
Everything around us.
I was at the Hall
of Records today.
In the last three months,
Robert Knox
has bought 7,000 acres,
Emma Dill, 12,000,
Clarence Speer, 5,000,
and Jasper Lamar Crabb,
25,000 acres.
Jasper Lamar Crabb?
You know him?
I think I would've
remembered.
Yeah. They're blowing
these farmers out of their land,
then picking it up
for peanuts.
You have any idea
what this land would be worth
with a steady
water supply?
About 30 million more
than they paid for it.
Hollis knew
about this?
That's why he was killed.
Jasper Lamar Crabb.
We got it.
What?
What is it?
"A memorial service
was held today
"for Jasper Lamar Crabb.
He passed away
two weeks ago."
Well,
is that unusual?
He passed away
two weeks ago,
and one week ago
he bought the land.
That's unusual.
Hello.
I'm Mr. Palmer.
Can I
help you folks?
Yes, uh, I hope so.
It's Dad, uh...
I can't seem
to handle him anymore.
My goodness.
It's nothing with Dad.
It's, uh, it's me.
Dad is
an absolute angel.
It's just that
he and my hu...
Oh, I don't know.
I'm anxious for him
to have the best.
Money is no object.
Perhaps if we met
with your father...
Uh... there
is one question.
Of course.
Do you accept people
of the Jewish persuasion?
I'm sorry,
but, uh, we don't.
Don't be sorry.
Neither does Dad.
We wanted to be sure,
didn't we, hon?
Would it be possible for me
to see a list of your patients?
We never reveal
the names of our guests.
You would
appreciate that
if your father
came to live with us.
That's exactly what
I wanted to hear you say.
Good.
Is it too late
for us to look around?
No. Allow me
to show you.
May we take a stroll
on our own?
If you'll confine yourself
to the main building.
It's almost bedtime.
We understand.
Come, my sweet.
Charley, you ought
to know better than that.
Sit down. Have a chair.
They're all there.
Every goddamn name.
You're looking
at the owners
of a 50,000-acre
empire.
They can't be.
They may
not know it,
but they are.
Hello, girls.
- Hello.
Are any of you
Emma Dill?
Yes?
Are you Emma?
Yes.
I've wanted to meet you
for a long time.
Why?
Did you know you
were a wealthy woman?
Oh, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
You own
a lot of land.
No more.
Some time ago,
my late husband owned a good deal
of beach property
at Long Beach,
but we lost it.
That's very beautiful.
Thanks.
Where did you get
this piece of material?
At the Albacore Club.
Abbacore?
Uh, no.
The Albacore.
It's a fish.
My grandson
is a member.
They take very
nice care of us.
How do they do that?
Oh, give us things,
not just like this
old flag, but...
But what?
We're an unofficial
charity of theirs, Mr. Gittes.
Would you come
with me, please?
Someone wants
to talk with you.
Good-bye, ladies.
- Bye.
I want you to meet
someone, Gittes.
Can we leave the lady
out of this?
Yeah. Why not?
I'd like to see her
to the car.
She knows
where it's at.
I'll stay.
Get in the car.
Maid's night off?
Why?
What do you mean, why?
Nobody's here,
that's why.
I gave everyone
the night off.
Easy. It's
an innocent question.
No question from you
is innocent, Mr. Gittes.
I guess you're right.
To you, Mrs. Mulwray.
Frankly, tonight
you saved my as...
You saved my neck.
Tell me, Mr. Gittes...
does this often
happen to you?
What's that?
I'm judging
only on the basis
of one afternoon
and an evening,
but if this is how
you go about your work,
I'd say you'd be lucky
to get through a day.
This hasn't happened
to me for a long time.
When was
the last time?
Why?
It's an
innocent question.
In Chinatown.
What were
you doing there?
Working for
the district attorney.
Doing what?
As little as possible.
The district attorney
gives his men advice like that?
They do in Chinatown.
Why did you leave
the police force?
Uh...
Do you have any, uh...
peroxide, or, uh...
anything like that?
Surely.
Will you
come this way?
My God!
It's a nasty cut.
I had no idea...
Oh! Sorry!
There.
Is it painful?
It must be painful.
What's wrong?
Your eye.
What about it? What?
There's something black
in the green part of your eye.
Oh, that.
It's, uh...
it's...
a flaw...
in the iris.
A flaw?
Yes, uh...
it's a sort
of birthmark.
Did you wear
a uniform?
Sometimes.
Must have looked
cute in blue.
Give me a break,
will ya?
I don't know you.
I want to know
more about you.
Not now.
You really don't like to talk
about the past, do you?
I'm tired.
No. Why does it bother
you to talk about it?
It bothers everybody
that works there.
Where?
Chinatown.
Everybody.
To me, it was
just bad luck.
Why?
You can't always tell
what's going on.
Like with you.
Why was, um...
why was it bad luck?
I was trying
to keep someone
from being hurt.
I ended up making sure
that she was hurt.
Cherchez la femme.
Was there
a woman involved?
Of course.
Dead?
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Yes, hello?
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Let me know.
Look, don't
do anything.
Don't do anything
until I get there.
I, uh...
I have to go.
Where?
Uh, just
that I have to.
I want to know
where you're going.
No, please.
Don't be angry.
It has nothing to do with you
or any of this.
Where are you going?
Please.
Trust me this much.
I'll be back.
There is, uh...
there is something
that I should tell you about.
The, uh, the fishing club
that old lady mentioned...
um, the pieces
of the flag...
The Albacore Club.
It has to do
with my father.
I know.
He... he owns it.
You know?
I saw him.
You saw him?
My f-f-father?
W-w-when?
This morning.
You didn't tell me.
Well, there hasn't
been much time.
What, uh...
what... what did he say?
What did he say?
That you were jealous.
And that he was afraid
what you might do.
Do?
To whom?
Mulwray's girlfriend
for one.
He wanted to know
where she was.
I want you
to listen to me.
Now, my father...
is a very
dangerous man.
You don't know
how dangerous.
how crazy.
Are you
trying to tell me
that he might be
behind all this?
It's possible.
Even the death
of your husband?
It's possible.
Now, please...
don't ask
any more questions.
Just wait
for me here.
I need you here.
[Shower Runs]
[Sobbing]
No, no, no.
Give me the keys.
You...
It's either that
or you drive yourself to the police.
The police?
Come on, Mrs. Mulwray.
You've got your husband's girlfriend
tied up in there.
She's not tied up.
You know what I mean.
You're holding her
against her will.
I am not.
O.K. Then let's
go talk to her.
No!
She's... she's
too upset.
What about?
Hollis' death.
L... I tried
to keep it from her.
I didn't want her
to know
until I could make plans
for us to leave.
You mean she just
found out about it?
That's not what it looks like,
Mrs. Mulwray.
What does it
look like?
Like she knows more
than you want her to tell.
You're insane.
Just tell me
the truth.
I'm not the police.
I don't care
what you've done.
I don't
want to hurt you.
You won't go to the police
if I tell you?
I will if you don't.
[Horn Honks]
She...
she...
she's my sister.
Take it easy.
If she's your sister,
she's your sister.
Why all the secrecy?
L... l... I can't...
Is it because of Hollis,
because she was
seeing your husband,
is that it?
I would never
have harmed Hollis.
He was the most...
gentle, decent man
imaginable.
And he...
he put up with more from me
than you'll ever know.
I...
wanted him
to be happy.
I borrowed
your husband's car.
I'll bring it back
in the morning.
Aren't you going...
coming back with me?
Don't worry.
I'm not going to tell
anybody about this.
That's not
what I meant.
Yeah.
Well, uh...
I'm tired, Mrs. Mulwray.
Good night.
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Gittes?
Yeah?
Ida Sessions
wants to see you.
Who?
Ida Sessions.
You remember Ida.
Yeah, I do.
Sure, you do.
I tell you what, pal.
If Ida
wants to see me,
she can call me
at my office.
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
8481/2 East Kensington.
Echo Park.
She begged me to call.
She's waiting for you.
[Click]
[Door Closes]
Find anything
interesting, Gittes?
What are you doing
around here?
Didn't you call me?
How come you happen
to know her?
I don't.
Come here. I want
to show you something.
Isn't that
your phone number?
Is it? I forget. I don't
call myself that often.
Well, just
to make sure,
we had Loach
give you a call.
What happened
to your nose, Gittes,
somebody slam
the bedroom window on it?
Nope.
Your wife
got excited.
She crossed her legs
too quick.
You understand
what I mean, pal?
Loach.
They look familiar?
Yeah. I took them.
So what?
How did she happen
to have them?
You tell me
or I guess.
You must really think I'm stupid,
don't you, Gittes?
I don't think
about it much.
Give me a few days.
I'll get
back to you.
I'd like to go home.
I want the other
pictures, Gittes.
What pictures?
This broad hired you,
not Evelyn Mulwray.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Somebody wanted
to shake Mulwray down.
She hired you.
That's how come you found out
he was murdered.
I heard
it was an accident.
Come on, Gittes.
Who the hell do you think
you're dealing with?
Mulwray had salt water
in his lungs.
You followed him
day and night.
You saw who killed him.
You even took pictures
of it.
It was Evelyn Mulwray,
and she's been
paying you off ever since.
You accusing me
of extortion?
Absolutely.
I don't need
a few days.
You're dumber than you think
I think you are.
Not only that,
I wouldn't extort a nickel
from my worst enemy.
I want the rest
of the pictures.
We're talking about
accessory after the fact,
conspiracy,
and extortion, minimum.
What do you think,
Evelyn Mulwray
killed her husband in the ocean,
then dragged him
to the reservoir
to make it look more
like an accident?
Mulwray was murdered
and moved
because somebody
didn't want his body found in the ocean.
Why is that?
He found out
they were dumping water there.
That's what they were
trying to cover up.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Come on.
I'll show you.
Come on, Lou.
You're in charge.
Make a decision.
Ha!
It's too late.
Too late
for what?
They only dump the water
at night.
Reach anybody?
Yelburton.
He's the new chief.
I know who he is.
Go on.
He says...
I know what he says.
Shut up.
Go on!
There's irrigation
in the valley,
and there's always
a little runoff
after they do that.
He says
Gittes knows this,
and he's been
going around
making irresponsible
accusations
all last week.
Let's swear out a warrant
for her arrest.
What are we waiting for?
He just
made lieutenant.
Wants to hang on
to his little gold bar.
Have your client
in my office in two hours.
And remember,
I don't have to let you go.
I've got you
right now
for withholding
evidence.
Loach.
Where's Mrs. Mulwray?
These her bags?
Is she going
on a trip?
What are you doing?
What's
going on here?
Is she going
on a vacation?
Mrs. Mulwray no home.
Mrs. Mulwray
no home, huh?
Well, I'll just have
a look around, huh?
Yeah, Yeah.
Bad for the glass.
Oh, yeah.
Bad for glass.
Salt water
very bad for glass.
Salt water?
Very, very bad.
See?
What's that?
Huh?
Right there.
There.
Huh.
You wait.
Chow hoi tai dai.
[Speaking Chinese]
How are you?
I've been calling you.
It's all right.
Have you...
have you slept?
Sure.
Have you had lunch?
Khan can fix you something.
Where's the girl?
Upstairs. Why?
I want to see her.
She's having a bath
right now.
Why do you
want to see her?
Going someplace?
Yes. We have
a 5:30 train to catch.
Jake.
J.J. Gittes
for Lieutenant Escobar.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
I told you,
we have a 5:30...
You're going
to miss your train.
Lou?
Meet me at
1972 Canyon Drive.
Yeah.
As soon as you can.
Why did you do that?
You know any good
criminal lawyers?
No.
Don't worry. I can
recommend a couple.
They're expensive,
but you can afford it.
Will you please tell me
what this is all about?
I found these in your
backyard in the pond.
They belonged to your
husband, didn't they?
Didn't they?
I don't know.
Yes, probably.
Yes, positively.
It's where he was drowned.
What?
There's no time to be
shocked by the truth.
The coroner's report
proves he had
salt water in his lungs
when he was killed.
I want to know
why it happened
before Escobar
gets here
because I don't want
to lose my license.
I don't know what
you are talking about.
This is the craziest,
most insane thing...
Stop it!
I'll make it easy.
You were jealous.
You had a fight.
He fell.
He hit his head.
His girl is a witness.
You had to shut her up.
You got the money
to keep her quiet.
Yes or no?
No!
Who is she?
Don't tell me
she's your sister.
You don't
have a sister.
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you
the truth.
Good. What's her name?
Katherine.
Katherine who?
She's my daughter.
I said
I want the truth!
She's my sister.
She's my daughter.
My sister,
my daughter.
I said I want the truth!
All right!
She's my sister
and my daughter!
Khan,
please, go back.
For God's sake,
keep her upstairs.
Go back.
My father and I...
Understand?
Or is it too tough for you?
He raped you?
Then what happened?
I ran away.
To Mexico.
Hollis came and...
and took care of me.
I couldn't see her.
I was 15.
I wanted to, but l...
I couldn't.
Then...
Now I want to be with her.
I want to take care of her.
Where are you going
to take her now?
Back to Mexico.
No. You can't
take the train.
Escobar will be
looking for you everywhere.
How...
H-how about a plane?
No. That's worse.
You better just
get out of here.
Leave all this stuff
here.
Where
does Khan live?
Get
the exact address.
All right.
Uh...
those didn't belong...
to Hollis.
How do you know?
He didn't wear bifocals.
Katherine,
say hello to Mr. Gittes.
Hello.
He lives
at 1712 Alameda.
Do you know
where that is?
Sure.
J.J. Gittes
and Associates.
Sophie,
get me Walsh.
Yes, Mr. Gittes.
[Click]
Jake?
Yeah.
Escobar's going
to try and book me
in about
five minutes.
What the hell's
the matter...
Relax and I'll tell you.
Wait in the office for me.
About two hours.
If you don't hear from me,
you and Duffy
meet me at 1712 Alameda.
Jesus.
That's in Chinatown,
ain't it?
I know where it is.
Just do it.
1712 Alameda.
[Car Door Closes]
[Doorbell Buzzes]
Come on in, Lou.
Looks like
we're both too late.
She flew the coop.
I don't suppose
you have any idea
where she went.
As a matter of fact,
I do.
Where?
Her maid's house.
I think she knows
something's up.
What's
the maid's address?
She lives in Pedro.
I'll write it down.
No, no, no, Gittes.
You're
going to show us.
What for?
Because
if she ain't there,
you're going downtown,
and you'll stay there
until she does show up.
Gee, Lou, I'm doing
the best I can.
Tell us about it
on the way to San Pedro.
Let's get
the little lady.
Lou, can I
ask you a favor?
I'd like to
bring her out myself.
She's not armed
or nothing.
She won't be a problem.
I just want
a minute alone with her.
It would mean a lot
to her... and to me.
You never learn,
do you, Jake?
I guess not.
O.K.
But...
I'll give you
three minutes.
Just three minutes.
Gee, thanks, Lou.
Yeah?
Hello.
Mr. Gittes.
Come in.
This is some surprise,
Mr. Gittes.
Call me Jake.
How you doing, Curly?
Just having supper.
Care to join us?
No, thanks.
How about some wine?
Hey, honey, this is...
I know.
No, thank you, Curly,
but I would like
a glass of water.
Come out in the kitchen
with me a second.
Sure thing.
Curly,
where's your car?
In the garage.
Where's that?
Off the alley.
Can you
take me somewhere?
Sure. After we eat.
Right now, Curly.
It can't wait.
I'll tell my wife.
Tell her later, Curl,
huh?
[Baby Crying]
Drive slow
for a block or two,
will you, Curly?
What's this all about?
I'll tell you
in a block or two.
How much
do you owe me?
Ah, gee, Mr. Gittes,
we're going out
tomorrow.
I know you been
real good about it,
but my cousin
Augie's sick.
How would you
like to pay me off
by taking a couple
of passengers to Ensenada?
You'd have
to leave tonight.
I don't know.
I might be able
to squeeze 75 bucks
out of it for you.
Maybe even 100.
Plus what I owe?
I'll throw that in,
too.
1712 Alameda.
It's in Chinatown.
Wait for me
until 8:30.
If I don't show up,
take them
to your boat.
You sure
this is O.K.?
Curly, do you know
how long I've been in this business?
Have you got your checkbook
handy, Mr. Cross?
I've got the girl.
You've got her? Where?
Do you remember
the figures we discussed?
Of course I do.
Where are you?
At your daughter's
house.
How soon
can you get here?
An hour.
Oh, there you are.
Well, you don't look
too much worse for wear, Mr. Gitts,
I must say.
Uh,
where's the girl?
I've got her.
Is she all right?
She's fine.
Well, where is she?
With her mother.
Got something I'd like
to show you, Mr. Cross.
What is it?
An obituary column.
Can you see all right
in this light?
I guess I can manage.
What does it mean?
That you killed
Hollis Mulwray...
right here.
In that pond.
You drowned him.
And you left these.
The coroner's report
shows Mulwray had
salt water in his lungs.
Hollis was...
always fascinated
by tide pools.
You know
what he used to say?
I haven't
the faintest idea.
That's where life begins...
sloughs, tide pools.
When we first come out here,
he figured if you dumped water
into the desert sand
and let it percolate
down to the bedrock,
it would stay there
instead of evaporate like
it does in most reservoirs.
You'd only lose 20%
instead of 70 or 80.
That's what you were
going to do in the valley.
It's what I am doing.
When the bond issue
passes Tuesday,
there'll be $8 million
to build an aqueduct
to the reservoir.
There'll
be irate citizens
when they find out
they're paying for water
they won't get.
That's
all taken care of.
See, Mr. Gitts,
either you bring
the water to L.A.,
or you bring L.A.
To the water.
How will you do that?
By incorporating
the valley into the city.
Simple as that.
How much are you worth?
I have no idea.
How much
do you want?
I just want to know
what you're worth.
Over 10 million?
My, yes.
Why are you doing it?
What can you buy
that you can't already afford?
The future,
Mr. Gitts.
The future.
Now where's
the girl?
I want the only daughter
I've got left.
As you found out,
Evelyn was lost to me
a long time ago.
Who do you blame
for that, her?
I don't blame myself.
See, Mr. Gitts,
most people never
have to face the fact...
at the right time
and the right place,
they're capable
of anything.
Claude, take those
glasses from him, will you?
It's not worth it,
Mr. Gitts.
It's really
not worth it.
Now take us
to the girl.
You remember "Night Train"
Claude Mulvihill,
don't you, boys?
Mr. Cross, these
are my associates,
Mr. Walsh and Mr...
You're under arrest,
Jake.
Good news.
Withholding evidence,
extortion,
accessory
after the fact.
I didn't extort nothing
from nobody.
This is Noah Cross,
if you don't know...
Evelyn's father.
He's the bird
you're after.
I can explain
everything...
Lieutenant.
Give me five minutes.
He's rich,
do you understand?
Shut up!
Thinks he'll get away
with anything!
I'll lock you
into the wheel of that car.
Lieutenant, I am rich.
I am Noah Cross.
Evelyn Mulwray is my...
He's crazy, Lou!
He killed Mulwray
because of the water thing!
Water?
Listen to me
for five minutes!
Lock him to the wheel
of that car.
Lou, you don't know
what's going on.
Katherine.
L... l... I am
your grandfather.
Come, miss.
My dear, I'm
your grandfather.
Katherine,
get in the car.
Go on, go on.
But...
No, no. Just go on.
I'll follow.
Get away from her.
Get away!
Evelyn.
Please, please
be reasonable.
Come to my...
Get away from her!
Evelyn!
How many years
have I got?
She's mine, too.
She's never
going to know that!
Evelyn, you're
a disturbed woman.
You cannot hope
to provide...
Evelyn, put
that gun away!
Let the police
handle this!
He owns the police!
Get away from her.
You'll have
to kill me first.
Get away! Get...
Katherine,
close the door.
Halt!
[Honk]
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah! Oh!
Oh, no!
Call the captain.
Get an ambulance.
No!
Turn him loose.
Turn them all loose.
Oh, no! Ohh!
Lord.
Aah!
Oh, Lord.
Oh, no, no!
Aah! Aah!
No! No!
Don't look.
Oh, no!
No! No!
No! Oh...
Oh, no...
As little as possible.
What's that?
You want to do your partner
a big favor?
Take him home.
Take him home!
Just get him
the hell out of here!
Come on, Jake.
Go home, Jake.
I'm doing you a favor.
Come on, Jake.
Forget it, Jake.
It's Chinatown.
All right. Come on.
Clear the area!
On the sidewalk!
Get off the street!
}}