- Is this the last one?
- I don't know.
There's no ether, either.
Jesus Christ.
You there! Is this the last one?
God, what a mess.
At least there's no gangrene.
There will be
if it doesn't come off soon.
I can't saw
if I can't keep my eyes open.
I'm sorry.
Let's coffee up.
He can wait a few more minutes.
God!
Glass.
- Is that Tucker's men?
- Yes, sir. I think it is.
How long has it been like this?
We found 'em this morning, sir.
They've been here for two days.
Is that you, Lieutenant?
Sons of bitches.
Come on. You better take cover.
I ain't kidding. These boys are
shooters. Come on. Go under cover.
There you go.
You went to the hospital?
It was no good.
What's going on here?
That seems to be
the question, all right.
See, you could ask the major ...
but he don't know.
He's busy.
He's busy trying to figure out
how come the officers' mess ...
run out of peach ice cream.
Then, of course, you got the general.
He come up to see the show.
All he knows is there ain't no show ...
which ain't entirely correct
'cause we started a balloon up ...
but they shot her down
before we got off the ground.
Nobody's made a run either way.
It's been a standoff all damned day.
Now, the major,
he's looking at the general.
He's thinking to himself,
"I better do something."
You know what that means.
I sure as hell don't want to be
the first one across this field.
They're supposed to be
beat up just like us.
Hell, everybody knows
Tucker's men are tough as cobs.
So far, the only thing been killed
out here is three milking cows.
Course, that's about to change.
You son of a bitch.
You know, some of the boys are saying
if we ain't gonna fight ...
we could just settle this whole
business with a little ...
high-stakes poker.
Wouldn't that be a sight?
A bunch of fellas sitting in
the middle of this field ...
drawing cards.
What is it, sir?
Looks like a suicide.
Tucker!
What's he doing?
- What did you say to him?
- I didn't say nothing.
Come on back, you son of a bitch!
- You won't make it no second time!
- All right by me.
Forgive me, Father.
- He's coming back again!
- Here he comes, boys!
- Ready!
- I got him.
Don't ...
Don't take off my foot.
You rest easy, son.
You'll keep your foot.
With God as my judge, you'll keep it.
- Bring up my ambulance.
- Sir?
Bring up my ambulance,
and bring my surgeon with it!
We got an officer
who's worth something lying here.
"The strangeness of this life
cannot be measured.
"In trying to produce my own death ...
"I was elevated to the status
of a living hero.
"I was also awarded Cisco ...
"the trusty mount that carried
me across the field that day.
"And on full recovery, was given
transfer to any station I desired.
"The bloody slaughter continues in
the east as I arrive at Fort Hayes.
"A tiny island of men and material
surrounded by a never-ending sea of prairie."
Lieutenant.
Where can I find Maj. Fambrough?
Down at the end of the hall.
Thank you.
"Lt. John J. Dunbar."
Lt. John J. Dunbar?
- Yes, sir.
- "Yes, sir."
Indian fighter.
Excuse me?
It says here that you're
to be posted on the frontier.
The frontier is Indian country.
I quickly deduced that
you're an Indian fighter.
I did not ascend to this
position by being stupid.
- No, sir.
- "No, sir."
It says here that
you've been decorated.
Yes, sir.
And they sent you here to be posted?
Actually, sir,
I'm here at my own request.
Really? Why?
I've always wanted
to see the frontier.
You want to see the frontier?
Yes, sir.
Before it's gone.
Such a smart lad,
coming straight to me.
Sir ...
Knight.
I am sending you on a knight's errand.
You will report to Captain Cargill ...
at the furthermost
outpost of the realm ...
Fort Sedgewick.
My personal seal
will assure your safety ...
through many miles
of wild and hostile country.
- I was wondering ...
- Yes?
I was wondering, sir,
how will I be getting there?
You think I don't know?
- No, sir.
- You think that.
- It's just that I don't know —
- Hold your tongue.
I am in a generous mood
and I will grant your boon.
See that peasant out there?
He calls himself Timmons.
He's going there this very afternoon.
You can ride with him if you like.
He knows the way.
Thank you. That is all.
Sir Knight?
I've just pissed in my pants ...
and nobody can do anything about it.
To your journey!
To my journey!
Haw!
Over a little bit, Jim!
- Have this by tomorrow.
- Yes, sir.
I'll have my crown now.
- Sir?
- I'll have my crown now!
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Are you deaf, fool?
I said I'll have my crown right now!
Now!
No.
- I'll get your crown.
- No.
Sir?
Major?
The king is dead.
Long live the king.
Get these kids out of here, come on!
Haw, Jim and Jake!
Gee a little bit, Jim!
The hell was that?
What is that?
What the hell is that?
Why don't you put that in your book?
"Were it not for my companion ...
"I believe I would be having
the time of my life.
"I know he means well ...
"but he is quite possibly
the foulest man I have ever met."
How far you make the Fort?
Far.
How far?
Forty, fifty mile, maybe.
What's the big hurry on Sedgewick?
It's to be my post.
My home.
You ain't hard to please,
I'll give you that much.
Look yonder.
What you got there?
Somebody back east is saying,
"Why don't she write?"
You stupid bastard.
Get up, Timmons.
Get up.
Come on. Get up.
Get up!
Someone poked me in my butt.
Was that you?
Goddamn it!
I'm gonna have a welt.
Cpl. Guest?
You don't have to talk to me,
just please come out.
It's the end.
Assemble the men
in front of my quarters.
You hate me.
But I feel none of the same for you.
You men stayed.
You stayed after
they took all our horses.
all the others deserted.
You stayed after the army
failed to re-supply us.
I have looked for that wagon
from Fort Hayes ...
just as you have ...
day after miserable day.
And all I can say
is that I'm proud of you.
Now get your things, men.
We're leaving this place.
The army can go to hell.
Go.
Get your things.
How come we haven't seen any buffalo?
You can't figure the stinking buffalo.
You can't. Sometimes you
won't see any for days.
Other times, they'll be thick,
like curls on a whore.
What about Indians?
Indians? Goddamn Indians!
You just as soon not see 'em
unless the bastards are dead.
They're nothing
but thieves and beggars.
Ho, up there!
Not what you would call
much of a going concern now, is it?
Go down there.
- Why? There ain't nothing down there.
- Because I said.
Go down there.
There, son of a bitch!
There ain't nothing here, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant!
Everybody's run off or got killed.
All right. Let's unload the wagon.
What? What, and leave it all here?
I'm staying, too.
There ain't nothing here.
No, not at the moment.
We don't know what's happened.
Things being as they are ...
we might as well just turn
around and get headed back.
This is my post.
"This is my post?"
Jesus H. Christ.
What, are you crazy, boy?
Fast son of a bitch.
- Jesus H. Christ.
- This is my post.
All right, put it down.
And these are the post provisions, all right?
Now get your ass off the wagon —
- Put it down!
- And help me unload.
We're just havin' a conversation,
now put it down.
I'll let them know where you are.
Good.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Jake and Jim!
Good mule!
Haw up there now!
Good mules!
"Have arrived to find
Fort Sedgewick deserted.
"Am now waiting for garrison's return
or word from headquarters.
"The post is
in exceedingly poor condition ...
"and I have decided to assign myself
clean-up duty beginning tomorrow.
"Supplies are abundant ...
"and the country is everything
I dreamed it would be.
"There can be no place
like this on Earth."
Bad horse.
"The animals in the pond
had not been poisoned.
"They had all been shot.
"But why? Was it for sport?
"Could it have been out of spite?
"My first guess would have been
that the men here were starving.
"But this rotting waste
speaks to the contrary.
"The caves are an even bigger mystery.
"What could have driven men
to live in caves?
"Perhaps they were frightened.
"Maybe there had been
some sort of revolt.
"I can make no sense
of the clues left me here.
"Perhaps my relief
will provide the answers."
Come on, Cisco. One more time.
Git up!
Come on! Git up, Cisco.
Git up! There you go!
Easy.
Only a white man would make
a fire for everyone to see.
Maybe there's more than one.
There might be three or four.
I know three or four ...
who will not be making
the trip back home.
We have nothing to show for this trail.
We have no rifles.
White men are sure to have rifles.
It's hard to say
how many might be down there.
We should forget this and go home.
Then go.
I would rather die ...
than argue about a single line
of smoke in my own country.
He will not quit until we are all dead.
"And if I ..."
Look at me.
Don't hurt my mules.
Stop.
Stop it.
Please don't hurt my mules.
"I am pleased with my efforts thus far.
"For all my improvements, though, there
remains an ugliness here I cannot dispel.
"An injury that goes beyond neglect
and like a bruise, it will be slow to heal.
"It's been almost 30 days.
"I have come to enjoy the patterns
of my life at Fort Sedgewick.
"Especially my daily
reconnaissance rides with Cisco.
"Each day, we go further into the prairie
and every discovery ...
"big or small,
becomes etched in my mind forever.
"It would seem I've been marooned,
as no one has yet come for me.
"I can only assume that there is a problem,
which the army will solve shortly.
"Maybe I am being foolish in my optimism ...
"but when I look to the eastern horizon ...
"I never fail to hope
that a column might be out there."
"Still no sign of
Capt. Cargill's command.
"Though well-supplied,
I've decided to ration my goods ...
"as if I were part of a post
instead of the whole affair.
"There's a wolf who seems intent
on the goings-on here.
"He does not seem inclined
to be a nuisance, however.
"And aside from Cisco,
has been my only company.
"He's appeared each afternoon
for the past two days.
"He has two milky white paws.
"If he comes calling tomorrow ...
"I will name him 'Two-Socks'."
"Almost a month and no one has come.
"The longer
this condition persists ...
"the less inclined I am
to believe that anyone will.
"Rain has forced me indoors
for most of two days now ...
"and I have begun work on an awning.
"It is the loneliest of times
for me now ...
"but I can say honestly
that I am not unhappy."
♪ How can I marry
a pretty little girl ♪
♪ When I got no coat to put on? ♪
♪ Soldier, soldier ♪
♪ Won't you marry me ♪
♪ Before the fight comes home? ♪
♪ How can I marry a pretty little girl ♪
♪ When I got no shoes to put on? ♪
♪ When I got no hat to put on? ♪
♪ Soldier, soldier, won't you marry me ♪
♪ Before the fight comes home? ♪
♪ How can I marry an ugly little girl ♪
♪ When I got a pretty wife back home? ♪
You there!
"Have made first contact
with a wild Indian.
"One came to the fort
and tried to steal my horse.
"When I appeared, he became
frightened and ran off.
"Have decided to bury excess ordnance
lest it fall into enemy hands.
"Keeping only the barest
necessities for myself.
"My afternoon rides have been pared
down to short circular patrols ...
"always keeping the post in sight.
"Am taking steps to prepare
for another visitation.
"Do not know how many more
might be in the vicinity ...
"but am assuming that where there
is one there's sure to be another.
"Most of my work has been geared
toward creating the illusion ...
"of strength and stability.
"I'm still alone, however,
and unless troops arrive soon ...
"all may be lost."
'Kicking Bird' has been keeping
to himself these last few days.
I do not like to see our
medicine man walking so alone.
What does his wife say?
She says that he is
keeping to himself.
That's not what I asked you.
Well, what did you ask me?
What did she say?
She said that he is keeping
to himself these days.
That's what she says.
Make sure that my meat is soft.
My teeth hurt.
May I come in?
No, let him sit with me.
Our country seems good
this summer ...
but I have not been out to see it.
But the buffalo are late.
And I always worry about
the bellies of our children.
I was thinking of a dance.
Yes. A dance is always a good idea.
It would be good to have a strong sign.
There's a funny thing about signs.
We know when they are bad or good.
Sometimes they are strange
and it's hard to understand them.
A smart man will think
on these things.
If he is still confused,
he will tell somebody.
For instance,
he might tell you or me.
A smart man always does this.
I have seen such a sign.
Really?
I saw a man.
A naked, white man.
Are you sure it was a man?
I saw his sex.
Did you speak to him?
No.
"It's been two days now, and nothing.
"My presence here must
have been reported by now.
"Have made all the preparations
I can think of.
"Cannot mount an adequate defense
as I am still alone.
"But will try to make
a big impression when they come.
"Waiting.
"Post-script ...
"The man I encountered was
a magnificent-looking fellow."
He might be a god.
Or a white chief
with special abilities.
That is why we should talk with him.
I do not care for this
talk about this white man.
Whatever he is, he is not a Sioux,
and that makes him less.
When I hear that more whites
are coming, I want to laugh.
We took a hundred horses
from these people.
There was no honor in it.
They don't ride well.
They don't shoot well.
They're dirty.
Those soldiers could not even
make it through one winter here.
And these people are said to flourish?
I think they will all be dead soon.
I think this fool is probably lost.
'Wind In His Hair's' words are
strong and I have heard them.
It's true "The Whites" are a
poor race and hard to understand.
But make no mistake.
"The Whites" are coming.
Even our enemies agree on this.
So when I see one man alone
without fear in our country ...
I do not think he is lost.
I think he may have medicine.
I see someone who might speak ...
for all the white people
who are coming.
I think this is a person
with which treaties might be struck.
'Kicking Bird' is always looking
ahead and that is good.
But this man cannot cover our
lodges or feed our children.
He is nothing to us.
I will take some men.
We will shoot some arrows
into this white man.
If he truly has medicine,
he will not be hurt.
If he has no medicine,
he will be dead.
No man can tell another what to do.
But killing a white man
is a delicate matter.
If you kill one,
more are sure to come.
It's easy to become confused
by these questions.
It's hard to know what to do.
We should talk about this some more.
That is all I have to say.
What's the matter, now?
We don't think this is
such a good idea.
If we take the horse
of a white god ...
they will make up songs about us.
Maybe.
They will ask us to go on raids.
Who gets the horse?
I do.
I do, but we share. Now who can say
this is not a great plan?
It's always the same.
Every time.
Yes, sir, I have.
No, I'll ask, sir.
We'll be heroes.
They'll write songs about us.
What happened?
I don't know. My arm doesn't work.
You shouldn't have fallen off.
Now we'll get in trouble.
It was your idea.
My idea was only to take the horse,
not fall down.
Otter hurt himself.
What are you looking at?
I'm the one who's hurt.
I will be when my father finds out.
His bow will be across my back.
I am 'Wind In His Hair'.
Do you see that
I am not afraid of you?
Do you see?
The party that went against
"The Utes" is coming back.
There are many hearts on the ground.
"I realize now that I have been wrong.
"All this time, I've been waiting.
"Waiting for what?
"For someone to find me?
"For Indians to take my horse?
"To see a buffalo?
"Since I have arrived at this post
I have been walking on eggs.
"It has become a bad habit
and I am sick of it.
"Tomorrow morning,
I will ride out to the Indians.
"I do not know the outcome
or wisdom of this thinking ...
"but I've become a target and
a target makes a poor impression.
"I am through waiting."
What are you looking at?
Son of a bitch!
No. Wait.
Wait.
You need help. You're hurt.
- You need —
- No!
Let me ... You need help.
You need help.
You're hurt. Let me help you.
You're hurt.
Don't.
She's hurt.
You are not welcome here.
No. She's hurt.
Go away from us.
You are not welcome.
Stop.
The soldier did not come to fight.
He is going away and we will let him.
I am in agreement with 'Kicking Bird'.
We will go down and talk to the white man.
And find out why he is here.
If this council decides
to talk to the white man ...
then it will be so.
But in my mind it's not right ...
that a chief as great as 'Ten Bears' ...
goes to ask the business of a puny,
trespassing white man ...
who has only a smart horse
and a few white man's clothes.
I will not go.
You will go.
And you will go.
That is all I have to say.
Welcome.
Hi!
Come.
Please, sit down.
Sit down.
Wait just a ... Just a minute.
His mind is gone.
Tatanka. Buffalo.
- Buffalo.
- Tatanka.
Buffalo. Tatanka.
"The fierce one, as I call him,
seems a very tough fellow.
"I hope I never have to fight him.
"From the little I know,
he seems to be honest and very direct.
"I like the quiet one immensely.
"He's been patient and inquisitive.
"He seems eager to communicate.
"I would conclude that he is a man
of some weight among his people."
Buffalo.
"I believe I made an even greater
impression on their next visit.
"I produced a coffee grinder,
something none of them had seen before."
Is the coffee not good?
It's too strong, maybe.
Sugar.
Put in.
Taste it.
Sugar.
You want some?
That's a lot.
Okay.
Yeah.
"It's good to finally
have some company.
"So much goes unsaid and I have
the feeling that these people ...
"the quiet one in particular,
want something from me.
"Made presents of coffee
and most of the sugar.
"It didn't figure to last anyway.
"Don't believe I go
too far in saying ...
"that a foundation
for good relations is being laid."
'Stands With A Fist'.
We will talk awhile.
Your wounds are healing well?
Yes, they are.
You are happy here, with my family?
I am glad to be here.
I am missing my husband.
Perhaps you will marry again
when the time is right?
Perhaps.
We have word from many places
that "The Whites" are coming.
They are coming
into everyone's country.
I think they will soon be in ours.
This white man who lives
at the old soldier fort ...
I have visited him and I believe
his heart is a good one.
I am afraid of the
white man at the fort.
I am afraid he will
tell others that I am here.
I am afraid they will
try to take me away.
I've heard they take people away.
Every warrior in camp
would fight them if they tried.
I cannot make the white man language.
He cannot speak Sioux.
It has been a long time
since I made the talk.
I want you to try.
I don't know how.
Yes, you do.
I can't.
I can't. It's dead in me.
I don't ask this for myself.
I ask this for all the people.
He knows things about "The Whites"
which we do not.
Now, you must remember.
I can't.
Will she make the white words?
She won't try. She is being difficult.
Well, she's the one who's crying.
Perhaps the difficulty is yours.
Christine!
Get 'em, Joe! Get them chickens!
Billy, you get away from those puppies!
Damn!
Get the kids,
and get them in the house.
Go on!
Christine!
Christine! Where are you?
I'm up here, mother.
- Get down now.
- Why?
Just do it.
Stay right where you are.
Get back. Do you hear me?
Joe, get in the house right now!
Willie!
- Who is it, Willie?
- They look like Pawnee.
My father and your father
are talking to them.
- What do they want?
- I don't know.
Go on. You heard him.
Get out of here.
Run, Christine!
I said run!
Joe!
Christine!
Mommy!
Come on, Two Socks. Bacon.
"Two Socks, like Cisco,
has become a trusted friend.
"He still won't eat from my hand ...
"but his keen eyes and ears never fail
to alert me when something is wrong."
Tatanka.
No.
No, I haven't seen any buffalo.
Sorry.
Are you hungry?
I have food. I have a lot of food.
"Nothing I've been told
about these people is correct.
"They are not beggars and thieves.
"They are not the bogeymen
they've been made out to be.
"On the contrary, they are polite guests
and have a familiar humor I enjoy.
"Real communication
is slow, however ...
"and the quiet one is
as frustrated as I am.
"Most of our progress has been
built on the basis of failure ...
"rather than success.
"I've thought to inquire if the
woman I found lived or not ...
"but it seems far too complicated
a subject, given our limitations.
"One thing is clear, however.
There are no buffalo.
"And it weighs heavy on their minds.
"Yesterday's meeting was the best yet.
"It seems I've been invited to the village
and I'm looking forward to going."
We were waiting for you.
Now tell him we are glad
that he is here.
Hello.
You ...
Here ...
Good.
Thank you. I feel good.
I feel good.
Ask him why he is
at the soldier fort.
The soldier fort.
Wait.
What is your names?
- Our names?
- What is his name?
He's right.
Introductions should come first.
He ...
Kick.
Kick?
More.
More kick?
More kicking?
Kicking.
Bird? Bird, kicking bird.
'Kicking Bird'.
What is he ...
Is he chief?
No.
A holy man.
Holy man.
Your name?
- I don't —
- How are you called?
Get up?
Stand up?
Stands?
Stands. Your name's "Stands"?
Stands.
- With.
- With?
- Stands with?
Fist?
Yes.
Stands With A Fist?
'Stands With A Fist'.
I'm John Dunbar.
John Dunbar.
Dumb Bear.
No, not Dumb Bear.
Dunbar.
Dun ...
Bar.
Not Dumb Bear.
Dunbar.
"There's been an exciting
breakthrough with the Indians.
"The woman I found
on the prairie speaks English ...
"and today, clear progress was made.
"She is white, and though I cannot be sure
how she came to be with these people ...
"I can tell she is not a captive.
"While I'm not afraid ...
"I don't feel completely
welcome by everyone in the village.
"My being here must
be 'Kicking Bird's' idea.
"He is very enthusiastic
and like two children ...
"we are both anxious
to know more about each other.
"But I find myself holding back.
"For some reason, I am reluctant
to answer all his questions.
"Maybe it's my sense of duty ...
"but something tells me
not to say too much.
"It was good to see
Fort Sedgewick again ...
"and yet I look forward to another
visit with my new neighbors.
"This is still my home, however ...
"and I remain watchful
for my relief and can only hope ...
"that my negotiations with the wild
people of the plains will bear fruit."
Buffalo!
Buffalo! I've seen buffalo!
Buffaloes!
Tatanka.
Tatanka?
Yeah.
"Riders were sent out
to pick up the trail.
"In the time it took to gather
my things at Sedgewick ...
"the entire tribe was well on its way.
"Their efficiency and speed
with which they moved ...
"was enough to impress
any military commander.
"Spirits are high, and overnight
I've gone from a person of suspicion ...
"to one of genuine standing.
"I am greeted with open smiles
and looks of appreciation.
"In short,
I have become a celebrity."
Loo ten tant!
- Loo ten tant!
"Scouts picked up the trail
exactly where I said it would be.
"It was not hard to find ...
"a gigantic swath of torn-up ground
extending to the horizon.
"The numbers it took to create
this impossible image ...
"was hard to imagine."
Loo ten tant!
"Who would do such a thing?
"The field was proof enough ...
"that it was a people
without value and without soul.
"With no regard for Sioux rights.
"The wagon tracks
leading away left little doubt ...
"and my heart sank, as I knew
it could only be white hunters.
"Voices that had been
joyous all morning ...
"were now as silent as the dead buffalo
left to rot in this valley ...
"killed only for their tongues
and the price of their hides."
Loo ten tant.
"It was suddenly clear now
what had happened ...
"and my heart sank
as I tried to convince myself ...
"that the white men who'd been killed
were bad people and deserved to die.
"But it was no use.
"I tried to believe that
'Wind In His Hair' and 'Kicking Bird' ...
"and the others who shared in the killing
were not so happy for having done it.
"But they were.
"As I looked at familiar faces,
I realized that the gap between us ...
"was greater than I could
ever have imagined."
"As they celebrated into
the night the coming hunt ...
"it was hard to know where to be.
"I don't know if they understood,
but I could not sleep among them.
"There had been no looks,
and there was no blame.
"There was only the confusion of a
people not able to predict a future."
Are you all right?
I can't.
No, I'm full.
I'm full, and I can't
tell the story anymore.
No.
You want to try it?
Here.
I can't. This is too much.
Good trade.
This is a good trade.
No, no, I can't.
I'm full, I'm tired.
No!
Loo ten tant! Loo ten tant!
Tatanka. Big tatanka.
Big tatanka.
That's my hat!
You're wearing my hat.
It's my hat.
I found it on the prairie.
It's mine.
No, you ...
My hat.
That hat belongs to the Lieutenant.
He left it on the prairie.
He didn't want it.
Well, you can see he wants it now.
We all know that it's a soldier's hat.
We all know who wears it.
If you want to keep it,
that's all right.
But give something for it.
Good trade.
There you are.
Come here, Cisco.
"It seems every day ends
with a miracle here.
"And whatever God may be,
I thank God for this day.
"To stay any longer
would have been useless.
"We had all the meat
we could possibly carry.
"We had hunted for three days,
losing a half a dozen ponies ...
"and only three men injured.
"I'd never known a people
so eager to laugh ...
"so devoted to family,
so dedicated to each other.
"And the only word
that came to mind was "harmony."
"Many times I've felt alone ...
"but until this afternoon ...
"I'd never felt completely lonely."
"Made a long patrol today.
"There's nothing to report.
"Time seems irrelevant except
for the fact that I am bored ...
"and these hours alone are endless.
"It is difficult for me
to muster any enthusiasm ...
"for my regular duties here.
"And the fort is showing
serious signs of neglect.
"The truth is, I am missing
the company of my friends.
"I can see all of their faces,
but somehow it is not enough.
"Tomorrow I will pay
them a visit.
"It may be forward of me,
but what can it hurt?
"After all, they are my neighbors."
"The night sounds have become
so familiar as to be comforting.
"My life on the prairie's a good one
and for the most part, I am content.
"The Indians have a great pull
for me that goes beyond curiosity.
"There's something wise about them
and I'm drawn to them ...
"in ways much stronger than my
obligations to the military."
Go home!
Damn him.
God! Go home!
Go!
Go home, Two Socks!
Bad wolf!
You were right.
He is a special white man.
He should have a real name.
"It is autumn now and I am spending
more time than ever with my friends.
"They have given me my own
lodge and I feel comfortable there.
"We talk every day, but I know
'Kicking Bird' is frustrated with me.
"He always wants to know how many
more white people are coming.
"I tell him they will most likely
pass through this country and nothing more.
"But I am speaking in half-truths.
"One day there will be too many, but I
cannot bring myself to tell him that.
"I am sure that 'Stands With A Fist'
knows that I am holding back ...
"but to her credit, she says nothing."
"A war party is going against the
Pawnee soon and I have asked to go.
"I sense I made a mistake in doing so ...
"but I could not bring myself
to take it back.
"They are my friends,
and from what little I gather ...
"the Pawnee have been
very hard on these people.
"I hope I have not
overstepped my bounds."
Come in, please.
Sit down?
'Kicking Bird' want to know ...
why you want to make war
on the Pawnee.
They have done nothing to you.
They are Sioux enemies.
Only Sioux warriors to go.
Tell him that
I have been a warrior ...
longer than many of the young men
who will go on this war party.
Tell him.
He said that the Sioux way
of being a warrior ...
is not the white way.
- You are not ready.
- I know, I understand.
Tell him I cannot learn
these ways in camp.
He also asks that you ...
watch over his family
while he is gone.
This thing he asks
is a great honor for you.
Tell him that I would be happy
to watch over his family.
He thanks 'Dances With Wolves'
for coming.
Who is Dances With Wolves?
It is the name
which all the people ...
are calling you now.
Dances With ...
That's right.
That day.
'Dances With Wolves'.
How do you say it?
Keep on with the white man
talk if it pleases you.
I like to make the talk.
I'm here.
We walk.
I cut this off.
I shaved it off. More.
Grass grows on the prairie.
"Grass grows on the prairie"?
- Wrong.
- Wrong?
You said, "Fire lives on the prairie."
I did?
No laughing, though.
That man is a fighter.
Again.
- That man is a fighter.
- Okay, I have it.
Yes.
Hoo hoo, right?
No?
Try this.
What's the word ...
for beautiful?
What are you doing?
It's hot, and we are
sitting in the shade.
I'm hungry.
How is 'Dances With Wolves'?
What do you mean?
How is he learning?
He is a fast learner.
What did you think I meant?
You go for water, today?
Then let us take you.
How did you get your name?
I was not very old ...
when I came to be with the people.
And I was made to work.
I worked every day, very hard.
There was a woman ...
who didn't like me much.
She used to call me bad names,
and sometimes she ...
Beat me?
And one day, she was ...
calling me these bad names ...
with her face in my face ...
and I hit her.
I was not very big, but she fell down.
She fell hard and didn't move.
And then I stood over
her with my fist ...
and I asked if ...
there was any other woman ...
who wanted to call me bad names.
No one bothered me after that day.
No, I wouldn't think so.
Show me.
Show me where you hit her.
Why are you not married?
- I'm sorry.
- I have to go.
I'm sorry.
Can I help you?
You are not talking today?
No, I am not.
Some of your words are wrong
but you are learning fast.
So what can I tell you today?
I want to know about
'Stands With A Fist'.
Why is there no man with her?
She is in mourning.
I don't ...
I do not understand "mourning."
She cries for someone.
Cries for who?
It is not polite
to speak of the dead.
But you are new, so I will tell you.
She cries for her husband.
He was killed not long ago.
That is how you came
to find her on the prairie.
How long will she cry?
It is 'Kicking Bird's' place
to say when she is finished.
He's the one that found her
when she was very little.
People are talking about you.
What are they saying?
They are proud of the medicine ...
you are making with
'Dances With Wolves'.
I have hurt him,
and I should go talk to him.
You can't. He is gone.
He left this morning.
Bet you were thinking:
"Now, why don't he write?"
Hello, Two Socks.
Come on.
I won't hurt you.
Come on. You can do this.
You can do this.
Come on.
This is easy.
This is easy, Two Socks.
I am in mourning.
No, we cannot.
- Yes.
- We must be careful.
We must be careful.
Okay.
Wait!
What?
Trouble.
The Pawnee are coming.
A big party of 40 or 50 men this time.
Hunters found them not far
to the north. Soon be here.
'Stone Calf', wait. I will follow you.
The Pawnee do not come for horses.
They come for blood.
Get your weapons and come to my lodge.
I will get them.
'Stone Calf', wait.
I have guns.
I have many rifles.
- At the fort?
- Yes.
No. The ride is long and
we can spare no men.
Guns would make one warrior like two.
Take one man and go quickly.
I will take 'Smiles A Lot'.
Okay!
Shoot the gun!
"It was hard to know how to feel.
"I'd never been in a battle
like this one.
"There was no dark
political objective.
"This was not a fight for territory
or riches or to make men free.
"It was fought to preserve the food stores
that would see us through the winter.
"To protect the lives of women and children
and loved ones only a few feet away.
"'Stone Calf' was a great loss, but even
the old men could not remember ...
"such a one-sided victory.
"And I gradually began
to look at it in a new way.
"I felt a pride
I'd never felt before.
"I'd never really known
who John Dunbar was.
"Perhaps the name itself
had no meaning.
"But as I heard my Sioux name
being called over and over ...
"I knew for the first time
who I really was."
When we were younger, he always
bragged about how brave he was.
And what a great chief he would make.
He thought I was impressed.
While walking on the prairie,
we surprised a small herd of buffalo.
And the first thing this brave
warrior did is run for a tree.
He would have forgotten
all about me ...
if he hadn't needed
my help to climb it.
And we sat there all day
as this old cow circled below.
Making loud noises and hitting
her head against the trunk.
Where are you going?
There is gambling tonight.
'Horseback's' games are always good.
I'm tired. 'Horseback' already
has a good rifle of mine.
Good night.
How long will
'Stands With A Fist' mourn?
I don't know.
I hope it will not be too long.
Has something happened?
What?
She has found love again.
With who?
Who do you think?
Tell me.
'Dances With Wolves'.
Are you certain of this?
When you see them together,
you will know.
What are people saying?
They like the match.
No one is angry?
It makes sense.
They are both white.
I suppose I will be the one
to say something.
She's your daughter now.
I know.
Relax. You can't see everything coming.
Stop it. Quit your playing.
'Stands With A Fist'.
You will mourn no more.
Sit, sit.
There's talk that you want
to get married.
To who?
To 'Stands With A Fist'.
That's the one, isn't it?
She's in mourning.
Not today.
'Kicking Bird' has released her.
He did?
What are you doing here?
'Kicking Bird' told me to wait.
You might have to wait a long time.
'Smiles A Lot' says he saw 'Kicking Bird'
riding on the prairie.
He says he was talking to himself.
A medicine man takes it pretty hard ...
when he is the last to know something.
What do I do?
You are pretty poor
and a Sioux girl is not for free.
I don't know if you can get married.
I have the buckskin ...
No, that's too much medicine.
Do you think my horse is
too much medicine?
For a girl.
Wait here. Maybe we can help you.
Wait.
That's all I do is wait!
"The whole village was eager
to take up a collection on my behalf.
"The generosity
of the people was astonishing.
"The more valued the gift,
the more easily it was given.
"Even the poorer families wanted to
give up animals they could not afford.
"It was hard to turn them away.
"'Black Shawl' was a mystery.
"I couldn't guess what she was thinking
and she offered no advice ...
"no words of encouragement.
"I may have been the brunt
of an inside joke ...
"that included the entire village ...
"but I was determined.
"'Wind In His Hair' told me if all the
gifts were gone in the morning ...
"my offer had been accepted.
"I spent a sleepless night wondering
what mis-step, if any, I had made.
"I had no idea what 'Kicking Bird's'
decision would be."
Turn around.
You look good.
You know, the man she mourned for ...
He was my best friend.
I didn't know that.
He was a good man.
It has been hard
for me to like you.
I am not the thinker
'Kicking Bird' is.
I always feel anger first.
There were no answers
to my questions.
But now I think he went away
because you were coming.
That is how I see it.
This is a good day for me.
And for me.
If you want this man,
take his hand in yours.
"I had never been married before.
"I don't know if all grooms
have the same experience ...
"but as 'Kicking Bird' began to speak about
what was expected of a Sioux husband ...
"my mind began to swim in a way that
shut out everything but her ...
"the tiny details of her costume ...
"the contours of her shape ...
"the light in her eyes ...
"the smallness of her feet.
"I knew that the love
between us would be served."
Have you heard all that I have said?
Yes.
Good, then take her inside.
She is your wife.
Good.
Thank you.
Bye.
'Dances With Wolves' door
is closed a lot these days.
I think they're having
trouble making a baby.
I don't think they're
having trouble at all.
If we pull the smoke flap shut,
they will come out for sure.
'Dances With Wolves',
are you in there?
Today I am riding away
to a far away place.
I would like you to ride with me.
It's good to be out.
Yes, it must be.
We are trying for a baby.
No waiting?
No waiting.
I was just thinking that of all
the trails in this life ...
there is one that matters most.
It is the trail of a true human being.
I think you are on this trail,
and it is good to see.
We call you the Busy Bee.
It is said that all the
animals were born here.
That from here they spread over
the prairies to feed all the people.
Even our enemies agree
that this is a sacred place.
It's quiet here.
We must wait for these people.
No, they've been gone a week.
Maybe more.
We will water the horses and go home.
You always ask about the white people.
You always want to know
how many more are coming.
There will be a lot, my friend.
More than can be counted.
How many?
Like the stars.
It makes me afraid for all the Sioux.
We should tell this to 'Ten Bears'.
The men who wore this came ...
in the time of my
grandfather's grandfather.
Eventually we drove them out.
Then the Mexicans came.
They do not come here anymore.
In my own time, the Texans.
They have been like all the others.
They take without asking.
I don't know if we are
ready for these people.
But I think you are right.
I think they will keep coming.
When I think of that,
I look at this helmet.
Our country is all that we have,
and we will fight to keep it.
Tomorrow we will
strike the village ...
and go to the winter camp.
You have everything
from the soldier fort?
Yes.
There's nothing for me there.
That's good.
The journal.
Stands With ... Wait!
Words are important!
The words in the book are like a
trail for people to follow.
Now, it tells everything about
my life here. I must get it.
Enough.
We cannot wait for you.
I'll catch up.
Injun!
Get him! Injun!
No!
Stay down. Stay.
My God.
God.
It's okay.
Something has happened.
'Dances With Wolves' is not coming.
He must have trouble.
Pick two good men and send them
back to the soldier fort.
Spivey.
- Spivey!
- Yeah, Sergeant.
Tell the major he's waking up.
Move your worthless ass.
You got yourself
a hell of a shiner ...
didn't you?
Major's coming through.
Does he speak English?
I don't know, sir.
Speak English?
Talk English? Talk!
I speak English.
Who are you?
Lt. John J. Dunbar. This is my post.
Why are you dressed like this?
I came out from Fort Hayes last April,
but there was nobody here.
Do you have proof of that?
My journal's on the bunk in my quarters.
My orders are in the journal.
It will tell you everything.
Spivey, you and Edwards
were the first ones here.
Did you find anything? A journal?
No, we didn't find nothing, sir.
Where's Edwards?
He's outside.
He didn't find nothing either.
Somebody find me Edwards.
You turned Injun, didn't you?
Didn't you?
What did you say your name was?
Dunbar.
D-u-n-b-a-r. John.
You say you're an officer?
- God. Did you read my orders?
- No.
They're in my journal.
There are no orders.
There's no journal.
Why are you out of uniform?
I have to relieve myself.
- Sergeant, take care of him.
- Yes, sir.
Let's go.
- He's a white man.
- Doesn't look white to me.
- They say he's a soldier.
- He's an officer.
Do you salute him or shoot him?
Here, you. Eyes front.
I said eyes front!
Don't shoot him! Hit him! Get him!
Get him!
Why are you out of uniform?
What's the army doing out here?
- Lieutenant's asking the questions.
- Bauer.
We're charged with apprehending ...
We're charged with apprehending hostiles
and recovering stolen property ...
retrieving white captives
taken in hostile raidings.
- There are no hostiles.
- We will ascertain that for ourselves.
If you'll guide us to these camps
and serve as an interpreter ...
your conduct will be re-evaluated.
- What conduct?
- With all due respect —
Your status as a traitor might
improve should you choose ...
to cooperate with the
United States Army.
There's nothing for you to do out here.
Are you willing to cooperate or not?
Speak up!
I am 'Dances With Wolves'.
What's that?
I have nothing to say to you.
You are not worth talking to.
Sergeant, form a detail and
take this man down to the river.
- Let him clean up his face.
- Yes, sir.
Not you, Spivey.
Lieutenant.
Major wants to see you.
Spivey.
Spivey. You got paper?
- What's it to you?
- Give me some, shit-bird.
Can you read?
No, I can't read.
What the hell's the difference?
You can't read either.
Now just give me some.
- Quick, give me some!
- All right. Hold your horses.
Bauer!
Let go of me!
Lap it up, Injun.
Go ahead. Lap it up.
You son of a bitch!
It's all right.
He's going to get hungrier, that's all.
But maybe that don't matter.
Word is they're going
to ship you back to Hayes.
And once you get there,
they gonna hang you.
Come on. Forget about him.
Go on. Get out of here.
Get up in there!
Spivey, what is that?
Looks like he's following us.
Hell, I'm going to shoot him.
Dang. You missed him.
- Don't shoot, damn it. It's my shot.
- Wait. I seen him first.
- Get down!
- Look at that stupid bastard.
He ain't even moving.
- Wait a minute! That's my shot.
- Shoot him!
Shoot him, Edwards.
He's standing there.
Shoot him!
Jesus Christ! Holy shit!
Bauer, get him off him!
He might have killed you.
I'll get that son of a bitch.
Sit down, goddamn it!
That's it. I got him!
Dead shot, boys. Come on.
Son of a bitch!
Get up!
I mean it! Get up!
Get up! Come on, get up!
What?
You bash that prisoner one more time,
I'll put those shackles on you.
You men get back here!
Goddamn it!
Boo.
Clear behind that stand of trees?
All right. Let's go.
I don't see nobody.
Indians!
No.
'Dances With Wolves' is quiet these days.
Is his heart bad?
Killing the soldiers at the river ...
was a good thing.
I did not mind killing those men.
I was glad to do it.
But the soldiers hate me now,
like they hate no other.
They think I am a traitor.
And they will hunt for me.
And when they find me,
they find you.
I think it would be wise
to move the village now.
I will be leaving.
I must go and talk with
those who would listen.
Quiet. You are hurting my ears.
Leave us alone.
You are the only white man
I have ever known.
I have thought about you a lot.
More than you know.
But I think you are wrong.
The man the soldiers are
looking for no longer exists.
Now there is only a Sioux
named 'Dances With Wolves'.
Let's smoke awhile.
"With 'Ten Bears', it was
always more than a while.
"There was purpose in everything he did
and I knew he wanted me to stay.
"But I was sure of myself.
"I would be an excuse and that's all
the army would need to find this place.
"I pushed him as far as I could
to move the camp ...
"but in the end he only smiled
and talked of simple pleasures.
"He reminded me that at his age
a good fire is better than anything.
"'Ten Bears' was an extraordinary man."
You have nothing to say?
What can I tell you?
What's ever on your mind.
You've made the decision.
My place is with you.
I go where you go.
You're not afraid?
No.
I told 'Ten Bears' we'd leave
when the snow breaks.
Did you tell everyone?
Not everyone.
It's all right.
You ...
finish your pipe?
Good pipe.
How ...
does it smoke?
I've never smoked it.
We come far ...
you and me.
I will not forget you.
'Dances With Wolves'.
I am 'Wind In His Hair'.
Do you see that I am your friend?
Can you see that you will
always be my friend?
Sergeant! Over here! Now!