(WOLF HOWLING)
(SQUEAKING)
(GROWLING)
(MAN YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
SAILOR:
What? What? It's here! Here!
(GROWLING)
(YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
CAPTAIN:
Overboard! Throw overboard!
(GROWLING)
CAPTAIN: Hurry up!
(CAPTAIN YELLING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
SAILOR: It is stuck!
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GROWLING)
(CAPTAIN SCREAMING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
MAN: (SINGING)
Onward Christian soldiers
Get back! Get back!
- Marching as to war
- They're all crazy!
MAN: Get off!
Swales, for God's sake,
give these poor wretches
some laudanum to calm
their shattered nerves!
- They won't take nothing, Dr. Seward!
- Well, give them something, anything!
I can't. Get away, come on.
Dr. Seward! Dr. Seward,
where's Miss Lucy?
Where's Miss Lucy to
help with my baby?
Mrs. Galloway, where
is my daughter?
Miss Lucy's upstairs
in the house, sir,
looking after that friend of hers.
Fine time to abandon us.
Swales, I'm coming down.
- Swales, I'm coming down. Out of the way!
- All quiet, sir!
"But anyway, you needn't worry.
"As soon as you finish law school,
"I'm sure our firm will
hire you in a second."
Hey.
"You will make a beautiful addition to the
firm of Snodgrass, Shilling and Wallop."
Oh! Oh, Lord! Quick!
Oh! Is it all right?
Yes, yes.
You know, Lucy,
you're so much braver
than I am, taking on all
those men like that.
But don't you think we ought to have
some influence, some say on things?
- After all, we are not chattels.
- We are not chattels.
- No, I know we're not.
- Miss Lucy.
Yes?
Your father says he needs
you in the wards right away.
- Yes, I'm coming.
- Do you have to go now, Lucy?
- Yes, into bed with you.
- All right.
- Here we go.
- Thank you.
Now, remember, Mina,
if you don't rest, you'll be stuck
in this bedroom all winter.
Yes, you're quite right.
- You go down to them. I'll be fine.
- Good night, darling.
Good night.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Lucy, we've got our work cut out.
I'm sorry, Papa, but Mina isn't
feeling at all well tonight.
I know she's our friend, but, really,
Mina's never feeling very well.
Now, Papa, that's not fair.
We invited her here for her health,
and we have to look after her.
Oh, Annie, don't
worry, I'll take him.
Let me take him, darling.
There we are.
Oh, it can't be as bad as that.
(BELLS TOLLING)
Bells!
What, bells?
Hollow bells! Listen!
Sunken bells.
Sunken bells. Are you mad, Swales?
It's just the church bells to
warn the ships, that's all.
(BELLS TOLLING)
(GROWLING)
(HOWLING)
(SNARLING)
MAN: That's it.
A little bit more. Right.
Come on, you two, get your
hands out of your pockets.
No, no, no!
Say, keep them bits
of timber separate.
Tell them women to get out of
the way if they're not helping.
WOMAN:
It's freezing, isn't it? Freezing.
Come on, now, son,
grab hold of this.
It'll give our mum some
tidy frocks, won't it, Dad?
Hey, watch that boom! It'll
knock your bloody head off.
Not likely. The thing
about these wrecks...
WOMAN 1: Hey, what is it?
WOMAN 2: He's in that contraption.
Perhaps it will have your
fingers up. But all right.
Aye, aye.
Should we not hitch the...
Leave all that there.
WOMAN: Morning, sir.
- Fancy.
- That he is! He's fancy.
- Sorry, no one allowed on board.
- I've got business on board.
- What sort of business?
- I'm a solicitor, Jonathan Harker,
and I've been on the road
all night from London.
SEWARD: Jonathan!
It's all right, let him pass.
Right. Carry on.
What the devil are you doing here?
Our firm was telegraphed yesterday
that this ship had been
sighted a week early.
Oh, God.
The man we represented
in the purchase
of Carfax Abbey, Count Dracula...
Count Dracula, of course!
- How stupid of me, I almost forgot in all...
- Is he safe?
- Who?
- Dracula.
Oh, yes. He's the only one who is.
Young Mina found him on the beach
last night, and we took him to Carfax.
As for the rest of the crew...
Look.
(FLIES BUZZING)
HARKER: What happened?
We don't know. Maybe
the ship's log will tell us.
MAN: All right, swing
them across, Harry.
Excuse me. Is all this
cargo the Count's?
Well, there's more down below,
but the rest of the crates
broke up on them rocks.
Filled up with some kind of dirt.
Dirt? What for?
Whatever it is, I'll take it.
I'll put it on me wagon.
You can't do that, Renfield.
The Count's not here
to sign for them
and they stay here until
he comes around himself.
I'm sorry, Harbormaster, but
the rights of the ship owner
are already completely sacrificed,
since the tiller of this
vessel is held in a dead hand.
Now, where's the rest of Dracula's
baggage? I'd like to inspect that as well.
- Come this way.
- Harker,
you sold me house right out
from under me and you sold
that poor old Count a right bill of
goods with your fancy silver tongue.
SEWARD: Renfield!
I've half a mind to tell
Dracula he been took good.
Mr. Renfield!
I wonder if I could impose upon you
to ask the Count when he rises
if he would join us for dinner
tonight at Billerbeck Hall.
What, at the loony bin?
At my home, Mr. Renfield. Come.
Well, I'll give him the message,
but I don't think he'll be in the
mood for any fancy socializing.
MAN: A little bit more.
MAN: Morning, ma'am.
Jonathan!
Thank God, you're here!
We've had the most...
There, there, that's
enough of that.
Save that till after
you're married.
I can't tell you how
dreadful it's been.
- Mina went...
- Slow down, Lucy, Lucy, Lucy.
Lucy, slow down. I had to come up
here to meet your new neighbor.
It was terrifying. Mina found
him washed up on the beach.
It's a miracle he's not dead.
God, you look lovely, Lucy.
I look dreadful. I haven't
been to bed all night.
(GRUNTING)
Now. Now, for the stairs.
(CREAKING)
(GRUNTING)
(WHIMPERS)
This is the last one.
And lucky for you, 'cause
I'm not a bloody machine.
(BAT SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
SEWARD: Pushed along
by the storm, no doubt.
No storm could have caused
that captain's throat wound.
I've never seen
anything so ghastly.
Oh, please, Jonathan,
not before dinner.
(SIGHS) I'm sorry.
And, Dr. Seward, that wolf
or dog or whatever it was...
Oh, a dog, I'm sure.
Probably the ship's mascot.
Early this morning, that big dog
belonging to the
dustman were found,
dead as a doornail.
Had its throat tore away.
- Tore away?
- Aye.
By some savage claw, they say.
Count Dracula.
Good evening.
- Miss Seward.
- SEWARD: Good evening, Count.
Dr. Seward. Miss Van Helsing.
My savior.
I trust you're feeling improved.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
I don't think she
looks well at all.
Well, perhaps a trifle pale.
HARKER: Count Dracula,
we haven't actually met.
SEWARD: Uh, this is, uh...
Yes, Jonathan Harker,
my new English solicitor.
I have enjoyed our correspondence.
And I, too, I must say.
I must thank you for finding me
an extraordinary house
here in Whitby.
HARKER: It's a pleasure.
(LAUGHING) I'm sorry.
But I don't see how anyone,
except possibly Milo Renfield,
could spend even a
day at Carfax Abbey.
A house, Miss Seward, cannot
be made habitable in a day.
And after all, how few days
go to make up a century.
Sorry, I don't understand.
I am of an old family.
To live in a new house would
be impossible for me.
SWALES:
I got dinner hot, if anybody cares.
I care, Mr. Swales. Come on, Lucy.
Come along, Count. Food.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
Miss Van Helsing.
It is difficult for me
to express precisely,
but there seemed to be a doom over the
ship from the moment we left Varna.
Count, um, some wine?
You haven't...
No, thank you, Doctor.
I never drink wine.
Before you arrived, we were
looking at the ship's log.
- It wasn't lost at sea?
- No.
The very last entry
was a strange word.
A word that Mina thought
meant "undead."
Undead?
Yes. Nosferatu.
Ah! It means, "not dead."
You were right.
No, with your permission and all
due respect to Miss Van Helsing...
Yes, I'm quite finished, thank you.
There is a distinction.
- The words "not dead," you see...
- SWALES: Damn!
Carry the simple meaning...
Dead, undead. I don't care.
They all frighten me.
Oh, I love to be frightened.
Do you?
(WALTZ MUSIC PLAYING)
This is written in an
obscure regional dialect.
The captain was a
Magyar. I am Szekely.
Unfortunately, I can't
translate it for you.
Magyar.
Szekely.
I had no idea, Count, that
your country was so complex.
Oh, yes, it is, Doctor, indeed.
It's very, very complex.
- MINA: More coffee?
- SEWARD: Mmm.
So, you've come to England,
Count, to settle down?
To settle down? No, hardly that.
I've come to wander through
the crowded streets of London,
or to be here, in the midst of
the whirl and rush of humanity.
To share its life,
its change, its death.
You...
You have a great
lust for life, Count.
How well you phrase it.
(GASPING)
- SWALES: Miss Van Helsing!
- Oh!
- Mina.
- I'm all right.
I'm all right. I'm just dizzy.
Swales, get the laudanum.
DRACULA: No. No drugs.
You must not pollute her blood.
Put her here on the couch.
(GROANING)
(GASPING)
Forgive me, Doctor. You see, in my
country, we are a simpler people.
The strain of the last day has been
too much for you, Miss Van Helsing.
And I am the cause, I fear.
No, no, no. It's just...
It's just this...
This pain in my head.
It runs down here into my neck.
I can remove this pain.
Yes, and so can I.
Swales, get my...
No. Such pains yield
readily to suggestion.
If you mean hypnotism, she'd
be better off having the pain.
Why?
I suspect Mr. Harker thinks
of some ugly waving of arms.
That is not my method.
Now, look at me.
When I will you to do a
thing, it shall be done.
Hear and obey.
From now on, you have no pain.
- And no will of her own, either.
- SEWARD: Lucy!
I admire your candor, Miss Seward.
It is precisely the
kind of stimulating
encounter I'd hoped to
find here in England.
- HARKER: Indeed.
- Yes, indeed.
I despise women
with no life in them.
No blood.
When you awake,
you will remember nothing.
Good Lord! Was it
something that I said?
DRACULA: Now, Mr. Harker,
come. We must talk seriously.
I want to sign the deed to
my new home here in England.
- Of course.
- LUCY: Tonight? I won't hear of it.
This was meant to be a party
to welcome our new neighbor.
Come, Count.
Come and dance with me.
- But I hardly know...
- It doesn't matter. I'll teach you.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
I meant,
I hardly know you.
Nonsense.
(LAUGHING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(WHISPERING) Jonathan?
Jonathan?
HARKER: Boo!
Oh, my God, Jonathan!
- Don't ever do that!
- Oh. (SHUSHING)
I thought you loved
to be frightened.
I think I shall go back
to bed, Mr. Harker.
Mr. Harker, is it?
I see. Looks like I'm not gonna be good
enough for the likes of you anymore.
Hobnobbing with
royalty now, are we?
Really, Jonathan, you pretend
to be so utterly modern.
- We were just dancing.
- Just dancing!
That's a right amazing
way of putting it.
Do you know, Jonathan,
if you go on being cross,
you're going to sprout
the most enormous wart
right on the end of your nose.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(MOANING)
(HANDLE RATTLING)
(GASPING)
(MINA GASPING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GASPING)
(WOLF HOWLING)
It's nothing.
(LAUGHING)
It's just a dog.
(GASPING)
Bloody hell, that hurts.
Bloody heck.
(MUMBLING)
Pump.
(PUMP SQUEAKING)
Oh...
Oh.
Here we go.
Nice and fat and juicy.
(CHUCKLING)
- (SCREAMS)
- Good evening.
It will not open.
You have nothing to fear.
I'm accustomed to barring my home.
There are wolves in Transylvania.
Not here, there ain't.
You must have patience with me.
You must try to understand me.
I can reward you with
a long and fruitful life,
but I must have your loyalty.
Can you give that?
Then come.
I've been bit by a bat.
Yes, I see.
MAN: Go on, then, lads.
Let the dog see the rabbit.
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Good morning, Dad. We got that.
Good morning, Burt.
- Morning, Billy, lad.
- Tally-ho.
WOMAN: Come now! Mind yourself!
Mind where you're going!
(CYCLE BELL RINGING)
(GASPING)
Mina?
What is it? Mina, what's
wrong? What is it?
The moonlight...
And the flapping...
- (BELL RINGING)
- Papa! Papa, come quickly!
Darling, try and tell
me what's wrong.
- I... I...
- What is it?
(CHOKING)
LUCY: Papa, come quickly!
- Papa, help her!
- What's wrong with her?
She can't breathe.
(STAMMERING)
My throat pains me so.
I can't get any air.
There's plenty. Take a deep breath.
- HARKER: What happened?
- I don't know.
She's so white. Asphyxia.
Just breathe in, darling.
Just breathe.
Mina, breathe.
- SEWARD: Breathe, please.
- LUCY: Try!
- Mina, breathe! Breathe! Mina!
- Try, darling.
- Mina, breathe, breathe!
- I can't breathe!
Oh, Papa, stop it!
- Breathe!
- Oh, Father, be careful!
Breathe! Mina, Mina! Breathe!
Oh, Papa, stop it!
Breathe, breathe.
- Try, darling, just...
- Breathe.
SEWARD: Breathe.
(GASPING)
(CHOKING)
Oh, my God, Papa. She's dead.
(LUCY CRYING)
Look at her throat!
Two punctures.
(LUCY SOBBING)
Not very large, but not wholesome.
Not wholesome, Papa?
What are you talking about?
Jonathan, get her out
of here. Jonathan, please.
12, Van Briggle Strasse, Amsterdam.
Yes, Professor Abraham Van Helsing.
Now, read the whole thing
back to me like a good girl.
Nothing for me, thank you.
Come on. You need your strength.
I should never have left her alone.
That's preposterous!
You had no way of knowing.
SEWARD:
Mina has died. No, not lied! Died!
Telegraph or come at once.
Your dear friend in this saddest
of occasions, Jack Seward. Yes.
Well, I do hope the
professor gets it.
The poor, poor man.
Poor Mina.
Do you think it was
her heart, Doctor?
Or that pain in her
head last night?
I don't know. It's so long since
I've practiced real medicine.
What do you think killed her?
Killed her? That's an odd word.
Yet there was no sign of disease.
What about those marks on her neck?
Marks on her neck.
Hmm. Perhaps she injured
herself fastening her shawl.
Oh, Father, don't be absurd.
You saw those wounds.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(SQUEAKING)
Hello?
Is anyone at home?
Count Dracula!
You needn't shout, Mr. Harker.
You frightened me.
I'm sorry.
I had a key. I had
to let myself in.
I wonder where Renfield can be.
I don't know.
I knocked, but he didn't...
Yes, well, the man is worthless.
It doesn't matter. At any rate,
you are here. Welcome. Come up.
Thank you.
Hello.
Good evening.
I'm sorry to hear of Miss
Van Helsing's death.
You know already?
Yes. News of death travels fast.
She was very ill.
I could tell last night when
I looked into her eyes.
Yeah. She'd been
frail all her life.
Oh, your key. I only had it
to inspect the property.
Yes, of course. Have you
brought the original deed?
Here.
If you'd like to
sign at the bottom.
And some customs documents
for your crates.
Now, I didn't know what
to say of their contents.
- Soil.
- Soil?
Just plain dirt.
Transylvanian earth.
I have a keen interest in botany.
Can you drive to London at
once to record the deed?
No.
Tomorrow. I must stay
with Lucy for the funeral.
Oh, yes. Of course.
- She's taking it...
- Not well.
She blames herself.
She was with me when
Mina was taken ill.
I see. And you and Miss
Seward will marry?
Yeah, I suppose so.
If I can ever persuade her
to settle down long enough.
Yes. She is stronger than
most women, isn't she?
(CHUCKLES) Yes, she is.
I must be getting back now.
Mr. Harker, would you deliver
this letter to Dr. Seward for me?
Of course.
I should like to offer
his daughter and he
the hospitality of my
home after the funeral.
You're welcome, of course, but
you are leaving, are you not?
- Good evening.
(YELLING)
I want you to help me!
Take me away from
this cursed place!
Let go of me, you bloody idiot!
You've got to help me!
You've got to save me!
Please, you've got to help me!
Help me get away from...
(GRUNTING)
(BAT SQUEAKING)
Get him in the clink, Mr. Swales.
(RENFIELD MUMBLING IN PROTEST)
SWALES: Hold the door,
Dr. Seward. Quick, please.
RENFIELD: Let me go! Please!
Get him in! Come on!
RENFIELD: The stench in here!
Don't you ever clean it out, Swales?
SWALES: Hold him! Hold him there!
The master's angry. He promised
me lives, not little ones.
Flies and spiders, but
big ones. Human lives.
PRIEST: "I am the
resurrection and the life.
"He that believeth in me, yea, though
he were dead, yet shall he live.
"And whosoever believeth
in me shall never die."
"I know that my redeemer liveth,
"and that I shall rise out of
the earth on the last day,
"and shall be covered
again with my skin
"and shall see the
Lord in my flesh."
"Behold, I show you a mystery.
"When the trumpet shall sound, the
dead shall be raised incorruptible,
"and we shall be changed.
"Then shall be brought to pass that
which says, 'Death, where is thy sting?
"'0, grave, where is thy victory?"'
(SOBBING)
HARKER: I don't see why not.
For God's sake, Lucy,
it'll do you no good
to stay around here
feeling sorry for yourself.
Feeling guilty for no reason.
You don't understand, Jonathan.
I don't want to feel happy,
to feel silly. Not now.
Then I'll come back tomorrow night.
You needn't, I can manage.
Can you?
Jonathan, let's not part enemies.
We're not enemies.
SEWARD: Lucy.
Oh, Lucy.
Mina's father, uh,
Professor Van Helsing,
is arriving from Paris this evening,
and we shall have to meet him.
I'm afraid we shall be
unable to take advantage of
Count Dracula's kind
invitation to dinner.
Invitation to dinner?
- You didn't tell me...
- Didn't I?
Well, it doesn't matter now, I'll
have to send word around excusing us.
- No, I'll go.
- Go?
- I should have thought you'd rather...
- As a courtesy.
He's sending a carriage
round at 8:00.
So, if you, uh...
(SHOVEL DIGGING)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
MAN: Whitby. Whitby.
This is Whitby station.
This train will call
at Scarborough,
Bridlington and Kingston upon Hull.
VAN HELSING: Ah, porter.
MAN: Whitby. Whitby.
There are two
portmanteaux in there.
Abraham!
Abraham.
In my own house.
How can I ever...
What happened?
What in God's name
could have happened?
I don't know, I don't know.
Jack, Jack, you must explain to me.
I insist. From the beginning.
- As patiently as you can.
- I am baffled.
(DOOR THUDDING)
(HINGES CREAKING)
Hello?
(GASPING)
Is anyone here?
Count Dracula?
DRACULA: Good evening.
Welcome to Carfax
Abbey, Miss Seward.
Thank you.
I regret Mr. Harker and your
father were unable to join us.
Let me see to your comfort.
Of course, you examined
her with great care.
There were no
functional causes. None.
She'd been nervous certainly.
- Sleepwalking.
- Sleepwalking?
Nightmares. I prescribed laudanum.
What? Laudanum?
For nervous prostration.
But a great loss of blood...
How?
Mina was so young.
So are you.
Tonight, I feel positively ancient.
There are worse things than
death. You must believe me.
If there are, I can't imagine them.
I have buried many friends,
and I, too, am weary.
I am the last of my kind,
descended from a conquering race.
My family was its heart's
blood, its brains, its swords.
But the warlike days are over.
Anyway, it's not healthy
to live in the past.
No, it isn't.
Jonathan Harker tells me
you speak some Rumanian.
- Oh, hardly...
- (SPEAKING IN RUMANIAN)
There, you do understand.
No, really, I have no
idea what you said.
I said it would be
nice to see you smile.
Then you should be pleased.
Oh, I am.
But I must warn you to take care.
Whatever for?
If at any time my company
does not please you,
you will have only
yourself to blame,
for an acquaintance who
seldom forces himself,
but is difficult to be rid of.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Murder! She's murdered my baby!
What's going on here?
Stop her! Stop her!
Help me! She's murdered my baby!
My God, no, Annie!
(ANNIE WAILING)
Annie! No!
No, Annie! Annie!
Stop her! She killed him!
No, Annie! Please don't!
(WAILING)
What's happening?
Two punctures directly
into the aorta?
She just opened the door
like she had a key!
She said could she
have my little Alex.
No, no, no. Please, please.
(ANNIE SOBBING)
And she was as hot
as a burning coal,
and her eyes were red like rubies,
and her lips all drawn back
and her breath so foul.
And she had these
long dreadful teeth
like fangs of a wolf,
like nothing from this earth.
Then she grabbed him
and I grabbed her.
And the next thing I remembered,
she's kneeling on the floor.
This woman, you did not know her?
Yes, I did. I did so.
It was Miss Lucy's friend, Mina,
that we put in the earth yesterday.
(ANNIE SOBBING)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
Listen to them.
The children of the night.
What sad music they make.
Do you think it's sad?
So lonely, like weeping.
I think it's a wonderful sound.
I really love the night.
It's so simple.
So deceptive.
So exciting!
You take the dawn for granted.
The warm, hot sunlight.
Ah.
But the night...
- Was made to enjoy.
- Yes.
Yes, it was.
It was made to enjoy life
and love.
Look at me. Look.
- You must forgive me.
- What for?
For intruding on your life.
I came of my own accord.
You should perhaps go.
No, I'd rather stay.
- It will be light soon.
- Not for hours yet.
I will see you again.
Oh, please.
SEWARD: Abraham?
Ah, Jack.
Will you take some breakfast?
Oh, yes, thank you, Jackie.
A little later, perhaps,
if you please. Thank you.
LUCY: Professor,
you should come inside now,
it's getting very cold.
I was just sitting
a while with Mina.
What are these?
Ah! Those tiny flowers are
from the garlic plant.
Whatever for?
Do you believe in
corporeal transference?
- No.
- In materialization?
- And not in astral bodies?
What is this to do with Mina?
You know the legends
of central Europe
of the werewolves and vampires.
Vampires?
Creatures who suck the
blood of the living.
You aren't saying
that you believe...
- that Mina was attacked by...
- A creature that is dead...
and yet not dead, a thing
that lives after its death
- by drinking...
- Oh, no!
It must have blood,
- or it dies an agonizing death.
- Please, stop.
Miss Lucy?
I wonder if I may?
This was to be Mina's
for her birthday.
She would want you to have it
and to wear it always.
Always.
Good evening, Miss.
Good evening.
I am Count Dracula.
Abraham Van Helsing.
Then it is your daughter,
sir, who brings me here.
I have come to pay my respects.
What is that around your neck?
This?
It's a gift from
Professor Van Helsing.
How kind.
LUCY: We were just going inside.
Perhaps you'd like to join us?
No, thank you.
With your permission, sir.
With my blessing.
Do sit down, Professor.
I'll bring you some tea.
Thank you, Miss Lucy.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(WOLF HOWLING)
Abraham, this is nonsense!
This is witchcraft!
This beast can tell us nothing.
There are no such
things as vampires.
(GROWLING)
(WOLF HOWLING)
(BELL TOLLING)
(NEIGHING)
There's nothing but the
Lord's own dead out here.
MAN: I can't hold him!
VAN HELSING: Let him go, man!
What if he should break a leg?
VAN HELSING: He won't.
Look, how alert!
You see, he knows.
He will find out where
lies the vampire
just as surely as you, Jack Seward,
could palpate a human cancer.
(NEIGHING)
Stop him! Dear God
in heaven, stop him.
Now, it is you, my
best beloved one.
You will be flesh of my flesh,
blood of my blood.
You shall cross land or
sea to do my bidding.
I need your blood.
I need...
(MOANING)
(GASPING)
Give me a wrenching iron, Jack.
Hold up the cross.
(WOOD CRACKING)
(GRUNTING)
That's not possible.
I saw her put...
Body snatchers!
SEWARD: The mines!
They run underneath the
entire town, everywhere.
(STAMMERING) No! No, Abraham,
please! I beg of you. No!
(BATS SQUEAKING)
(BATS SCREECHING)
(SHOUTS)
The cross.
The cross!
Mina?
Papa.
(SPEAKING IN DUTCH)
(SCREAMING)
SEWARD: Mina, no!
(MINA SNARLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SIZZLING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
Papa.
(VAN HELSING SOBBING)
- Mr. Harker.
- Mrs. Galloway,
I'm sorry to knock you up at
this hour, but is Miss Lucy...
In her room, sound asleep.
Which is where we should all be,
if we had more common sense.
(CHUCKLING) Yes, you're right.
I think I'll do the same. I'll
wait till morning to say hello.
Good night.
(KNOCKING)
Lucy?
It's Jonathan.
Lucy, what's the matter?
Lucy!
Lucy, what is it? Lucy!
- Come, Abraham, we need to get...
- JONATHAN: Lucy!
- Jonathan.
- Dr. Seward.
- Thank God, you're back.
- Doctor, quickly. Lucy, she's so cold.
Professor.
She has lost a great deal of blood.
There's scarcely any pulse.
She'll have to be given
a blood transfusion.
Pray to God that one
of us has her type.
Swales!
Take these and rub them against
the inside of all
doors and windows.
Crush them against
the glass, so that
the fragrance permeates
the whole room
and keeps away all evil, and don't
forget the little room in there.
Oh, good God, Professor.
Not garlic.
I'm sick to my stomach as it is.
Are you feeling weak?
No, it doesn't matter.
She needs more than
your blood, Jonathan.
What she doesn't need is to breathe
the odor from those
wretched plants.
Do not trifle with me. There
is a grim purpose in all I do.
- Just a little bit longer.
- All right.
(GROANING)
Ah, the devil.
DRACULA: I'm not as bad as that.
I did not hear you come in, Count.
I am often told I have
a light footstep.
I was looking in the mirror.
It reflects the whole room,
and yet I cannot see...
Forgive me, Doctor.
I dislike mirrors.
They are the playthings
of man's vanity.
You are a most unusual
creature, Count Dracula.
Yes.
How is the fair patient?
Her diagnosis presents
difficulties.
I feared it might, my friend.
Would you care to see what
I have prescribed for her?
Anything that you
prescribe for Miss Lucy
has the greatest interest for me.
My prescription is a
most unusual one.
(GASPING)
You are a wise man, Professor,
for one who has not lived
even a single lifetime.
You flatter me, Count.
But not wise enough to
return to Holland at once,
now that you have learned
what you have learned.
I prefer to remain.
In the past 500 years, Professor,
those who have crossed
my path have all died,
and some not pleasantly.
Come here!
Your will is strong.
Then I must come to you.
Sacrilege.
Sacrilege!
(WOLF GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(WOLF HOWLING)
Abraham, the color's
returning to Lucy's cheeks.
Professor?
Abraham, what has happened to you?
Dracula has been here.
What for?
- He came to kill me.
- SEWARD: What?
It is he who is the vampire.
SEWARD: Abraham, this night
has been a monstrous...
He came to kill me, and now
he will prey upon you.
What's happening?
Please, for God's sake! Will
someone tell me what is happening?
HARKER: She looks...
Alive?
She's the devil's undead.
Nosferatu.
You can't seriously
expect me to believe that
Count Dracula is
some hideous monster.
I don't expect you
to believe anything
but what is.
What are you gonna do?
To save her soul,
I must take out her heart.
Heavens and earth, no!
It's not your choice.
She was my daughter.
If we fail here,
it is not merely a matter
of life and death,
it is that we shall
become such as she.
- That we and your Lucy...
- No, it's not possible!
May become foul things
of the night. There is work.
Wild work to be done.
And now,
are the powers of all the devils
against us.
No!
- LUCY: Mrs. Galloway.
- Yes?
Would you be kind enough to make me
a cup of tea? I feel rather cold.
No wonder.
The doctor's orders were
that you should stay in bed.
But how he thinks I could
keep you there, I don't know.
(DOOR CLOSING)
- Mrs. Galloway.
- Good morning, Mr. Harker.
- Where's Lucy? You're supposed...
- Oh, she's in her room.
She's looking much better
and asking for tea.
(HOOVES GALLOPING)
I'll get the car.
HARKER: Lucy, stop!
For God's sake, Lucy! Stop!
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Get out of my way, Jonathan.
There! Now, you must believe me.
Lucy, no. You can't
possibly go to him.
He's no danger to me.
He's a monster! A vampire!
- You're fools, all of you!
- No!
She means to warn him.
Jonathan, if you try to stop me,
I shall kill myself.
I charge you on your
living soul, Lucy Seward,
that you do not die
or think of death
until this great evil
which has fouled
your life is true dead himself!
You dare try to confuse me!
Tormenting him who is the
saddest, the kindest of all.
Kind?
If I could send his soul to
everlasting, burning hell, I would!
I despise you. All of you.
Get out of my way.
- Lucy, no!
- Let me go!
Let me go!
You must not go.
No!
Be calm.
(WHISPERING) Be calm.
(MOANING)
Take her home, Jack.
Watch over her.
Abraham, what are you going to do?
Miss Lucy's life is at
stake and so is her soul.
Jonathan and I must go and find
this monster and
utterly destroy it.
(HINGES CREAKING)
HARKER: Oh, God, what a stench!
(HARKER GROANING)
Take the cross, Jonathan.
Take the cross.
(CREAKING)
Gentlemen, how kind of you to call.
I have underestimated your
powers, Count Dracula,
to move about in daylight hours.
It is always daylight somewhere
on Earth, Professor.
After my rest, my need is
only to stay in darkness.
(CREAKING)
(DOOR SLAMMING)
You fools.
Do you think with your crosses and
your wafers you can destroy me?
Me!
You do not know how many
men have come against me.
I am the king of my kind!
You have accomplished
nothing, Van Helsing.
Time is on my side.
In a century, when you are dust,
I shall wake and call Lucy,
my queen, from her grave.
- No.
- Yes.
I have in my time had
many brides, Mr. Harker,
but I shall set Lucy
above them all.
You won't get Lucy.
She's mine already.
No!
(SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
God!
HARKER: Damn you!
(THUDDING)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
Help me, Professor!
Professor!
Oh, no!
(BAT SCREECHING)
(SPEAKING IN DUTCH)
(PRAYING IN LATIN)
But I helped him.
I saw that two of those crates were
safely delivered from the ship.
Yes, but you must
not blame yourself.
He probably had other coffins
brought to him other ways.
You know this man's cunning.
Pity my poor Lucy,
then. He's probably
got them scattered all
over Whitby by now.
Then we'll find them and
tear them open, one by one.
- In there? She can't be so ill.
- I couldn't help it.
When she came round, she
was like a wild thing.
You have given her
medication? Laudanum?
My own daughter? Certainly not.
No, please. Can I have a
moment alone with her?
Please, I must. I must.
But remember, Jonathan,
she's not what she will seem.
Jonathan.
What happened to your face?
You're frightened of
me, too, aren't you?
Oh, I can't bear it.
I don't understand. I don't understand.
What's happening to me?
You seem yourself again.
I've never felt so weak.
Weak? You have the
strength of 10 men.
Jonathan, can you still love me?
I worship you.
(WHISPERING) I worship you.
Will you tell me something?
Of course.
What were you doing, you and
my father and the professor,
in the cemetery to Mina?
I can't... I can't...
You say you love me,
but you don't trust me.
I would trust you with
my life, my soul.
Then tell me, what were you doing?
You and the professor at Carfax.
I only want to know if
you can still love me.
Oh, Lucy, please. Please.
There's no need to
hide your schemes
and your plots from me, is there?
No.
Jonathan, it's no use.
Whatever he wants to
know, he finds out.
He knows everything you
think, everything you do.
Lucy, stop, please!
- All right. All right.
- Stop it!
- No.
- Don't worry.
No. Lucy, please.
There's nothing to be
frightened of, I love you.
- I love you.
- No.
(SHUSHING)
(WHISPERING)
I love you. I love you. I love you.
- No, please.
- I love you.
(MOANS)
(SNARLING)
(HARKER SCREAMING)
Professor! Professor!
(LUCY SCREAMING)
Oh, no.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
(WHIMPERING)
LUCY: Oh, no.
(GASPING)
(SOBBING)
- SEWARD: She'll sleep now.
- HARKER: But shouldn't we stay with her?
It's all right. My people
will look after her.
- You two, you need some rest.
- MAN: Give me them back!
Give me them back!
- Give me them back, you old niggly.
- What?
Dr. Seward, make him
give me them back.
- He's collecting bugs.
- SEWARD: Bugs?
And he's eating them alive.
He's disgusting!
You'll see what
disgusting is tonight...
- Hey, get down there!
- ...when he comes.
- Excuse me. When who comes, please?
- You know.
Give me them back, you
crab-faced old buzzard.
You've got no blood in you, anyway.
And besides, I've got one
here that you didn't find.
Right, in the straitjacket with him.
Get him in. Come on.
SEWARD: Do you think Dracula
will come back tonight?
Of course he will.
Well, we must obviously be ready.
(WOLF HOWLING)
Good evening.
(CLEARING THROAT)
(MUTTERING)
RENFIELD: They shouldn't
have tied me up like this.
I would have gone
quiet, like a kitten.
I'd like a kitten.
A nice, little,
sleek, playful kitten
that I could feed you to.
I'd play with him,
and I'd stroke him,
and I'd feed him and
feed him and feed him...
(RUSTLING)
Swales! Mr. Swales! Mr. Swales!
He's coming to get me. He's climbing
straight up the wall to get me.
I'm dying, and he's
laughing with his red mouth
and those sharp white
teeth of his like rats.
Hundreds and thousands
and millions of them.
(WHIMPERING)
Oh, God, help my poor soul.
Renfield.
I'm the slave. I'm the dog, master.
But please don't kill me.
For the love of God, let me live.
Did I not promise you
that you should come
to me at your death
and enjoy centuries
of life and power
over the bodies and
souls of others?
But I don't want human life.
(WHIMPERING)
You betrayed me. You sought
to warn them all against me.
Then punish me.
Torture me, I deserve it.
But please, let me live.
Oh, Renfield.
You disappoint me so.
(PATIENT SHOUTING)
(LOUD CRASHING)
(PATIENTS SCREAMING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(RUMBLING)
Oh, Miss Lucy! Miss Lucy!
Dracula?
Quick!
Miss Seward, sir! I don't
have the key! The key!
HARKER: Hurry, Doctor. Come on!
(WIND HOWLING)
HARKER: Quickly!
VAN HELSING: Lucy!
Lucy!
No! Come on!
SEWARD: Where is he taking her,
Abraham? Where is he taking her?
SEWARD: Go left, down the
lane here. Down the lane.
SEWARD: Faster! Won't this
contraption go faster?
HARKER:
It won't go any bloody faster.
SEWARD: The forest! Try the forest.
Lucy, come.
Come to me.
No, you must go on a bit longer
as a creature of the sun.
Only until we have left behind
those who would destroy us.
And then?
And then you will join
me on a higher plane,
feeding on them.
We will create more
of our kind, Lucy.
HARKER: Which way?
I know that way lies
Scarborough, but I don't know.
Listen Listen!
Hey! Hey! Hey, there, driver!
Tom Hindley, is that you?
Yes, sir. It's me. Morning.
What are you doing out
here at this hour?
I had to pick up another
of them damn crates
and take to the docks at
Scarborough, before I could get...
TOM: Whoa!
Whoa!
(HORSES NEIGHING)
Look, that crate!
Scarborough. The port!
- HARKER: Then he's leaving England.
- VAN HELSING: After him!
Hurry.
HARKER: Hindley!
- VAN HELSING: Pull in front of him.
- HARKER: For God's sake, stop, man!
Hindley!
I can't stop them!
For God's sake, what
are you doing, man?
I'm doing me best, aren't I?
Pull over, man! Pull over.
Hindley!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Whoa!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
MAN: You stupid ha'porth!
Maniac!
(SHOUTING AT HORSE)
Come! Come on!
Whoa, Billy! Hey! Ho!
Whoa, Billy! Hey!
Hindley!
Come on! Whoa! Hey, Billy.
HARKER: Hindley!
(SHOUTING)
(SCREAMING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
SEWARD: Look out!
This thing mocks us, Abraham.
If we are beaten,
then there is no God.
HARKER: The axle's cracked.
Scarborough, how far is it yet?
It's 10 miles. It's no use.
Come on, we must try.
FISHMONGER:
Fresh mackerel! Really fresh!
VENDOR: Eels, all fresh today!
(CAR HONKING)
Get your fresh mackerel,
two bob a box.
Where is it?
You, sir. This wagon.
You did see it arrive?
Is that the one with
the big crate on it?
HARKER: Yes, where is it?
It's out there, aboard
the Czarina Catherine,
- bound for Rumania.
- HARKER: Take us to her. We'll pay you.
VAN HELSING:
Please, we must catch that ship.
What?
You stay here in case they are
not on board. Keep well. Bye.
Take care.
- Hey! Stop!
- Hey! Hey!
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Dracula, where is he?
- (SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Count Dracula is on this ship!
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Nosferatu.
The cargo hold!
Where is it?
Come on!
Jonathan, here.
I see it.
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
No!
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GUN CLICKING)
(SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(DRACULA SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(MOANING)
(FLAPPING)
(WOLF HOWLING)