Nice fat deposit.
You're sure in the right business, Sally
Thank you
Well, good morning
Deposit
Another nice deposit
You and Sally are sure
in the right business.
I'm in a hurry, please
Hi, Kate
Have you cleaned up the house
across the way?
I haven't had time yet
You should always do that one first
Anne!
Come here
Did you ever see that kid out there before?
I think maybe he was in the bar last night
Send Joe in
Joe
Hello, Pretty Boy
-Call me, Kate?
Yeah. Take a look out the window
There's a kid Who's been following me
all the way to the bank and back.
Come here, you young squirt, come here
-You want me?
What's the idea of throwing that stone?
Any law against throwing stones?
You're tough? Come here!
What are you hanging around here for
anyway?
Would she talk to me?
-Kate?
What for? What do you want?
Just wanna talk to her
What do you want, you?
-Nothing.
You live around here?
In Monterey?
-Salinas.
What's your name?
You're not talking? Now, look
why are you following Kate around?
What's the idea, squirt?
Any law against following
around the town...
madam, whatever you call her?
I don't know if there's any law against it
but she don't like it.
She owns that house over there, too
don't she?
But don't you go hanging
around there, squirt. You're too young
Now come on. Now beat it
Is that her real name?
-Kate. Is that her real name?
Sure, as far as I know. Why?
What's her last name?
Nobody's got any last name
around here, kid. Why?
You tell her I hate her
I should have gone right on in there
Should have gone right on in there
and talked to her.
Cal wasn't home all night.
Boy, is he gonna catch it from Dad
You know what the girls in class call him?
-No, what?
The Prowler
-I'll tell him that.
You better not, Aron
Promise me you won't
-Why not?
Please don't. I don't want you
Hi, Cal
-Hi.
Hello, Cal
Excuse me for talking
We're going down to see the icehouse
that Dad's gonna buy.
Do you want to come?
-What icehouse?
The one he's buying
to freeze the vegetables with
He's been talking about it every night
for the last week.
Is Dad gonna be there?
Why sure, he's gonna buy it
I'll skip it
You're gonna have
to see him sometime, Cal
-Come on.
Hey, Aron
Yeah?
Why don't you ask me where I've been?
-Would you tell me?
-No.
Then what's the use of my asking?
-Is Dad mad at me?
Well, you were out all night
He was worried
Yeah, I bet
You gonna come or not?
Okay. I'll see you at supper
He's coming
You see, Will, I got the idea
from an article I read.
They dug up a mastodon
somewhere in Siberia.
Been in the ice for thousands of years
and the meat was still good.
Mastodon?
What have you got to say for yourself?
This is my son, Cal
When you were his age,
I imagine you thought it only right
to let your father know
before you stayed out all night
Or at least to offer some kind
of apology when you did come home
Well, times change
As I was saying,
a mastodon is a kind of elephant
Hasn't lived on the Earth for a long while
And the meat was still fresh?
-Sweet as a pork chop.
You're more excited about this
than you've been for a long time
Now, I seem to be, don't I?
See, Will, I've been sort of
in a rut out there in the ranch
Sixteen, 17 years, I've kept out of things
-I know.
But now I feel that
if I could only do something
some little thing for, before I die
some little thing for progress...
for people, maybe.
Call it anything you want
I might make up for all the years
I've been lying fallow.
So, lately I've been reading up all I can
about refrigeration.
And I can't get it out of my head
that you can keep anything good.
As long as you can get it cold enough
Like that mastodon there.
-Good afternoon, Abra.
Good afternoon, Mr. Trask
Hello, Mr. Hamilton
-Hello.
Hello, Son
-Hi, Dad.
Now my son, Aron, that is,
thinks I may have a good idea here
Dad wrapped a head of lettuce
in wax paper...
and kept it in our icebox
for over three Weeks...
and it still came out fresh and good
Right?
Quite right, Son
Dad, is it all right if we look around?
-'Course, Aron. Belongs to us now.
Do you know where the biggest market
for vegetables is in the winter?
-Where?
New York City
And they can't raise them there
But the railroad had promised me
those fruit cars.
Don't you have anything to say to me, Cal?
-Yeah.
it's about time. Well?
I read in the Monterey newspaper
that if we get into this war
there are gonna be some fortunes made
But you're gonna make them
in beans and corn, and stuff like that
You don't need all this ice
-You're perfectly right.
Beans are up to 3 cents
You wanna make a profit, you plant beans
And they keep, too, don't they?
But I'm not particularly interested
in making a profit, Cal.
Look here, Will
I'm not an inventor nor a scientist
but I know I have an idea here
I come from a whole family of inventors
People full of ideas like this one.
I'm the only one that didn't have an idea
and the only one that ever made a dime
You wanna make a profit, you plant beans
Put out that cigarette!
That place is full of sawdust!
Come on, Adam, he's just thoughtless
-Thoughtless? He's inconsiderate.
I don't know.
I'm at my rope's end with that boy
I don't understand him. I never have
Aron I've understood since he was a child
Help me up
He doesn't like anybody, does he?
-Who, Dad?
No, Cal
it's dark in here and spooky
Why is he so alone all the time?
-He wants to be.
Nobody wants to be alone all the time
Dad's made a wonderful buy, hasn't he?
We'll freeze vegetables.
It'll really give him something
to live for now.
What's the matter, Abra
don't you like Cal?
I guess I don't know him very well
-I love him.
Well, naturally, he's your brother
He's scary.
-Scary?
When he looks at you
Sort of like an animal
I don't know, he scares me
Aron, when are we gonna get married?
Just as soon as I get through
with that darned school.
I wish it was right now
-So do I.
Do you?
Abra
-When we get--
I love you, Aron
When we get married,
it's going to be perfect
Everything about it is going to be perfect
You're gonna make
a wonderful mother, Abra
I hope so
-You are.
A perfect one
You don't remember your mother at all
do you, Aron?
No, she died
right after Cal and I were born
Must be hard never to have had a mother
-What's that?
Look, what's he doing up there?
-Crazy guy.
He's watching us
-No, he isn't.
Yes, he is, too
Let's move over here. Aron
-He's not watching us.
I feel as if he can still see us
I love you, Aron
Really, I do. Really
Sure. I love you, too
Cal, stop! Stop that, Cal!
What are you doing? Stop it!
"Blessed is he
whose transgression is forgiven
whose sin is covered
"Blessed is the man unto whom
the Lord imputeth not iniquity...
and in whose spirit there is no guile
And you are forgiven, Cal
I think there is no iniquity
in your actions...
only something I do not know
Why did you push that ice down?
I don't know
Was it
Was it vengeance? Anger?
Fear that I would punish you
for not coming home last night?
What was it?
I wanted to see it slide down the chute
Perhaps you had better read from here on
-I'll read it, Dad.
No, it's for Cal to read
Start at the fifth verse
Verse 5
"I acknowledge my sin unto thee
and mine iniquity have I not hid.
I said, I will confess my transgressions
unto the Lord...
"and thou forgavest
the iniquity of my sin. Selah
Go on
Six
And I suggest a little slower, Cal
And you don't have to read
the verse numbers.
For this shall every one that is godly
pray unto thee.
And surely in the floods of great waters
they shall not come nigh unto him
Selah."
Seven
Not the numbers, Cal
"Thou art my hiding place,
thou shalt preserve me from trouble
"thou shalt compass me about
with songs of deliverance. Selah
-Eight.
You have no repentance! You're bad!
Through and through, bad
Excuse me. I'll go out and wait for Abra
You're right. I am bad.
I knew that for along time
I didn't mean that, Cal. I spoke in anger
Well, it's true
Aron's the good one
I guess there's just a certain amount
of good and bad you get
from your parents...
and I just got the bad
-That's not true.
Cal, listen to me
You can make of yourself
anything you want.
It's up to you. A man has a choice
That's where he's different from an animal
You don't listen. You'll never remember
My mother
she's not dead and gone to heaven
is she?
Why do you ask that?
She's not dead at all
She's not buried in the East
like you said, either.
She's alive
What makes you think so?
-I heard from a guy.
-Who?
I don't know his name
He was just passing through
How come you told Aron and me she died?
I thought it would save you pain
-Pain?
If she was still alive,
where do you think she'd be?
I have no idea. She went East
How do you know?
When she left the ranch we lived on
when you and Aron were born...
I heard she went East
What was she like? Was she bad?
I guess she
I never really knew what she was like
She wasn't like other people.
There was something she seemed to lack
Kindness, maybe. Conscience
I never knew what she was after
-How come she left you?
I never knew that, either
She was so full of hate
-Hate for you?
For everything
You won't tell Aron that she didn't die?
No
Must not do anything to hurt Aron
Where'd you get that scar
you got on your shoulder, Father?
I've told you, Cal
it's an old wound I got
in the Indian campaigns
-Why do you ask that now?
What'd she look like? Was she pretty?
She had the most lovely hands
Like ivory
She took such good care of them
Her mother had arthritis
She was always afraid
it would come to her in her hands
Talk to me, Father
I got to know who I am.
I got to know who I'm like
I got to know
Where is she?
I'm telling you, truthfully, Cal
after she left, I never heard from her
Cal, wait. I want to talk more with you
If you leave this room now
we may never be able to talk again
You coming home tonight, Cal?
What's the difference?
You're home. You're the one he wants
Good evening, Cal
High strung. Very high strung
Good evening, Abra.
Where is my chess victim?
He's waiting for you, Mr. Albrecht
-Good.
What do you suppose he meant by that?
Go on, beat it!
Your wife has called up three times
-My wife's a--
I know she is. Now beat it
Joe!
All right, fella, you've run out of money
Mr. Hawks
What do you want?
-I want--
What do you want to drink?
-Beer.
Hey!
Where's my drink?
-All right.
That's not very neat, is
it's okay
You'd better get out of here
-How come?
You're the one who followed Kate
this morning.
It's a free country, isn't it?
-it's a free country.
Only, Joe said if I saw you again
I was supposed to tell him.
You can tell him if you want to
You're just a kid, ain't you?
-I'm older than you are.
Yeah, sure, but that isn't
-Hey!
All right
Kid, please
you oughtn't to go around
throwing stones and things
That isn't nice. And drinking beer
There's Joe
Look, kid, please go.
You don't want to get yourself hurt
You could tell him now, if you want to
There's your chance.
You sure have got a nerve, haven't you?
-Do you know Kate?
This is Kate's place.
She's treating you okay?
-Sure.
I gotta go now, kid
Is she nice?
Don't let Joe see you, please
She doesn't treat you rough
or anything, does she?
Please, kid, I gotta go now
It was nice meeting you.
Isn't there anything nice about her at all?
What's the matter, kid?
She had pretty hands. Did you see them?
-Hands?
Did you look at them?
No, I don't think I ever saw them
She always wears gloves.
Where is she?
You mean now?
-Yeah.
Back in her office, probably
-Where's that?
Back that way
Will you show me?
Look, kid, please don't start any trouble
I'm not gonna start any trouble. Come on
We .... You can just point the door to me
and I'll go there.
No, honest
This is a tough place. I can't lose this job
I'm not very good at it, anyway
-You won't lose it.
If I step out of line
Kate will throw me out on my ear
Come on, will you?
You can just show me where the door is
Come on
Be a sport
There's the door
Thank you. You can go back now
What are you gonna do?
Please, kid, don't make any trouble
I'm not gonna make any trouble.
I'm gonna wait till you're gone. Okay?
Will you let me talk to you? Please
I gotta talk to you
Joe!
Get out of here! Joe! Tex!
Call the sheriff! Get him out!
Call the sheriff! Get him out of here!
I want to talk to her!
I want to talk to you!
Please, talk to me!
Talk to me, please! Mother!
Is there any law against a guy
trying to see his own mother?
No, I guess there isn't
Here
Put this on your cheek. Here
Drink some coffee
How did you find out about Kate, anyway?
That guy I saw you talking to
in the bar the other night?
The one they call "Rabbit
I thought so. He never was any good
I remember when he used
to work on your father's ranch
Well, he won't be around anymore, Cal
He's left town for good.
What do you hang around bars for?
-Any law against hanging--
Yes, there is! I'm the law
Get that through your head
Shut up!
Does Adam know that you
roam around over here at night?
Adam's an old friend of mine
you know, Cal, from...
Way back in his ranch days
I was afraid when you moved here
last year...
that you might find out something
about Kate.
But then she was over here on the Bay
and you were way over on the other side
of the mountains in Salinas.
-So I figured it'd be all right.
You think he'll ever find out about her?
He'd never come over here
Here. You might as well look at this now
it's a picture of your father
and your mother on their wedding day
You're the first person
I've ever showed it to.
I knew it
I knew it was true
When that old guy told me in the bar
I knew it.
How did you know it was true?
Cause she ain't no good
and I ain't no good.
I knew there was a reason why I wasn't
I hate her
And I hate him, too
Come on, I'll take you home
-You don't have to drive me home!
I know I don't have to take you home!
Here
A little bit of the hair
of the dog that bit you
Come on now
How did Dad meet her?
Where did she come from?
Nobody ever knew
where she come from, really
There were a lot of drifters in those days
Of all the people
How come he married her?
You have no idea how pretty she was, Cal
Young and full of spirit
And your father hadn't been
off the ranch much, you know
He's not a worldly man
Did she shoot him?
-Yes, she did.
How com e?
I don't know
Did he do something to her?
Did he hurt her?
-No.
It wasn't in him to hurt her
After she left him, he died.
He walked around, but he died
He must have done something to hurt her
No. No, sir
He gave her everything
that any woman could ask for
You see, your father has more kindness
and more conscience
than any man that I've ever known
He's a good man, Cal.
Don't sell him short, boy
it's going to work
If only I can keep them
cold enough long enough
it's going to work
All right, there she is. Let's try it
Step back, girls.
All right, bring her on. Come on
Now do you think it'll Work?
Good morning, Mr. Trask
-Good morning.
Somebody swiped our coal chute
right off the wagon.
Dear, dear.
Times are getting pretty lawless
it's this war in Europe
There's a wave of lawlessness
spreading through the country
Anyway, somebody swiped our chute
Is that where you're loading?
-Yes.
We'll move on, then. Good day, Mr. Trask
it's this war in Europe
Do you know where Aron is?
He's out in the fields. He's checking
Can I do something for you?
No. There were just some matters
I want to talk over with him.
What have you got there?
I figured it would save some time. Sol
it's very ingenious, Cal. Very ingenious
Did you think of it?
Yep
I'm very pleased
with the way you're taking hold
and are working so Well, Cal
Thanks. Thanks, Dad
Think you better have your lunch now
it's time.
Hi, Cal
Aron's out in the field
-I brought his lunch.
Okay, I'll take it to him
-Cal.
Lydia, vamoose
He'll be herein a minute
I've been fixing Aron's lunch.
I'll fix yours, too, if you like, after this
No, thanks
Would you be eating with her
if I weren't here?
Who?
No, I didn't ask her to come up here
Girls follow you around, don't they?
-Does she bother you?
She doesn't bother me
Who is she?
I never saw her before in my life
I'll bet
You're really working
at this lettuce business, aren't you, Cal?
Do you think it'll turn out all right?
Your father will lose quite a lot of money
if it doesn't.
Just about all he's got
I like your father
Do you?
I threw away about $3,000 once
Yeah?
-When I was 13.
You threw it away?
It was a diamond ring worth about that
At least, my father told me
that's what he paid for it.
I threw it in the river.
Made Dad terribly angry
I reckon it would
But I forgave him.
And it's been all right ever since
You forgave him?
-Yes.
You forgave him 'cause you threw
a ring of his worth $3,000 into the river?
-That's right.
And you forgave him?
That's right
Is there an egg in this basket?
You see, I thought he didn't love me
That made me feel awful.
Girls love their fathers terribly
Do they?
My mother died when I was 13
and Dad got married again soon after that
Did you know that?
No, I didn't know that
Are you interested in hearing about me?
Yeah
When Dad got married again
it made me sick.
I just hated everybody
I used to sit and just glare at people
or I wouldn't even answer
when they spoke to me.
Why you telling me all this?
-I want to.
I was that way for months
I just hated everybody.
I thought nobody in the world loved me
And it was awful
Then I found this ring
that Dad gave my new mother
so I took it and threw it in the river
-Good.
I thought you'd like that
Did he ever find it?
-Never.
They tried
What'd they do to you?
Dad punished me. Not badly, I guess
But I felt
he shouldn't have punished me at all
I felt he should have loved me more
because I did it.
But he didn't
isn't it funny?
I'm grown up now
but I still understand kids better
than I do grownups.
You're not so grown-up
-I'm very grown-up.
That's a matter of opinion
I'm very grown-up
More so than Dad, because I forgave him
for not understanding.
And the minute I forgave him in my mind
I felt better
Now we get along fine
We love each other.
Not like we did when I was 13
but enough so we can live together
till I get married.
He's just my father now
Nothing to rave about.
I still don't like her much
but then, she's a woman
My, that girl just hates me, doesn't she?
You better tell her I'm your brother's girl
I don't have to explain anything
to anybody.
I'll go now and leave the field to her
My, your hair's in a mess
Dad, what's that?
That's something Cal rigged up
it's a good idea.
Aron! I brought your lunch
Looks like a coal chute
Coal chute?
Okay, woman, where's the beans?
Cal!
What makes you think you have the right
to come and take something like this?
You probably lost those men their jobs
Now, you take it back.
He's praising Cal and Cal is lapping it up
Aron! Look, have one of those
made of wood.
It'll save a lot of time
-Yes, sir!
Good waste of time and money
-And lettuce.
-What'd you say?
I said, it's a good idea if it works
it's gonna work, 'cause it's gotta Work
it's gotta work, 'cause I said so
If it don't work, it ain't that kid's fault
I never saw anybody work
so hard in my life.
Let's go, Pete. Now, Leonard!
Good luck, Adam
Do you know the principle
of the internal combustion engine?
No, I'm afraid not.
Will, I'll never be able to
Sure you will. You just listen to Roy
He's been to the automobile school
in Chicago.
Mr. Trask has just revolutionized
the entire vegetable market.
Wait till those cars get to New York
-Don't you worry.
It's about time he owned
his own automobile...
and about time he learned to drive it
Now don't you think so, Roy?
-I'll do my best.
Now pay strict attention, boys
Don't touch that!
Wait till it's explained to you
No, now for heaven's sake,
don't touch anything, anybody
The power of the explosion
is exerted on a piston...
and through connecting rod
and crankshaft...
through transmission
thence to rear wheels
-Got that so far?
Sure, he's got that
Now, we go on
to the operation of the automobile
This here's the ignition key
Would you mind putting out
that cigarette, please.
Turn this doohickey here to the left
That puts her on battery.
See where it says "bat"?
-Yes.
-Bat, short for battery.
That's right. Good boy
Thank you. Thank you very much
First you gotta retard the spark
If you don't retard the spark,
she'll probably kick your blasted arm off
Now remember that
This here is the spark
You push her way up. Listen
This here's the gas. You push her
-Down.
You had lessons before
No, I just saw you do it
You're a pretty smart old buzzard
-Thank you very much.
Keep your eyes open, don't you?
-Try to.
Now, this here is the crank
See this wire sticking out of the radiator?
That's the choke.
Now watch careful.
Grab hold of the crank like this
Push in till she catches
See how my thumb is turned down?
I noticed that. Why do you do that?
If you put her around this way
with my thumb around her...
she'd probably knock
my blasted thumb off
Dear, dear. First you lose your blasted arm
and then you lose your blasted thumb.
That's kind of Wrong way around
-How's that?
He made a joke.
I never did see him so happy
You pull out this choke
turn her around to suck gas in
Then you give her a hard spin
She caught, first time!
-Caught on what?
Advance the spark and retard the gas
Reach over real quick and switch
to mag. That's magneto.
So, there you are
isn't that wonderful?
Of course, it isn't exactly
going anywhere, is it?
That's the easy part
-Adam.
I want you all to repeat after me
Spark up, gas down
Switch to bat
Crank to compression, thumb down
You get that? Let's have it again
Spark up, gas down
What's the matter?
-Big snow slide.
Closed the pass and stopped the cars
about 100 miles out.
Can see water running out of the cars
it's still a good idea.
Cold can preserve things
Someday, somebody'll prove it
It was your idea
-No!
It was presumptuous of me
to think it would be I.
Guess we bit off more lettuce
than we could chew.
What do you know about that?
I thought he'd really be hurt.
You don't understand him
-You can't go in there.
I gotta see Will Hamilton
He won't be through for an hour
They just started.
-Let me see him.
There's a war in Europe
These boys are trying
to get themselves in shape. So beat it
Right, left
Now, deep knee bends, follow me
-What's that?
That's the fire bell
We better have a look
-It may be the Germans.
Fire, Germans, who cares? I surrender
Howdy, Mr. Albrecht
-Hello, Cal.
-Mr. Hamilton.
There's a fire somewhere
No. I rang the bell
-You rang it?
Yeah. I had to see you
You know, you're crazy
You're really crazy.
I knew it when you pushed that ice
down the chute.
Let's get out of here
before they start up that piano again
There must be some easier way
to stop the Germans than this, anyway
You see, I gotta make some money
-Sure, everybody's got to.
Remember, you said that
if you wanna make money.
You ought to raise beans?
Yeah, beans are up 3.5 cents now
Now, the way I figure it, it's like you said
The country's gonna get into war, isn't it?
I don't see any way out
War's good for business
-The best there is.
See, that's why I wanna go into beans
See, I gotta get enough money
to give my father back what he lost
I see
You think you can make
all that money back?
I gotta
You know, you're crazy
Look, Cal, don't you know
that you gotta have money
in order to make money?
I'll get some money
-How?
I'll get it
Look, don't get so near to me.
I don't wanna get all hot again
How much money could you get?
-What do you think I need?
If you had $5,000
$5,000?
It's a little different when you start
putting it into figures, isn't it?
I know you wanna help your father
but a kid your age can't be expected
to put his hands on $5,000.
Maybe if you could raise $100 or so
we could let you have a little share
I don't want a little share
I want the whole thing.
-I'll get $5,000.
Maybe if you and Aron Went in together
Aron ain't got nothing to do with this
This is my deal.
I'll get the $5,000
What're you gonna do, borrow it?
Yeah
All right. If you can borrow $5,000
I know a farmer who's got over 800 acres
-it's under cultivation.
All right. What do we do?
If we can guarantee him 5 cents a pound
and make him a seed loan
he'll plant beans.
So will a lot of other farmers
Why, we can contract
all the bean acreage you want
That's it. That's great. When do we start?
How do you know the price
will go above 5, though?
Did you read the newspapers
this morning?
We're apt to be in war any minute
You know I got a contract
with the British Purchasing Agency
and I got a friend in
the Quartermaster Corps
Do you know
that we could sell all the dry beans
that we can find
at 10 cents a pound or more?
That's what I want. That's it. See?
-How much will I make?
Enough for what you want
What does Cal stand for?
-Caleb.
It's in the Bible
What's your brother's name?
-Aron.
That's in the Bible, too
What's he like?
He looks like you
Is he like me?
No. He's good
I'm more like you
How's Adam?
How's your father?
I don't wanna talk about him
You don't?
-No.
I didn't know who you were
when you were here before.
I knew you didn't
Aren't you afraid
to come around here again?
Yeah, I am. No. Well, kind of
What do you want?
Just to look at me?
I want $5,000
All right, come on in. Sit down
Come in
Try that chair
You got your father's eyes
That's all I can see of him
You're a nice looking boy
-Yes, ma'am.
I was very beautiful once
Caleb and Aron
Your father still thinks
he's living in the Bible, huh?
Them's just names
Joe says that you go to school in Salinas
Are you good in your studies?
I get by with them
Does Aron get by with them?
He's bright
What are you gonna do when you finish?
You're going to college?
Maybe
Or back to some ranch?
No, I don't like the ranch
You take after me
Makes me mad just to think about a ranch
Sit down
Thanks
What do you want with $5,000?
I want to go into business
You're a little young for that, aren't you?
-I'm old enough.
Yeah, I guess you're right. I guess you are
What business do you wanna go into?
-Beans.
Beans are up to 3.5 cents now
And if we get into war,
they're gonna go up to 10, 12
-If we get into the war.
That's a gamble you have to take
Will Hamilton says that
-Will?
You going into business
with Will Hamilton?
You see
my father, he lost about all he had in
Yeah, I know. I heard about that
I wanna make enough to pay him back
What's the matter with him?
Can't he make any money?
Yeah
Only
Only he's too good to bother with money
Okay
What makes you think I'd give you $5,000?
I don't know who else to ask
You got a lot of nerve coming to me
Why? I didn't do anything to you
it's a good business venture
I'll pay you back. I'll give you interest
You're a business woman, ain't you?
One of the best, Son
You know, Sam told me that you think
I ought to be run out of town.
You're afraid that your father and Aron
might find out about me, is that it?
This $5,000, now
That wouldn't be
any kind of blackmail, would it?
I never thought about that
But now that you do, it's a good idea, huh?
I guess, maybe
-it's not.
Anyway, I'm not gonna hurt
your precious father or your brother
Do they know anything about me?
-No.
Father thinks you're in the East
and Aron thinks you're dead
Then, there's no reason to think
that they ever will find out about me
We don't exactly move in the same circles
What are you staring at?
How come you did it?
Did what?
Shot my father?
Did he tell you that?
How come you ran away from all of us?
How come you shot him?
Ran away and did all that kind of stuff?
-None of your business.
I shot him because he tried to stop me
I could have killed him if I'd wanted to
but I didn't.
I just wanted him to let me go
-Why?
Because he tried to hold me
He wanted to tie me down
He wanted to keep me
on a stinking little ranch
away from everybody.
Keep me all to himself
Nobody holds me
But he loved you
-Love.
He wanted to own me
He wanted to bring me up
like a snot-nosed kid...
and tell me what to do.
Nobody tells me what to do
Always so right himself
Knowing everything.
Reading the Bible at me
What are you grinning at?
-Nothing.
Maybe you know what I'm talking about?
Always so right himself?
Yeah
Maybe like you said out there
maybe you are more like me.
Yeah, you got sense
Maybe you don't fall for that slop
any more than I do.
Maybe you know what people
are really like. What they want
I got the toughest house on the coast
and the finest clientele
Half the stinking city hall go there
They sneak in at night
and I walk in this front door
in the daytime, see.
And I built it up from nothing
Now you want $5,000 of my money
to go into business
to pay your father back what he lost
You know, that's funny
I don't think he'll know where I got it
No, but it's funny just the same
Your father
He's the purest man there is, isn't he?
He thought he had me all tied up
with his purity.
And now I give you $5,000
of the money that I made..
To save him his purity
If you don't think that's funny
you'd better not go to college
Okay
Tell Will Hamilton to come and see me
He's a good businessman
How'd he ever happen to let you go
into this bean business, anyway?
I don't know
I do. Maybe he likes you
Maybe
You're a likable kid
You give this to him
If he wants to gamble
that we get into the war
it's okay with me
You're a likable kid
Go on, get out of here
Go on, get out. I'm running a business
Them Germans can't fight
-No.
Hi, partner
Every day in every way,
we're getting richer and richer
Kaiser
All we have to do is call his bluff
He'll come to heel like a dog.
We'll be there to clean up this mess
for those foreigners in a couple of weeks
Cal, stop it
There's Cal
Hi, boy. Hey, want some?
-Hello, Cal.
Thanks
Your own Woodrow Wilson said you gotta
make the country safe for democracy.
Didn't he say that?
-Yes, he said that.
Will you go?
I think the war will be over. I don't think
If you believe in all this, why don't you?
If you really think it's right.
I didn't say it was right, Aron
No, I guess you didn't
Why don't you go back
and join the parade?
Nothing'll ever make me go. Nothing
I just don't believe it's right
Did you water them good?
-Sure, lots of water.
Not too much, though
-No, just right.
Marty Hopps got a telegram today
His boy was killed.
I remember the day we sent him off
A lot of troop ships have sunk
they don't tell us about.
-it's gonna be along war.
Those Germans got an army
They're a military nation
Go back Where you came from, German!
Go on home, German!
This is just the start
That rock through the window
is just the beginning.
The German people don't want this war
And the stories they tell
of what the Germans are doing
it simply is not true. Not the good ones
I've been wondering lately
if we shouldn't all go back to the ranch
You can't get away from it there, Dad
I don't know, somehow, on a ranch
I don't know ....
War seems to be
city people's business somehow
Farmers. What's a farmer got to do
with war?
You tired, Dad?
My eyes, I guess.
I work too hard at the Draft Board
Better have my glasses looked at
see if they're all right.
I had a look at the bank account
the other day...
not much left after my great fiasco
Let's not worry about money, Dad
Let's don't worry about money
Hey, Rantani!
Ain't this some sight?
Beans!
Yeah, boy, some beans
You come here everyday, boy
what do you think...
you gonna make them grow quicker?
He's crazy
Hey, where have you been?
Come on
We're gonna have lots of fun tonight
You won another cigar
-Wait a minute.
You wanna try one? No?
Pick up my cigar
I'm waiting for somebody
-You're waiting for me.
No, I'm not
Why don't you let me
take you for a nice ride?
If you don't stop bothering me
I'll have to call someone.
-Hello, Cal.
What's the matter?
I was trying to tell this gentleman
that I was waiting for somebody.
This is a lousy place
to keep your girlfriend waiting for you
Sir, it won't happen again
-I hope not.
Lots of lousy characters around here
Sorry, miss.
Here I am, lady
That's the first time
that ever happened to me
What're you doing out here?
-I'm meeting Aron.
I thought I'd come out early
and look around.
You never been out here before?
-Not at night, no.
What time you gonna meet him?
-At 8:00.
Thought I'd try and cheer him up
He's been so depressed lately.
Yeah, I know
I'm so glad you happened to be here
8:00?
You got a half hour?
How are you, Cal?
We never see you around anymore
I'm around
I've been over to the house several times,
but you were never there.
-I never go home anymore.
Aron says he hardly ever sees you
I feel awfully sorry for him
You're terrible
That's the first time
that ever happened to me, too
Wonder if we can see Aron from here
I feel awfully sorry for him
He's right, you know.
I mean, it's awful, the war and people
killing each other.
Why feel sorry for Aron?
Feel sorry for the people.
But it just seems to affect him
so personally.
I'll agree with that
He's right
He's always right
And he has always been right
Now let's talk about something else
All right
8:00
We got a lot to see
Will we be back in time for Aron?
All right. I'd love to
Easy
Here's your cigar,
and where have you been hiding?
Who was that?
-Who?
-That girl.
I don't see nobody
She was standing right ....
Girls follow you around, don't they?
What are girls like that like?
All right, never mind
These Huns have been the aggressors
in every war in Europe...
since the time of Julius Caesar
I couldn't attempt to describe to you
the horrors committed by the Germans
Look
Would we have time?
After the Germans had been through
-the women of the town...
That German's here again
It is not true. It is lies, all lies
Come on, Cal. Is it scary?
Here we go
It is lies, all lies
I'd like to give that guy
a piece of my mind.
See over there. That's Castroville
Everything looks so small down there
Higher and higher and higher and higher
What?
Growing and growing
and growing and growing
What are you talking about?
-I'll tell you sometime.
Does Aron really love me?
I seem to have sort of lost him
I mean, we're going
to be married someday, but
Well, if he does love me, he doesn't
I can't tell anymore
Cal, can I ask you something?
Yeah, go ahead
These girls that you always
go around with.
You know, remember there was
that little Mexican girl once.
What are girls like that like?
You don't really love them, do you?
Why do you go out with them?
Is it because you're bad?
You're not angry, are you?
Well, why do you, then? Are you bad?
-Do you think I'm bad?
I don't know
I guess I don't know
what is good and what's bad
I mean, Aron is so good
and I'm not
Not good enough for Aron, anyway
Because sometimes when I'm with Aron
Aron likes to talk about our being in love
and think about it
and that's all right, but
These girls that you go out with, do you
Maybe I don't know what love is, exactly
I know love is good the way Aron says
but it's more than that, it's got to be
I shouldn't talk to you this way
but I don't know who else to talk to
Sometimes I think I'm really bad
Sometimes I don't know what to think
Aron'll knock that out of you
-Will he?
He's got to
The way I figure it out
Aron never having had a mother
he's made her everything good
that he can think of...
and that's what he thinks I am
That's who he's in love with
it's not me at all.
Cause I'm not a bit like that made-up one
Not a bit.
I don't mean I think I'm really bad
Look at that star
It must be a planet, it's so bright
Probably
I bet that girl's waiting for you
down there somewhere.
She can just wait
She was pretty
You've been awfully nice, Cal
taking care of me.
I love Aron. I do, really I do
do
To give these fiends a lesson that
Have you seen Abra, Mr. Albrecht?
Lies. All lies
What's the matter with you tonight, Gus?
Gus, come on
There's Aron
You're a good Shoemaker
There's Aron, down there
Major, why don't you stay out of politics?
Mr. Albrecht
They're pushing him around
What are they doing?
That'd kill Dad if he knew that
Hey, operator,
when does this thing move again
Hey!
Cal, don't!
Watch yourself, get back!
Please. Somebody pull him back
Don't bother me!
Come on
Gus, come on, have a drink
-No, Charlie, no drink.
What are you waiting for?
Mr. Albrecht, calm down
They're not bad fellows.
Aron, you are a child
All I tried to do was buy him a drink
Gustav
Silence
You all loved him a few Weeks ago
what's gotten into you?
I'm sick of him sticking up
for the Germans.
You a friend of the Germans?
-I'm a friend of this German.
There are rose plants in that border there
Please be careful where you step.
We liked him. He made us laugh
because of his funny German accent
Let him read this
in his funny German accent
-What is it?
Let him come down and read it
He doesn't have to read anything
-I will read it.
Here, give it to me
The Government, with deep regret
informs...
that your son was killed in action
15th of April.
He died a hero and an American
I'm sorry, Mrs. Hopps. I did not
You're not sorry enough
I don't think he's sorry
-He's not sorry at all.
Listen, why don't we all go on home
-You're not sorry enough.
Why aren't you in the war?
This will make you sorry
Hello, Charlie
Danny, what are you fellows
doing here, anyway?
Get up
Loretta, I didn't expect to find you here
Evening, Rose
Looks like they messed up
your rose garden a little here, Gus
Somebody owes you an apology
How about you folks all going home now?
I think this'll do for tonight
Good evening, Mrs. Albrecht
-May I?
Come in
This place will be fixed up
just like it was before.
-I'm gonna see to it.
-Ja. He will see to it
Where were you?
Where did you get his coat?
You all right?
You had to start slugging, didn't you?
Were you showing off for her?
You had to start slugging
I was trying to help you
-I don't need your help.
If you want to slug people,
do it for yourself and not for me
And don't lie to me about trying to
-Aron, I tried to help you!
Great big Aron
-You finished?
-No!
Cal, stop it! Don't
-Don't.
Don't do that
Abra, don't do that!
Wait here
I was trying to help him
Who am I kidding?
I tried to kill him
Mike, give me a drink
Don't drink any more
-Why?
No, please. it's not good for you
-it's good for me.
No, you're gonna get drunk
-Yeah, I'm gonna get drunk.
Please forget it, what happened up
on the ferris wheel.
It didn't mean anything, really
Please, forget it. It didn't mean anything
Say it didn't. Please, say it didn't
Someday he's gonna know
who his real son is.
What?
Someday he's gonna know
I don't understand you. You scare me
I know. I scare myself
-Abra.
Fix me another drink
I want that money. Now you give it to me
-You know I haven't any money here.
Okay
-When will you get it?
In the morning, I suppose
Okay. I'll sleep here
Come on. You've gotta go home
If you still feel the same way
in the morning...
you come back, we'll go to the bank
and I'll see that you get everything
that's coming to you.
I'll buy out your share.
I'll go on and make a fortune with it
Okay. That seems fair to me, Will
Abra
What?
Who is it?
-Cal.
-Cal?
Yeah
What on earth are you doing here?
-I want to see you.
Wait till I put something on
I gotta tell you something
Can you keep a secret?
Yes. What is it?
What's the matter? You look terrible
I got it
-What?
Remember that money? Dad lost?
On that lettuce business?
-I got it.
You mean you earned it all back?
I've earned every cent
-That's wonderful, Cal.
You got any time off tomorrow
from the hospital?
I get an hour at lunchtime. Why?
Thursday's Dad's birthday
And I'm gonna give a party for him
And I Want you and me
you and Aron and me...
to be there
I'm gonna give him that money
just like it was a birthday present
You could come
and help me get some junk
and we could decorate the house
-Sure.
And we'll get balloons
and all that kid stuff, birthday stuff
-We can go to the five and 10.
Will you do it?
-I'd like to.
I'm sort of
Why did I hit Aron?
Why did I hit him so hard?
Will you help me?
Will you really help me?
I'll help you, Cal
Be careful
How'd I get up here?
Is your father coming?
-Yeah.
-Cal, don't get nervous.
I think it looks beautiful
Don't you? I love the way it looks
It looks festive, doesn't it?
-Yes, it does.
Yes, Cal, it looks very pretty
Do you think this is childish?
-Not a bit.
The room looks lovely.
Your father's going to love it
How's the turkey?
it's a good turkey.
Smells ready
-it'll be ready.
Aron didn't get him anything?
He told me he had something.
-What?
He didn't tell me what it was
It won't stack up against mine, will it?
-No.
Do you wanna see mine?
-I'd like to.
I got it wrapped up
-Show it to me.
Wanna see it?
-Yes.
Okay
You like it?
-it's pretty.
You think it's pretty?
Don't drink any more wine
Did Aron tell you what the present was?
-No.
-You sure?
Honestly, he didn't
I'd tell you if he did. Honestly, I would
Now everything's gonna go off fine. Here
The brooms
Don't you do anything to give me away
-I wouldn't.
We'll let him come in
and let the house speak for itself
We'll act like it was any other old day
-Yes. Wait, Cal.
Cal
You look wonderful
Thanks
But I need my son
It isn't that he doesn't want
to fight for his country. He does
I need him to work the farm
Things can't be as bad as you say
Mr. Piscora.
You must be making plenty of money
out of your crops.
No money. I sold this year's crop
for 5 cents before I even planted it
Everything cost so much now
And now I got to sell next year crop
Sol need my boy.
I can do nothing about it, Mr. Piscora
In all conscience,
I cannot excuse your son
Come on, Poppa
-I don't like it.
I'm telling you. I don't like it
Hello, Abra. Nice to see you
-Gonna stay to dinner?
Yes, I am. Is something the matter?
No, nothing. I guess I shouldn't
have taken that job in the Draft Board
Did you notice the snow on Mount Toro?
-Yes, I saw it.
Say, that means we got
a good year coming in.
We could use it
-Let's go in.
-Happy birthday, Dad.
Happy birthday, Mr. Trask
Is it possible? I'm very touched
-Are you surprised?
I had no idea. I'd forgotten completely
-We knew you had, didn't we?
Completely. I don't know what to say
We got turkey
-And champagne.
Champagne, and we got all the things
We got the trimmings here
-isn't that pretty?
Got something for you
Presents, too. isn't that nice. Look
Ain't you gonna open it up?
-Yes.
Dad, Abra and I have one for you, too
only we can't exactly give it to you.
I didn't tell Abra I was going to do this
but we're engaged.
I couldn't have wished for anything nicer
A lovely birthday present
You have my blessings
-Thank you, Dad.
But you haven't opened Cal's present yet
-No.
But I can't imagine having
anything better than this.
Excuse me
Course I suspected it right along
But, Cal, coming on my birthday.
What's this?
What is this?
I made it. And it's for you.
it's all the money you lost on the lettuce
You made it? But how?
Go on
-Beans
Beans?
Yes, we bought futures at 5 cents
and the war came along
and the price Went sky-high
So, that's for you
it's all the money you lost
in the lettuce business.
It's for you
-I made it for you.
You will have to give it back
No, I made it for you, Dad
I want you to have it.
You will have to give it back
-Who? I can't give it--
-To the people you got it from.
No, the British Purchasing Agency?
-I can't give it back.
Give it to the farmers you robbed
We didn't rob anybody, Dad
We paid 2 cents a pound,
2 cents over market for that stuff
I sign my name
and boys go out and some die
and some live helpless
without arms and legs.
Not one will come back untorn
Do you think I could take
a profit from that?
I don't want the money, Cal!
I couldn't take it!
I thank you for the thought, but
-I'll keep it for you.
I'll wrap it up
and we'll just keep it in here
I'll never take it!
Son, I'd be happy if you'd give me
something like your brother's given me
Something honest and human and good
Don't be angry, Son.
If you want to give me a present
give me a good life.
That's something I could value
I hate you!
What are you doing?
He doesn't want anything from me
Cal, don't
Please, don't
Abra!
Don't you ever touch her again
I don't trust you
You're no good
You're mean and vicious and wild
And you always have been.
You know it, too, don't you?
Father and I have put up
with every vicious thing..
You could think of since you were a child
And we've always forgiven you.
But now I don't want you to go near Abra
I don't want you to talk with her
Just stay away from her!
You want to go some place with me?
-Why should I?
I got something to show you
Think you'll find it very interesting
-What are you talking about?
Maybe our mother didn't die
and go to heaven after all, Aron
What do you mean by that?
-Maybe she didn't.
Maybe she's alive someplace
What are you up to now?
Remember when we were kids,
we used to make up stories about her?
You said she must have looked
like heaven's youngest angel, remember?
Remember that time I shot that rabbit?
You cried and you said
that she would have cried, too,
cause she was so tenderhearted
And you said I was bad
you remember that?
I just want to show you something
it's not gonna take very long.
What's the matter, you afraid?
I'm not afraid to look at anything
you could show me.
Can you look at the truth, just once?
Come on, you can look
at the truth just once. Can't you?
Come on
I want to show you something
It won't take very long.
Oh, Cal
Hello
Mother, this is your other son, Aron
Aron is everything that's good, Mother
Say hello to your mother
Say hello to your mother, Aron!
Joe!
Play another song!
-Quiet!
Five!
"I'm thinking of the lilac trees
that shook their purple plumes
"I'm thinking of the rivulet
with its cool and silvery flow
Of the old gray rock that shadowed it
and the peppermint below"
-Where is Aron?
I don't know. I'm not my brother's keeper
Where did you go?
-For a ride.
What did you quarrel about?
-You.
You're angry about the money
-No, I'm not angry.
I like it. I think it's great
I'm gonna go away
and take that money with me
I think I'll start me a little business
Just like my mother did.
What do you know about your mother?
-I know where she is and what she is.
And I know why she left you
Couldn't stand it.
You didn't really love her
any more than you do me
Because of your goodness, your rightness
You never gave either one of us
an inch, ever...
from what you thought was right
You kept on forgiving us,
but you never really loved us
I know why you didn't love me
Because I'm like my mother
and you never forgave yourself
for having loved her.
I'm not gonna forgive him.
I'm never gonna forgive him
-Where is Aron?
He's with her, with his mother
She's over there in Monterey
if you want to know.
She owns one of them houses
I took Aron there tonight
because I was jealous.
I've been jealous all my life.
Jealous, I couldn't even stand it
Tonight, I even tried to buy your love
But now I don't want it anymore
-I can't use it anymore.
Don't talk to your father like that
I don't want any kind of love anymore
It doesn't pay off
No future in it
Let him go if he wants to
No, I won't
You hate me, too, don't you?
I'm afraid of you
What you did to Aron tonight,
I don't know what it will do to him
I feel like I'm to blame, too
-Adam!
Here. What is it?
Drunk and had a couple of fights
He's gone kind of crazy.
He's at the station now.
Wait, I'll drive you down in my car
Cal!
What happened between you and Aron?
-Why?
He's gone kind of crazy.
He's drunk and had a couple of fights
and seemed determined
to get himself hurt.
He's leaving on that troop train tonight
and says he's gonna enlist tomorrow
at King City.
Adam's on his way down there now
to talk to him before the train leaves
I think you better get down there
-Yeah.
My car's downstairs
Do you know what a stroke is, exactly?
This one is a leakage of blood in the brain
caused by shock.
There have been earlier, smaller leakages
The left side is paralyzed
and the right side partly.
In other words,
your father is nearly helpless
-Will he die?
He might live a week or a year
He might die tonight
-Will he know me?
You'll have to find that out for yourself
Good day
Good day, Doctor. Good day, Sam
Cain rose up against his brother Abel
and slew him.
"And Cain went away and dwelt
in the land of Nod, on the east of Eden
Now why don't you go away some place?
He's right
-No.
Yes, he is. He's right. That's what I'll do
Who's gonna wash these things for me?
Thank you
There you are
-How is he?
He's fine. He's my darling
Washed his face, combed his hair
Can I go in there now?
Just for a minute. I want him to rest
Gotta get lots of sleep.
-How is he, really?
Haven't I seen you at the hospital?
Not part of the family, are you?
-No.
I didn't think so
I can tell you,
I won't have this job for long
That's my luck. Always seem to get them
when they're old and ready to die off.
Now doesn't he look nice?
He's going to be a darling patient
Even tried to smile at me
didn't you, my dear?
I don't want you to tire my patient
-Please go.
Now listen, miss,
don't you try to order me about
I'll report you to the doctor
Will you go out of the room
and shut the door?
Father
Can you hear me?
I did an awful thing
I'm sorry
Mr. Trask, can you hear me?
Is it just Cal you won't answer?
Can you answer?
I think you can understand me, though
I think behind your eyes
you're just as alert as ever
You understand everything I say
only you can't show it.
Excuse me, Mr. Trask,
for daring to speak to you this way
but it's awful not to beloved.
it's the worst thing in the world
Don't ask me how I know that
I just know it.
It makes you mean and violent and cruel
And that's the way
Cal has always felt, all his life
I know you didn't mean it to be that way
but it's true.
You never gave him your love
You never asked him for his.
You never asked him for one thing
Cal is going away, Mr. Trask
But before he goes ....
He did something very bad,
and I'm not asking you to forgive him
You have to give him some sign
that you love him...
or else he'll never be a man
He'll just keep on feeling guilty
and alone, unless you release him
Please, help him
I love Cal, Mr. Trask,
and I want him to be whole and strong
and you're the only one who can do it
So try, please try
If you could ask him for something
Let him help you so that he knows
that you love him.
Let him do for you
Excuse me, Mr. Trask, for daring
to speak to you this way, but I just had to
You've tired my patient
and I most certainly shall report it
to the doctor in the morning.
You don't know that he accuses you.
You don't know what he's thinking about
Stop it, Cal.
You gonna cry for the rest of your life?
-No.
Then stop it
Goin' there and talk to him
before it's too late.
-I can't.
Please try
Get it straight
Get through to him, somehow.
Please try, Cal, before it's too late
Is there any coffee around here?
-I'll get you some in a minute.
Try
Is there anything to read around here?
What would you like?
Something to get my mind off my feet
-There's something in there.
I tried to believe it was born in me
and that I couldn't help it
but that's not so.
A man has a choice
You used to say that was where
he was different from an animal.
You see, I remember
A man has a choice,
and the choice is what makes him a man
You see, I do remember
Look, I can't find any coffee
-Get out!
Look
Do something
for me
Yes
That woman
the nurse, can't stand her
Get me another
I can't stand her, either
What did he say?
He said, "Don't get anybody else
He said, "You stay with me
and you take care of me