Jamie!
Jamie, off the grass!
Off the grass!
Nice plane finish!
-Which side will win the war?
-Ours, of course.
-Oh, that war.
-Well, China isn't our war.
We're awfully lucky.
-Living here, having everything.
-Naughty!
The harder I work, the luckier we get.
I only meant lucky.
Luckier than him.
We're luckier than most.
He's luckier than some.
Out of the way.
Chip across the water.
The Japanese will win. They've got
better planes and braver pilots.
I may join the Japanese Air Force.
For heaven's sake!
Father, look! Zero Sen!
It's my plane! Zero Sen!
Amah, I'll have...
...the butter biscuits.
Mrs. Graham, she...
...not want you eat before bed.
You have to do what I say.
--backed by
reinforcements into Malaya....
...certain to influence Japan against
further military action.
As Far East tensions grow,
British nationals evacuate...
...for Australia and India.
A steamer left Shanghai yesterday
with 450 British on board...
...to Hong Kong.
A third of occupied China's
British community...
...estimated at 15,000, has left
in recent weeks.
Little hope of progress remains...
...between Roosevelt
and the Japanese ambassador.
Singapore revealed that Japanese
forces in Indochina...
...have reached the strength of
perhaps 50,000.
Hello...
...Ace.
-I was dreaming about God.
-What did he say?
Nothing. He was playing tennis.
Perhaps that's where God is
all the time.
It's why you can't see him.
I don't know about God.
-Good night, Jamie.
-Perhaps he's our dream...
...and we're his.
Go to sleep. It's the Lockwoods,
party tomorrow.
Can I take my glider?
Dream of flying.
Mother...
...if God is above us, does it mean
up, like flying?
Good night.
-Mistress, very beautiful.
-Thank you, Amah. Off we go.
Behave yourself.
Thank you, Yang.
Squeeze up.
Mind the plane. Prop it against
the seat. Right, Yang.
Settle down, Sinbad!
Take the Wang Pu Road.
Let's avoid the crowds.
-See you back on board.
See you, Charlie.
Green apples! Green apples!
No mama. No papa.
No whiskey soda.
Slow down. Checkpoint coming up.
God rest ye merry gentlemen
Hello, darling.
Lovely to see you.
-Big kisses.
-There he is.
-Leave Shanghai while you can.
-They leave us alone.
Lockwood's invited a Chink.
Sorry, but don't mind him.
-English humor?
-Scottish whiskey.
Are our days numbered?
All our days are numbered.
Ours higher than yours.
You've been in Shanghai 100 years.
It's only an incident.
The Japanese, four years. Nothing.
Long enough to spoil your harvest
and steal what's left of it.
A million Chinese peasants are
trying to enter Shanghai.
The Japanese get hungry too.
We have the guns, the planes
and 500 million fighting back.
-We'll be here after every war.
-Here's to that.
I hope we'll be here too.
Always delighted to return
hospitality.
-Very good. Utterly convincing.
-Thank you.
Zero?
Nakajima. Two machine guns.
I rely on you for keeping up-to-date
on the war.
Especially military aviation.
-I hear you resigned from the Scouts.
-I'm now an atheist.
-Where are you going?
-To see something!
Oh.
Your boy tells me he's an atheist.
Always thought he was.
-Chow time.
-Thank you.
Enemy aircraft sighted!
He's on my tail! On my tail!
Jamie!
Stand still, John.
Jamie.
Don't run.
Come, you're
missing the party.
-I left my plane.
-Never mind.
-Don't look back.
-Thanks.
They're waiting for something
to happen.
-They didn't look angry.
-It's not anger. It's patience.
-Is it time to close ranks?
-Get Mary and the boy out.
Somewhere safe. Singapore?
We're moving into the hotel.
Why?
-To see how things are going.
I don't want you two alone
in the house.
Jamie?
I didn't mean it. It was a joke.
Keep away from the window.
Get dressed. Do what Mother
tells you. We're leaving.
I am dressed.
Am I going to school?
There's no school today.
We'll see if Yang can take us home.
Never mind the suitcase. Come on!
-Taxi! Over here! Taxi!
Excuse me!
Good heavens, this is ridiculous!
-Keep holding my hand!
Stop shoving me!
-Excuse me! Excuse me!
-Yang!
Quickly!
Yang, get us to the waterfront.
Jamie, for God's sake, sit down!
Jamie, get out of the car. Quickly!
-What will we do?
-Get out.
Perhaps there'll be a boat.
Sorry. Max was right.
Don't push me!
Mary!
Hold on to him!
John!
Hold on.
-John!
Stay together! Hang on to Jamie!
Jamie, don't let go!
My plane!
Jamie!
Mum?
Mum! Mummy!
Jamie!
Mummy! Mum! No!
Jamie! Jamie!
Go home. I'll find you there! Go home!
Mummy!
Mother!
Mama?
Father!
Mother!
What do you think you're doing?
Where's my mother and father?
Come on, man!
Come on, kid!
Come on!
Wait! Wait!
Come on, cycle harder!
Wait!
Please!
Excuse me, everyone.
I surrender.
"I surrender.
I surrender. I surrender."
No mama! No papa! No whiskey soda!
American boy?
-American boy?
-English.
English?
I'm waiting for my chauffeur.
English boy.
English boy, you come now.
Thank you.
You come now.
-You come now.
-No! No!
Hey!
English boy!
Hey! Hey, English boy!
I surrender! I surrender. Please!
Please, sir!
I surrender!
Excuse me, sir.
My name is James Graham. I'm British.
I'd like to surrender, please!
Please!
Please, I'm British.
I'd like to surrender.
Please, sir.
Please!
English boy!
I surrender!
Please!
Help me!
Help me! I'm British!
-Help me!
Stop running.
Please! No! Please!
Help me! Help me!
Hello.
Kid. Kid, you okay?
Kid, you all right?
I think so.
Where do you live?
13 Amherst Avenue.
I'm waiting for my parents.
They've been delayed.
Delayed?
Some kind of crazy British kid.
What's your name?
James Graham.
I'm writing a book on contract bridge.
Are you with the American fleet?
American fleet? It looks like
you almost lost your shirt.
Maybe I can help you find
your parents.
I know just the man.
Do you know General Winter?
My father knows important people.
Do you know my father?
He owns a textile mill
on Szechwan Road.
Mr. Lockwood? He's with
the British Association.
Perhaps you don't know anyone.
How about Louis Charles and Michael
of the Avenue Foch gang?
Know about psychic bidding?
It's in my book.
Let's say you need three diamonds.
You just think three diamonds.
Then your partner,
when he gets four aces...
...he shouts and you put down the....
You put down your aces and then....
I can't remember it now.
Probably my parents are on a ship
to Hong Kong.
Then they'll send for me.
My father will give you a reward.
He gave a taxi driver $5
for bringing me home from Hankow.
Ever been to England?
Kid, you're starting to get
on my nerves.
Look what I found under my truck.
I'm sorry already.
Come on in, boy.
He's either hungry or crazy.
You need to lie down?
My father has a cotton mill at...
...Pootung.
-He'll be ingratiated to you.
Ingratiated is a fine word.
He once gave a taxi--
In a minute.
Your tongue's running away.
That's a well-kept set of teeth.
Someone has paid a lot of bills
for that sweet mouth.
Frank, you'd be surprised how
people neglect their kids' teeth.
Basie, I got you three.
I wasn't able to sell
any goddamn portholes.
Those Hankow merchants...
...they're charging $10
for a bag of rice.
Cathedral School too.
Cathedral?
Is he a kind of priest?
The Cathedral School.
It's a school for taipans.
You must know some
important people, son.
What do they call you?
I once met Madame Sun Yat-Sen.
She didn't call me anything.
I was 3.
Madame Sun?
I was presented.
-Presented.
-You two keep getting presented.
We'll be up to our asses in junk,
eating rats when the Japs walk in.
The Japs are not looking for us.
Nantao Creek is full of cholera.
They've got more sense.
It's a changed world.
Even if I sell this stuff...
...there wouldn't be enough to get
a sampan upriver.
We'd have to strip the Queen Mary!
So we don't have any rice for you.
Let's leave the boy alone.
All these new words and now this.
Fancy candy?
-What did you say your name was?
-Jamie.
I'm building a man-flying kite...
...and writing a book
on contract bridge.
Jim. A new name for a new life.
Jim's parents got
taken with the other Brits...
...and now Jim's looking for them.
Don't worry about Frank, he always
eats after me. Don't you, Frank?
I always eat after you, Basie.
Because I think for us both.
Jim, chew your food.
Chew every mouthful six times
to get the benefit.
Frank, we might do all right
in one of those camps.
Doesn't look like we'll
leave Shanghai soon.
You're a tired boy, Jim.
Where am I gonna sleep?
Shanghai Jim.
Find any gold teeth?
Buying and selling, Frank. You know.
Life.
Okay, sit. Sit.
Make a muscle.
Why can't he sell me?
Nobody wants you.
You're worth nothing.
Skin and bone.
Pretty soon, you'll be sick
all the time.
Basie....
First, I could show you
some rich pickings.
Hundreds of houses left empty.
Is that right?
I'll show you the houses
I lived in before Frank found me.
They were luxuriant!
Luxuriant?
You had good sense being born there.
It was good living.
There certainly was good living!
There was opulence!
Opulence.
All right.
We'll go look at these houses.
Let's go, Frank.
Opulence.
That one has whiskey, gin
and a white piano.
That one has whiskey, gin....
-Whiskey and a radiogram.
-What about the boarded one?
It has a mirrored dance floor,
radiogram, fountain...
-...and crystal chandeliers.
-Crystal chandeliers?
-I think they were crystal.
-You're tired.
What about cash?
What about money?
I did see money.
Piles of notes on the table.
I'm taking you there.
Turn right here.
I knew she'd come back.
Take it easy.
Mother!
-Damn it, they're Japs.
-I see. Back out.
I can't back out! There's no reverse!
-Just go forward.
-Come on!
Jesus Christ, Frank.
I want these back when they're done.
Basie....
Basie.
Engine number two on fire.
On fire, come in.
Come in, Red Dog Leader.
Red Dog Leader, come in.
Adjusting propeller? Red Dog Leader.
Engine two on fire.
On fire, on fire, on fire....
Good King Wenceslas looked out
On the feast of Stephen
When the snow lay round about
Deep and crisp and even
It's just a little fever.
Don't worry. We've all had it.
Do you feel better now?
It's perfectly all right.
I can wash it.
Excuse me.
There's been a mistake.
It may have been my fault.
I'm terribly sorry.
Attention, prisoners!
For camp transport, assemble outside.
Outside. Make one line.
Number one prisoner group to gate.
Prisoners, number one truck.
Have you forgotten the cutlery?
No, I haven't.
Basie.
No.
You can't drink water from here.
People are dying of dysentery.
But we can drink boiled water.
Boiled water?
Many thanks, Basie.
You're welcome, Jim.
You've got nice manners.
I appreciate that.
Now it's chow time.
Get in line.
Keep the ball in play,
first in line.
I think your father would agree.
Actually, he would agree.
After the war, you two
should play tennis.
I want you to get Mrs. Partridge's
potato while you're there.
I think she died, Basie.
She died, but didn't hand
in her dinner pail.
Okay, go. Go on. Hurry.
And, Ace, don't forget to bow
to the sergeant.
We gotta get out of here.
The camps are full. It's our
bad luck to be taken here.
The Japs haven't enough camps
for us all.
This is disgusting. Get some water.
Come on, children.
She's with God now.
What are you doing, Basie?
Looks like your size, Jim.
I don't want her shoes.
I don't want them.
-I don't want them.
-Somebody will.
Basie, leave her!
Fine! I don't want her shoes!
Stop it. Leave her. Leave her!
Stop it. I don't want her shoes!
Pipe down.
It's the lorry. The lorry!
The lorry!
Come on!
Come on.
-No!
Come on! Don't you see?
This place is to see who dies!
Healthy ones go. Sick stay.
Tell him who we are, then--
We don't say anything.
Just look him in the eye.
Name?
-George Flynn.
Summers.
Excuse me.
-I'm a doctor. Let me through.
That's not fair!
I'm a British citizen!
You can't do this!
No! I'm with them!
-Please!
Paul. Your name Paul?
Get your sister to smile,
I'll show you a magic trick.
Don't leave me!
Take me with you, Basie!
Listen!
Listen, Basie! Take me with you!
I can't stay here!
I'll work for you. I'll do anything!
Take me with you!
Basie! Basie!
-Soochow.
-Soochow!
I've been there lots of times.
Straight in that direction!
Head straight in that direction.
My parents were members of the country
club. Straight that way.
I've lived here my whole life!
I know my way everywhere.
I can speak--
Soochow!
Here we go!
Nice pair of golf shoes.
A friend left them to me.
You wouldn't want
a watch, would you?
No. Sorry.
Now do you know where we are?
We're here, okay?
We have to turn left here.
We have to turn left, okay?
You do what I say or we'll never get
to Soochow.
And then you'll be shot.
I look after him for his daddy.
-You're American, are you?
-Definitely.
I worked underground
for the Kuomintang.
As a conjurer?
That must be the camp.
We'll live right by the airfield.
-I don't see a camp.
Over there. See?
Those huts at a distance.
What do I do with this?
They want us to carry stones!
Please, on the truck is
a sick old man. Please....
On the truck, there's an old man.
-No, no, no.
Please!
Papa! Papa!
I'm all right.
-Use your wedge!
-That boy, running wild!
Spends most of his time
at the 19th hole.
You'll be blackballed by
the country club, Jim.
Hello, Jim.
That's a splendid cabbage. Thanks.
Now number seven for the sketch.
'tis partly my
own fault which death or absence--"
"Stay, gentle Helena, hear my excuse."
That's not fair!
Give us our marbles back.
Give us our marbles back!
At least one more chance.
Mrs. Phillips!
Mrs. Gilmour!
Dr. Rawlins, I've got my homework.
Can you do this?
Now don't speed up.
Keep the rhythm.
She's gone, Dr. Rawlins.
She just looked at me. She looked
at me! I've done it!
I can bring her back to life!
Watch her eyes. I can do it again!
She thought she was dying in England.
Stop it, Jim!
You pumped some blood into her brain,
just for a moment.
Give the mosquito net to Mr. Radik.
Just give it to him.
You give the mosquito net
to whoever's dying next?
Future passive. "I shall be loved."
Amabor. It's like
losing the war, dying.
"They were being loved."
Amabantur. Can I have his shoes
when he's dead?
You pragmatist.
-"You will have been loved."
-Amatus eris.
We have to beat them.
-Who?
-The Japanese.
It's how we'll win, refusing to die.
-What happens when war ends?
-Do you want it to end?
If we stay in the camps,
the Japanese will look after us.
We're an embarrassment to them.
They can't feed us much longer.
They'll fight the Americans.
You admire the Japanese?
They're brave.
-That's important?
-If you want to win a war.
We don't want them to win.
I know.
Remember, we're British.
Yes.
I've never been there.
Put that down.
Tomorrow, gerunds.
What about English?
Think of it as the antidote.
We are never sure of sorrow
Joy was never sure
Today will die, tomorrow
Time stoops to no man's lure
With love grown--
Learn it as a poem.
It's not just a string of words.
-Would you look at Mr. Radik?
-Yes, of course.
Those from the hospital garden?
I have to give Basie something--
Good thing you're friends.
He's a survivor.
Because he only drinks boiled water.
You'll wear yourself out looking
after everyone.
Keeps himself busy, doesn't he?
Young Jim.
-The caterers are arriving.
-I'll be there!
Won't taste the same without you.
Wait for me!
What about mines?
-Get out.
Maybe the Japs put down mines.
-Hey, boss. Boss!
-Boss, it's the kid.
Come in.
-Would you like a Hershey bar?
-Please!
So would I. Have you got one?
Stop breathing so much.
There ain't enough air.
There isn't enough air for you
in China.
-Here are your clothes.
-Better than the Shanghai laundry.
-Did you get a cork?
-I got one.
Good boy.
-That's fine.
-I've never seen that one. What year?
-'45.
-'45? How'd you get that?
I subscribe. It has Packard,
Studebaker, Jell-O. Things from home.
-Can you get me a sewing needle?
-I'll try.
-What's that?
-It's a trap.
Get out of here.
It's all right. You're almost one of
us. You see that Mustang?
-It's the Cadillac of the sky.
-That's right. B-29s too.
B-29s?
The Super fortress.
A hemisphere defense weapon.
Where from?
Okinawa. Philippines. Tokyo's in
bombing range now.
-Tokyo?
-Time to think of going home soon.
We'll have to leave the camp?
One side feeds you,
the other tries to kill you.
It's turned around. It's all timing.
-Tell me when it's time? Promise?
-Promise.
It'd be simpler to live here.
You've the British dorm to go to
when they're sick of you.
They are sick of me.
The British dorm's so lethargic.
Will you let me?
This'll be the place on Thanksgiving.
I'll have pheasant.
Pheasant?
Just made the traps.
Works like a noose.
Stick out your arm. Neat.
I've seen no pheasants, have you?
-Outside the wire.
-Which wire?
-Our wire.
-That cIose?
At the edge of the airfield,
across the canal.
An American initiative.
Whoever delivers gets the gravy.
How's your friend, Dr. Schweitzer?
I brought Amy Matthews
back to life for a minute.
That's worth a Reader's Digest.
Increase your word power.
pragmatist.
-Good word.
If I set the traps, could I live here?
-It's a consideration.
-Take me with you?
Frankly, it's a tossup now between
you and Dainty.
Take me!
Give me a good reason I should.
I'm your friend.
Chow truck's here.
-Mr. Maxton keeps my place.
They cut the bloody rations!
-Don't worry. I'll get yours.
-You're just like your father.
They cut our rations in half!
I'll get ours. You sit down.
You cut the bloody rations!
You cut them!
Mr. Maxton.
I've got yours, Mr. Maxton.
I've got some! I've got some!
Hello, everybody.
Sit there.
Eat, please.
The rations have been cut.
They're like animals.
82, 83, 84....
Sorry.
87 weevils today, Mr. Victor.
Above average, but the trend is down.
Must you, Jim?
-Sorry.
Some of us will die just before we're
saved, so use everything.
-You'll miss this camp after the war.
-Will I?
I'll locate my parents when the people
in the camps come out.
-I'll tell my dad you looked after me.
-Think I'll get the reward?
-What reward?
-You told everyone.
I was much younger then.
Why'd the Japanese close the school?
To punish the grownups.
I wonder how you'll take to school
in England.
It might be strange.
The best teacher's
the university of life.
For heaven's--
Could we finish our meal? We know
your views on the university of life.
-We should eat the weevils.
-I know. Dr. Rawlins told you.
-He said we need the protein.
-Yes, he's right.
We should all eat the weevils.
Do you believe in vitamins?
Strange child.
Perhaps it's time you moved
into the men's dormitory.
You're not 12 anymore.
The Americans are over Nantao again.
They're bombing the Shanghai docks!
Coney Island pilots.
-What was that?
-A 29 going down.
-A 200-pounder.
-That was close.
-Too close for Nagata.
-He won't like that.
What's happening, doctor?
Reprisals, and damned silly it is too.
-Keep the patients from the windows.
-Yes, doctor.
Hey!
Get away! This is British food!
Leave it alone!
It's our food. Get away!
Guards!
Mines. That was a mine. I told you.
Somebody lobbed a grenade.
Say, Basie, I bet he hits a mine.
I bet you there are no mines.
You can walk right through.
You got a bet.
So far, so good.
He's seen something.
Jim's a black cat.
That's a dead boy, Basie.
I'll give you odds.
My harmonica...
...and my next meal
against your wristwatch.
You're on, my friend.
I double my bet.
My next two meals.
-You'll lose a lot of weight.
-What else you betting?
-My Life.
-Who's on the cover?
Two cigarettes on Jim!
Sunglasses on Nagata!
Keep going, sarge!
The lucky kid.
Cleaned me out.
-Hello, Jim.
-Hello, Nina.
-Would you like a Hershey bar?
-Yes.
So would I, kid. You got one?
Don't let me down, kid.
You're an American now.
How you doing, Frank?
The river's east. You can go
up the bank or up the middle...
...or go north of east,
but you gotta go across canals.
Don't know if it's buildings or what.
Where'd you get a map?
A cork and needle?
-A compass that actually works.
-Put it down.
-Is it time?
-No, I'll tell you when.
-You won't forget?
-Fat chance.
-I almost feel human.
-Without me, you'd have no compass.
No, without you
I wouldn't have the needle.
The best way is across the river.
Nagata!
Jim, the curtain.
Jim, come here.
You're in charge of my stuff.
You see this mosquito net?
See?
What's it tell you?
Rawlins is on the take.
-You're so clever, Basie.
-Yeah.
Only cost me two batteries.
How are you feeling?
I've had worse.
I was beaten by a stoker once.
Were you a stoker?
Ship's steward.
Shanghai-Frisco line.
Why did he beat you?
Shanghai-Frisco will be
the trip now. Huh, Jim?
Basie, where do you live?
Here.
No, I mean after the war.
Somewhere else.
Until you find a place,
you could live at Amherst Avenue.
I'd like you to come
and meet my parents.
We could fill up the pool...
...and we'll eat three times a day.
You're not feeling
sorry for me, are you?
-No one feels sorry for you, Basie.
-That's right.
-And you always eat first.
-You said it, kid.
I've been thinking about
going upriver.
I know.
Listen--
The plan is,
we're going to get a sampan.
Take it up the Yangtze estuary.
Rendezvous with some Hakka friends.
Are they proper pirates, you mean?
Let's just call them gentlemen
of fortune, shall we?
Did you ever see...
-...the Hell Drivers in Shanghai?
-Yes. On the newsreels.
I saw them crash
through a burning wall.
That's what I'm going to call
our little outfit.
With 250 calibers...
...we are going to be
the lords of the Yangtze.
Actually, that may be a better name.
It's at the beginning and end of war
that we have to watch out.
In between, it's like a country club.
But you gotta know how to stay
balanced and make the right friends.
Because this war
is definitely winding down.
And after that?
After that...
... I retire in luxury,
start a barber college....
What are you doing here?
I told you to look out for my stuff.
They were bigger than me.
Look who's here.
So you were under the net?
Cleaned up your room.
Stay with me, darling!
Everybody inside, quick!
Away from the buildings!
Oh, God. Please, no!
My husband's in there!
Go! P-51, Cadillac of the sky!
P-51, Cadillac of the sky!
Jim?
Jim, get off the roof!
Jim!
Horsepower!
Get down, Jim. Go on, get down!
P-51! Aren't they beautiful?
-Get down!
-I touched them!
I felt their heat! I can taste them.
Oil and cordite.
Come back to the hospital.
Remember how we helped
to build the runway?
If we'd died like the others,
our bones would be in the runway.
-In a way, it's our runway.
-No, it's their runway, Jim.
Try not to think so much.
Try not to think so much!
I can't remember
what my parents look like.
I used to play bridge
with my mother in her bedroom.
She used to comb her hair.
I'd watch her.
She had dark hair.
What's happening?
The guards are leaving!
They're taking us upcountry.
They're moving us to Nantao!
There's food there.
One suitcase!
We leave in one hour! One suitcase!
Our rations are at Nantao.
He's gone.
Him and Dainty.
He's gone?
He's escaped?
He can't have. He promised me!
He knew it was time.
-Where am I gonna go?
-We'll all have to leave now.
He knew it was time.
Boy.
Difficult boy.
Just look...
...later here for escort!
Jim, where's my husband?
Where's Mr. Victor?
We are civilians. Listen to me.
I am a British doctor.
They are my responsibility!
We must have rest and food.
We're going upcountry, Jim.
Will there be food there?
There's none here.
Mrs. Victor, we're going upcountry.
Mrs. Victor.
Come on, Jim.
No.
Don't go. It's better here.
Jim!
You'll die here.
Don't worry, Mr. Maxton.
Pretend you're dead, Mrs. Victor.
Mrs. Victor.
Surrender reached the
Japanese in a broadcast by Hirohito.
He said Japan will endure the
unendurable and suffer greatly.
The war minister and others
committed suicide outside the palace.
Japan is devastated,
destroyed in spirit...
...as Hiroshima and Nagasaki
have been destroyed.
More than 100,000 people
were killed...
...in two single-bomb explosions,
which ended the Pacific War.
The Russian declaration of war...
...has sent a million
soldiers into Manchuria.
Tokyo was hit with a dawn-to-dusk
raid by 1500 B-29 bombers.
But Japan's war was lost.
Her goal to create...
...a new empire incinerated
in a flash...
...hotter than the sun.
Everyone stands in awe of
the new super-weapon.
Only a few scientists knew the power
in splitting the uranium atom.
It reached us in a shock wave...
the atom bomb.
Each of the two bombs...
...had the power of
20,000 tons of explosives.
Nagasaki is
Japan's gateway to China...
...just 500 miles from Shanghai.
I saw that! I saw it! I saw it!
The white light.
I thought it was Mrs. Victor's
soul going to heaven.
Jim!
Bastard!
He gave me a mango.
I'll give you
a whole fruit salad!
There's Frigidaires
falling from the sky!
-He was my friend!
-He was a Jap!
The war's over!
You walked here from Nantao Stadium?
What did you see? Rich pickings?
Crystal chandeliers, cocktail bars...
...white pianos?
I learned a new word today.
Atom bomb.
It was like a white light
in the sky.
Like God taking a photograph.
I saw it.
I can bring everyone back.
Everyone.
-Everyone. Everyone.
-Jim!
-Didn't I teach you anything?
-Yes!
Yeah.
You taught me people will do
anything for a potato.
Three years with him?
Come on. I'll take you
back to your dad.
We'll fill the pool
and eat three meals a day.
Kid, you want a Hershey's bar?
Yes, please, Basie.
I surrender.
Come along. Off you go.
Gather in, children.
Mum?
Ju-- Julie!
Jamie?
Jamie.