I busied myself to think of a story...
...which would speak
to the mysterious fears of our nature...
...and awaken thrilling horror.
One to make the reader
dread to look around.
To curdle the blood,
and quicken the beatings of the heart.
Tell the captain,
we've got to take in the topsail.
She's going to rip!
Please, captain!
We have to drop the sails!
All hands to the mast!
Take the wheel! Come on!
Captain, we've hit the ice!
We've hit the ice!
Iceberg ahead!
Hard to starboard!
Go back!
Help! Help!
-Help!
-Hold on, Vernon!
Hold on!
Put your backs into it, men!
Let's go!
Captain, this is useless.
The ice stretches for miles.
What do you suggest we do?
Lay down and die?
The men are exhausted, sir.
They can't go on, man.
I tell you, I have not come this far
to give up now.
They knew the risk
when they signed on.
And we are gonna chop our way
to the North Pole if we have to.
Then you run the risk of mutiny,
captain.
-Did you say mutiny?
-Yes I did, sir.
We proceed north as planned.
At the cost of how many more lives?
As many as it takes!
There's something out there.
What is it?
What the hell is that?
Who is your captain?
I am.
Who the devil are you?
I've no time to talk.
You bring your men and your weapons
and follow me.
-Now!
-Stay where you are.
I give the orders here.
Get the dogs! Get them!
Leave them.
They're already dead.
Get back to the ship now!
Everybody back to the ship!
Bears don't kill like that, nothing does.
Maybe it wants the man
with the captain.
-Or it wants the captain.
-The devil's come for the captain.
For the last time, I made my way from
St. Petersburg to Archangel on foot.
From there I took a whaling ship north.
When we hit the ice, I used the dogs.
What's out there?
Listen to me. I have spent six years
planning this, my entire fortune.
I will not be stopped by you
or some phantom.
Do you share my madness?
-No, not madness.
-What, then?
There's a passage to the North Pole,
and I will find it.
At the cost of your own life?
The lives of your crew?
Lives come and go.
If we succeed,
our names will live on forever.
I will be hailed
as the benefactor of our species.
You're wrong.
I, of all men, know that.
Who are you?
My name...
...is Victor...
...Frankenstein.
Mother!
Oh, my wonderful son Victor!
You are the handsomest, kindest,
cleverest...
...most wonderfulest boy
in the whole world!
Madam! You will spoil the boy, really.
Would you two leave us, please,
Mrs. Moritz?
Doctor.
Come along, Justine.
Victor, this is Elizabeth.
She's coming to live with us.
She's lost both her mother and father
to the scarlet fever, Victor.
She's an orphan now.
You must think of her
as your own sister.
You must look after her,
and be kind to her.
Always.
Mother, oh.
How is the imminent arrival?
Oh, a little frisky today.
When you were a little boy,
you used to chase fireflies in the field.
Yes, and when I trapped them
in my jar, they died.
-And do you remember how you cried?
-Yes.
Because you wanted to keep them
glowing by your bedside...
...to light you as you read.
You were so hungry for knowledge.
Such a serious little boy.
You've become
such an earnest young man.
All these strange and ancient books.
You'll be an even greater doctor
than your father.
But you know, Victor,
life shouldn't be all study.
There's such fun to be had.
-Give me that back.
-No.
Give me that back, Mother.
Change partners. And twirl!
-Now, Caroline.
-You're right.
-You mustn't exert yourself. Please.
-I know.
Don't worry, madam. Your new baby
will be a natural dancer.
Excellent.
You'll be the envy
of all the young ladies and gentlemen.
Justine.
Justine, may I have this dance?
-Madam!
-Hurry!
You must make a decision!
How can I?
The baby's in the wrong position.
I can't proceed.... I can't....
Cut me. Save the baby.
She'll be all right.
Your father's the finest doctor
in Geneva.
Father?
Father, how is she?
I did everything I could....
Everything I could....
Mother? Mother!
Bring her back.
Please, bring her back.
No!
Oh, Mother.
You should never have died.
No one need ever die.
I will stop this.
I promise.
Victor, you're completely obsessed.
Please explain what that is.
It's energy. It never disappears,
it merely changes form.
It's possible to convert
this candle wax...
...into the convulsions
of a mechanical dog.
But the applications of this
are limitless. Really.
Oh, please come outside, Victor.
It's such a beautiful day.
Go away, I'm busy.
What's this?
It's for spraying down the electric eels.
Now, put it down. Put it down.
It's not for playing with.
It's not for playing with. Put it down,
put it down-- Don't do that.
I warned you. Don't-- Don't--
Give me that, you little....
Come on!
We should be grateful to Victor...
...for abandoning his experiments
for one afternoon.
Well, who says I have?
What do you mean?
Look!
We're all going to die.
-You knew this would happen.
-Not for certain.
But I had hoped the conditions
would be right. They're common here.
I've never seen one quite as large,
though. Look.
-Isn't it wonderful?
-Victor, you shouldn't have done this.
It's all right, it's all right.
-We must take cover. A tree!
-That's exactly the wrong thing to do.
It's a much larger conductor
than we are.
Victor, what about Willie?
-What are we to do?
-Come on.
Spread out.
Elizabeth, take this. Now, quickly.
-Come on, quickly!
-What is that?
Dig it right into the ground. Go ahead.
-Now what?
-Justine, take this. Come on.
-Willie!
-Everyone down.
Give me your hands. It'll be fine.
Now take him. Now, that's good.
I hope you know
what you're doing.
-Willie? Willie, don't look up!
-Willie.
-Victor--
-Wait!
One, two, three....
Now.
So how do you feel, Elizabeth?
Alive.
Ladies and gentlemen, dear friends.
Gather round and listen.
As you probably know,
tomorrow my dear son Victor...
...leaves me to pursue,
what I'm sure...
...will be an illustrious career
in a profession...
...I am not altogether
unassociated with.
Oh, modesty.
My one regret is that his mother...
...my late wife, is not here...
...to share the pride...
...which our son fills me with tonight.
Yes.
She wanted you to have this, Victor.
On your graduation.
And in it she has written:
"This is the journal
of Victor Frankenstein."
The rest of the leaves are blank...
...to be filled with the deeds
of a noble life.
We'd better go in,
before they miss us.
Just a little while longer. Please.
I don't know when we'll be
alone together again.
Oh, dear Victor.
I shall miss you laughing at me.
I'll miss you making me laugh.
So how do brothers and sisters
say goodbye?
Perhaps they never have to.
I won't, if you won't.
Are you my sister?
Sister...
...friend...
...lover.
Wife?
Yes.
Then come with me to Ingolstadt.
Marry me now.
-Victor, no.
-Well, then I'll stay.
I want more than anything else
in the world to be your wife.
But as long as you're away,
I belong here.
I want to make this house live again.
I want to make this
a great home for our children.
And now you must go, and do
the great things you need to do.
I want you so much.
I'll be here when you return.
Each holiday. Every visit.
Then on our wedding night.
Until our wedding night.
Lots of stairs, I'm afraid.
-How was your journey?
-Good, thanks. I made good progress...
-...over the mountains.
-I am pleased.
-As I said, we've only got attic space.
-It's exactly what I'm looking for.
But Frau Brach,
there will be a great deal...
...of scientific equipment and rigging
to be delivered.
Every day, for the next week.
I trust you have no objections.
I'm sure you appreciate the need
for a proper laboratory.
Oh, Putzi likes you.
This will be perfect.
"The foolish and vain
force their views by the rod.
But knowledge is power
only through God."
Our motto. Easily forgotten
by you young men in a hurry.
But perhaps the greatest mistake
that all students make...
...during their time here,
is to suppose...
...that they can ever have
an original or creative thought.
We have all imagined that
in our time.
But gentlemen, you have not come
here in order to think for yourselves.
You are here to learn
how to think for your patients.
You must learn, therefore,
in the first place...
...to submit yourselves...
...to the established laws
of physical reality.
But surely, professor...
...you don't intend we disregard
more philosophical approaches?
Philosophical?
Those which stir the imagination as
well as the intellect, as in Paracelsus.
Paracelsus.
An arrogant and foolish Swiss.
Albertus Magnus?
His nonsense was exploded
500 years ago.
Cornelius Agrippa?
A sorcerer. An occultist.
What is your name?
Victor Frankenstein, sir. Of Geneva.
Another Swiss.
Mr. Frankenstein, here at
the University of Ingolstadt, we teach--
And indeed, hope to advance.
--the science of medicine.
Chemistry, biology, physics.
We study hard science.
Surely, the greatest possible advances
lie in combining these things.
We do not study the ravings
of lunatics and alchemists...
...hundreds of years in their graves...
...because their kind of amateur,
fanatical, fantastical speculation...
...does not heal bodies or save lives.
Only science can do that.
Now, have we your permission
to continue?
-Nice coat.
-Why, thank you.
Don't take it too hard.
Krempe doesn't approve
of public humiliation.
-I am not mad!
-My dear fellow, of course you're not.
In fact, that's just what I'd expect
a perfectly rational person...
...to say to a complete stranger.
Henry Clerval, by the way,
and I'm completely crazy.
-Victor Frankenstein.
-Of Geneva.
-Yes, I noti--
Why don't you look where I'm going?
That's Schiller.
Ornament of the playing field.
-Really.
-He's new as well.
You can tell because he goes around
looking at things with his mouth open.
What are you here for?
-Research.
-Very grand.
I'm here to become a mere doctor.
I'm told it has something to do
with healing the sick.
Which is a pity, really, because
I find sick people rather revolting.
Still, I'll have a good time,
get my degree--
If I can stop failing Anatomy.
--and settle down to relieve rich
old ladies of their imaginary ailments...
...and then relieve their very real
and beautiful daughters.
-Who was that? He was at the lecture.
-That's Waldman.
-Yes.
Interesting case.
They say in his youth...
...he could break into heaven
and lecture God on science.
Ran into trouble with the authorities
years back.
Something to do
with illegal experiments.
But what kind of experiments,
I wonder?
So what was it you were saying?
Rich old ladies and their daughters?
Yes, it's a life of sacrifice, I know,
but someone's got to do it.
And that is why
the central nervous system...
...and its crowning achievement,
the brain...
...are as complicated and mysterious
a set of organs...
...as you are ever likely to encounter.
Mr. Frankenstein,
the incision is yours.
Excellent.
Mr. Clerval,
you may remove the cranial lid.
"Henry, now fully recovered, continues
his struggle to pass Anatomy."
I was always terrible at anatomy.
"Professor Waldman is very tolerant
of us. I'm learning a great deal."
-Professor Waldman is remarkable.
-And so is Henry.
"God bless you, all my love, Victor."
-That's very nice.
-"P.S. I've fallen in love."
I beg your pardon?
"She's dark, sleek, and beautiful...
...and always wags her tail
whenever she sees me.
Her name is Putzi, and she's the
friendliest sheepdog that I've known."
"P.S. Elizabeth,
I dream of how your hair shines...."
"Of how your lips taste.
I dream of your arms and breasts...
...and of the time
on our wedding night...
...when we will be alone
together at last."
What else does it say?
It says, "I'm working very hard
to make lots of new friends."
More coffee, anyone?
Once and for all, Frankenstein!
Life is life, death is death.
These things are real.
-They are absolute.
-That is rubbish and you know it!
That premise has been repeatedly
challenged by your own staff!
Yes, you, sir! We don't know
where life ends or death begins.
Hair continues to grow after what we
choose to call death. So do fingernails.
We know that a man's brain may die...
...but his heart and lungs may
continue to pump and breathe.
Now, you know that.
Mr. Frankenstein of Geneva,
I warn you...
...what you are suggesting is not only
illegal, it is immoral.
Rubbish!
"Dear diary, why does no one
understand me? P.S. I am not mad."
You.
-Explain yourself.
-Professor, I'm sorry.
Listen, I came here to learn
all about the new science.
About galvanism,
Franklin's experiments.
Combination of modern disciplines
with ancient knowledge...
-...to protect and create--
-To create what?
Sir, we can change things. We can
make things better. You know that.
We are on the verge
of undreamed-of discoveries...
...if we only have the courage to ask
the right questions. You must help me.
Come on.
-Victor....
-Come on.
Henry.
Lock the door.
Now, for thousands of years...
...the Chinese have based
their medical science on the belief...
...that the human body is a chemical
engine run by energy streams.
-Fascinating. How do they explain--?
-Don't touch that!
Their doctors treat patients...
...by inserting needles like these
into the flesh...
...at various key points,
to manipulate these electric streams.
I see.
So electricity is the key.
Now, look at this.
Go on, touch it.
-It feels warm.
-It is.
Yes. How do you do?
Turn it off!
-I can't, it's not working.
-Try to stay calm, Henry.
Simply a matter
of reducing the polarity.
A monkey's arm is basically
the same as ours.
-No arm is this strong!
-Now, this must work.
Let me help you, professor.
You shall, of course, tell no one.
They wouldn't believe you anyway.
Dearest Victor.
Nothing much changes here.
Mrs. Moritz continues to love and
torment Justine, in equal measure.
Willie grows more precocious
every day...
...and Father almost expires
with pride...
...at the very thought of you
and your work.
And I....
Well, I just miss you, very much.
Please write soon, Victor.
No, I'm serious.
You take vaccine, for instance.
Thirty years ago the entire concept
of vaccine was unheard of...
...and now we save lives every day.
-But that isn't the whole answer.
-What do you mean?
That sooner or later the best way
to cheat death will be to create life.
Now you've gone too far.
-There's only one God, Victor.
-No, leave God out of it.
If you loved someone,
they had a sick heart...
...wouldn't you give them a healthy
one? It's not impossible.
We can do it, we're steps away.
If we can replace one part of a
human, we can replace every part.
And if we do that,
we can design a life.
We can create a being
that will not grow old or sicken.
One that's stronger than us,
better than us.
One more intelligent than us,
more civilized than us.
-In our lifetime?
-No.
How close did you get, professor?
Too close.
Professor, I beg you,
let me see these notes.
No. My work now,
and its application...
...lies exclusively
in the preservation of life.
I abandoned my other researches
many years ago.
Why?
Because they resulted in abomination.
You're not sticking that in me.
It's got a pox in it, I hear.
-Pox? They've given us pox?
-Pox.
It's not pox, it's a vaccine
that will prevent plague in this city.
-What's that?
-It's a tiny, harmless amount...
-...of anti-smallpox serum.
-You just said pox!
I said it was harmless.
It's a necessary precaution,
without which this godforsaken city...
...would be immediately
put under quarantine.
You doctors kill. I don't care what
you say. You're not sticking that in me.
Yes, I am. It's the law!
-Sit him down, someone.
-You're not sticking that in me!
You're not sticking that in me!
-Sir?
-Professor? Sir?
Find him!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
It's no use, Victor, he's gone.
-No! No, Henry!
-Let him go!
-No! No, this shouldn't happen!
-Let him go! Victor, stop!
-It shouldn't happen!
-Stop!
It need not happen!
The hell with you!
Whatever you say, whatever you
call it, you doctors are killers.
You murder people!
Evil! You're evil!
Evil!
You're the ones that deserve to die.
God will punish you. He'll punish you!
God will punish you!
My God, you were so close!
Of course, the power!
The materials were wrong.
You needed auxiliary sources.
"The experiment a failure.
Resulting reanimant
malformed and hideous to behold.
This factor dependant on the
appropriate raw materials."
Raw materials....
-Come on, Henry.
-I can't help you, Victor.
-You won't. What are you afraid of?
-Everything! What if the authorities--?
We'll do this in secret. I've got the raw
materials, I've got Waldman's journals.
-You stole his journals?
-We owe it to him to complete this.
-He was one step away.
-He never wanted this.
Couldn't face it, that's different.
Even if it were possible,
and even if you had the right--
Which you don't.
--to make this decision for us...
...can you imagine there wouldn't
be a terrible price to pay?
I think for the chance
to defeat death and disease...
...to let everyone on Earth
have the chance at life...
...sustained, healthy life...
...to allow people who love each
other to be together forever....
For all of that,
I think it's a risk worth taking.
Please, Justine, just leave me alone.
I won't talk about it.
But all these letters,
you read them to us every week.
I wrote them. I wrote the letters.
He hasn't written to me in months.
Elizabeth....
Something horrific is happening
to him. I can feel it.
At first I wasn't sure,
but I knew I had to hide it from Father.
Now there are rumors of cholera.
I can look after Father and Willie.
You go to Ingolstadt--
That's not possible. He won't want me.
He's probably found someone else.
If he was mine,
I would have gone already.
But he isn't mine.
He's yours, and you must go to him.
Raw materials, that's all they are.
Tissue to be re-used.
The very finest brain.
-But they all died of cholera, sir.
-No matter.
Thank you.
The assembled organs must have
the appropriate nutrients and heat...
...and crucially, more direct power.
More direct power.
Amniotic fluid is the
chief biogenic element.
The subject is injected with this.
The copper acupuncture needles...
...are inserted at key energy points.
Now, after the removal of current,
the dead toad should retain animation.
But independently
of external power sources.
Yes.
That's it.
That's the combination.
That's the combination!
That's it!
Victor? Victor!
Victor, open the door!
-Victor, please!
-What do you want?
There's cholera. It's an epidemic!
The city's been placed
under martial law.
-Are you listening to me, Victor?
-Yes. And?
The militia's arriving
to quarantine the city.
Most of us are getting out
while we still can.
Krempe knows you're here.
What if he tells the authorities?
Goodbye, Henry.
Victor, it's me.
Elizabeth.
Can you hear me?
Victor, I have to see you.
-Go away.
-Please, Victor!
I won't leave here until you see me.
Come in the side door.
Alone!
What's happened to you?
How can you live here like this?
And that stench.
Don't go in there!
-We have to leave. It isn't safe.
-No, I have to stay.
-Even if it means you'll die?
-Yes.
Well, let me help you.
No, that's impossible.
We made a promise.
Victor, I beg you.
Look, I know that this
is difficult for you to understand...
...but I cannot abandon this work
now.
It is too important. Not just for me,
but, believe me, for everyone.
And it must come first.
Before us?
Elizabeth...
...I love you so much, but....
Goodbye.
Elizabeth! Elizabeth!
Oh, God! Elizabeth!
Elizabeth!
Live! Live! Live!
Live!
Yes!
No....
No!
It's alive.
No.
What have I done?
"Massive birth defects.
Greatly enhanced
physical strength.
But resulting reanimant...
...is malfunctional...
...and pitiful...
...and dead."
Tomorrow this journal and
its secrets must be destroyed...
...forever.
Oh, God.
No!
You fool,
Victor Frankenstein of Geneva.
How could you know
what you'd unleashed?
How is it pieced together?
Bits of thieves, bits of murderers....
Evil stitched to evil stitched to evil.
Do you really believe this thing
will thank you for its monstrous birth?
Evil will have its revenge.
God help your loved ones.
What do you think you're doing?
He's got cholera! He's the one
who's been spreading the plague!
Get him!
Come here, you--
Keep away from him.
No, kill him now!
He went this way.
There now. Easy. Easy. Just a bit.
-That's it. There, now, rest easy.
-Henry, you're here.
Of course I'm here.
It was touch and go with you, though.
I feared cholera,
turned out to be pneumonia.
Yes, I'm becoming
something of a doctor.
Even Krempe
seems pleased with me.
At this rate,
I might even pass Anatomy.
-The epidemic?
-Dreadful.
There's nothing we can do for them.
The vulnerable, anyone who's
without shelter or food...
...the newborns, especially, will die.
-Are you sure?
-I'm certain of it.
Thank God.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
Well then, that's my shift finished.
I'll see you later.
Elizabeth.
-Please, please, forgive me!
-Of course I do.
Victor, I don't know what you're
working on, and I don't want to know.
But it nearly killed you.
It's over, it's finished.
It should never have started.
It's dead! It's dead.
-Felix!
-Yes?
Don't forget the onion scraps.
All right, I've got them.
Go on, get.
Come on. Come on.
Go on, go on. Go on. Get.
-How are the pigs?
-Happy they've been fed.
-How are your hands?
-They're bleeding again.
Let me see them.
That's better.
There.
-The soup's ready.
-Come on, Grandpa. Sit down.
Thank you.
We'll never get through the winter
with this yield.
-The ground's frozen hard.
-We'll sell another pig at market.
We can't.
Not until they lift the quarantine.
Even then, it's one less for us. Last
month's rent, he'll be back for that.
Come on. We'll do this together.
You're right.
We've got to,
before the snow comes.
Come on, then.
The ground's frozen solid. We'd need
20 men to do this. It's useless!
-It's getting late.
-We don't have enough to eat.
We'll manage. Let's go.
Look. Look.
They must be gifts
from the Good Spirit of the Forest.
Father, nothing in this life
comes free of cost.
-I would like to know who and why.
-Was it the Good Spirit, Grandpa?
-I believe it was.
-Don't fill their head with nonsense.
Who's there?
Felix? Children?
Right.
What's this one?
-Friend?
-Friend! Well done!
That's very good.
You've got lots of friends,
haven't you? Grandpa and....
Friend....
Friend.
Family.
Father.
You must travel with them
for the entire journey.
This equipment
must not be left unattended.
My father will take delivery of them
in Geneva. Understand?
I do, sir.
-Going somewhere?
-Henry, look.
Look at this locket Victor gave me.
Isn’t it beautiful?
-Yes, it's lovely. Is this really you?
-Yes, it's a bad likeness, I know.
But for now,
it will serve instead of a ring.
Congratulations
on the entirely expected!
-When?
-As soon as we get home.
We'll be there for New Year's Eve.
-He's taking over Father's practice.
-And expanding it.
I'm going on ahead now the
quarantine's lifted. So much to do.
Now, the practice needs a partner.
Now, there's not much money...
...but there is food and board
and some very good company.
And it's the ideal position for someone
who has finally passed Anatomy.
So we were wondering if...
...there was anybody
that you could recommend?
Victor, I-- I don't know what to say.
Well, please say yes.
-Yes.
-Yes!
-Yes, yes!
And you can write that down
in your journal!
"This is...
...the journal...
...of...
...Victor...
...Frankenstein...
...of...
...Geneva."
Come on, quickly.
Come on, then, off you go.
Quickly, now.
-Merry Christmas.
Come on, now. Come on.
Time for bed.
In you go.
"For the Good Spirit of the Forest."
Are you
the Good Spirit of the Forest?
Not exactly. Where's your father?
I said, where's your father?
Who's there? Maggie?
-No.
-Oh, it's you.
-What have you done to Maggie?
-Is he in there?
Hiding behind a blind old man?
Get away! Get away!
Don't blame me.
Blame your son
for not paying his rent on time.
My God.
Thank you, my friend.
Thank you so much.
Won't you come and sit by the fire?
Please, don't be afraid.
Come. Come in.
Have a rest, sit down.
That's better.
I'm glad you finally came in.
A man shouldn't have to hide
in the shadows.
Better that way, for me.
Why?
People are afraid.
Except you.
It can't be as bad as that.
Worse.
I can "see" you with my hands,
if you'll trust me.
-Papa, Papa, he hurt Grandpa!
-Who hurt Grandpa?
-What was that noise?
-Tell me what the noise was.
What happened, Maggie?
Poor man.
Have you no friends?
There are some people.
But they don't know me.
Why do you not go to them?
Because I am so very...
...ugly.
And they are so very...
...beautiful.
Father! Get out of here!
-Get out of here, monster.
-Leave him alone!
We have to leave here.
No.
I will have revenge!
Frankenstein!
Geneva.
-Quickly, quickly.
-She's here, she's here!
-Willie!
-We got your letter!
It's the first one
I was allowed to read.
Congratulations, Elizabeth.
-I'm happy for you.
-Thank you, Justine.
Oh, is that the locket?
Look how handsome Victor is.
-Can I take this to show Peter?
-Yes, but, Willie, it's not a toy.
Let him go.
Don't dawdle, William!
Justine, you idiot. Pay attention.
Anyone would think
you're the one that's getting married.
-Yes, Mother.
-What's wrong?
Nothing. Really.
Just leave it. You've ruined it now.
No! No!
Frankenstein.
You, with me.
-Have you seen Willie?
-Isn’t he back yet?
Claude went
to find if he'd lost track of time.
-They say he never arrived.
-Far too late for him to still be out.
-William!
Willie!
Willie....
This isn't a game!
Willie!
It's so late.
We're all so tired. I'm so tired.
Father! I'm so pleased to see you.
What's wrong?
William!
We checked the east ridge.
There's nothing there.
Damn!
Elizabeth?
I found him!
Elizabeth!
No!
We did everything we could, sir.
You just rest easy now.
We did everything we could.
Sir, I'm terrified for my girl.
She's still out looking for William.
We parted badly. I was cruel to her.
I didn't mean it.
I think she finds it hard, with your
wedding. She loves you dearly.
I couldn't bear it if anything
happened to her.
She's all I've got. Please, help me!
We'll organize another search
now that it's light.
We will find her, Mrs. Moritz,
I promise.
-How is Father?
-His heart is breaking.
Mr. Frankenstein...
...we've apprehended the murderer,
five miles from here hiding in a barn.
We found this on her.
It's yours, I believe, sir?
Sir, you must come immediately.
The townspeople have gone mad.
-What are they doing?
-They must have broken into the jail!
For God's sake, can't you stop them?
They've gone wild!
This is a lynching mob!
Stop! This is unlawful.
-Justine.
-Justine!
Victor! Help me!
I was trying to find him!
I went to the lake, but it was dark!
I wanted to bring him to you!
He must be there for the wedding!
I'm sorry! He's so tiny.
We managed to close the gates
on the mob, Claude.
What about Justine?
We've cut her down.
We can bury her in the morning.
Thank you, Claude. Get to bed.
The sea of ice.
I will meet you there...
...on the sea of ice.
Oh, Justine, forgive me.
Victor, tell me. Who is this man?
How do you know he's responsible?
I'll tell you everything
after I destroy him.
This is a matter for the police.
They wouldn't understand.
Well, neither do I.
Then just accept it.
Get up.
You do speak.
Yes, I speak.
And read.
And think.
And know the ways of man.
How did you find me?
Your journal.
Then you mean to kill me.
No.
You murdered my brother,
didn't you?
I took him by the throat
with one hand...
...lifted him off the ground...
...and slowly crushed his neck.
And as I killed him,
I saw your face.
You gave me these emotions. But
you didn't tell me how to use them.
Now two people are dead...
...because of us.
Why?
There's something at work in my soul
which I do not understand.
What of my soul? Do I have one?
Or was that a part you left out?
Who were these people
of which I am comprised?
Good people? Bad people?
-Materials, nothing more.
-You're wrong.
Do you know
I knew how to play this?
In which part of me
did this knowledge reside?
In these hands?
In this mind? In this heart?
And reading and speaking.
Not things learned,
so much as things remembered.
Trace memories in the brain,
perhaps.
Did you ever consider
the consequences of your actions?
You gave me life,
and then you left me to die.
Who am I?
You....
I don't know.
And you think I'm evil.
What can I do?
There is something I want. A friend.
A friend?
Companion.
A female.
Someone like me.
So she won't hate me.
Like you?
Oh, God,
you don't know what you're asking.
I do know that...
...for the sympathy
of one living being...
...I would make peace with all.
I have love in me
the likes of which...
...you can scarcely imagine.
And rage, the likes of which
you would not believe.
If I cannot satisfy the one...
...I will indulge the other.
And if I consent, how will you live?
We would travel north,
my bride and I...
...to the furthest reaches of the Pole.
Where no man has ever set foot.
There, we would live out our lives...
...together.
No human eye
would ever see us again.
This, I vow.
You must help me. Please.
If it is possible
to right this wrong...
...then I will do it.
-Victor!
-Victor.
Are you all right?
-Yes, I'm safe. I'm safe.
-What happened?
Tell us.
Victor.
Victor, you have to
tell us what happened!
One month, that's all I ask.
And then we can be married
and we can forget this whole business.
-I promise.
-Promise? Promise.
Oh, don't dare use that word to me.
You promised to tell me who this man
was. You promised to stop this work.
-Your promises mean nothing.
-Elizabeth.
-I have to leave this house.
-Where will you go?
-Somewhere I can recover.
-This is ridiculous.
I haven't got time to argue.
Oh, isn't it convenient?
Or doesn't it fit in with your plans?
Don't you ever think
of anyone or anything but yourself?
God forgive me.
Why her?
Materials, remember? Nothing more.
-Your words.
-No.
You will honor your promise to me!
I will not.
Go on, kill me now.
That is mild
compared to what will come.
If you deny me my wedding night,
I will be with you on yours.
Elizabeth!
Elizabeth.
Wait. Wait, please wait. Please.
I have to speak to you. Please!
What do you want to say?
Don't go.
Please, don't go.
I'm frightened.
Of what?
I have done something
so terrible...
...so evil.
And I'm frightened
that if I tell you the truth...
...that I will lose you.
You'll lose me if you don't.
I...
...don't know...
...what...
...to do.
Will you marry me, Victor?
Marry me today.
Tomorrow, tell me everything.
But you must tell me the truth.
And together, we can face anything.
Whatever you've done,
whatever has happened...
...I love you.
To share the truth, the whole truth,
for good or ill...
...to stand by each other
in sickness and in health...
...and in joy,
from this day forward...
...till death do you part.
Who is this man, sir?
-How shall we know him?
-Believe me, you'll know him.
He killed Master William,
and Justine Moritz died for it.
No hesitation, lads.
Shoot the bastard on sight!
Henry?
Don't worry about a thing.
You two look after each other.
I'll look after your father.
I'm sorry, sir. The last ferry's gone.
There's nothing now till morning.
-Damn.
-I'll secure you lodgings for the night.
-Thank you, Claude.
-Come on.
-Keep your pistols dry!
-They're dry enough.
And if they fail, we've others.
And if those fail...
...we can always gut the bastard.
-Go to your post.
-Yes, sir.
Don't worry, sir.
You're well guarded.
Now, why don't you
go on upstairs to your wife?
It's not often
a man has his wedding night.
You're soaking.
Brother and sister no more.
Now husband and wife.
Victor?
Lock the door.
-Lock the door.
-Victor.
I saw him in a flash of lightning.
He ran to the lake.
You two stay here.
We lost him.
Elizabeth!
Don't bother to scream.
Please.... Please don't hurt me.
You are lovelier than
I ever could have imagined.
Elizabeth!
I keep my promises!
For God's sake,
tell me what happened.
No point. I know what I have to do.
God. No, Victor! You can't do this,
I won't let you!
She's gone. I love her.
What would you do?
Leave her in peace.
My father would have done this
for my mother.
Your father's dead.
Then there's nothing left to lose.
Nothing but your soul.
Live!
No!
Live. Live.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Say my name.
Please, say my name.
Remember! You must remember.
Elizabeth?
That's it.
That's it, you remember.
Now, stand. Stand.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
You remember.
She's beautiful.
She's not for you.
Come.
Elizabeth?
Say my name.
Elizabeth.
Yes.
Elizabeth!
You're beautiful.
Say my name.
Elizabeth, come to me.
Come to me.
Say my name, Elizabeth.
Vic....
That's right, Elizabeth.
Victor.
No, you're mine.
You're mine.
-Leave her alone! No!
-Get away from her. She's mine.
She's mine! She said my name!
She remembers!
She's mine!
No!
All that I once loved
lies in a shallow grave...
...by my hand.
I followed the trail he left for me--
North.
Always north.
--for months now...
...with one intent:
To kill him.
Now...
...I'm tired.
I'm so very, very tired.
What did he say?
He's dead.
He died raving
about some phantom.
What is it out there, captain?
He told me a story that...
...couldn't be true.
He was mad, I think.
A warming breeze.
-The ice will melt yet.
-And what then, captain?
-We head north.
-No.
Who are you?
He never gave me a name.
Why do you weep?
He was my father.
"And yea, I gave my heart
to know wisdom...
...and to know madness and folly...
...and I perceived that all is
vanity and vexation of spirit.
For in much wisdom is much grief...
...and he that increaseth knowledge,
increaseth sorrow.
For God shall bring every work and
every secret thing into judgment...
...whether it be good,
or whether it be evil."
-Captain--
-He has a right to bear witness.
Jesus, it's breaking up!
Get back to the ship, captain.
Leave the damn torch! Leave it!
Come with us.
I am done with man.
Hang on, I've got you!
Help! Help!
Here, captain. Here, captain.
Quick, grab my hand!
Where to now, captain?
Home.