Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
No son, never.
The blood stays
on the blade.
One day you'll understand.
Some of it I have remembered.
And the rest I
took from dreams.
St. Michael the Archangel
defend us in battle.
Be our protector.
Against the snares. And
the wickedness of the devil.
Now son, who's that?
St. Michael.
Who is it?
And what did he do?
He cast Satan out
of Paradse.
Good boy!
Johnny!
What's the battle?
Natives against the
Dead Rabbits.
Which are you?
What do you think?
Dead Rabbits!
Well,well, Monk!
Are you with us
or not?
For the last time Vallon,
only if the money is right.
I'll give you 10 per notch.
10?
You have my word.
10 per notch. Per new notch.
Then I'm your man.
Is this it, Priest?
The Pope's new army?
A few crusty bitches
and a handful of ragtags!
I know Bill. You swore, this was
a battle between warriors.
Not a bunch of Miss Nancy's.
So warriors is what I brought.
The O'Connell Guard!
The Plug Uglies!
The Shirt Tails!
The Chichesters!
The Forty Thieves!
Bene.
On my challenge, by the ancient
laws of combat...
...we are met at
this chosen ground...
...to settle for good and all...
...who holds sway,
over the Five Points.
Us Natives, born rightwise
to this fine land....
...or the foreign hordes
defiling it!
Under the ancient laws of combat
I accept the challenge of the so called Natives.
You plague our people at
every turn!
But from this day out, you
shall plague us no more!
Let it be known, that the hand
that tries to strike us from this land...
...shall be swiflty cut down!
Then may the Christian Lord, guide
my hand, against your Roman popery!
Prepare to receive
the true Lord!
Priest!
Look at me!
Who is this under my knife?
Father, get up! Get up!
Where are you?
No, my son.
Don't never look away!
Soon be over, Priest.
Finish it!
You may need this to cross
the river.
Ears and noses will be the
trophies of the day.
But no hand shall touch him!
No hand shall touch him!
He'll cross over whole!
In honour!
Not before I get what's owed!
No!
It's fair. A touch indelicate,
but fair.
My sympathies.
What shall we do with
the boy?
Look at me.
Give him to the law.
See he gets a good
education.
Okay, boss. Say goodbye
to your father.
Hey. Take it easy!
Hurry! Come in here!
Come here, boy. You're
going to Hell's Gate!
There he is!
Get him!
Priest Vallon died a
noble death.
But his Dead Rabbits is done
and outlawed.
Let no one even speak their
name from now on.
In this place, you've
grown from a boy into a man.
Put to death the earthly
things in you.
Immorality. Impurity.
Passion. Vengeance.
The Lord has forgiven you.
You also must forgive.
You go forth to a country torn
apart by civil strife.
Thank you, Reverend.
Lend your hand to the work
that yet remains.
That this war may end.
And the plague of slavery,
that brought this confergration down upon us  ...
...vanish forever
from the earth.
In the second year of the
great civil war...
...when the irish brigades
marched through the streets...
...New york was a city
full of tribes.
War chiefs. Rich and poor.
Lincoln will make all
white men slaves!
It wasn't a city really.
It was more a furnace.
Where cities someday
might be forged.
That's the spirit boys.
Go off and die for your
blackie friends.
We should have run a better man against
Lincoln when we had the chance.
They are trying to say ,we
are no different than niggers.
You ain't.
Go back to Africa,
niggers!
The angriest talk was of
the new conscription act.
The first draft in Union
history.
Join the army lads. Three square
meals a day and good pay.
When the Irish came, the city was
in a fever.
Since the time of the great famine
they'd come streaming off the boats.
And they got a right warm welcome.
Go back to Ireland, you
dumb Mick!
You'll remember that!
Get back on the boat, Paddy!
I came only 2 hours down
river from Hell Gate...
..but they all took me
for an immigrant.
Why not?
There were a 1000 different
accents in New York..
..and to the Natives you see,
they were all the same.
Come here to take the chill off
your soul and the weight off your heart.
Welcome to America son, your long
arduous journey is over.
Go back to your own country.
Vote Tammany!
America for Americans!
New York loved William
Tweed and hated him.
And those of us trying
to be thieves....
...we couldn't help but
admire him.
Mr. Cutting. Gentlemen.
Thank you for coming.
It's an honour.
Mr. Tweed?
Sir! Please! Excuse me?
I think your're frightening
them.
So?
Don't mind him, he used to
be an Irishman.
The Five Points!
Murderer's Alley. Brickbat Mansion.
The Gates of hell!
In this wild place....
Look upon the face of this
poor child.
She lives in squalor, in this
godforsaken den of vice and
misery behind me.
Every year the Reformers came.
Every year the Points got
worse.
As if it liked being dirty.
Where am I going to go?
Move.
The Reverend wants you out
of here.
You may or not know Bill, that every
day I go down to the waterfront...
...with hot soup for the Irish
as they come on shore.
As part of building a political
base.
I've noticed you there.
You may have noticed me?
Indeed I have!
Throwing torrents of favours and
withering abuse on every person who
step off those boats.
If only I had the guns Mr. Tweed...
...I'd shoot each and everyone of them,
before they set foot on American soil.
Mulbeery street and Worth. Cross.
Orange and Littlewater.
Each of the Five Points is a
finger...
...when I close my hand
it becomes a fist.
And any time that I wish, I
can turn it against you.
I understand. But we're talking
about different things.
I'm talking about civic duty.
Responsibilites we owe to the people.
Schools and hospitals. Sewers
and utilities.
Street construction, repairs and
sweeping. Business and saloon licences...
St. Michael the Archangel...
Defend us in battle.
Be our protector against the snares
and the wickedness of the devil.
Streetcars, ferries,
rubbish disposal.
There's a power of money to
be made in this city, Bill.
With your help, the people must
be made to understand...
...that all these things are best
kept, in what I like to call the
Tammany family.
That is why I am talking about
an alliance between our organisations.
You're talking about muscle
work.
That too. Muscle to match
our spirit.
You own the crushers, get
them to do it.
The police? Oh, no! Jezus,no!
The appearance of the law must
be upheld.
Especially while it's been
broken.
Give me the strength, for what I
must do.
Who are you?
I said, who are you?
What are you doing here?
I just like it down here
is all.
See what's in his pockets,
Jimmy.
Now look, boys. I really don't
want to fight.
You don't want to fight?
Don't worry, son. Ain't gonna
be much of a fight.
Don't kill me.
Where did you get that?
I told you I didn't want
to fight!
Why not?
Look how good you done.
You're the priest's son
aren't you?
You! Get away from me.
You understand?
You don't remember me, do you?
I was the one tried to help
you.
What?
I was the one tried to help
you.
When the Natives took you.
That was you?
Yeah. I thought you was killed.
They just locked me up
You know that.
This long?
I kept trying to escape, you know.
Did more time for that.
So what are you doing back
here?
Guess I missed the place.
Bowery boys.
The Five Points.
Paradise square!
The streets here are always
livelier in the evening.
Who are the gangs around now?
We got the Daybreak boys
and the Swamp Angels.
They work the River
Luton ships.
The Frog Haulers shanghai sailors
down around the bay.
Shortails were rough for awhile,
but they became a bunch of jackrolling
dandies.
Lolling around Murderer's Alley
looking like Chinamen.
Hellcat Maggie she tried to open
up her own grog shop.
But she drunk up all her own
liquor and got thrown out
on the street.
Now she's on the lay
for everything.
The Plug Uglies they're from
somewhere in the old country.
They got their own language.
No one understands what they're
saying.
They love to fight the cops.
And the Nightwalkers and Ratpickers.
They work on their backs and
kill with their hands.
They're so scurvy, only the
Plug Uglies...
...will talk with them.
But who knows what they're
saying.
The Slaughterhouses and the
Broadway Twisters are a fine
bunch of Bengal boys!
And the little  Forty Thieves.
I used to run with them
for a while.
Till they got taken over by
Benjer the Cockroach and his red
eyed buggers.
Benjer is a germ.
If you try to leave the
gang, they say...
...he hacks the blood off you.
The righteousness are nothing but
a bunch of repetitious grab ups..
The True Blue Americans call
themselves a gang...
...but all they really do is stand
around on corners damning Engeland.
Do you believe one word that
the British say...?
Anything about the sand of
the Dead Rabbits?
You don't say that name!
That name died with your...
It's been outlawed.
When I was in the blockhouse,
the chinks told me...
...that the Natives celebrate
their victory...
....every year.
Is that true?
Aye, that they do.
It's quite a fair.
The Butcher himself has got
to invite you...
...or you don't go.
Look where you are going, Johnny!
You look stunned and
poorly, sir!
Quite a pair of conversationists
aren't you!
Maybe not. We're deep
thinkers.
Gentlemen, I leave you in the grace
and favour of the Lord!
Jenny, finest bludget in all
the Points.
She is a prim looking
star gazer!
But I'd check my pockets
if I were you.
Because I do believe she lifted
your time piece.
I let her take it.
I let here take things all
the time.
Is that right?
Yeah.
We always liked a good fire
in the Points.
You generally pick up a swag
and if the cops came along...
...you really got a show.
The municipal police fought
the metropolitan police.
The metropolitan police fought
the streetgangs.
Hurry up before the Black
Joke get here!
There were 37 amateur fire-
brigades.
They all fought each other.
The Black Joke are on
their way!
Okay boys, get the hoses!
It's the Black Joke!
Go get 'm boys!
Give those Bowery boys
help!
Quick before there's nothing
left!
Go back to the Bowery,
ya bum!
For gods sake. They're taking
everything!
In your next time of trouble
ma'm....
...call Tammany first!
It's not too late. You can
still save my house!
Let's go!
I thought you said you
were hungry!
Grab what you can. Let's get
out of here!
May I point out that this building
is burning to ashes?
And may I point out that this
area is the provenance...
..of my own America's firebrigade.
And that you lot only belong
in the Bowery.
May I point out that you are
outmanned, outmanouvered...
...and at the moment outfought!
Am I?
There's the Black Joke!
Let's get 'm!
Clear the way for
Bill the Butcher.
Okay boys, to work!
What's the point?
The fire's near burnt eveything
of value inside.
Boys forget that one.
Next building over.
Mustn't let it spread!
Grab what you want from
that one!
What are you doing? There's
nothing wrong with this one!
Come on. Johnny. Get up!
Leave that.
You two, on your way!
His name's Amsterdam.
How's the beak?
Ain't so bad.
You. You got anything or you
can get out.
Is that it?
That's it.
Right. Here's the rake.
Everything comes here we
fence it.
Johnny takes our tribute to the
Natives and we chop up....
....the winnings, each to his
equal portion of the gang.
Does that meet with your
approval, Hell Gate?
My approval?
What's the matter Jack Sprat,
can't you think for yourself!
I'll slit your fucking throat!
You boys settle with me, before
settling with each other.
I come for my due
and proper.
This ain't a bad haul.
You know, when the folks say the
country is going to hell...
...I always tell them, look at
all the hard work...
..our fine young lads are doing
down in the Points.
Oh, yeah. This is just the
thing for Mrs. Mulraney.
Alright Happy Jack. Leave us for
something to give Bill de Butcher.
Would ya?
Not my favorite tune.
Thank you, boys.
You keep out of trouble
now.
Every year the Natives celebrated
the killing of my father all over again.
At Sparrow's Chinese Pagoda
in Mott street.
The chinks hated the Natives
worse than we did.
The drum rolls and the Butcher
drinks a glass of fire.
When you kill a king, you don't
stab him in the dark.
You kill him where the whole
court can watch him die.
Got any timber?
Hi, Maggie. Rightie or leftie?
Give us a drink.
Help yourself.
Two minutes. Place
your bets.
Gentlemen. The match is due
to commence.
The count to be is,
25 rodents in 3 minutes.
Rouser against the vermin.
Satisfied?
50!
Yes!
Where are you going, boil?
I'm here to pay tribute
to Bill.
Are you now?
Give it to me. I'll give
it to him.
No thanks. I'll give it to
him myself.
What do you want to keep, the
money or your teeth?
John?
Welcome.
From me and the lads, sir.
Mate of yours?
Where's he from?
He's not from here, sir.
YOU!
That's close enough!
Your friend can't look me
in the eye...
...that's not an admirable
characteristic.
No one can look you in the
eye, Bill..
...not when you're playing
cards.
This is whist, it's a
gentleman's game.
Make a gentleman's bet.
I am betting large, Bill!
That ain't large.
Don't make that noise
again, Harvey.
I like a man who's willing
to burn for his swag.
How do you fair on water?
Come closer.
Closer. I ain't gonna bite!
There's a Portugese ship lying
low in the harbour....
...quarantined three weeks.
Get there before the Day Break
Boys strip her.
Maybe you and me wil talk
some more.
Consider it done, sir.
Good boy.
And you...
...whatever you name is.
What is your name?
Amsterdam, sir.
Amsterdam?
I'm New York.
Don't you ever come in
here empty handed again.
You gotta pay for the pleasure
of my company.
Take him for a boat ride, John.
Maybe he'll save your life
again.
If the Day Break boys catch us on
this river, they'll slit our throats!
I'll do it myself, if you don't
keep quiet!
I never liked the harbour
after dark.
And now each night they brought
on shore the bodies of the soldiers.
So many mothers don't even have the solace
of knowing where their sons have fallen.
I lost my own eldest in Antida.
His mother and I weren't able
to recover his remains.
It was a mournful sight.
The war can't last forever.
But we had business of our
own.
The Day Break boys have already
been here.
There's nothing left. Let's
go back.
What in hell...?
Jimmy..get down!
Jezus..that'll bring the
harbour cops for sure!
Out of the way!
Let's take a look.
Jezus..they killed everybody!
There's nothing here but...
Watch it....dead sea crabs.
Come on! Let's go.
Shove off!
No. Wait for Amsterdam!
Where is Amsterdam?
Take him, damn fool!
What in the hell for?
Look in my glims. I said no
less than 15!
Is this fresh?
Four hours most.
Much obliged, gents.
What's that word?
It means bodysnatchers.
I didn't ask the meaning.
I asked the word.
Ghoul?
That's a good word.
A fresh outrage in the
Five Points.
A notice that you can
be proud of.
Thank you.
Low thing, to do that to
a body.
Low.
Why? They could've left that
ship with nothing.
Instead they made the Police
Gazette.
A periodical of note.
A body is supposed to stay
beneath the earth....
...wearing a wooden coat...
..until the resurrection.
These two are just a pair of
bug eating sons of Irish bitches.
Just like you.
Don't seem to bother them none.
Maybe they don't share your
religious scruples.
Maybe they're just a couple
of fiddeling bends.
I've been called a lot of things,
mister...
...but I've never been called..?
Fiddeling bends.
Fiddeling bends. Right.
If I knew what in the hell
that meant..
...I might be inclined to
take offense.
A fiddeling bend is a fellow
who would steal anything...
...dead or alive.
Because he's too low to work up a
decent lay for himself.
Count that careful.
I'm telling you that's all there
is. That's all they gave us.
That's all they gave us.
Chiseler!
If you had said chiseler, now
that's a word I understand.
Is that what you're calling us?
I can think of a number of things
to call you, boil!
Right. But I asked if you was
calling us chiselers?
Supposing I am?
Well, then we got business.
That we do!
2 dollars on McGloin!
5 pieces on the kid!
5 on Amsterdam!
Come on, McGloin, it's
just a kid.
Watch his left, McGloin!
Alright, that'll do.
What do you say now, huh?
That'll do, for Christ sake.
Drag him off.
That's enough, kid.
You got him.
McGloin? How would that head
look without the ears and nose on it?
You'd better leave that head
alone, Bill.
I think I'm gonna trim the beak
and the ears off that head.
Make a nice pot of soup out of
that head.
You can find a tastier head
than that, Bill.
I ain't got no stomach
for an Irish stew.
The mighty McGloin.
Almost fish hooked by
a sprat.
On the seventh day the Lord rested.
But before that He did...
...He squatted over the side
of England...
...and what came out of him?
Ireland!
No offense, son.
None taken, sir.
I grew up here.
AllI ever knew of Ireland was in
the talk of others in the asylum.
From which part of that
excrementitous island were your
forebares spawn?
I've been told Carrey.
But I lost proof of it in my
language in the asylum.
I was raised in a similar
establishment myself.
Everything you see belongs to
me, to degree or another.
But beggars, quick thieves,
here in Paradise..
...gymmills, blind tigers on
the waterfront...
...anglers and the musers. The
she-he's and the chinks.
Everybody owes...
...everybody pays, because...
...that's how you stand up,
to the rising of the tide.
Is that right boys?
Yes Bill, that's right.
Enlist. Join up! Serve
your country.
Volunteer and get your 50
dollar bonus!
We need 30,000 volunteers..
...and we're prepared to pay
677 dollar per volunteer.
Please read this. Thank you.
Would you like one to
fill out?
3 square meals a day.
Young man?
Enlist and...
...serve you country.
3 square meals a day, gentlemen!
If you're interested, I suggest...
Everywhere you went, people
talked about the daft.
You could buy your way
out for 300 dollars.
But who had 300 dollars?
For us it had might as well
been 3 millions.
The recruters were too scared
of the gangs...
...to come after us.
Besides, we never dreamt the war..
...would ever touch
New York.
Good morning, sir.
You!
Don't you run into me.
Fair enough!
I said don't run in to me!
Sorry!
Everything in place?
It seems so.
Then I leave you in the grace
and favour of the Lord.
Thank you.
Why that dirty...!
Oh, no!
Allow me!
Thank you kindly, sir.
It's my pleasure.
I hope you don't mind if
I speak...
..I don't want to appear forward.
Well sir, that depends on what you
say!
Would you call me wreckless, if I say
that you are the prettiest girl
in New York?
Only New York?
This is my stop.
May I walk with you a little
then?
That sir...would be too bold.
For every lay we had a
different name.
An Angler put a hook on the
end of a stick...
...to drop behind store
windows and doors.
An Autumn diver picked your
pocket in church.
A Badger, gets a fellow in bed
with a girl...
..and robs his pockets when
they're on the go.
Jenny was a Bludger..
...a girl pickpocket.
And a Turtle dove.
A Turtle dove goes uptown...
...dressed like a housemaid.
Picks out a fine house...
...and goes right through the
back door. Robs you blind.
It takes a lot of sand to
be a Turtle dove.
I'll have my medal back.
Oh, jezus.
Don't do that again.
I said, don't do that!
Go back to the Points
and let me do my business...
...or I will open your throat.
Alright.
Go on then.
I would.
Give me back my medal.
Make it quick.
I don't know which one's
yours.
Suppose I help myself to
everything.
Suppose you do.
Shall I walk with you a
little, then?
What do you suppose a fellow
can earn up here in a day?
Maybe we can pile in together?
I think you're a bit rough for
this game.
Besides, I work alone.
Alone?
What do you core to
the Butcher?
Nothing.
Nothing?
The Butcher and me have a
special arrangement.
I don't want to see
you again!
I don't blame you.
Pennies in their pockets and
hope in their eyes.
They peer to the west.
Searching the horizon for a
glimpse of land and salvation.
A glimpse of America.
Seeing all this poverty must be
most unsettling, Mrs. Schermerhorn?
Some days the uptown gangs
came to us.
The Schermerhorns were one of the
oldest families in New York.
They didn't run the city..
...but they were listened to quite
carefully, by them who did.
Commissioner Brunt, said you
wanted to view the Points....
...in all its splendor an
squalor.
Spare nothing concerning the
conditions, said he!
Nothing except our safety,
constable.
I'm sure we can be in no danger
while we're in the constable's
company, my dear!
Quite so, madam. Witness!
Shall we continue on?
You dare to leave it there?
Safe as a bank, Mr. Greely.
They all know it's mine.
Is that man drunk?
Dead as good friday, miss.
Good day, Mulraney.
Boys?
Jack?
Slum socialable?
Track finding. Reform studying.
May I present...
The Schermerhorns hardly require
an introduction from you, Jack.
Mrs. Schermerhorn and her
daughter.
The gentleman of course is...
Mr. Greely. The famous
publisher.
It's a pleasure and an
honour, sir.
Of the Tribune.
I am William Cutting.
How do you do, Mr. Cutting?
As of this moment,
extremely well.
How do you do?
Orange blossom. Delicious!
Mr. Cutting is...
What a peach! You had a fine
carreer on the stage.
...one of the Five Points local...
Please to meet you, sir.
..leaders.
Mr. Greely!
Pleased to meet you,
Mr. Cutting.
The Five Points welcomes you..
...to these streets...
..and you shall pas in
safety.
I'll see to their safety.
Thank you, Bill.
This way.
Good day lads.
Criminals who brag
a dote show.
He knows who I am!
Inderdeed, sir. You are well
known in these parts.
I find that strangely flattering.
Never did like crushers.
Well draw it mild, son.
Happy Jack don't fill his lungs
without me telling him to.
Do you think my watch would be
safe in that lamp post, Bill?
Why don't you hang it
up there and see?
Some day.
Some day is right.
Is this the new lad?
just another bastard I folded
in the warmth of my embrace.
Hey!
Just wanted to see your face,
son.
No harm intended.
You get to know a lot by
butchering meat.
We're made up of the same
things.
Flesh and blood. Tissue. Organs.
I love to work with pigs.
The nearest thing in nature to
the flesh of a man, is the
flesh a pig.
Pig, huh?
That's right.
This is for you, mother.
Here you are.
God bless you.
She ain't really my mother.
I knew that, Bill.
This is the liver.
The kidneys. The heart.
This is a wound.
The stomach will bleed and bleed.
This is a kill.
And the artery. This is a kill.
You try it.
Go ahead.
Don't follow the blade
on the rib.
Very good!
And the artery.
Bleed 'm slow. Let them think
about it for a while.
Slow death.
Good!
You'll each bill the city
5000 dollars a month...
..for supplies and services..
...for which you will
receive 10%.
Bill! Mr. Glour will work out
the details. Thank you.
That's how we do things
around Tammany, gentlemen.
Who's this?
Thank you, boys.
Good day, sir.
You got something on
your mind?
Bill's taking quite a liking
to you.
If you're up to something..
...I don't want no
part in it.
I was in Hell Gate for
16 years.
I'm just trying to make my
way is all...
...just like you.
Less of course you got
a better notion?
No.
I can't get a days work
done...
...for all the good citizens
coming here..
...harrassing me about
crime in the Points.
Some even go so far to accuse
Tammany of connivance..
..in this so called rampant
criminality.
What can I do?
I can't have this.
Something has to be done.
What do you have in mind?
I don't know. Maybe we
should hang someone.
Who?
No one important necessarily.
Back alley thieves, with
no affiliations.
How many?
3 or 4.
Which?
Vier.
You stand here convicted..
...of ludeness, jackrolling...
...sneak thievery, chloral
hydrating, sodomy..
...strangulation and corruption
of the public good.
Chin up.
Handsome bunch of gallows
food!
There's my old friend.
How are you feeling, Arthur?
I'm okay. Okay you know.
Say hello to Amsterdam.
He nearly fish hooked McGloin.
Nearly!
I see that you are dressed for
the occasion, Arthur.
You know me, Bill. Always
like to look me best.
That's the spirit.
Nice locket. I'll give you
a dollar for it.
It's me mother's.
Dollar and a halve?
Done.
I'll miss you, Arthur.
See you in the hot
country, Shamus.
Is my son present here?
Where's my little fellow?
Look at your dad.
Farewell dear boy.
I never struck a foul blow..
..or turned a card.
May God greet me as a friend!
That night the Reformers
held a dance.
That was the Five Points
alright....
...hangings in the morning,
a dance in the evening.
To be sure!
It's not a matter of words,
but by the way she smiles at me.
She smiles at a lot of
people, John.
A penny, for a fighting
Irishman?
Are you from Carey?
I am sir.
It ain't much.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, we are
delighted to see so many young faces..
...at our first annual
mission dance.
This will be a real circus!
The mission welcomes Christians
of every stamp...
...and we are happy to greet
our Roman catholic friends...
...who join us here tonight.
Ladies....come with me.
We're going to start the dance
in just a moment.
Good evening, your Holyness.
Good evening, Reverend.
You should have shaved
closer!
Good evening, Reverend.
I'd like to make a pardon.
Miss...?
Everdeane.
Miss Everdeane.
Gentlemen, over here! If
you don't mind.
Thank you.
Open it. Hold it up!
Into the mirror.
That one!
Our queen has chosen.
Sir...
...your lady!
Regular services are held in
the church at 6 and 8.
Go to hell.
What do you think your
doing?
I'm dancing.
Why did you pick me?
That's none of your business.
Would you mind telling me?
Sorry!
I'm not much of a dancer.
Try and stay calm.
I've never been to a dance
before!
It's best not to look down.
You can hold me tighter if
you like.
Alright.
Okay!
Why didn't you dance
with Johnny?
Because...
...I didn't want him.
I'm not good in this.
Wait!
What?
Wait.
How does this open?
It takes too long to lace
back up...
...we'll be here all night.
Alright. I'll take it off.
There was a baby.
They cut it out.
Sorry!
It's fine.
Have you got any scars?
A few.
What's that then?
That?
A gift from Mr. Cutting.
A gift?
A gift!
Was it your birthday?
No.
What did you give him?
The answer to that has nothing
to do with you.
Don't tell me you're angry
with me?
No..I'm through with you.
Well, you're quicker then
most fellows...
...generally they wait till
afterwards!
I ain't interested..
...in the Butcher's leavings.
Stay away from the pikers.
15 to 1. Bug Eye Ward!
Amsterdam!
Everyone was working
for the Butcher.
We ran his errands..
...made his money...
...took a piece...
...and said thank you, sir.
Gentlemen in the ring!
Even Tweed!
The fight's over!
Even me.
My father's son.
What the hell is this?
Sorry, Bill.
The city ordenance against
boxing...
...is a blight. I grant you.
I'm losing money while
you speak.
Go out there and collect
those bets.
How do I collect, if no one
won the fight?
This counts as a no decision.
You've got that covered,
right?
Didn't anyone pay off the
god damn police?
Yes, the municipal police...
...this is the metropolitan
police.
You're going to repay me
every cent.
Wait! Mr. Tweed!
Who asked for your opinion?
Let him speak!
We don't answer to you.
The law says there's no
boxing in the city, right?
That's right, in the city.
Where does the city end?
The winner...in the
75th round...
Allow me to acknowledge the
man who's vision..
...and enterprise, made possible
the staging of this noble combat...
...in this inspiring and entirely
legal surroundings, Mr. William Cutting!
And his young associate.
Well done. You're a
quick learner.
We done good.
We done well.
May I have your kind
attention?
May I remind you of the wonders
of my museum on Broadway...
...P.T.Barnum's gallery of
wonders!
It's a funny feeling
being taken...
...under the wing of a dragon.
It's warmer than you think.
That's the building of our
country right there, Mr. Cutting.
Americans are borning.
I don't see no Americans.
I see trespassers.
Irish, who do jobs for a nickel...
...that niggers do for a dime...
...and a white man used to
get a quarter for.
What have they done? Name one
thing they've contributed!
Votes!
Votes, you say?
They vote on who the
Archbishop tells them...
...and who tells him?
Their king in the pointy hat,
who sits on his throne in Rome.
He's got mixed feelings with
regards to the Irish.
Bill, deliver these good and
fervant folk to the polls.
And there will be a handsome price
for each vote that goes Tammany's way.
Miy father gave his life...
...making this country
what it is.
Murdered by the British, with all
of his men, July 25 juli, 1814.
You think I'm going to help
you, befoul his legacy?
By giving this country to them...
...who's had no hand in
fighting for it.
Why? Because they come off the
boat crawling with lice...
...and begging you for soup?
You're a great one for the
fighting Bill, I know...
...but you can't fight
forever.
I can go down doing it .
And you will.
What did you say?
I said, you're turning you
back on the future.
Not our future.
That document makes you
a citizen...
...this one makes you a
private in the Union army.
Now go fight for your country.
Next.
Sign here, son.
Or make your mark.
Here's your musket. Make sure
you keep it dry on the boat.
Where  are we going?
I heard Tennessee.
Do they feed us now, you think?
My children, my chidren.
We must heal the divisions between us!
This war must cease. North and
South must stand united.
What happens at the finish?
Then we have ourselves a rowdy dow!
Ain't you never been to a theatre before?
No.
Mr Legree, lay down your whip.
Miss Elisa join hands with mr. Shelby.
And Topsy. Dear little Topsy.
Cradle Uncle Tom's head.
Leave the nigger dead.
Down with the Union!
For the blood of the Irish.
Bill, get down!
Somebody's popped the Butcher!
Who's man are you?
Speak smart and speak up!
What's he saying?
I think he's making his peace with God.
To hell with that!
He makes his peace with me.
I'm hearing your confession tonight,
you Irish whore!
Who's man are you?
We speak English in this country.
Do you see this knife, I'm
gonna teach...
...you to speak English with
this knife!
Who's man are you?
Well that didn't tell us very much.
Fine waist coat.
Shame, I don't think it can be mended!
Will I keep it as a souvenir?
Where's Legree? Where's Topsy?
Jezus, let's continue.
Intermission is over.
Now that was bloody Shakespearian.
What?
Do you know who Shakeapeare was, sonny?
He was the fellow who wrote the
King James' Bible.
Mr., I don't know what you are
talking about.
Because you're an ignorant
Irish welp!
Just like your father.
That's it. Tear my head off and
destruct the world.
Just like the other stupid Irish
in this country.
That's why I never ran with your dad.
Get off me you crazy bastard!
It means if you're not strong,
you'd better be smart.
I don't know if your being too clever
or too dumb.
But whatever it is, remember
this much.
For all his faults, your father was
a man who loved his people.
Amsterdam. Amsterdam. New York is
calling you.
Look at that. What in Christ's
name is that?
Rythms of the  dark continent,
thrown into the kettle...
...with an Irish shindig. Stir it around a few times.
Poured out as a fine American mess.
A jig, doing a jig!
A little keep sake.
Good on ya, sir.
Come upstairs with me Bill.
Have I ever had you before?
So you don't call me by my
christian name.
Bill. My god you're alright!
I heard the news and came over
as quick as I could.
As timely as the angel of death.
You're not suggesting that I would
stoop to what your suggesting?
Stop slabbering. If I thought
it was you...
...you'd be in a wooden coat.
I've got a hole in my shoulder
and it hurts...
...so have a drink and shut up.
Or shut up and get out.
I believe I'll have a drink.
Carefull, Tweedy the morts
are frenchified!
No, I'm clean.
Jenny.
Bill.
I'll wrap you up.
It's gotta be tight.
Loves to make me cry.
You can take it!
There's my boy.
It's alright.
To the Butcher!
We're all much obliged.
Forever.
To the Butcher!
Why don't you get out of here, Johnny?
Go on. Go!
Is there anyone in the Five Points
you haven't fucked?
Yes!
You!
Belt down!
Try it and I'll bite ya.
You were gonna bite me.
I dont think you want me.
Find out.
Oh, Jenny!
I can't sleep.
I hope you don't mind us
laying here, sir?
Whatever takes your fancy,
young friend.
Is your shoulder keeping you up?
I don't sleep too much.
I sleep with one eye open. I only
got one eye.
How old are you Amsterdam?
Not too sure. Never did
figure it.
I'm 47.
47 years old.
You know how I stayed alive
this long? All these years.
Fear!
The spectacle of fearsome acts.
Somebody steals from me, I cut
off his hands.
He offends me, I cut out his tongue.
He rises against me, I cut off his
head, stick it on a pike!
Raise it high up, so all in the
streets can see.
That's what preserves the order
of things.
Fear.
That one tonight. Who was he?
A nobody. A coward.
What an end that
would have been.
I killed the last honourable man
15 years ago.
Since then....
You've seen his portrait downstairs?
Has your mouth been glued up with juice?
I asked you a question!
I said I've seen it, sir.
You got a murderous rage in you.
I like it.
So much life boiling up in you.
That's good!
The priest and me lived by the
same principles.
Only faith divided us.
He gave me this you know?
That was the finest beating I
ever took.
My face was pulp. My guts pierced.
My ribs all messed up.
When he came to finish me...
...I couldn't look him in the eye.
He spared me because...
....he wanted me to live in shame.
This was a great man.
A great man.
So I cut out the eye that
looked away.
Sent it to him wrapped in
blue paper.
I would've cut them both out if I
could afford being blind.
I rose up again with a full heart...
...and buried him in his own blood.
Well done!
He was the only man I killed
worth remembering.
I never had a son.
Civilisation is crumbling.
God bless you!
If you've got anything to say...
...now is the time to say it.
Who is he to you, Jenny?
I was 12 years old.
My mother was dead. I was living
in a doorway.
He took me in. Took care of me in
his own way.
After they cut out the baby...
He doesn't fancy girls that
scarred up.
You should know, in your own mind...
...that he never laid a hand on me
till I asked him too.
Who are you?
Gentlemen, you are most welcome to
this palace of enchantment...
...with visions to rival the tales of
Sheherazade and the Arabian Nights!
Flex your head to the teutonic beauty!
Feast you eyes on the magnificent blue...
...of these creatures.
Gentlemen, you see our caged birds well!
How would you like to make them sing?
They could be singing for you.
May God put the spirit of the
holy steel in my spine...
...and the love of the blessed
Virgin in my heart.
Amen.
Easy now. What did you say?
He's not who he says he is.
He's not who he says he is?
Count you blessings he considers
you a friend!
The only thing he considers every day
and night is how to kill you!
Those eyes want me to take
them out for you!
I'll bury it up you fundunem where
it belongs!
I can read right through them!
They're empty...
His name is Vallon.
Don't do it Bill!
His name is Vallon!
Curious people these celestials.
You know why they use short
sleeves?
So everyone can see he's got
nothing stashed.
I hope it doesn't become a fashion.
Johnny?
Get up!
Ladies and gentlemen, if I may have
your kind attention.
As some of you have surely
noticed...
...our friend and benifactor, Mr Cutting...
..is tonight wearing a waistcoat
of certain distinction!
May we appeal to him, to favour us...
...with another exciting exhibition.
Of skill. Courage. Daring and drama!
What's gonna happen?
The spider's kiss!
The wheel of death!
William Tell!
The butterfly!
The spider's kiss!
The Butcher's apprentice!
A command performance!
Where have you been?
A command performance indeed.
I want you to get out of here!
And for this, I must beg the
indulgence...
...of my former...
... assistent in matters of impailment...
...the Butcher's original apprentice.
What do you say, Jen?
One more time for the
sweet souvenir.
Come on!
Don't do it!
She'll be alright.
Remember this?
Of course!
You may feel more comfortable without
that garment, Miss Everdeane!
You'll have to filch me a
new one, Bill!
Anything in your pockets tonight?
I ain't started working yet.
What about that locket I
gave you?
Apologies my dear. Pick it up.
Whoopsie daisy!
Now its good and broke!
I can't seem to get anything
right tonight.
You got the sand to give 'm a
grand finale?
Maybe when you're aiming a
little straighter.
Enough of this heathen music.
Get rid of these goddamn monkeys.
Strike up boys!
This is a night for Americans!
Jenny!
Hats off!
We hold in our hearts the memory
of our fallen brothers...
...whose blood stains the very streets...
...we walk today.
Also on this night, we pay tribute
to the leader of our enemies.
An honourable man...
...who crossed over bravely.
Fighting for what he believed in.
To defeat my enemy, I extinguish
his life...
... and consume him as I consume
these flames.
In honour of Priest Vallon.
In honour of Priest Vallon!
That's a wound !
I want you all to meet the son of
Priest Vallon.
I took him under my wing...
...and see how I'm repaid.
He saved my life one day so he
could kill me the next...
...like a sneak thief.
Instead of fighting like a man.
A base defiler. Unworthy of
a noble name.
That'll do Mcgloin.
Spread him out.
I hate blackies. You..you get to watch.
This is fresh meat!
We need to tenderise this meat
a bit.
Alright, lets kiss goodnight to
that pretty face of yours!
No...!
What'll it be then. Rib or chop.
Loin or shank.
The liver!
The spleen!
The kidney!
The lung!
The liver!
The tongue!
The heart! The heart!
The heart?
This boy has no heart.
Then kill him!
He ain't earned the death!
He ain't earned the death of
my hands!
He'll walk amongst you marked
with shame.
A freak. Worthy of Barnum's
museum of wonders.
God's only man, speared by
the Butcher.
Here. Here. This way.
Come on.
I want to show you something.
My mother's bones share this
grave.
I've saved 20 cents out of every
dollar I've ever earned since ....
...I was thirteen.
That's 215 dollars.
For bludgeoning and the rest.
This is what I wanted to show you.
This is where we're going to go,
as soon as you get better....
...San Fransisco, California.
You can have anything you want
out there.
These men are pulling gold right
out of the river.
With their own hands.
We're here and need to get there.
Start here.
Go down 'round here.
Up to San Francisco.
The shortest way to go.
Will you go with me?
No need to fire that, miss.
Or even aim it.
An audience with yor mangled
friend is all I want.
I've 44 notches on my club.
Do you know what they are for?
To remind me of what I owe God
when I die.
My father was killed in battle too.
In Ireland, in the streets.
Fighting those who were taking
their privilege.
What only could be got and held...
...by the decimation of a race.
That war is a thousand years old
and more.
We never expected it to follow
us here.
It didn't.
It was waiting for us when
we landed.
Your father tried to carve out a
corner in this country for his tribe.
That was him. That was his Dead Rabbits.
I often wondered, if he'd lived a
bit longer...
...would he have wanted it to
be more.
Why did you rifle through his
pockets then?
For safekeeping.
I thought maybe you could do
with it.
Blood stays on the blade.
That's a sorry looking pelt.
And it's been so nice and quiet
for the last three months.
Tell me, this charge. Does it sit
on easy with you?
No. Not uneasy , Bill.
I wouldn't say that.
But... my allegiance is
to the law.
I'm paid to uphold the law.
What in heaven's name are you
talking about?
You may have misgivings, but don't go believing
that, Jack. That way lies damnation.
I'm in no danger of
damnation, Bill.
Here's the thing.
I don't give a fuck about your moral conflicts...
..you meatheaded shit sack.
That's more or less the thing.
I want you to go out there. You
and nobody else.
None of your little minions.
I want you to go out there...
...and I want you...
...to punish, the person...
...who's responsible...
...for murdering this poor
little rabbit.
Is that understood?
Right!
Help yourself to some decent meat
on the way out.
Damn it!
Is that you, boy?
I didn't mean nothing by that shot
you know?
You scared me is all.
You know I'd never do you harm.
Come out now, lad.
Remember your father and me?
Are you to young to remember your Uncle Jack?
The times we had.
You know I won't hurt you.
This is bad for everybody.
What's next, dead politicians?
I could spare half a dozen
of you...
...easier than I can spare him.
Still, I think it shows dash.
Give the boy some time, we'll
settle with a good dust up.
The lads!
There are more of us coming off
the ships each day.
I heard 15,000 Irish a week.
And we're afraid of the Natives!
Get all of us together...
....we ain't got a gang..
...we got an army.
And all we need is a spark. One
spark, to wake us all up.
It was me who played you false.
I'd take it back if I could.
Take it back?
Johnny, I ought to kill you!
Get out of the Points and
don't come back.
Where are you going, boil?
Come along.
Come on.
Tell us John, what's the trouble?
No trouble, Bill.
Still hiding out with
your friends?
No, I'm not with them, Bill.
I'm with you, with the Natives.
You always were a Native, as far
as I'm interested, John.
Till you became a stag.
You tell me you're a Native?
Do you want to know what
a Native is?
A Native is a man, who's
willing to give his life...
...for his country.
Like my father done.
Are you willing to do that,
my young friend?
John? Johnny?
Johnny?
I'll get you off.
It hurts too much.
Just kill me.
Please. Please.
Please.
I'm sorry, Johnny.
Oh, Mary mother of God, pray
for us sinners...
...on the day of our death...amen.
Rest in peace, Ma.
What are you doing here, boil?
What's that nigger doing in
this church?
What's a Dead Rabbit doing with
the Natives,huh?
No niggers among the Natives.
Niggers as robbers is
one thing...
...but niggers in a church,
that's something else!
You run with the Natives, you go
pray with the Natives!
You're going to wind up on a stake
like your man did!
McGloin?
Father! Jezus, do you know there's
a nigger in your church?
Jezus!
The earth turns...
...but we don't feel it move.
And one night you look up...
...one spark and the skie's on fire.
It's a touching spectacle.
We'll come back when you're
ready for us.
The past is the torch that
lights our way.
Where our fathers have shown
us the path.
We shall follow.
Our faith is the weapon most
feared by our enemies...
...for thereby shall we lift our
people up...
...against those who will
destroy us.
Our name is called the Dead Rabbits,
to remind all of our suffering...
...and as a call to those who
suffer still...
...to join our ranks.
However so far they may have strayed
from our common home across the sea.
For with great numbers, must come
great strength.
For the salvation of our people.
We don't want your business.
How many other men live here?
You all have to register.
You can't force me to join
no army.
Have you got 300 dollars?
Of course not!
Who the hell's got 300 dollars?
If you are drafted, release from militairy
service can only be secured...
...for 300 dollars, according to
the conscription act.
300 Dollars?
Otherwise you have to serve!
Who the hell's got 300 dollars?
You have to serve, sir!
You tell me!
Boys!
I was born here, sir. You
immigrated here!
Sweet jezus. War does terrible
things to men.
Get back up town, where you
belong!
300 dollars. It's another rich
man's war!
Sir, I request an audience
with this man.
Don't they speak English in
New York anymore!
Don't understand.
You do speak English!
I wonder if miss Everdeane can angle
her rifle in another direction?
I wonder Mr. Vallon, if you understand
the value of this sort of publicity?
The Archbishop himself, shoulder to shoulder
with half the Irish in the Five Points.
I'm offering my boy, to form an
alliance with you...
...against Bill Cutting and his
slate of Native candidates.
I'll negotiate a handsome fee, for
every Irish vote...
...you send Tammany's way, in the
coming elections.
I need a new friend in the Five
Points, son.
I'd like that friend to
be you.
Now just a moment, Mr. Tweed.
Suppose we do get you those votes.
Would you back an Irish candidate
of my chosing..
I don't think so.
What if we get you all the
Irish votes?
Mr. Vallon, that will only happen
in the reign of Queen Dick!
Beg your pardon?
That means it will never happen.
Now I might be persuaded to back
an Irish candidate...
...for, let's say alderman.
Alderman?
We've already got an Irish
alderman.
So we have, that's why....
What's bigger than an alderman?
Sheriff!
Alright, Mr Tweed, you back an
Irishman for sheriff...
...of the city and county of
New York...
...and we'll get him elected.
I love the Irish, son...
..but higher than alderman you
shall never climb.
Why not?
For one thing, no man living can
consolidate the Irish vote.
I can!
And for another, I mean no
offence...
...no one's yet found an Irish
candidate...
...for sheriff worth voting for.
Monk!
Here.
Got me looking as sober as me own
grandfather!
He was a great man, I'm sure.
He was a drunken bastard.
Can I say what I want?
That's why I wanted you.
Our elected representatives are a
gang of thieves!
Who swear to better our lot...
...while dipping their hands deep
into our pockets.
I stand shoulder to shoulder with
community leaders like Bill Cutting...
....against any, an all in roads in
our democracy.
I'll see to it, that no one
takes away...
... what you earned by pluck and application.
To invading hordes of Hibernians.
Go to the polls and put
your mark...
... next to the name Walter McGinn.
Against the potatoes weeders, like
them over there...
...thieving our jobs.
Why should so many Irish die down
south...
...when the first war to win...
...is not down in Dixie, but
right here...
...in these streets!
Who's the finest streetfighter in
the Five Points?
Monk!
That's right and let the whole
damn city hear it!
That man was right born for this.
He's killed 44 men and laid low a
couple of hundred more.
Is that right?
Right.
I should have run him for mayor!
Alright, line 'm up.
It's election day!
Come on, you bastard. We need
your vote.
Bastard? I fought for you
nigger...
...I lost an arm for you!
Well, that's a start. Come on.
Rise and shine, rise and shine.
This great country of ours, even
hop fiends get their vote.
Less heart and more haste,
darling.
Where are you going ?
I already voted today.
Cast for Monk and Tammany, by god!
Twice.
Twice?
Only twice? You call that doing
your civic duty?
Come with me.
Oh no, you don't. Get back and
sit down.
Here's another one!
Clean him up good.
Shave the beards off boys and send
them back to vote again.
Okay boys, vote Tammany.
Tammany!
What our great city needs is a new
court house.
Now I propose it should be a
modest, economical structure.
Excuse me one moment.
What is it?
Monk's already won by 3,000 more
votes, then there are voters.
Only 3? Make it 20, 30.
We don't need a victory, we need a
Roman triumph.
We don't have anymore ballots.
Remember the first rule of
politics...
...ballots don't make the results...
..the counters do. Keep counting.
It's from Bill.
Monk?
Citizens of the Five Points!
Mr. Cutting is attempting to
draw me...
...into an argument...
...that would no doubt end in
bloodshed...
...and the compromising of my
office.
What do you think?
Shall I engage in silence, this
relic of the ancient law...
...or, shall I be your chosen
voice...
...in a new testament, in a new
world?
There you are, Bill.
The people have spoken.
The very notion of violent
reprisal benumbs them.
Come on up.
Let's see if we can resolve our...
...grievances the democratic way.
That my friends, is the minority
vote.
Now you tasted my mutton, how do
you like it?
Look, I want you to see this.
This is you, right here!
Notch 45, you Irish bug bastard.
Why don't you burn him?
See if his ashes turn green.
Fortune favours them all!
You killed an elected official?
Who elected him?
You don't know what you've done
to yourself.
I know your works.
You're neither cold nor hot.
So because you are luke warm...
...I will spew you out of my
mouth.
You can build your filthy world
without me.
I took the father, now I'll take
the son.
You tell young Vallon, I'm going
to paint...
...Paradise square with his blood.
Two coats!
I'll festoon my sleeping
chamber with his guts.
As for you Mr. Tammany
fucking hall...
...you come down to the Points
once more...
...and you'll be dispatched by my
own hand!
Now get back to your
celebration...
...and let me eat in peace.
I paid you fair.
Down!
Raise!
You son of a bitch!
Challenge.
Challenge accepted.
And then it came...
...the first day of the draft.
Thomas O'neill.
Andrew Lewis.
Joseph Flynn.
They read out the draftees names
as if they were dead already.
J.B. Gleeson.
The O'Conell Guard.
The Plug Uglies.
As for us.
The Forty Thieves.
The tribes were gathered.
The Chichesters.
The drums were beating.
The Dead Rabbits.
The American guard.
The Atlantic Guard.
The Slaughterhouses.
The Bowery Boys.
Confederation of American Natives.
James Mooney.
But all we could see...
...was the hand in front of us.
Shaun O'Connell.
C.W. Morris.
When?
Whenever you like.
Daybreak tomorrow.
Ground?
Paradise square.
Weapons?
That I leave up to you.
Bricks, bats, axes, knives.
Pistols?
No pistols.
Good boy.
Terms are resolved.
Counsel is concluded.
To hell with your damned draft.
Get 'm boys.
Rip 'm apart.
Kill the rich bastards.
Hotel!
They're not getting my son!
Uptown town at the draft office...
...the cops broke a few skulls.
And everybody ran away.
But the word was spreading...
...in the dark.
Up on fifth avenue, the Schermerhorns
and their mob...
...breathed a little easy.
Just a brief blist of anger, over
Mr. Lincoln's draft.
Entirely justifiable in my view.
There are two sides to that
question.
Ther are several sides to that
question, Mr. Schermerhorn.
But only one right side.
As with any question, it
holds the abuse...
...of any executive power.
In any case, Mr. Greely...
...we can all be thankful, it
wasn't any worse.
It may be worse yet, sir.
I saw them. I don't know
what to think...
What is it you are so fond of
saying, Mr. Tweed?
Mr. Greely, you won't like this...
...but what is it?
I don't remember.
You can always hire one half
of the poor...
...to kill the other half.
I've come to say goodbye.
I've booked passage for
California.
Jenny, give me one more day and
I'll go with you.
You'll be dead by then.
What would you have me do?
I don't know.
This will all be finished
tomorrow.
No it won't.
This whole place is going to
burn anyway.
I've heard of the poor are going
from door to door...
...in the Five Points, asking those
supporters for further riots...
...to place a candle in the
window.
Irish, Poles, Germans.
Ah, Mr. Greely, the city is not mad...
...I prophesise a dark night.
Nobody goes to work today.
We're shutting the factories down!
When the sun rose next...
...the city had split in half.
From all over New York
they came...
...ironworkers, factory boys,
street cleaners!
Irish, Polish, German...
...anyone who never cared about
slavery in the Union.
Anyone who couldn't buy his way out.
Let the sons of the rich...
....go and die they cried.
Let the sons of the poor...
...stay home.
The earth was shaking now.
But I was about my father's business.
Oh, mighty Lord...
...you are the dagger in
my hand.
Guide my hand on this day of
vengeance.
We give thanks to the Lord....
...for He is good.
With you, the swift cannot flee.
Nor the strong escape.
Let my sword devour, till its thirst
is quenched with blood....
...and my enemy sleeps forever.
For you and the God of
retribution.
For the Lord crushes the wicked.
The Lord is merciful.
And his love endures forever.
Amen.
Get the women upstairs!
From 18th precinct. The mob is
ransacking houses...
....in 27th street and 7th
avenue.
We have no force to send.
From 15th precinct.
All the stores are closing on
8th avenue.
From fear of the mob in 17th
street.
From 4th.
The rioters are attacking
coloured boarding houses...
...robbing them and setting them
on fire.
From 21st.
The mob have just broken open
a gun store...
...on 3rd avenue and are arming.
Marshall's office on 3rd avenue
is burning down.
The police is of no avail.
Show yourself, please!
Two coloured men brought in
almost dead.
There are 50 more outside.
They need help.
The blacks are being attacked
all over the city.
There's the 300 dollar man!
Get him!
Did your daddy buy you out of
the army!
Can he buy me out of the
army too?
There is danger of mob
attacking armoury...
...corner 21st street, 2nd
avenue.
There's about 500 stand of arms
in it.
The line is dead. They're trying
to cut all the wires!
From 1st.
Riot at Pier 4, North River.
They have killed negros there.
A crowd is here and are going to
destroy the station.
Get her bag!
From 18th precinct.
The mob have attacked the
armoury.
...on 2nd avenue an 21st street.
There is danger of fire in the
building.
All 300 police wounded or
unaccounted for.
From 20th.
Send 100 men to disperse mob....
Building corner 33rd street, 2nd
avenue...
...set on fire by the mob.
Barnum's American museum on
fire!
Animals are escaping.
Let go!
Gunboat Liberty! An ironclad berth now
lying on the foot of Wall street.
They're ready to open fire on
the mob!
The mob are now going to 5th
avenue...
....to attack the Tribune office.
From 16th.
The mob is coming down to
station house.
We have no men!
From 16th. The seventh regiment
has arrived....
...on the foot of Canal street.
They're on their way to
Bog Wade.
The mob is about 4500 strong.
They are going to burn down
Harlem Bridge.
Harlem Bridge is to be torched!
The rats have taken over
the city!
From 21st. There's an attack on
the coloured people in 2nd avenue.
There's a mob headed for the
coloured orphan's asylum.
Send troops to protect the
children.
7th Avenue, 28th street. They
have just killed a negro.
There's a negro!
Get him!
Sir, the major general wants to
know what to do....
...with the prisoners captured.
Prisoners? Don't take any.
The mob isn't taking any
prisoners!
Put the mob down!
Don't take a prisoner till
you've put the mob down!
Soldiers now on 38th street.
The mob will not disperse!
What are your orders?
Here the come!
Let's stick together!
Troop. Halt!
Present arms!
On your order, Vallon!
I order you to disperse.
Fire!
Drive them into the square.
Bill!
Bastards!
Shang!Hold on!
Thank God.
I die a true American.
Tomorrow morning...
...get our people down to
the docks.
I want every man and woman
coming off the boats...
...given hot soup and bread.
We're burying a lot of votes
here tonight.
In the end....
...they put candles on the
bodies...
...so their friends, if they
had any...
...could know them in the dark.
The city did this free
of charge.
Shang, Jimmy Spoils, Hellcat.
McGloin and more.
Friend or foe...
...it didn't make no difference
now.
It was four days and nights...
..before the worst of the mob
was finally put down.
We never knew how many New
Yorkers died...
...that week, before the city
was finally delivered.
My father told me we was all
born of blood and tribulation.
And so then too, was our
great city.
But for those of us who...
...lived and died in them
furious days...
...it was like everything we
knew...
...was mildly swept away.
And no matter what they did to
build this city up again...
...for the rest of time...
...it would be like no one even knew
we was ever here.
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player