Welcome to Gattaca.
You keep your workstation so clean.
- It's next to godliness.
- Godliness ...
I reviewed your flight plan. Not
one error in a million keystrokes.
Phenomenal. It's right that someone
like you is taking us to Titan.
Has the committee approved the
mission? There's talk of delay.
You shouldn't listen to talk.
You leave in a week.
You've got a substance test.
If you have to take a substance
test, report to the testing centre.
Jerome. Never shy.
Pisses on command.
- A beautiful piece of equipment.
- You tell me every time I'm here.
I see a great many in my job.
Yours happens to be exceptional.
Why didn't my folks
order one like that for me?
- Have I ever told you about my son?
- No.
Remind me to, sometime.
So you're about to go up.
One week left.
Please tell me
you're the least bit excited.
I'll tell you
at the end of the week.
Congratulations, Jerome.
Thank you.
How many launches are there
in a day? A dozen?
- Sometimes more.
- Only you watch every one of them.
If you're going to pretend
like you don't care, don't look up.
The most unremarkable of events.
Jerome Morrow, Navigator 1 st Class,
is about to embark -
- on a one-year manned mission
to Titan, the 14th moon of Saturn.
This highly prestigious assignment
was guaranteed Jerome at birth.
He has all the gifts required.
A genetic quotient second to none.
There's nothing remarkable about
the progress of Jerome Morrow.
Except that I am not Jerome Morrow.
I was conceived in the Riviera.
Not the French Riviera.
The Detroit variety.
They used to say that a love child
has a greater chance of happiness.
They don't say that any more.
I don't know
why my mother trusted God -
- rather than her local geneticist.
Ten fingers, ten toes, that's all
that used to matter... Not now.
Only seconds old, the ex act time
and cause of my death was known.
Neurological condition, 60%,
manic depression, 42% probability.
Attention deficit disorder,
89% probability. Heart disorder ...
... 99% probability.
Early fatal potential.
- Life expectancy: 30.2 years.
- 30 years?
- The name for the certificate?
- Vincent Anton.
That's a good name.
I know he'll do something.
You'll do something.
I quickly thought of myself
as others did. Chronically ill.
Every skinned knee and runny nose
was treated as a fatal threat.
The insurance won't cover it. If he
fell ... There's nothing I can do.
Like most other parents then,
they wanted their next child -
- to be conceived in what
has become the natural way.
Your extracted eggs, Marie, -
- have been fertilized
with Antonio's sperm.
We have screened two healthy boys
and two very healthy girls.
Without predispositions
to any inheritable diseases.
Let's select the most compatible
candidate. What gender do you want?
We would want Vincent
to have a brother to play with.
You have specified hazel eyes,
dark hair and ... fair skin.
I've eradicated
prejudicial conditions:
Premature baldness, alcoholism,
propensity for violence, obesity.
We didn't want ...
Diseases, yes, but ...
We would like to leave
a few things to chance.
Give your child the best start. We
have enough imperfection built-in.
Your child doesn't need any
additional burdens. It's still you.
Simply the best of you.
You could conceive naturally 1,000
times and never get such a result.
That's how Anton came to be.
A son worthy of my father's name.
- I'm proud of you, son.
- See how much he's grown.
When we played blood brothers -
- I understood my blood was
very different from Anton's.
I'd need a lot more than a drop
if I was going to get anywhere.
We played chicken.
When our parents weren't watching -
- we'd swim as far out as we dared
and see who'd turn back first.
Come on, you coward!
Of course it was always me.
Anton was the stronger swimmer
and had no excuse to fail.
300 million,
350 million, 400 million.
Maybe it was my love of the planets
or just my dislike for this one, -
- but for as long as I remember
I've dreamed of going into space.
750 million,
800 million, 850 million.
How many astronauts are there?
I bet I could be one if I wanted.
Don't eat that. It's Pluto.
My goals didn't change a lot.
Much to my parents' dismay.
Vincent ...
Be realistic. With
a heart condition like yours ...
- There's a chance my heart's fine.
- One chance in 100.
- I'll take it.
- They won't.
You've got to understand something.
You'll only get inside a spaceship
to clean it.
He was right. I lied on my resume,
but my real resume was my cells.
Why waste money on training me -
- when there are 1, 000 other
applicants with a cleaner profile?
It is illegal to discriminate.
"Genoism", it's called.
But no one takes the law seriously.
If you refuse to tell, they take
a sample from a door handle -
- or a handshake. Even the saliva
on your application form.
A legal drug test can become-
- an illegal peek
at your future in the company.
Sure you want to do this?
You know you're going to lose.
It was the last time we swam
together. Out into the open sea.
Knowing each stroke out was one
we'd have to make back.
But something was different. Every
time Anton tried to pull away -
- he found me right beside him.
Until finally
the impossible happened.
Vincent!
For once in our lives Anton was
not as strong as he believed -
- and I was not as weak. That
made everything else possible.
Like others in my situation I moved
around getting work where I could.
I must've cleaned
half the toilets in the state.
The underclass wasn't determined
by social status or skin colour now.
- Welcome to Gattaca, gentlemen.
- Today discrimination is a science.
There's your cleaning material.
Start here and clean to the back.
I want to see my smiling face
on that floor.
Dreaming of space, Your Majesty?
Come here.
Start by cleaning this space.
I knew how far away I was from my
goal when I stood right beside it.
- Don't clean the glass too well.
- What do you mean?
You might get ideas.
But if the glass is clean, it'll be
easier to see me on the other side.
I knew it was just brave talk.
No matter how much I studied, -
- the best test score in the world
needs a blood test to match it.
I had to go to extreme measures.
The man who came didn't exactly
advertise in the Yellow Pages.
Stand straight.
- How did you hear about me?
- People.
Any distinguishing marks?
Tattoos, scars, birth marks?
No.
Are you serious about this?
I hope you're not wasting my time.
- I'd give 100%.
- That'll get you halfway there.
That's an old edition,
but I know it all by heart.
- The commitment is binding.
- You have somebody in mind?
For the genetic elite, success
is attainable, but not guaranteed.
There is no gene for fate.
And when a member of the elite
falls on hard times -
- their genetic identity
becomes a valued commodity.
One man's loss is another's gain.
He's got impeccable credentials.
An unbelievable expiration date.
He'll practically live forever.
His IQ is off the register.
Better than 20/20 vision. Strong
heart. He could run through a wall.
If he could still run.
He was a big-time swimming star.
You could go anywhere with this
guy's DNA tucked under your arm.
- You look so right together.
- We don't look anything alike.
Nobody looks at photos today.
Christ, you could have my face.
- How do I explain the accident?
- It happened out of the country.
No one knows he broke his back. He's
still a fully productive citizen.
- Just fill in his last year.
- You're a foreigner.
They don't care where you were born.
Blood has no nationality.
As long as it's got what they want,
it's the only passport you'll need.
- Who lives up there?
- Well, I certainly don't.
The process of becoming him began.
Myopia is one of the most obvious
signs of a disadvantaged birth.
- Isn't there another way?
- Surgery will leave scars.
It's contact lenses or a white cane.
- Besides, the colour doesn't match.
- He's right.
My eyes are prettier.
I take 25% of all you make.
If it fails, all this equipment
must be returned in seven days.
- And you lose your deposit.
- Wait! You said 20%.
- 20%.
- It's not negotiable.
- I guess that's it.
- No. There's still the height.
How tall were you
before the accident?
- His profile says he's 6' 1 ".
- I can wear lifts.
Even with lifts
you're not that tall.
So what?
No ...
- We never discussed that.
- I thought you were serious.
I am. I'm not doing that.
No.
Now Jerome knew I was committed.
I endured the pain by reminding
myself that when I did stand up -
- I'd be exactly two inches
closer to the stars.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah. Do you want to go dancing?
You had to be a right-hander.
No one orders southpaws any more.
Jerome Morrow. It's a nice name.
- It's my name.
- I can't be you without it.
What makes you think
you can be me at all?
Look at this.
- Look at it.
- It's nice.
- Is it real?
- Are you colour-blind? It's silver.
Jerome Morrow was never meant
to be one step down on the podium.
With all I had going for me,
I was still second best.
Me!
So how do you expect to pull it off?
I don't know, exactly.
Your signature needs work.
Soon we were put to the test.
Jerome had the genes to get
into Gattaca, but not the desire.
- Do you really want to be in there?
- Not in there. Up there.
- What's up there?
- That's want I want to see, Jerome.
Call me Eugene. My middle name.
If you're going to be Jerome,
you better start getting used to it.
- I must go. Where's my sample?
- In the fridge. Door on the left.
- Which pouch?
- Any of them.
- You think I should test it?
- If you like.
- What's wrong with the machine?
- You've been drinking again!
- I haven't.
- Christ, it's eight in the morning!
This is no joke.
My interview is in an hour!
- There's more vodka than piss!
- I had half a glass to celebrate.
- Friday's will be all right.
- There's only Wednesday left.
That's the one.
It's not too late to back out.
This is the last day
you will be you and I will be me.
Well?
- Congratulations.
- What about the interview?
That was it.
I got it.
Of course you got it.
Each day I would dispose of
all my loose skin, nails and hair.
To limit how much of my In- Valid
self I'd leave in the Valid world.
Eugene prepared samples of his
body matter so I'd pass for him.
Urine for the substance tests.
Blood for the security checks
and vials filled with other traces.
Eugene gave me his identity
while I paid the rent -
- and kept him in the style
to which he'd become accustomed.
Eugene had never been called
"utero", "faith birth", "In- Valid".
As a "Valid", he suffered
under the burden of perfection.
I was now a member of a new
and detested segment of society.
One of those who won't accept
their fate. A "borrowed ladder".
Or... a "de-gene-erate".
In the guise of Jerome Morrow
I've risen quickly in Gattaca.
Only one of the mission directors
has come close to exposing me.
He may have more success exposing
me in death than he did in life.
I think we can rule out suicide.
Thank you.
This will take a while.
We may have to push things back.
Irene, I want you
to assist the investigators.
- That would put me behind.
- I appreciate your sacrifice.
- I won't lose my place in line?
- Your place is assured.
So kindly inform the authorities
we will cooperate in any way, -
- although we can't tolerate
a major disruption.
- Thank you, Irene.
- Thank you, Director.
- How will this affect the mission?
- We'll go ahead as planned.
The launch can only be this week.
Tragic though this event may be, it
hasn't stopped the planets turning.
- What happened?
- I'm going up.
- End of the week.
- That soon?
- What about the mission director?
- He's dead.
Are you serious?
They found him beaten so badly
they had to check his name tag.
You are serious.
There's nothing
between us and ignition.
I'm going up.
- The man was murdered?
- I didn't do it.
- It'll be crawling with Hoovers.
- I'll handle the J. Edgars.
What if they do find something?
I'll be out of their jurisdiction.
We have to get drunk immediately.
Good evening, gentlemen. I hear
you're leaving us, Mr. Morrow.
- We're going to miss you.
- You've opened the wine, I hope?
Pour yourself a glass, Cavendish.
How old is the specimen?
- I kissed him five minutes ago.
- I'll see what I can do.
- You want the full sequence?
- Yes.
Good luck.
- 9.3. Quite a catch.
- Yes. Quite a catch.
God, I've told Cavendish ... This
has only been open five minutes!
Wine needs to breathe.
They say being weightless is the
closest thing to being in the womb.
I can't believe you pulled this off.
They're sending you up there.
Up there! You, of all people.
You'll be alone
in that room for a year.
- It's bigger than your tin can.
- What are you going to do?
I have my books.
I travel in my head.
I wish you had company.
Someone you didn't have to pay for.
- I wouldn't have it any other way.
- What are you going to do?
I'm going to finish this.
What's Titan like
this time of year?
What's Titan like?
Titan is exactly like this.
The cloud around it is so thick,
no one can tell what's underneath.
- Maybe there's nothing there.
- There's something there.
- You should be going, not me.
- Why is that?
Because up there
your legs wouldn't matter.
I'm scared of heights.
I'm sorry.
Do you want this?
I'll save some for you, shall I?
I'm so sorry.
I'm really, really sorry.
Don't give me a hard time.
Give me a break.
- Come on! Help!
- I'm sorry.
I wasn't drunk ...
... when I walked
in front of that car.
I stepped right out in front of it.
I'd never been more sober, ever.
- Go to sleep.
- I couldn't even get that right.
If at first you don't succeed,
try, try again.
Go to sleep.
I'm proud of you, Vincent.
You must be drunk
to call me Vincent.
- How much do you need?
- 20 minutes.
You can go.
It's all right, Irene.
You're excused.
We found our man. It's the only
specimen we can't account for.
- Every 10 years things go our way.
- Tell me about the eyelash.
An unregistered In-Valid. A janitor.
He disappeared a few years back.
- The specimen could be from then.
- Nothing lies around here for long.
Would a janitor come back after so
long to kill a man he never knew?
His profile suggests he's violent.
It also suggests he's a sick man.
There's a 90% chance he's dead.
That leaves a 10% chance
he's still alive.
The owner of the eyelash is the
murderer. I'll do a cross-check ...
- He has no living relatives.
- That's a damn shame, sir.
Check the entry log.
Alibis, grudges.
I see a lot of dry eyes. The mission
director was not universally loved.
He was leading cutbacks
in the programme.
With all due respect, sir ...
Whatever you say.
Jerome the metronome.
I could play the piano
by that heartbeat of his.
- We have a suspect.
- That is a relief. Who is he?
We found an unaccounted-for
specimen. Here's his picture.
- An In-Valid.
- We're still following other leads.
- I'm posting this immediately.
- I'm curious, Director.
An advantage, I should imagine,
in your line of work.
- Your hiring practices ...
- Our "recruitment philosophy".
- Who do you have to be, to be here?
- We don't take common citizens.
Are they all equally excellent?
Occasionally we've had to accept
candidates with minor shortcomings.
But nothing that would stop them
joining the police, for example.
Now, there are enough of the right
kind to warrant a new standard.
Bodies with minds to match.
Essential, as we push out further.
- Yet you still monitor performance.
- To see they meet their potential.
- And exceeding it?
- No one exceeds his potential.
If he did, we just didn't accurately
gauge his potential right off.
- All right?
- Terrific.
The entry log for the past week.
What about you, Irene?
Do you have an alibi?
- I was alone.
- I find that hard to believe.
I'll take care of that
for you, Mr. Morrow.
I see I'm not the only one who looks
up every time there's a launch.
- It's awful about the director.
- Awful it didn't happen sooner.
Didn't he threaten to cancel your
mission? Somebody did you a favour.
- Do they know who I should thank?
- They found an eyelash.
- Does it have a name?
- Just some In-Valid.
Jerome ...
I had you sequenced.
I read your profile.
I'm sorry.
Seems you're everything
they say you are and more.
You're engineered
just like the rest of us.
Not quite.
"Unacceptable likelihood of heart
failure." That's how they put it.
The only trip I'll take in space
is around the sun on this satellite.
If there's anything wrong with you,
I can't see it from where I stand.
If you don't believe me ...
Here. Take it.
If you're still interested,
let me know.
I'm sorry. The wind caught it.
Please check
the latest Gattaca bulletin.
Jerome. Is this
the approach path we discussed?
- Absolutely, Director.
- Quite right.
Listen, I want what I ordered.
It's a completely different colour.
No. I'm bored of talking to you.
I'll call you back.
That was about your hair dye.
They've sent me "Summer Wheat".
It's too light.
"Why don't you try a change?"
We can't use it!
- I'll probably have to pay for it.
- We can't stay here.
- The idiots I have to deal with ...!
- They think I killed the director.
- What makes them think that?
- They found my eyelash.
- Where?
- In the corridor.
Thank God it wasn't in your eye.
My picture is everywhere. I can't
turn around without seeing my face.
- They'll recognize me. They will!
- I don't recognize you.
They won't accept one of their elite
could've suckered them for so long.
No, we do as we planned. You're
Jerome Morrow, Navigator 1 st Class.
I'm not Jerome Morrow.
I'm a murder suspect.
What are you doing?
That's more than a day's worth!
- We can't stay here.
- Stop that! Fine ... fine!
Leave if you want. But don't
take that stuff. It's mine!
I would've chosen a brave partner -
- if I'd known you'd go
belly-up on me at the last gasp.
You can't quit on me now.
Do you want me to wheel in there
and finish the job myself?
- They are going to find me.
- You still don't understand ...
When they look at you, they
don't see you any more. Only me.
Keep your lashes on your lids
where they belong.
How could you be so careless?
- I'm going out.
- Where?
I want some fun before they nail me.
- Are you sure that's a good idea?
- You said not to change anything.
- Who's going?
- I'd say everybody.
If I don't go
it'll look suspicious.
You don't want to look suspicious,
do you?
Thanks.
Who ordered this?
What are we doing here?
I'm following a lead. Forgive me,
but I'm a detective. I follow leads.
- Why should the suspect be here?
- He's an In-Valid.
- This is where the In-Valids are.
He's been in hiding all these years.
You think he'll lie down for us now?
- What do you suggest?
- Go back to the scene.
Sweep the area around Gattaca.
- You're a navigator? At Gattaca?
- That's what it says, doesn't it?
- It doesn't say you're crippled.
- I hurt my leg training, you moron.
How dare you question me?
What's your number?
- Your number, you fucking flatfoot!
- What do you want? An apology?
It gets to you that I can live your
dreams. I'm leaving this dirtball!
- You're harassing me!
- My mistake.
What's your number?
This is a crime scene.
What's this man doing here?
- What are you doing, old man?
- My job, sir.
- This is evidence.
- But it's just trash.
You didn't know?
Wonderful, wasn't it?
12 fingers or 1, it's how you play.
That piece can only
be played with 12.
- What's all this about?
- It's probably nothing.
No. I don't want to give you
a contaminated specimen. Get it?
Thanks. You never know
where those swabs have been.
I want to show you something.
Come on, we'll miss it.
Come on. We'll miss it.
What did I tell you?
Strange. Your eyes look different.
- I guess it must be the light.
- Must be.
Positive match. I'm impressed.
- The cup was used recently?
- Two samples, two days.
He may have returned to the
crime scene to get a drink of water.
- Or he may still work there.
- We checked all the service staff.
I don't think he cleans any more.
I think he's there in disguise.
- A borrowed ladder at Gattaca?
- Far-fetched, but not impossible.
He can't be among the elite. He's
mentally and physically inferior.
Maybe he is an imposter
and maybe the director found out.
Let's sample every employee
intravenously.
We'd close them down for days. No,
take a fingertip or a urine sample.
I suggest blood from the vein.
I hope I'm not out of line.
It's only a matter of time, sir.
What's with the plungers, Lamar?
You open up a blood bank?
The detectives fear my methods
may have been compromised.
- Goddamn! Are you out of practice?
- Let me look at that.
- It's all right.
- Luckily, we have enough.
If you need any more,
you can get it off his shoes.
Irene.
- So you didn't do it after all?
- I guess someone beat me to it.
I guess.
I leave in two days.
I guess you know that. But ...
That's the last.
- Something's wrong.
- He's not here.
- I say we test again.
- No. No more disruptions.
- You have a murderer in your midst.
- Your presence is more of a threat.
The window for our latest launch is
open for seven days every 70 years.
- It's crucial we leave on time.
- This mission means a lot to you.
Your late colleague opposed it.
Take another look at my profile.
I haven't a violent bone in my body.
My apologies.
He won't trouble you any further.
This is not the only place
we can look.
Let's start making the rounds.
I'm luckier than most.
Not as lucky as some.
- I know something about that.
- What heart problem have you had?
Did you get yours broken once?
I had this crazy idea you were more
interested in the murder than in me.
You're right.
That's a crazy idea.
Would you like to dance?
It's funny. You work so hard
to get away from a place ...
And when you finally get to leave,
you find a reason to stay.
- A year is a long time.
- Not so long.
Just once around the sun.
Hello, I'm your detective
for the evening. Please stay here.
Don't leave! Am I speaking
in some strange foreign language?
Check lenses, dentures, napkins,
cigarette butts, saliva off cups.
That's a familiar face.
Check him out.
- I thought you wanted to dance.
- Where are you going?
Jerome!
- Are you insane?
- Come on!
Where did they go?
Come on.
- I can't do that!
- You just did.
Don't touch your face.
Don't swallow. Clean his teeth.
Vincent!
Who's Vincent?
I ...
Don't say anything.
What happened?
The scars on your legs?
Remember the '99 Chrysler LeBaron?
I bumped into the front fender.
Looked left instead of right.
- Is that the new or the old excuse?
- The old one.
- You are involved with the murder.
- That's not true, Irene.
Isn't that the man from last night?
He's nobody.
He's one of our best. He has nothing
to do with this business.
Jerome Morrow.
You don't look well, Jerome.
Why don't you go home?
- Yes?
- Jerome Morrow.
He's ill. A little nausea.
It's quite common before a mission.
I want to visit him. I understand
you can show me the way.
You don't know who he is, do you?
- Hello?
- Be yourself today.
- I was never very good at it.
- Tell the investigators you're ill.
- How long have I got?
- Not long.
I guess he's not home.
- I'm here to see Jerome Morrow.
- That's me. Come up.
I guess he's home.
Come in.
Hello, sweetheart.
Where's my kiss?
- Good to see you're feeling better.
- Of course, now that you're here.
Who's your friend? How can I help?
- It's about the director.
- Again?
- I hope it's no trouble.
- No, no.
- I won't show you around. Sorry.
- Can't we do this another time?
- This won't take a moment.
- Maybe he can tell me why I'm ill.
Who were you expecting?
- We have our man in custody.
- I'll come right away.
- How are you, Jerome?
- Not bad, Jerome.
- How the hell did you get up here?
- I can walk. I've been faking it.
Irene ...
Don't touch me!
I don't even know who you are.
- I'm the same as I was yesterday.
- No more lies, Jerome.
My name is Vincent Anton Freeman.
I'm a faith birth or a de-gene-erate
or whatever. But I'm not a murderer.
- You're a God-child?
- We do have one thing in common.
Only I don't have 20-30 years left
in mine. It's 10,000 beats overdue.
- It's not possible.
- You know what isn't possible.
Don't you, Irene?
They've got you looking so hard for
any flaw, that that's all you see.
For whatever it's worth, I'm here
to tell you that it is possible.
It is possible.
Congratulations, sir. His spit was
found in the dead director's eye.
While I obsessed over an eyelash,
your instincts pointed the way.
So the In-Valid wasn't involved?
No, our friend acted alone. This
mission meant everything to him.
He'll only live to see this launch.
Since nothing can stop the launch
now, he's very, very cooperative.
- So, will you celebrate tonight?
- Of course.
- I think she likes us.
- In time she'll get used to it.
- What was he like?
- Just a cop.
- Did you get his name?
- No.
- He'll be back.
- They have their man. It's over.
No, it's not. I have to meet him.
Vincent?
My God, you have changed.
- Don't you recognize your brother?
- Are we brothers?
Our parents died thinking they'd
outlived you. I had my doubts.
- What are you doing here?
- I have a right to be here.
- You don't.
- You sound as if you believe that.
I committed no murder.
You must be disappointed.
You committed fraud. You're in
trouble. I can get you out of here.
- I've struggled to get here!
- You've gone as far as you can go.
There's still a million miles to go.
Can you only succeed
by seeing me fail?
God! Even you are going to tell me
what I can and can't do now?
I don't need any rescuing.
But you did, once.
- How do you explain that?
- You didn't beat me. I beat myself.
- Who are you trying to convince?
- Do you want me to prove it?
It's not important, Anton.
It's forgotten.
I'll prove it to you.
Do you want me to prove it?
I do.
Vincent!
Vincent! Where's the shore?
We're too far out!
Do you want to quit? Do you?
No.
Vincent!
How are you doing this, Vincent?
How have you done any of this?
We have to go back.
- No. We're close to the other side.
- Do you want to drown us both?
You want to know how I did it?
This is how I did it. I never
saved anything for the swim back.
You couldn't see, could you?
That night, crossing the street.
You crossed anyway.
If you're still interested,
let me know.
Sorry ...
The wind caught it.
You're flying today, aren't you?
Look at what a mess you're in.
- I have your samples ready.
- I don't need any where I'm going.
You might when you get back.
Everything you need
to last you two lifetimes.
- Why have you done all this?
- So Jerome will always be here.
- Where are you going?
- I'm travelling, too.
- I don't know how to thank you.
- No, no ...
I got the better end of the deal.
I only lent you my body.
You lent me your dream.
Not until you're upstairs.
- What is this?
- New policy.
- Flight got you nervous?
- There's a problem, Lamar.
I never did tell you about my son,
did I? He's a big fan of yours.
Just remember that I was as good
as any and better than most.
- He wants to apply here.
- I could have gone up and back.
Unfortunately, my son's
not all that they promised.
But then,
who knows what he could do?
Right?
For future reference, right-handed
men don't hold it with their left.
Just one of those things.
You're going to miss your flight,
Vincent.
For someone who was never meant
for this world, -
- I'm suddenly having a hard time
leaving it.
Of course, they say every atom in
our bodies was once part of a star.
Maybe I'm not leaving.
Maybe I'm going home.