Oh, for a muse of fire...
that would ascend the
brightest heaven of invention.
A kingdom for a stage,
princes to act...
and monarchs to behold
the swelling scene.
Then should the warlike harry,
like himself,
assume the port of Mars...
and at his heels,
leashed in like hounds,
should famine, sword and fire
crouch for employment.
But pardon, gentles all,
the flat, unraised spirits...
that have dared
on this unworthy scaffold...
to bring forth
so great an object.
Can this cockpit hold
the vasty fields of France
or may we cram
within this wooden "o"...
the very casques that did affright
the air at Agincourt?
Oh, pardon.
Let us, ciphers
to this great account,
on your imaginary forces work.
For it is your thoughts
that now must deck our kings,
carry them here, there,
jumping o'er times,
turning the accomplishment of
many years into an hourglass.
For the which supply,
admit me, chorus, to this history,
who, prologue-like,
your humble patience pray...
gently to hear,
kindly to judge...
our play!
My lord, I'll tell you.
That self bill is urged,
which, in the 11th year...
of the last king's reign was
like to have passed against us.
But how, my lord,
shall we resist it now?
It must be thought on.
If it pass against us, we lose the
better half of our possession.
But what prevention?
The king is full of grace
and fair regard.
And a true lover
of the holy church.
The courses of his youth
promised it not.
Since his addiction
was to courses vain,
his hours filled up
with riots, banquets,
sports and never noted
in him any study.
But, my good lord,
how now for the mitigation...
Of this bill
urged by the commons?
Doth his majesty incline
to it or no?
He seems...
indifferent,
or rather swaying more
upon our part.
For I have made an offer
to his majesty,
as touching France.
[Footsteps approaching]
Where is my gracious
lord of Canterbury?
God and his angels guard your sacred
throne and make you long become it.
Sure we thank you.
My learned lord,
we pray you to proceed...
and justly and religiously unfold...
why the law salique
that they have in France,
or should or should not
bar us in our claim.
And pray, take heed
how you impawn our person,
how you awake
our sleeping sword of war.
We charge you,
in the name of God, take heed.
For never two such kingdoms did
contend without much fall of blood.
Then hear me,
gracious sovereign.
There is no bar to make against
your highness' claim to France...
but this, which they
produce from Pharamond.
"In terram salicam
mulieres ne succedant."
"No woman shall succeed
in Salique land."
Which Salique land
the French unjustly gloze...
to be the realm of France.
Yet their own authors
faithfully affirm...
that the land Salique
lies in Germany...
between the floods
of Sala and of Elbe.
Then doth it well appear
the Salique law...
was not devised
for the realm of France,
nor did the French possess
the Salique land...
until 421 years after
defunction of king Pharamond,
idly supposed
the founder of this law.
King Pepin,
which deposed childeric,
did, as heir general,
being descended of blithild,
which was the daughter
to king Clothair,
make claim and title
to the crown of France.
Hugh Capet, also, who usurped the
crown of Charles, the duke of Lorraine,
sole heir male of the true line
and stock of Charles the great,
could not keep quiet in his conscience
wearing the crown of France...
until satisfied that fair queen
Isabel, his grandmother,
was lineal
of the Lady Ermengare,
daughter to Charles,
the aforesaid duke of Lorraine,
by the which marriage the line
of Charles the great...
was reunited
to the crown of France.
So it is clear
as is the summer sun.
[Men chuckling]
All appear to hold in right
and title of the female.
So do the kings of France...
unto this day.
Howbeit, they would hold up
this salique law...
to bar your highness
claiming from the female.
May I, with right
and conscience,
make this claim?
The sin upon my head,
dread sovereign.
Stand for your own.
Unwind your bloody flag.
Your brother kings
and monarchs of the earth...
do all expect that you
should rouse yourself...
as did the former lions
of your blood.
Never king of England had nobles
richer and more loyal subjects...
whose hearts have left
their bodies here in England...
and lie pavilioned
in the fields of France.
Oh, let their bodies follow,
my dear liege,
with blood and sword and fire
to win your right.
In aid whereof,
we of the spirituality
will raise your highness...
such a mighty sum
as never did the clergy...
at one time bring in to
any of your ancestors.
Call in the messengers
sent from the Dauphin.
Now are we well resolved,
and by God's help and yours,
the noble sinews of our power,
France being ours,
we'll bend it to our all...
or break it all to pieces.
Now are we well prepared to know the
pleasure of our fair cousin Dauphin.
Your highness, lately sending into France
did claim some certain dukedoms...
in the right of your great
predecessor, king Edward III.
In answer of which claim,
the prince, my master,
says that you savor
too much of your youth.
He therefore sends you, meeter for
your spirit, this tun of treasure.
And in lieu of this, desires
you let those dukedoms...
that you claim
hear no more of you.
This the Dauphin speaks.
What... treasure, uncle?
Tennis balls, my liege.
We are glad the Dauphin
is so pleasant with us.
His present and your pains
we thank you for.
When we have matched
our rackets to these balls,
we will in France,
by God's grace,
play a set shall strike his
father's crown into the hazard.
And we understand him well,
how he comes o'er us
with our wilder days,
not measuring what use
we made of them.
But tell the Dauphin
I will keep my state,
be like a king and show
my sail of greatness...
when I do rouse me
in my throne of France.
And tell the pleasant prince
this mock of his...
hath turned his balls
to gunstones,
and his soul
shall stand sore charged...
for the wasteful vengeance
that shall fly with them.
For many a thousand widows
shall this his mock,
mock out of
their dear husbands,
mock mothers from their sons,
mock castles down.
And some are yet ungotten
and unborn...
that shall have cause
to curse the Dauphin's scorn.
So get you hence in peace,
and tell the Dauphin...
his jest... will savor
but of shallow wit...
when thousands weep
more than did laugh at it.
Convey them with safe conduct.
Fare you well.
This was a merry message.
[Scoffs]
We hope to make the sender
blush at it.
Therefore, my lords,
omit no happy hour...
that may give furtherance
to our expedition.
For we have now no thought
in us but France,
save those to God
that run before our business.
Therefore, let every man
now task his thought...
that this fair action
may on foot be brought.
[Chorus] Now all the youth of
England are on fire...
and silken dalliance
in the wardrobe lies.
For now sits expectation
in the air...
and hides a sword,
from hilts unto the point,
with crowns imperial,
crowns and coronets...
promised to Harry and his followers.
[Meows]
Well met, Corporal Nym.
Good morrow,
Lieutenant Bardolph.
[Cat meows]
[Sniffs]
[Meows, paws running]
What, are you and Ancient Pistol friends yet?
For my part, I care not.
I say little,
but when time shall serve,
there shall be smiles.
But that shall be as it may.
Come, I will bestow a breakfast
to make you friends,
and we'll be all three
sworn brothers to France.
- Let it be so, good corporal.
- I will do as I may.
It is certain, corporal, that Ancient
Pistol is married to Nell quickly.
For certainly she did you wrong,
for you were betrothed to her.
- [Clattering]
- [Man, woman shouting, laughing]
How now,
mine host Pistol?
Base tyke!
Callest thou me host?
Now, by this hand,
I swear I scorn the term!
Nor shall my Nell
keep lodgers!
No, by my troth,
not long.
For we can't lodge or board
a dozen or 14 gentlewomen...
who live honestly
by the prick of their needles,
but it shall be thought
we keep a bawdy house straight.
- Pish!
- Pish for thee, Iceland dog!
Good Corporal Nym,
show thy valor
and put up thy sword.
- Will you shog off?
- [Shouts]
Pistol, I will prick your guts
a little in good terms, as I may.
That's the humor of it.
[Groaning]
- Braggart vile!
- Ahh, hear me when I say,
he that strikes
the first stroke,
I'll run him up to the hilts,
as I'm a soldier.
An oath of mickle might,
and fury shall abate.
[Footsteps approaching]
My host Pistol!
You must come to my master,
and you, hostess!
He's very sick
and would to bed.
Good Bardolph, put thy face between his
sheets and do the office of a warming pan.
- Away, you rogue.
- [Sighs]
Faith, he's very ill.
By my troth,
the king has killed his heart.
Good husband,
come home presently.
[Sighs]
Come, shall I make you two friends?
We must to France together.
Why the devil should we keep
nives to cut one another's throats?
You'll pay me the eight shillings
I won of you at betting?
Base is the slave that pays.
By this sword,
he that makes the first thrust,
I'll kill him,
by this sword, I will.
If ever you come of women,
come in quickly to Sir John.
He is so shaked with
a burning quotidian fever...
that it is most lamentable
to behold.
Sweet men, come to him.
Poor Sir John.
[Crying]
A good portly man of faith.
[Men chattering, laughing]
## [Medieval]
[Man] Aye, to a cheerful look,
a pleasing eye...
and a most noble carriage.
[Laughing continues]
But do I not dwindle?
My skin hangs about me
like an old lady's loose gown.
Company, villainous company
have been the spoil of me.
[Shouts, laughs]
Whoo!
Hey! Hey!
I was as virtuous
as a gentleman need to be. [snickers]
Virtuous enough.
Swore a little.
- [Murmuring in protest]
- [Clears throat]
Diced not above
seven days a week.
Went to a bawdy house
not above once in the quarter.
- Ohhh!
- [Shouting]
Paid money that I borrowed,
three or four times.
Lived well
and in good compass.
What? You were so fat,
Sir John,
that you must indeed
be out of all compass.
Do thou amend thy face,
and I'll amend my life.
[Men laughing]
[Sir John, Nell laughing]
[Exclaims, laughs]
[Laughing]
[Panting]
If sack and sugar be a fault,
then God help the wicked.
Mmm? If to be old
and merry is a sin,
if to be fat
is to be hated,
then no, my good lord,
when thou art king,
banish Pistol, banish Bardolph,
banish Nym.
But sweet Jack Falstaff,
Aliant Jack Falstaff,
and therefore more valiant
being as he is,
old Jack falstaff,
banish not him
thy Harry's company.
Banish plump Jack,
and banish all the world.
[Harry's voice]
I do. I will.
[Whispering] but we have heard the
chimes at midnight, master Harry.
[Whispers]
Jesus.
The days that we have seen.
[Harry's voice]
I know thee not, old man.
[Hoofbeats passing]
[Dog barking]
The king hath run
bad humors on the knight.
Nym, thou hast
spoke the right.
His heart is fracted
and... corroborate.
The king's a good king,
but it must be as it may.
He passes some humors
and careers.
Let us condole the knight,
for, lambkins,
we will live.
The French, advised
by good intelligence...
of this most dreadful
preparation,
shake in their fear...
and with pale policy seek
to divert the English purposes.
Oh, England, model
to thy inward greatness.
Like a little body
with a mighty heart.
What mightst thou do
that honor would thee do...
were all thy children
kind and natural?
But see, thy fault France
hath in thee found out.
A nest of hollow bosoms which he
fills with treacherous crowns...
and three corrupted men.
One, Richard Earl of Cambridge,
and the second,
Henry Lord Scroop of Masham,
and the third, Sir Thomas Grey, knight,
of Northumberland,
have for the gilt of France...
oh, guilt indeed...
confirmed conspiracy
with fearful France,
and by their hands
this grace of kings must die,
ere he take ship for France.
The traitors are agreed.
The king is set from London,
and the scene
is now transported, gentles,
to Southhampton.
Before God, his grace is bold
to trust these traitors.
They shall be apprehended
by and by.
How smooth and even
they do bear themselves,
as if allegiance in their bosoms sat
crowned with faith and constant loyalty.
The king hath note of all they intend by
interception which they dream not of.
Nay, but the man
that was his bedfellow,
whom he hath dulled and cloyed
with gracious favors...
That he should,
for a foreign purse,
so sell his sovereign's life
to death and treachery. [clatter]
Now sits the wind fair,
and we will aboard. [chuckles]
My lord of Cambridge
and my kind lord of Masham...
and you, my gentle knight,
give me your thoughts.
Think you not that
the powers we bear with us...
will cut their passage
through the force of France?
No doubt, my liege, if each man
do his best. I doubt not that.
Never was monarch better feared
and loved than is your majesty.
We therefore have great
cause of thankfulness.
Uncle of Exeter, enlarge the
man committed yesterday...
that railed against
our person.
We consider it was excess of
wine that set him on, [all chuckle]
And on his more advice
we pardon him.
That's mercy,
but too much security.
Let him be punished, lest example breed
by his sufferance, more of such a kind.
Oh, let us yet be merciful.
So may your highness,
and yet punish too.
Sir, you show great mercy
if you give him life...
after the taste
of much correction.
Alas, your too much love
and care of me...
are heavy orisons
against this poor wretch.
If little faults proceeding on
distemper shall not be winked at,
how shall we stretch our eye
when capital crimes, chewed,
swallowed and digested,
appear before us?
We'll yet enlarge that man,
though Cambridge,
Scroop and Grey,
in their dear care
and tender preservation...
of our person
would have him punished.
And now to
our French causes.
Who are the late commissioners?
[Cambridge] I one, my lord.
Your highness bade me
ask for it today. So did you me.
- And I.
- Then, Richard Earl of cambridge, there is yours.
There yours,
Lord Scroop of Masham,
and sir knight, Grey of
Northumberland, this same is yours.
Read them...
and know...
I know your worthiness.
My Lord of Westmoreland,
uncle Exeter, we will aboard tonight.
Why, how now, gentlemen
what see you in those papers
that you lose so much complexion?
I do confess my fault and do
submit me to your highness' mercy.
- To which we all appeal.
- The mercy that was quick in us of late...
by your own counsel
is suppressed and killed.
You must not dare for shame
to talk of mercy!
For your own reasons turn into your bosoms
as dogs upon their masters worrying you.
- [Shouting]
- [All shouting]
See you, my princes and my noble
peers, these English monsters.
What shall I say to thee,
Lord Scroop,
thou cruel, ingrateful,
savage and inhuman creature?
Thou knave thou!
Thou that didst bear the key of all my counsels,
that knewest the very bottom of my soul,
that almost mightst have
coined me into gold,
which thou have practiced
on me for thy use.
May it be possible
that foreign hire...
could out of thee extract one spark
of evil that might annoy my finger?
'Tis so strange...
that though the truth of it stand
off as gross as black and white,
my eye will scarcely see it.
So... constant and unspotted
didst thou seem...
that this thy fall
hath left a kind of blot...
to mark
the full-fraught man...
and best indued
with some suspicion.
I will weep for thee.
For this revolt of thine, methinks,
is like another fall of man.
I arrest thee of high treason by the
name of Richard Earl of Cambridge.
I arrest thee of high treason by the name
of Thomas Grey, Knight of Northumberland.
I arrest thee of high treason by the
name of Henry Lord Scroop of Masham.
Hear your sentence.
You have conspired
against our royal person,
joined with an enemy
proclaimed and from his coffers...
received the golden earnest
of our death wherein.
You would have sold your king
to slaughter,
his princes and his peers
to servitude,
his subjects to oppression
and contempt...
and his whole kingdom
into desolation!
Get you therefore hence, poor
miserable wretches, to your death,
the taste whereof God of his mercy
give you patience to endure...
and true repentance
of all your dear offenses.
Bear them hence.
[Men shouting]
Now, Lords, for France,
the enterprise whereof shall
be to you, as us, like glorious,
since God so graciously hath brought to light
this dangerous treason lurking in our way.
Cheerly to sea.
The signs of war advance.
No king of England
if not king of France.
[Sighs]
Prithee, honey-sweet husband,
let me bring thee to staines.
No, for my manly heart
doth yearn.
Bardolph, be blithe.
Nym, rouse
thy vaunting veins.
Boy, bristle
thy courage up.
For Falstaff is dead,
and we must yearn therefore.
Would I were with him, wheresome'er
he is, either in heaven or in hell.
Nay, sure,
he's not in hell.
He's in Arthur's bosom, if ever
a man went to Arthur's bosom.
He made a finer end and went away
an it had been any Christian child.
He parted even
just between 12:00 and 1:00,
even at the turning of the tide.
For after I saw him
fumble with the sheets...
and play with flowers and
smile upon his finger's ends,
I knew there was
but one way.
For his nose
was as sharp as a pen,
and he babbled of green fields.
"How now, Sir John," quoth I.
"What, man?
Be of good cheer."
So he cried out,
"God, God,
God,"
Three or four times.
Now I, to comfort him, bid him
he should not think of God.
I hoped there was no need to trouble himself
with any such thoughts yet.
He bade me put
more clothes on his feet.
I put my hand under the bed
and felt them,
and they were as cold
as any stone.
Then I felt to his knees,
and so upward... and upward,
and all was as...
cold as any stone.
They say he cried out for sack.
[Laughs] That he did.
And of women.
No, that he did not.
[Boy]
Yeah, that he did.
He said they were...
devils incarnate.
He could never abide carnation.
It was a color he never liked.
He said once the devil
would have him about women.
Well, he did in some sort...
handle women.
[Laughing]
But then he was rheumatic and
talked of the whore of Babylon.
Do you not remember he saw a flea
stick upon Bardolph's nose?
He said it was a black soul
burning in hell. [chuckling]
Well, the fuel is gone
that maintained that fire.
That's all the riches
I got in his service.
Whall we shog?
The king will be gone
from Southampton.
Farewell, hostess.
I cannot kiss.
That's the humor of it.
But...
Adieu.
Let housewifery appear.
[Chuckles]
Keep close.
I thee command.
[Knocking]
Farewell.
[Whispers]
Adieu.
[Chorus]
Follow, follow.
For who is he whose chin is but
enriched with one appearing hair...
that will not follow these
culled and choice-drawn cavaliers...
to France?
Thus comes the English...
with full power upon us,
and more than carefully it us concerns
to answer royally in our defenses.
Therefore,
the dukes of Berri...
and of Bretagne,
of Brabant and of Orleans
shall make forth.
And you, prince Dauphin...
My most redoubted father,
it is most meet we arm us
against the foe.
For peace itself
should not so dull a kingdom,
but the defenses, musters,
preparations should be maintained,
assembled and collected,
as were a war in expectation.
Therefore, I say 'tis meet
we all go forth to view...
the sick and feeble
parts of France.
And let us do it
with no show of fear!
No, with no more than if we heard
that England were busied with,
uh, a Whitsun morris dance.
[Chuckling]
For, my good liege, she is so idly
kinged by a vain, giddy, shallow,
humorous youth,
that fear attends her not.
O peace, prince dauphin.
You're too much mistaken
in this king.
Question, your grace,
the late ambassadors.
With what great state
he heard their embassy,
how well supplied
with noble counselors,
how modest in exception
and withal how terrible...
in constant resolution.
Well, 'tis not so,
my lord high constable.
Though we think it so,
'tis no matter.
In matters of defense, 'tis best to weigh
the enemy more mighty than he seems.
Think we king Harry strong.
And, princes, look you
strongly armed to meet him.
For he is bred
out of that bloody strain...
that haunted us
in our familiar paths.
Witness our too-much
memorable shame...
when cressy battle
fatally was struck...
and all our princes captived...
by the hand
of that black name,
Edward,
black prince of Wales.
This is a stem
of that victorious stalk.
And let us fear
the native mightiness...
and fate of him.
[Door opens]
[Footsteps approaching]
Ambassadors from Harry, king of England,
do crave admittance to your majesty.
Go and bring them.
You see, this chase
is hotly followed, friends.
Good my sovereign,
take up the English short,
and let them know of what a
monarchy you are the head.
Self-love, my liege, is not so vile
a sin as self-neglecting.
[Door opens]
From our brother England?
From him, and thus
he greets your majesty.
He wills you, in the
name of God almighty,
that you divest yourself
and lay apart...
the borrowed glories
that by gift of heaven,
by law of nature
and of nations,
belongs to him
and to his heirs.
Namely, the crown.
Willing you overlook
this pedigree.
And when you find him
evenly derived...
from his most famed of famous
ancestors, Edward the III,
he bids you then resign your crown
and kingdom, indirectly held from him,
the native and true challenger.
Or else what follows?
Bloody constraint.
For if you hide the crown,
even in your hearts,
there will he rake for it.
Therefore, in fierce
tempest is he coming,
in thunder and in earthquake,
like a Jove,
that if requiring fail,
he will compel.
This is his claim,
his threatening and my message.
Unless the Dauphin
be in presence here,
to whom expressly
I bring greeting to.
For the Dauphin,
I stand here for him.
What to him from England?
Scorn and defiance,
slight regard, contempt...
and anything that might not
misbecome the mighty sender,
doth he prize you at.
Thus says my king.
Say, if my father render a fair
return, it is against my will,
for I desire nothing
but odds with England.
And to that end, as matching
to his youth and vanity,
I did present him
with the Paris balls!
He'll make your Paris Louvre
shake for it.
And be assured
you'll find a difference,
as we, his subjects,
have in wonder found,
between the promise of his greener
days and these he masters now.
Tomorrow...
Shall you know
our mind at full.
[Chorus] Thus with imagined wing
our swift scene flies,
in motion of no less celerity
than that of thought! [explosion]
Work, work your thoughts, and
in them see a siege! [men shouting]
Behold the ordinance
on their carriages,
with fatal mouths gaping
on girded harflew.
Suppose the ambassador
from the French comes back,
tells Harry that the king does
offer him Katherine, his daughter,
and with her to dowry, some
petty and unprofitable dukedoms.
The offer likes him not.
And the nimble gunner with linstock
now the devilish cannon touches,
and down goes all before them!
[Explosion]
[Shouting continues]
Once more unto the breach,
dear friends!
Once more, or close the wall up
with our English dead!
[Explosion]
In peace there's nothing so becomes a
man as modest stillness and humility.
But when the blast of war
blows in our ears,
then imitate the action
of the tiger!
Stiffen the sinews,
summon up the blood,
disguise fair nature
with hard-favored rage.
Then lend the eye
a terrible aspect.
Let it pry through the portage of
the head like the brass cannon.
Let the brow o'erwhelm it as
fearfully as doth a galled rock...
o'erhang and jetty
his confounded base,
swilled with the wild
and wasteful ocean.
Now set the teeth
and stretch the nostril wide,
hold hard the breath and bend up
every spirit to his full height!
On, on, you noblest England!
[Explosion]
Now attest that those whom you
called fathers did beget you.
And you, good yeoman, whose
limbs were made in England,
show us here the mettle
of your pasture.
Let us swear that you are worth
your breeding, which I doubt not!
For there is none of you so mean and base
that hath not noble luster in your eyes!
I see you stand like greyhounds in
the slips, straining upon the start.
The game's afoot!
Follow your spirit,
and upon this charge, cry,
"God for Harry,
England and Saint George!"
[All] God for harry,
England and Saint George!
[All shouting]
[Shouts of
encouragement]
Up to the breach,
you dogs!
Avaunt, you cullions!
[Panting]
Captain Fluellen, you must
come presently to the mines.
The duke of Gloucester
would speak with you.
Tell the duke it is not so good
to come to the mines.
For look you, the mines is not
according to the disciplines of war.
By Cheshu, I think he will
blow up all,
if there is not
better direction. [explosion]
The duke of Gloucester,
to whom the order...
of the siege is given, is altogether
directed by an Irishman.
[Trumpet blowing]
It's Captain Macmorris, is it not?
- I think it be.
- By Cheshu, he is an ass in the world.
[Chuckles]
He has no more directions...
in the true disciplines of the
wars than is a puppy dog.
Here he comes, and the Scots
captain, Captain Jamy, with him.
Oh, no, Captain Jamy is a marvelous,
valorous gentleman, that is certain.
I say... good day,
Captain Fluellen.
Good day to your worship,
good Captain James.
How now, Captain Macmorris?
Have you quit the mines? By Christ, la.
The workish give over.
The trumpets
sound the retreat.
By my hand,
'tis ill done.
Captain Macmorris,
I beseech you now,
a few disputations as partly
touching the disciplines of the war,
partly to satisfy
my opinion...
and partly for
the satisfaction of my mind,
as touching the direction
of the military discipline.
That is the point. It is no time
to discourse, so Christ save me.
The town is besieged, and the
trumpet calls us to the breach.
We talk, and, by Christ,
do nothing.
By the mass, ere these eyes of mine
take themselves to slumber,
I'll do good service, or I'll
lie in the ground for it.
Captain Macmorris,
I think, look you,
under your correction, there
are not many of your nation.
[Explosion]
What is my nation?
Who talks of my nation
is a villain...
and a bastard and a knave
and a rascal?
Look you, if you take the matter otherwise
than it is meant, Captain Macmorris,
peradventure I shall think
you do not use me...
with that affability as in discretion
you ought to use me, now look you,
being as good
a man as yourself.
I do not know you
so good a man as myself.
So Christ save me,
I will cut off your head!
[Shouts]
[Rumbling]
[Men shouting]
[Explosion]
How yet resolves
the governor of the town?
This is the latest parle
we will admit.
Therefore, to our best mercy
give yourselves,
or, like to men proud of
destruction, defy us to our worst.
For as I am a soldier, if I
begin the battery once again,
I will not leave
the half-achieved Harflew...
till in her ashes
she lie buried.
Therefore,
you men of Harflew,
take pity of your town
and of your people...
whiles yet my soldiers
are in my command,
whiles yet the cool
and temperate wind of grace...
o'erblows the filthy
and contagious clouds...
of heady murder,
spoil and villainy!
If not, why, in a moment
look to see...
the blind and bloody
soldier with foul hand...
defile the locks of your shrill,
shrieking daughters,
your fathers taken
by their silvered beards...
and their most reverend heads
dashed to the walls,
your naked infants
spitted upon pikes...
whiles the mad mothers
with their howls confused...
do break the clouds!
What say you?
Will you yield and this avoid?
Or, guilty in defense,
be thus destroyed?
The Dauphin, of whose
succor we entreated,
returns us that his powers are not
yet ready to raise so great a siege.
Therefore, dread king,
enter our gates,
dispose of us and ours,
for we no longer
are defensible.
[Sighs]
Go you and enter Harflew.
There remain and fortify it
strongly against the French.
Use... mercy to them all.
For us, dear uncle,
the winter coming on...
and sickness growing
upon our soldiers,
we will retire to Calais.
Tonight... in Harflew
will we be your guest.
Tomorrow... for the march
are we addressed.
[Kisses,
whispers in french]//[cooing]
Alice.
[Sighs]
Alice,
tu as ete en angleterre,
et tu parles bien le langage.
Un peu, madame.
Je te prie, m'enseignez.
Il faut que j'apprenne
a parler.
Comment appelez-vous
la main en anglais?
La main?
Elle est appelee"de" hand.
"De hand."
Mm-hmm.
Et les doigts?
Les doigts?
Ma foi, j'oublie les doigts.
Mais je me souviendrai.
Les doigts?
Je pense qu'ils sont appeles
"de fingres."
Le main, de hand.
Le doigts, de fingres.
Mm-hmm.
Je pense que je suis
le bon ecolier.
J'ai gagne deux mots
d'anglais vitement. [mutters]
Comment appelez-vous les ongles?
Les ongles?
Nous les appelons
de nails.
"De nails."
Ecoutez, dites-moi
si je parle bien.
De hand, de fingres
etde nails.
C'est bien dit, madame.
Il est fort bon anglais. [laughs]
Dites-moi I'anglais
pour le bras.
De arm, madame.
Et le coude?
D'elbow.
"D'elbow."
Je m'en fais la repetition...
De tous les mots que vous
m'avez appris des a present.
Il est trop difficile,
madame, comme je pense.
Excusez-moi, Alice,
ecoutez: De hand, de fingres,
de nails, de "arma,"
de "bilbow."//d'elbow, madame.
O, seigneur dieu,
je m'en oublie! D'elbow.
Comment appelez-vous
le col?
De "nick," madame.
- "De nick."
- Mmm.
Et le menton?
De chin.
"De chin."
Le col, de nick.
Le menton, de chin.
Oui, sauf votre honneur,
en verite,
vous prononcez les mots aussi
droit que les natifs d'angleterre.
Je ne doute point d'apprendre par la
grace de dieu, et en peu de temps.
N'avez-vous pas deja oublie
ce que je vous ai enseigne?
Non, je reciterai
a vous promptement:
De hand, de fingres.
Tsk. Mmm.
- De "mails"?
- De nails, madame.
"De nails, madame."
[Chuckling]
- De arma, de belbow.
- Sauf votre honneur, d'elbow.
Ainsi dis-je:
D'elbow, de nick, [mutters]
Etde chin.
Oh.
Comment appelez-vous
le pied et la robe?
De foot, madame,
et de coun.
- F-footet 'le coun.
- Mmm.
[Both chuckling]
O seigneur dieu!
Ce sont mots de son mauvais
corruptible,
Gros, et impudique et non pour
les dames d'honneur d'user.
Je ne voudrais prononcer ces mots devants
les seigneurs de france pour tout le monde.
De footet 'le coun!
[Laughing]
[Chuckling]
Neanmoins, je reciterai une
autre fois ma lecon ensemble.
- De hand, de fingres,
- [chuckling]
De nails, de arma, de...
[gibberish]
De nick, de chin, de foot
et 'le coun!
[Chattering, chuckling
continue]
'Tis certain...
He hath passed the river Somme.
And if he be not fought withal,
my lord, let us not live in France.
Normans.
But bastard Normans!
Norman... bastards!
Where have they this mettle is not
their climate foggy, raw and dull?
- O, for honor of our land.
- By faith and honor,
our madams mock at us and
plainly say our mettle is bred out!
And they will give their bodies
to the lust of English youth...
to new-store France
with bastard warriors!
Where is Montjoy, the herald?
Speed him hence.
Let him greet England
with our sharp defiance.
Up, princes,
and with spirit of honor edged
more sharper than your swords,
hie to the field.
Bar Harry England,
that sweeps through our land...
with pennons painted
in the blood of Harflew.
Go down upon him.
You have power enough.
And in a captive chariot into
Rouen bring him our prisoner.
This becomes the great.
Sorry am I his numbers
are so few,
his soldiers sick and famished
in their march.
For I am sure when he
shall see our army,
he'll drop his heart
into the sink of fear...
and, for achievement,
offer us his ransom.
Therefore, lord constable,
haste on montjoy.
Prince Dauphin,
you shall stay with us in Rouen.
Not so, I do beseech
your majesty.
Be patient, for you
shall remain with us!
Now forth, lord constable
and princes all,
and quickly bring us word
of England's fall.
[Man shouting]
[Hoofbeats approaching]
[Hoofbeats galloping,
horse whinnies] [man shouts]
Come. Come in.
Captain Fluellen?
Come you from the bridge?
Is the duke of Exeter safe?
De is not...
God be praised and blessed...
any hurt in the world, but keeps the bridge
most valiantly, with excellent discipline.
Captain! I thee beseech
to do me favors.
The duke of Exeter
doth love thee well.
Aye, I praise God, and I have
merited some love at his hands.
Bardolph, a soldier firm
and sound of heart...
and buxom valor,
hath by cruel fate and giddy
fortune's furious, fickle wheel...
Touching your patience,
Ancient Pistol,
fortune is an excellent moral.
Fortune is Bardolph's foe
and frowns on him...
for he hath stolen a pax
and hanged must he be.
Therefore, go speak.
The duke will hear thy voice.
Speak, captain, for his life,
and I will thee requite.
Ancient Pistol, I do partly
understand your meaning.
Why, then,
rejoice therefore!
'Tis not a thing
to rejoice at.
Look you, if he
were my brother,
I would desire the duke
to do his good pleasure...
and put him to execution.
[Fluellen]
Discipline ought to be used.
Then die and be damned...
and figo for thy friendship!
How now, Fluellen,
comest thou from the bridge?
Aye, so please your majesty.
The duke of Exeter hath very
gallantly maintained the bridge.
What men have you lost?
I think the duke
hath lost never a man...
but one that is like to be
executed for robbing a church.
One Bardolph, if
your majesty know the man.
[Fluellen] His face is all bubukles and
whelks and knobs and flames of fire.
His lips blows at his nose.
[Fluellen] 'tis like a coal of fire...
sometimes blue, sometimes red.
But his nose is executed
and his fire's out.
Get up!
[Thunder rumbling]
[Man]
Shh!
[Shouts]
[Cheering]
- Oh!
- [Laughs]
- Oh, oh, oh, oh!
[Laughing]
Do not, when thou art king,
hang a thief.
No,
thou shalt.
[Thunder rumbling]
We would have all such offenders
so cut off.
We give express charge
that in our marches...
through the country there be nothing
compelled from the villages,
nothing taken but paid for,
none of the French upbraided
or abused in disdainful language.
For when lenity and cruelty
play for a kingdom,
the gentler gamester
is the soonest winner.
Thus says my king,
"Say thou to Harry of England,
"though we seemed dead,
we did but sleep.
"Tell him we could have
rebuked him at Harflew.
"Now we speak,
and our voice is imperial.
"England shall
repent his folly.
"Bid him, therefore,
consider of his ransom...
"which must proportion
the losses we have borne...
"which in weight to re-answer
his pettiness would bow under.
"To this add defiance,
and tell him, for conclusion,
"he hath betrayed
his followers...
whose condemnation
is pronounced."
So far my king and master,
so much my office.
- What is thy name?
- Montjoy.
Thou dost thy office fairly.
Turn thee back, and tell
thy king I do not seek him now,
but could be willing to march on
to Calais without impeachment.
Go, therefore,
tell thy master here I am.
My ransom is this
frail and worthless trunk,
my army but a weak
and sickly guard.
Yet, God before,
tell him we will come on,
though France himself and such
another neighbor stand in our way.
So, Montjoy, fare you well.
The sum of all our answer
is but this:
We would not seek
a battle as we are,
nor, as we are,
we say we will not shun it.
So tell your master.
I shall deliver so.
Thanks to your majesty.
I hope they will not
come upon us now.
We are in god's hand, brother,
not in theirs.
[Thunderclap]
March to the bridge.
It now draws towards night.
Beyond the river
we'll encamp ourselves...
and on tomorrow...
bid them march away.
Now entertain
conjecture of a time...
when creeping murmur
and the poring dark...
fills the wide vessel
of the universe.
From camp to camp through
the foul womb of night...
the hum of either army
stilly sounds...
that the fixed sentinels
almost receive...
the secret whispers
of each other's watch.
Fire answers fire,
and through their paly flames,
each battle sees
the other's umbered face.
Steed threatens steed
in high and boastful neighs,
piercing the night's dull ear.
And from the tents,
the armorers,
accomplishing the knights,
with busy hammers closing rivets up
give dreadful note of preparation.
Proud of their numbers
and secure in soul,
the confident
and over-lusty French...
do the low-rated English
play at dice...
and chide the cripple,
tardy-gaited night...
who, like a foul and ugly witch,
doth limp so tediously away.
[Horse whinnies]
[Man] I have the best armor
in the world.
Would it were day.
[Man #2] you have an excellent armor,
but let my horse have his due.
It is the best horse of Europe.
Will it never be morning?
## [Flute]
[Chattering continues]
My lord of Orleans
and my lord High Constable,
you talk of horse and armor?
You are as well provided of both
as any prince in the world.
I will not change my horse...
for any that treads
but on four hooves.
When I bestride him,
I soar.
I am a hawk, and he is
pure air and fire!
The dull elements of earth
and water never appear in him,
but only impatient stillness
while his rider mounts him.
Indeed, my lord, it is a most
absolute and excellent horse.
[Chattering continues]
My lord constable,
the armor in your tent tonight...
Are those suns
or stars on it?
Stars, Montjoy.
Some of them will
fall tomorrow, I hope.
And yet my sky
shall not want.
Will it never be day?
I will trot tomorrow a mile,
and my way shall be paved
with English faces.
I will not say so, for fear I
should be faced out of my way.
I'll go arm myself.
[Chattering continues]
[Horse whinnies]
The Dauphin longs for morning.
He longs to eat the English.
I think he will eat
all he kills.
He never did harm that I heard of.
Nor will do none tomorrow.
Would it were day.
[Chattering continues]
Alas, poor Harry of England.
He longs not for
the dawning as we do.
If the English had any apprehension,
they would run away.
Hmph.
That island of England
breeds very valiant creatures.
Now is it time to arm.
Come, shall we about it?
It is now 2:00.
But let me see, by 10:00, we shall
have each a hundred Englishmen.
The poor, condemned English,
like sacrifices,
by their watchful fires
sit patiently...
and inly ruminate
the morning's danger.
[Chorus]
And their gesture sad,
investing lank, lean cheeks
and war-worn coats,
presenteth them
unto the gazing moon...
so many horrid ghosts.
## [Flute]
Ahh.
[Laughing]
Oh, now,
who will behold the royal
captain of this ruined band,
walking from watch to watch,
from tent to tent?
Let him cry,
"Praise and glory on his head,"
For forth he goes
and visits all his host.
Bids them good morrow
with a modest smile...
and calls them "Brothers,
friends and countrymen."
A largesse universal,
like the sun...
his liberal eye
doth give to everyone,
thawing cold fear...
that mean and gentle all...
behold, as may
unworthiness define,
a little touch of Harry
in the night.
Good morrow, old
sir Thomas Erpingham.
A good soft pillow for that good white head
were better than a churlish turf of France.
Not so, my liege.
This lodging likes me better...
since I may say,
"Now lie I like a king."
[Chuckles]
Lend me thy cloak, Sir Thomas.
Brothers both, commend me
to the princes in our camp.
Do my good morrow to them, and
anon desire them all to my pavilion.
We shall, my liege.
Shall I attend your grace?
No, my good knight.
I and my bosom
must debate a while,
and then I would
no other company.
The lord in heaven
bless thee, noble Harry.
God have mercy, old heart.
Thou speakest cheerfully.
[Clears throat]
Qui va la?
A friend.
Discuss unto me.
Art thou officer...
or art thou base,
common and popular?
I am a gentleman of a company.
Trailest thou
the puissant pike? Even so.
What are you?
As good a gentleman as the emperor.
Ah, then you are a better
than the king.
The king's a bawcock
and a heart of gold,
a lad of life,
an imp of fame,
of parents good,
of fist most valiant.
I kiss his dirty shoe,
and from heartstring,
I love the lovely bully.
What is thy name?
Uh, Harry Le Roy.
Le Roy?
A... a Cornish name?
No, I am a Welshman.
Knowest thou Fluellen?
Aye.
Tell him I'll knock his leek about
his pate upon Saint Davy's day.
Do not wear your dagger in your cap
that day, lest he knock that about yours.
Art thou his friend?
And his kinsman too.
The figo with thee then.
I thank you.
God be with you.
My name is Pistol called.
It sorts well
with your fierceness.
Captain Fluellen.
Shh!
In the name of Jesus Christ,
speak lower.
If you would take the pains but to
examine the wars of Pompey the great,
you shall find that there is no Tiddle
Taddle nor Pibble Babble in Pompey's camp.
The enemy is loud.
You hear him all night.
If the enemy is an ass and
a fool and a prating coxcomb,
is it meet that we should
also be an ass...
and a fool and a prating coxcomb
in your conscience now?
[Whispers]
I will speak lower.
I pray you and beseech you
that you will.
[Man murmuring]
[Speaking in
foreign language]
[Foreign language continues]
Brother John Bates,
Is not that the morning
which breaks yonder?
I think it be,
but we have no great cause
to desire the approach of day.
We see yonder
the beginning of the day,
but I think we shall
never see the end of it.
[Twig snaps]
Who goes there?
A friend.
Under what captain serve ya?
Under Sir Thomas Erpingham.
A good old commander
and a most kind gentleman.
I pray ya, what thinks he
of our estate?
Even as men
wrecked upon a sand...
that look to be washed off
with the next tide.
He hath not told
his thought to the king?
No, nor it is not
meet he should.
I think the king
is but a man as I am.
The violet smells to him
as it doth to me.
His ceremonies laid by,
in his nakedness
he appears but a man.
Therefore, when he sees
reason to fear, as we do,
his fears, out of doubt,
be of the same relish as ours are.
He may show what
outward courage he will,
but I believe as
cold a night as 'tis...
that he could wish himself
in Thames up to the neck.
[Bates] And so I would he were,
and I by him.
At all adventures,
so we were quit here.
I think he would not wish himself
anywhere but where he is.
Then I would
he were here alone.
Methinks I could not die
anywhere so contented...
as in the king's company,
his cause being just
and his quarrel honorable.
That's more than we know.
Aye, and more than
we should seek after.
We know enough if we know
we are the king's subject.
If his cause be wrong,
our obedience to the king...
wipes the crime of it
out of us.
But if the cause be not good,
the king himself hath
a heavy reckoning to make.
And all those legs
and arms and heads...
chopped off in the battle...
will join together at
the latter day and cry all,
"we died at such a place."
Some swearing,
some crying for a surgeon,
some upon their wives
left poor behind them,
some upon the debts they owe,
some upon their children
rawly left.
I'm afeared
there are few die well...
that die in a battle...
for how can they charitably
dispose of anything...
when blood is their argument?
Now if these men
do not die well,
it will be a black matter for
the king that led them to it.
So if a son that is by his father
sent about merchandise...
do sinfully miscarry
upon the sea,
the imputation of
his wickedness, by your rule,
should be imposed upon
the father that sent him?
But this is not so.
The king is not bound to answer the
particular endings of his soldiers...
nor the father of his son,
for they purpose not their deaths
when they purpose their services.
Besides, there is no king,
be his cause never so spotless,
can try it out with
all unspotted soldiers.
Every subject's duty
is the king's,
but every subject's soul
is his own.
'Tis certain.
Eevery man that dies ill,
the ill upon his own head.
The king is not to answer it.
I do not desire
he should answer for me.
Yet I determine
to fight lustily for him.
I myself heard the king say
he would not be ransomed.
Aye, he said so
to make us fight cheerfully.
But when our throats are cut, he may
be ransomed, and we ne'er the wiser.
If I live to see it,
I'll never trust his word after.
You pay him then!
You'll never trust
his word after?
Come. 'tis a foolish saying.
Your reproof
is something too round.
I should be angry with you
if time were convenient.
Let it be a quarrel between us,
if you live!
Be friends,
you English fools! Be friends!
We have French quarrels enough!
Upon the king.
Let us our lives,
our souls, our debts,
our careful wives,
our children...
and our sins lay on the king.
We must bear all.
Oh, hard condition.
Twin-born with greatness,
subject to the breath
of every fool.
What infinite heart's ease
must kings neglect...
that private men enjoy?
And what have kings
that privates have not too...
save ceremony?
And what art thou,
thou idle ceremony?
What drinks thou oft instead of
homage sweet but poison flattery?
Oh, be sick, great greatness,
and bid thy ceremony give thee cure.
Canst thou, when thou
commandest the beggar's knee,
command the health of it?
No, thou proud dream,
that playest so subtly
with a king's repose.
I am a king that find thee,
and I know...
'tis not the balm,
the scepter and the ball,
the sword, the mace,
the crown imperial,
the intertissued robe
of gold and pearl,
the farced title
running fore the king,
the throne he sits on...
nor the tide of pomp...
that beats upon the high shore
of this world.
No, not all these,
thrice-gorgeous ceremony,
not all these,
laid in bed majestical,
can sleep so soundly...
as the wretched slave,
Who, with a body filled and
vacant mind, gets him to rest,
crammed with
distressful bread,
never sees horrid night,
the child of hell,
but like a lackey,
from the rise to the set...
sweats in the eye
of Phoebus...
and all night sleeps...
in Elysium.
Next day after dawn, doth rise
and help Hyperion to his horse...
and follows so
the ever-running year...
with profitable labor
to his grave.
And but for ceremony...
such a wretch,
winding up days of toil...
and nights with sleep...
had the forehand
and vantage...
of a king.
My lord, your nobles,
jealous of your absence,
seek through the camp
to find you.
Good old knight,
Collect them all together
at my tent.
I'll be before thee.
O God of battles,
steel my soldiers' hearts.
Possess them not with fear.
Take from them now
their sense of reckoning...
if the opposed numbers
pluck their hearts from them.
Not today, o God,
oh, not today.
Think not upon the fault my
father made encompassing the crown.
I Richard's body
have interred new...
and on it have bestowed
more contrite tears...
than from it issued
forced drops of blood.
Five hundred poor
I have in yearly pay...
who twice a day
their withered hands...
hold up toward heaven
to pardon blood.
And I have built
two chantries...
where the sad and solemn priests
sing still for Richard's soul.
More will I do...
though all that I can do...
is nothing worth...
since my penitence comes,
after all,
imploring pardon.
[Man] My liege!
My brother Gloucester's voice.
I know thy errand.
I will go with thee.
The day, my friends,
and all things...
stay...
for me.
[Drums beating]
Hark how our steeds
for present service neigh.
Mount them and make incision
in their hides...
that their hot blood
may spin in English eyes.
Do but behold
yon poor and starved band.
Your fair show shall
suck away their souls,
leaving them but
the shales and husks of men.
There is not work enough
for all our hands.
Why do you stay so long,
my lords of france?
Yon island carrions, desperate of their
bones, ill-favoredly become the morning field.
They have said their prayers,
and they stay for death.
A very little little let us do,
and all is done.
Then let the trumpets sound the
tucket sonance and the note to mount...
for our approach will
so much dare the field...
that England shall crouch down
in fear... and yield!
[Chattering]
Where is the king?
The king himself has rode
to view their battle.
Of fighting men,
they have full threescore thousand.
That's five to one.
Besides, they are all fresh.
'Tis a fearful odds.
Oh, that we now had here but one ten
thousand of those men in England...
That do no work today.
What's he that wishes so?
My cousin Westmoreland?
No, my fair cousin.
If we are marked to die, we are
enough to do our country loss.
And if to live,
the fewer men,
The greater share of honor.
God's will, I pray thee,
wish not one man more.
Rather, proclaim it,
Westmoreland, through my host,
that he which hath
no stomach to this fight...
let him depart.
His passport shall be made...
and crowns for convoy
put into his purse.
We would not die
in that man's company...
that fears his fellowship
to die with us.
This day is called
the feast of Crispian.
He that outlives this day
and comes safe home...
will stand at tiptoe
when this day is named...
and rouse him
at the name of Crispian.
He that shall see this day
and live old age...
will yearly, on the vigil,
feast his neighbors...
and say, "tomorrow
is Saint Crispin's."
Then will he strip his sleeve
and show his scars...
and say, "these wounds
I had on Crispin's day."
Old men forget,
yet all shall be forgot but
he'll remember with advantages...
what feats he did that day.
Then shall our names, familiar
in their mouths as household words...
Harry the king,
Bedford and Exeter,
Warwick and Talbot,
Salisbury and Gloucester...
be in their flowing cups
freshly remembered.
This story shall
a good man teach his son.
Crispin Crispian
shall ne'er go by,
from this day to
the ending of the world,
but we in it
shall be remembered.
We few,
we happy few,
we band of brothers.
For he today that sheds his
blood with me shall be my brother.
Be he ne'er so vile,
this day shall gentle his condition.
And gentlemen in England
now abed...
shall think themselves accursed
they were not here...
and hold their manhoods cheap...
whiles any speaks
that fought with us...
upon Saint Cispin's day!
[Cheering]
My sovereign lord!
Bestow yourself with speed!
The French are bravely
in their battle set...
and will with all expedience
march upon us!
All things are ready
if our minds be so!
Perish the man whose mind
is backward now.
Thou dost not wish more help
from England, coz?
God's will, my liege.
You and I alone, without more help,
could fight this royal battle.
You know your places!
God be with you all!
[Cheering]
Once more I come to know
of thee, if for they ransom,
thou wilt now compound before
thy most assured overthrow.
Who hast sent thee now?
The constable of France.
I pray thee bear
my former answer back.
Bid them achieve me
and then sell my bones!
Good god, why should they
mock poor fellows thus?
Let me speak proudly.
Tell the constable we are but
warriors for the working day.
Our gayness and our gilt
are all besmirched...
with rainy marching
in the painful field,
but by the mass,
our hearts are in the trim.
Herald,
save thou thy labor.
Come thou no more for ransom,
gentle herald.
They shall have none,
I swear,
but these my joints!
[Cheering]
Which, if they have
as I shall leave of them,
shall yield them little.
Tell the constable.
I shall, king Harry.
And so fare thee well.
Thou never shalt
hear herald anymore.
My lord,
most humbly on my knee,
I beg the leading
of the vaward.
Take it, brave York.
Now, soldiers, march away,
and how thou pleasest, God,
dispose the day.
[Shouting]
And so our scene must
to the battle fly...
where, oh, for pity
we shall much disgrace...
with four or five
most vile and ragged foils...
right ill-disposed
in brawl ridiculous...
the name of Agincourt.
[Horse whinnies]
[Chattering]
[Men shouting]
[Horse whinnies]
[Shouting]
[Metal clanging]
[Galloping hoofbeats rumbling]
Ready!
- [Shouting]
- Fire!
[Shouting]
[Shouts]
[Arrows whooshing]
[Screams]
Why, all our ranks are broke.
O perdurable shame!
Shame and eternal shame.
Nothing but shame.
Let us die in arms.
Once more back again.
We are enough yet living in the field
to smother up the English in our throngs...
if any order
might be thought upon.
The devil take order now!
I'll to the throng!
Let life be short!
Else shame will be too long!
Well have we done,
thrice-valiant countrymen!
Yet all's not done!
Yet keep the French the field!
[Shouting]
[Horse whinnying]
[Whinnying continues]
[Thunder rumbling]
Kill the boys and the luggage.
'Tis expressly against
the law of arms.
'Tis as errant a piece
of knavery, mark you now,
as can be offered.
In your conscience,
now, is it not?
'Tis certain there's
not a boy left alive.
[Sobs]
I was not angry
since I came to France!
Until this instant!
Here comes the herald
of the French, my liege.
What means this, herald?
Huh? Com'st thou again for ransom?
No! Great king!
I come to thee
for charitable license...
that we may wander o'er this
bloody field to book our dead...
and then to bury them.
To sort our nobles
from our common men.
For many of our princes...
woe the while...
Lie drowned and soaked
in mercenary blood.
O, give us leave, great king,
to view the field in safety...
and to dispose
of their dead bodies.
I tell thee truly, herald,
I know not if the day
be ours or no.
The day is yours.
Praised be god...
and not our strength for it.
[Groans]
[Thunder rumbling]
What is this castle called...
that stands hard by?
They call it Agincourt.
Then call we this...
the field of Agincourt...
fought on the day
of Crispin Crispianus.
Your grandfather
of famous memory,
an't please your majesty,
and your great-uncle, Edward,
the black prince of Wales,
as I have read
in the Chronicles,
fought a most brave battle
here in France.
They did, Fluellen.
Y-your majesty says very true.
[Clears throat]
If your majesty
is remembered of it,
the Welshmen did good service in
a garden where leeks did grow,
wearing leeks in their Monmouth caps,
which, as your majesty know,
to this hour is
an honorable badge of service.
And I do believe your majesty
takes no scorn...
to wear the leek
upon St. Davy's day.
I wear it for
a memorable honor,
for I am Welsh, you know,
good my countryman.
All the water in Wye...
cannot wash your majesty's Welsh blood
out of your body, I can tell you that.
God bless it and preserve it, so long
as it pleases his grace...
and his majesty too.
Thanks, good my countryman.
By jeshu, I am your majesty's countryman!
I care not who know it.
I shall confess it to all the world!
And I need not be ashamed
of your majesty, praised be god,
so long as your majesty
is an honest man.
God keep me so.
Doth fortune play
the housewife with me now?
News I have
that my Nell is dead.
Tsk!
[Exhales]
Old do I wax,
and from my weary limbs
honor is cudgeled.
Well,
bawd I'll turn...
and something lean
to cutpurse of quick hand.
To England will I steal,
and there I'll... steal.
[Grunts] herald, are
the dead numbered?
Here is the number
of the slaughtered French.
This note doth tell me of...
10,000 French...
that in the field
lie slain.
Of princes
in this number, 126.
Added to these, of knights,
esquires and gallant gentlemen,
eight thousand
and four hundred...
of the which
five hundred...
were but yesterday
dubbed knights.
Here was a royal
fellowship of death.
Where is the number
of our English dead?
[Paper rustles]
[Thunder rumbling]
"Edward, the duke of York,
"the earl of Suffolk,
"Sir Richard Ketly,
Davy Gam, esquire."
[Thunderclap
in the distance]
None else of name...
and of all other men...
but five-and-twenty.
'Tis wonderful.
Come.
Go we in procession
to the village...
and be it death proclaimed
through our host...
to boast of this...
or take that praise
from God which is his only.
Is it not lawful,
an't please your majesty,
to tell how many
is killed?
Aye, captain,
but with this acknowledgement:
That God fought...
for us.
Yes, my conscience.
He did us great good.
Do we all holy rites.
Let there be sung
non nobisandte deum.
The dead with charity
enclosed in clay.
And then to Calais...
and to England then,
where ne'er from
France arrived...
more happy men.
# Non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
[men's chorus]
# Non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# tuo da #
# gloriam ##
Peace to this meeting.
Unto our brother France,
health and fair time of day.
Joy and good wishes to our most fair
and princely cousin Katherine.
And as a branch and member
of this royalty...
by whom this great assembly
is contrived,
we do salute you,
duke of Burgundy.
And, princes French and peers,
health to you all.
Right joyous are we to behold your
face, most worthy brother England.
Fairly met.
So are you,
princes English, every one.
My duty to you both,
on equal love,
great kings of France...
and England.
Since that my office
hath so far prevailed,
that face to face and royal
eye to eye you have congreeted...
let it not disgrace me if I
demand before this royal view...
why that the naked,
poor and mangled peace...
should not in this best
garden of the world,
our fertile France,
put up her lovely visage?
Alas,
she hath from France
too long been chased,
and all her husbandry
doth lie on heaps,
corrupting in
its own fertility.
And as our vineyards,
fallows, meads and hedges,
defective in their natures,
grow to wildness,
even so our houses and ourselves,
our children have lost...
or do not learn
for want of time...
those sciences which
should become our country,
but grow like savages,
as soldiers will...
that nothing do
but meditate on blood...
to swearing and stern looks,
diffused attire,
and everything that seems...
unnatural.
And my speech entreats
that I may know...
the let why gentle peace...
should not expel
these inconveniences...
and bless us with
her former qualities.
Lf, duke of Burgundy,
you would the peace...
whose want gives growth to the
imperfections which you have cited,
then you must buy
that peace...
with full accord
to all our just demands.
I have but with
a cursorary eye...
o'erglanced the articles.
Pleaseth your grace to appoint
some of your council...
to sit with us once more...
we will suddenly pass...
our accept
and peremptory answer.
Brother, we shall.
Yet leave
our cousin Katherine...
here with us.
She is our capital demand...
comprised within
the fore-rank of our articles.
She hath good leave.
Fair Katherine,
and most fair,
will you vouchsafe
to teach a soldier...
terms such as will enter
at a lady's ear...
and plead his love suit
to her gentle heart?
Your majesty
shall mock at me.
I cannot speak your England.
Oh.
Fair Katherine, if you will love me
soundly with your French heart,
glad to hear you confess it brokenly with your English
Do you like me, Kate?
Pardonnez-moi. I cannot
tell what is "like me."
An angel is like you, Kate,
and you are like an angel.
Que dit-il? Que je suis
semblable a les anges?
Qui, vraiment, sauf votre
grace, ainsi dit-il.
[Sighs]
Mon dieu.
Les langues des hommes
sont pleines de tromperies.
What says she, fair one?
That the tongues of men
are full of deceits?
Oui. That the tongues of
the mens is be full of deceits.
That is the princess.
I'faith, my wooing is fit
for thy understanding.
I know no ways to mince it in love,
but directly to say, "I love you."
Then, if you urge me farther than to say,
"Do you in faith?" I wear out my suit.
Give me your answer... i'faith do... and so
clap hands and a bargain. How say you, lady?
Sauf votre honneur,
me understand well.
Marry, if you would put me to verses or
to dance for your sake, why, you undid me.
If I could win a lady at leapfrog
or by vaulting into my saddle...
with my arm around my back,
I should quickly leap into a wife.
I could lay on like a butcher and
sit like a jackanapes, never off.
But before God, Kate,
I cannot look greenly...
Nor gasp out my eloquence nor
I have no cunning in protestation.
If thou canst love a fellow
of this temper, Kate,
that never looks in his glass
for love of anything he sees there,
let thine eye be thy cook.
I speak to thee plain soldier. If thou
canst love me for this, take me.
If not, to say to thee
that I shall die, 'tis true,
but for thy love,
by the lord, no.
Yet I love thee too.
If thou would have
such a one, take me.
And take me, take a soldier.
Take a soldier, take a king.
And what sayest thou
then to my love?
Speak, my fair,
and fairly, too, I pray thee.
Is it possible that I should
love the enemy of France?
No, kate.
It is not possible that you
should love the enemy of France.
But in loving me, you should
love the friend of France,
for I love France so well that
I will not part with a village of it.
I will have it all mine.
And, Kate, when France
is mine, and I am yours,
then yours is France,
and you are mine.
I cannot tell what is that.
No, kate?
I will tell thee in French...
which I am sure will
hang about my tongue...
like a new-married wife
about her husband's neck, //hardly to be shook off.
Je quand sur
le possession de France...
et, uh, quand vous
avez la possession,
uh, de moi...
Let me see...
[chuckles]
Uh, oh...
[stammers]
Donc, uh, votre est france...
et, uh, vous etes mienne.
It is as easy for me, Kate,
to conquer the kingdom...
as to speak so much more French!
I will never move thee in French
unless it be to laugh at me.
Sauf votre honneur,
le francais que vous parlez...
Il est meilleur
que I'anglais lequel je parle.
No, faith, it is not.
But tell me, Kate,
Canst thou understand
thus much English?
Canst thou love me?
I cannot tell.
Well, can any of your neighbors
tell, Kate? I'll ask them.
By mine honor, in true English,
I swear I love thee,
by which honor I dare
not swear thou lovest me.
Yet my blood begins to flatter
me that thou dost...
withstanding the poor and untempering effect of my vis
Now beshrew
my father's ambition!
He was thinking of
civil wars when he got me.
Therefore was I created
with a stubborn outside,
with an aspect of iron, that
when I come to woo ladies,
I fright them.
But, in faith, kate, the elder I wax,
the better I shall appear.
My comfort is that old age,
that ill layer-up of beauty,
can do no more spoil
upon my face.
Thou hast me... ifthou
hast me... at the worst.
And thou shalt wear me...
if thou wear me...
Better and better.
And, therefore, tell me,
most fair Katherine,
Will you have me?
Come, your answer
in broken music,
for thy voice is music,
and thy English, broken.
Therefore, queen of all,
Katherine,
wilt thou have me?
That is as it shall please
le roi mon pere.
Nay, it shall
please him well, Kate.
It shall please him, Kate.
Then it shall also content me.
Upon that, I kiss your hand,
and I call you my queen.
Laissez, mon seigneur,
laissez, laissez.
Ma foi, je ne veux point que
vous abaissiez votre grandeur...
En baisant la main d'une de
votre seigneurie indigne serviteur.
Excusez-moi, je vous supplie,
mon tres-puissant seigneur.
Then I will kiss
your lips, Kate.
Les dames et demoiselles pour
etre baisees devant leur noces...
Il n'est pas
la coutume de France.
Madame my interpreter,
what says she?
That is not be the fashion
for the ladies of France...
Oh, I cannot tell
what Isbaiserin English.
To kiss?
Your majestyentends
betterque moi.
Ah, it is not a fashion for the maids in
France to kiss before they are married?
Oui, vraiment.
Oh, kate.
Nice customs curtsy
to great kings.
You and I cannot be confined within
the weak list of a country's fashion.
We... are the makers
of manners, Kate.
Therefore, patiently...
and yielding.
You have witchcraft
in your lips, Kate.
There is more eloquence
in a sugar touch of them...
than in the tongues
of the French council.
[Thudding]
Here comes your father.
God save
your majesty.
My royal cousin,
teach you
our princess english?
I would have her learn,
my fair cousin,
how perfectly I love her,
and that is good english.
[Chuckles]
We have consented
to all terms of reason.
And thereupon
give me your daughter.
Take her, fair son,
and from her blood
raise up issue to me...
that the contending kingdoms
of France and England...
whose very shores look pale with
envy of each other's happiness...
may cease their hatred...
and this
dear conjunction...
plant neighborhood...
and Christian-like accord
in their sweet bosoms...
that never war advance...
his bleeding sword...
'twixt England
and fair France.
Amen.
Now, welcome, Kate,
and bear me witness all...
That here I kiss her
as my sovereign queen.
God, the best maker
of all marriages,
combine our hearts in one,
our realms in one.
As man and wife, being two,
are one in love,
so be there 'twixt our kingdoms
such a spousal...
that never may ill office
or fell jealousy...
which troubles oft
the bed of blessed marriage...
thrust in between
the paction of these kingdoms...
to make divorce
of their incorporate league...
that English may as French,
French Englishmen,
receive each other.
God speak this.
Amen.
[Group] Amen.
Thus far, with rough
and all-unable pen...
our bending author
hath pursued the story...
in little room
confining mighty men...
mangling by starts
the full course of their glory.
Small time,
but in that small
most greatly lived...
this star of England.
Fortune made his sword...
by which the world's
best garden he achieved...
and of it left
his son imperial lord.
He sixth, in infant bands crowned king of France and E
did this king succeed...
whose state so many
had the managing...
that they lost France...
and made his England bleed...
which oft our stage
hath shown,
and, for their sake,
in your fair minds
let this acceptance take.
[Man]
# Non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
[men's chorus]
# Non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# non nobis domine, domine #
# non nobis domine #
# sed nomeni #
# tuo da gloriam #
# tuo da #
# gloriam ##
>> Napisy pobrane z http://napisy.org <<
>>>>>>>> nowa wizja napis闚 <<<<<<<<