- Hello, Eddie.
- Hello, Ben.
What gives?
We're looking for a couple of Indians
broke out of jail.
Young bucks in fancy shirts.
If you see anything of them,
telephone my office at Palm Grove.
Okay.
Those Indians they're looking
for must be from around here.
- They always head for home.
- Home being Key Largo.
Want something, Jack?
- Mr. Temple around?
- He ain't here.
Hotel is closed.
- When will he be back?
- I don't know.
Have a beer?
- The bar is closed.
- That's right.
I told you, didn't I? Hotel's closed.
In the summertime, everything's closed.
Give him a drink.
Give him a drink!
You heard me! Give him a drink!
- You said beer?
- Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.
Think nothing of it.
Bargain Lass on the outside
is running very fast and very hard.
It's Lady Bountiful,
they haven't caught her yet.
Come on, Lady Bountiful.
Come on, Lady Bountiful!
Come on!
Lady Bountiful by three lengths.
How's that for picking them?
Can I pick them or can't I?
That's him.
I'll take it up.
If he wants you, he'll send for you.
I like Fancy Free.
Carrying 118 pounds.
That's a lot of weight.
- What do you think?
- Fancy Free.
- You play the ponies?
- No.
- Why not?
- I haven't the money.
Aw. Angel, another beer for the gentleman.
You see, I play the long shots.
Betting on a favorite, what do you win?
When a horse comes in for me,
he pays plenty.
Take Fancy Free,
"Morning Line, 12-1."
Oops, that's ridiculous.
He should be 4-1, even less.
Look at that breeding.
"By Chance Play,
out of Misconstrue by Omaha."
Course, he hasn't won in 11 starts, true.
But he's been twice on the money.
And today he's running
a $3,000 claiming race.
Ought to be a cinch.
Yes?
What's your name?
McCloud. Frank. By John, out of Helen.
I'm Miss Dawn.
Miss Gaye Dawn.
You. He wants you.
Uh, please excuse me.
Who's that?
- I don't know.
- What's he want?
Old man Temple.
Look, mister, if you're thinking
of putting up here, the hotel's closed.
- Won't be open for another month.
- What are you doin' here?
- We're guests.
- Yeah, but you just said...
We're here by special arrangement.
I don't plan to stay.
I just wanna see Mr. Temple.
Oh, well, why didn't you say so?
He's out by the boathouse.
- Mr. Temple?
- Yeah?
My name's McCloud. Frank McCloud.
McCloud, huh?
- Well, not Major McCloud?
- Yes, sir.
Nora!
Nora! Nora!
Come here! When did you get here?
A few minutes ago.
I'm on my way to Key West.
Did you come on the bus? I saw it stop.
Hey, Nora!
Hurry up!
Come here!
Look who's here.
This is George's wife.
This is Major Frank McCloud.
How do you do, Mrs. Temple?
Your husband and I were
in the same outfit overseas.
As if she didn't know.
I wrote you a letter, Major, to St. Louis.
It was sent on to Portland,
St. Paul and Memphis,
all those places, before it came back.
- Ever been down here before?
- No, sir.
George was right.
The Keys are different than
anything I've ever seen. And hotter.
Uh, don't look for it to get
any cooler before November.
The thermometer will go down to about 100.
The sand flies and mosquitoes
will disappear.
It'll be right livable for about
three months on the Keys.
Except for the tourists.
- That Black Caesar's Rock?
- How'd you know?
For one who's never been here,
I know a lot about these Keys.
They were a favorite subject with George.
He used to dig
for pirate gold right over there.
He never lost hope of finding
Blackbeard's own treasure.
He must've dug 10,000 holes.
- Ever find anything?
- Oh, sure.
Saltwater, every time.
How long you gonna be with us, Major?
- An hour or so.
- An hour?
You can spare more time than that, surely.
We got a lot to talk about.
I'll talk as long as you like, Mr. Temple.
Good, then you'll stay overnight.
He can have George's room.
Yes, Dad.
- May I help you?
- Yeah, if you will, please.
Afternoon, Mrs. Temple.
Mr. Temple.
Any news of the Osceola brothers?
Oh, I'm sorry, Ben.
I want you to meet my son's
commanding officer, Major McCloud.
- How do you do?
- Officer Ben Wade. Sawyer.
How do you do?
If you don't mind, Mr. Temple,
we'd like to have a look around.
Ah, you won't find those Indians,
'cause they ain't here.
Maybe they're in the mangrove swamps.
Maybe.
Or maybe if you wanna go wading,
you might find them. Maybe.
But if I was you,
I'd save myself the trouble.
No doubt they'll give
themselves up before morning.
Well, they sure enough ought to.
That's a fact, Mr. Temple.
'Cause the longer they stay at large,
the tougher it's gonna be on 'em.
Fool Indians.
Thirty days to do and they bust out.
Well, 30 days in jail for an Indian
is like 30 years for somebody else.
Anyway, I'd like to have a look around.
Now, look here, Clyde, if Mr. Temple
says they ain't here, they ain't.
His word's good enough for me,
and it ought to be good enough for you.
Sorry to bother you, Mr. Temple.
Come on, Clyde.
Those two brothers and my boy, George,
grew up together.
There's no harm in them.
They just went to Palm Grove
and got a little snootful
and started to take Florida
back for the Indians.
Came mighty near succeeding, too.
I sent word for them to
come in and give themselves up.
Not that I'm supposed to know where
they are, you understand.
Oh, Major, I want you to meet
Mr., uh, Mr....
- Bass.
- Garcia.
We've already met.
My son's commanding officer overseas.
Yeah?
They were in the
Italian Campaign together.
- From Salerno to Cassino.
- Yeah.
My boy, George, was killed in Cassino.
Yeah?
What's going on here?
Nothing, Mr. Temple.
What's the matter with her?
- Nora? Nora!
- Yes, Father.
What ails that girl? She hurt?
Case of one too many,
that's all, Mr. Temple.
Now, look here! If you people can't
behave yourselves, you gotta leave.
What did you hit her for?
I'll let you in on something.
She's a lush, the lady.
After she bends the elbow a few times,
she begins to see things,
rats, roaches, snakes, bats, you know.
A sock in the kisser is the only thing
that'll bring her out of it.
Your room's ready, Major.
How long have they been here?
That one, Curly, and the woman
showed up first.
Dad Temple told them
we were closed for the summer,
but he offered to rent
the whole hotel for a week.
It was so much money,
Dad couldn't afford to turn it down.
Mr. Brown and the others arrived
in that big boat four days ago.
Which one is Brown?
He's in number 11. Never comes out
of his room except at night.
What's he like?
He's a lady-killer, or thinks so.
Rich, I guess, from the way the others
jump when he lifts a finger.
Out of season in this heat.
Why would they decide
to sit down on Key Largo?
They'll be leaving here
tonight or tomorrow.
Major?
- Were you with George when he died?
- Yes.
Was he in very much pain?
He never knew what hit him.
I was afraid he might have suffered.
Come down to Dad's room
when you're ready, Major.
Excuse me.
Staying the night, huh?
I'm Curly Hoff.
I heard how you were with
old man Temple's son in Italy.
The kid got it, huh?
Ah, too bad.
I hope you didn't take offense
at the way we handled you downstairs.
You caught Toots and me at a bad time.
We were ready to bite anybody's head off.
Especially a certain blonde's.
Look, five of us. We come down here
for the deep-sea fishing.
All the way from Milwaukee.
More than a year, we'd been planning
to come down here and fish our brains out.
So what happens? One guy brings a blonde.
And after we all swore
up and down, no dames!
But he's gotta bring her, this guy.
Well, if she isn't drunk and crying,
she's got a hangover and arguing.
One minute she gets sore at you
and won't talk to you at all.
The next she's making a play for you
right in front of the guy.
And he gets sore at us, mind you, not her.
Everything's spoiled,
including our dispositions.
It's cost us all this dough, and for what?
The world's worst time.
Now, I ask you, can you blame us
for getting rude?
- No, I don't blame you.
- How about a little drink, pal?
Not right now, thanks.
Hotel Largo.
Come on, just to show
there's no hard feelings.
No, thank you.
Oh, thank you very much.
- Storm signals are up.
- What does that mean?
Hurricane's on its way.
See what I mean? Hurricanes yet.
Dad's in here, Major.
Sit down, Major.
The war's over, Mr. Temple.
I'm not a Major anymore.
Oh, I know the men that were in it
don't like talking about the war,
and I don't like imposing on you.
But this letter here from the War
Department is the only facts we have.
And, well, it leaves us in the dark
about a few things.
I'll tell you everything I know,
Mr. Temple.
Will you, Frank? Will you?
I'd be most grateful.
- Where shall I start?
- Anywhere.
Well, he was a good soldier, Mr. Temple,
from start to finish.
You'd have been proud of him
like every man in his regiment was.
- Were they, Frank?
- And with good reason.
It wasn't just a matter of doing his duty.
He was always looking
for a way to do more.
And finding it.
George was a born hero, Mr. Temple.
He couldn't imagine his death.
Only dishonor.
No, of course not.
It's a wonder he lasted till Cassino.
When you believe like George believed,
maybe dying isn't very important.
Once, outside San Pietro,
George and a couple of others
established a forward observation post.
They got a direct hit,
and the others were killed.
That left it up to George.
For three days and three nights
he stayed awake directing our fire.
Most of that time,
I was on the other end of the line.
To keep himself awake,
he talked into the phone.
Talked and talked.
Most of his talk was about you two.
You'd be surprised how much
I know about you both.
For instance, inside your wedding ring,
Nora, there's an inscription,
"Evermore."
That's right.
And you, Mr. Temple.
Do you remember telling George what
this hollow is above the upper lip?
Before he was born, you said
he knew all the secrets of life and death.
Then at the moment of his birth, an angel
came and put his finger right here.
And sealed his lips.
I remember that. Yup.
He couldn't have been more than seven years
old when I told him that fairy story.
What's it like where he's buried?
Just crosses on a slope.
High up, there's what's left of a church.
You can see a river from where George is.
I'd like to pay a visit to that place.
Yep, I would.
Nora, maybe we'll do just that.
Go to Italy and see
where George is buried.
It belongs to us, don't it?
That plot of ground?
I'm very grateful to you, Frank.
Thank you.
There was a storm warning, Dad.
You better see to the boat, dear.
What brought you down this way, Frank?
I like the sea and thought maybe
I'd like to make my living on it.
- Doing what?
- Doesn't matter. Hand on a fishing boat.
Life on land's become
too complicated for my taste.
What did you do before the war, Frank?
I was circulation manager for a newspaper.
- You never went back to it?
- Yeah, but I couldn't stick it.
I've done lot of things
since I left the paper.
Driving taxis, waiting on tables,
anything to make a dollar.
Including day labor.
Getting kind of rough.
Major, this is Mr. Feeney.
- Hi, pal.
- How do you do?
How's your ground tackle off the stern?
Plenty heavy.
Then we'd better just double up
on these bowlines.
Where'd you learn about boats?
My first sweetheart was a boat.
Hey!
How do you like that boat?
Nice craft. She ought to be away
from those reefs with this blow comin' up.
That so?
Put that on that piling over there.
Charlie!
Charlie Wenoka and his family,
Crawfish Island.
The Wenokas are royalty.
Charlie's a prince of the Seminole nation.
His ancestors go back to the gods.
He sells seashells by the seashore.
Hello, Mama Ochobee.
Every Indian around here is
a descendent of Mama Ochobee.
She admits to being 108 years old.
But she has a son who's 112.
So, we suspect Mama doesn't tell
the truth about her age.
New husband?
Him new husband? No, Mama.
Not new husband.
- Got cigarette?
- What?
- You got cigarette?
- Yeah.
Pretty big blow coming, Mama?
Pretty big.
The Indians always know.
Don't ask me how, but they do.
More will be along. They always come to
us from as far as Matecumbe Key.
This one was born in our hotel lobby
during the last big blow, weren't you?
Yes.
Hello, Tom. Hello, John.
- Tom and Johnny Osceola, Frank.
- How are you do?
- How do you do?
- Hello.
We get Mr. Temple message.
We here give ourself up to police.
He thinks it's the best thing.
What Mr. Temple say, we do.
Him good friend to Indian.
Why don't you go on over to the hotel?
And Dad'll call Palm Grove.
Thanks, Miss Nora.
Poor fellas, they got into some trouble
and were arrested.
Yes, I know.
Mr. Temple told me about them.
They really trust Dad Temple.
All the Indians.
As far as they're concerned,
he's the United States of America.
You're very happy here, aren't you?
- Very.
- You're never lonely?
Did George tell you?
I met him at a USO dance.
He was lonesome. He wanted company.
I was working at a defense plant.
I knew lots of people,
but I was lonesome, too.
Before George, my life
hadn't made much sense.
I never had much of a home,
and I didn't like what I had.
George...
George gave me roots.
When he went overseas,
I came down here to stay with his father.
And the roots took hold.
Now I'm, I'm like one of those mangroves.
Our local police always get their Indian.
You close the shutters
while I get the oil lamps.
Hey, pal. Getting ready
for the hurricane, eh?
How's about joining me
for that little drink now?
No, thanks.
- You're not a drinking man?
- No, not right now.
Hey, Curly.
What all happens in a hurricane?
The wind blows so hard
the ocean gets up on its hind legs
and walks right across the land.
And singing this song,
"Rain, rain go away.
Little Ralphie wants to play."
Isn't that Ben Wade's car?
Nora! Have you seen him?
No, Dad, I haven't.
Here's a good one.
They're snooping around looking
for these two boys, and here they are.
Better go out there and sit
in his car and wait for him.
Or better yet, go and find him.
What's so funny, Toots?
There are two cons in a cell, see?
And one con was trying to sell
the other one a fountain pen.
And he says,
"This pen is guaranteed for life."
What's the matter? Don't you get it?
A con.
"Guaranteed for life."
We get it, all right.
Have you seen Wade or Sawyer
anywhere around, Frank?
No, sir, I haven't.
- His car's out there in the rain.
- Yes, I know.
It's funny.
How about a drink, everybody?
What'll it be, Miss Temple?
Nothing, thanks.
- How about you, Pop?
- Uh...
He's not supposed to drink anything.
That leaves it up to you, pal.
Another time.
What's the matter? Don't you like me?
I'm beginning to think
I got smallpox or something.
Are you still laughin'
at that stinking joke?
Here's another one.
Elevator's busting through a roof, see?
And the elevator boy's saying
to a couple of passengers,
"I told you there was no 11th floor."
Explain it for us, Toots.
Wise guy.
What's the idea of them?
They shut the electricity off,
we still have light.
I hear that a hurricane blows off roofs,
uproots trees and puts
the snatch on people.
And they all go flyin' around
in the sky together. Is that right?
Absolutely.
It's raining in on Ben's car.
You better close the windows, Nora.
Ralph, go put up the windows in that car.
What, get caught out in that hurricane?
Not me, brother.
I'll take it.
Don't you answer it.
Yes?
No, Mr. Temple's not here now.
No, she's not here either.
Me?
I'm a guest at the hotel.
No, we haven't seen him.
Give me that phone.
Yes. If Sawyer shows up,
I'll have him call you right back.
Easy does it, soldier.
The phone rang, and the girl
started for it and I stopped her.
The soldier wants to get rough,
so we show him our rods.
I'm glad the old man's in a wheelchair.
He'd be lots of trouble.
- Who was on the phone?
- The law.
That means he won't be long.
Then what?
We'll see.
You'd think this rain would
cool things off, but it don't.
- Gonna have a hurricane, are we?
- Yeah, so they say.
I'm not afraid of that gun.
Go ahead! Shoot!
Yeah, I'm not afraid.
Brown!
Hey, you! Brown!
Are you thieves or what? You want money?
Is this a robbery?
That's right, Pop.
We're gonna steal all your towels.
That big gun in your hand
makes you look grown-up, you think.
I'll bet you spend hours posing
in front of a mirror holding it.
Trying to look tough.
- Shut up.
- You scum.
Toots...
- Tell him not to call me names.
- Shut up, Toots.
Now, listen.
I don't want any trouble.
With you. With anybody.
Now, how about it? Gonna act sensible?
Why are they pointing those guns at us?
Now, look, Pop. Forget the questions.
What you don't know won't hurt you.
We'll be out of here in a couple of hours.
Try to put up with us that long, huh?
What're we gonna eat tonight, sister?
Pompano, maybe?
Am I to understand we're your prisoners?
Well, put it this way, Pop, you're gonna
be my guests for a little while.
You know, back in Chi, in the old days,
we used to pay $8 to $10
for an order of pompano.
They used to fly it in,
the way they served it,
done up in a brown paper bag.
Got any champagne, miss?
No champagne.
Well, that's too bad.
Champagne and pompano.
They really go together.
This one's coming around.
Still feel tough?
Sawyer.
You won't get away with it, Rocco.
Why'd you hurt that boy?
He's a cop, that's why.
Well, who are you?
Why are you here?
- Answer me!
- Oh, stop hollering, old man.
Johnny Rocco, of course.
Hot water.
Get some.
Yeah, that's right.
Johnny Rocco.
- I know that name.
- Sure, Pop. Who doesn't?
Johnny Rocco the gangster, Mr. Temple.
The one and only Rocco.
Rocco. Rocco?
What's that, Pop? I'm kind of deaf.
Rocco!
Oh.
He said, "Rocco."
But they threw you out of the country.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
After living in the USA
for more than 30 years,
they... They called me
an undesirable alien.
Me, Johnny Rocco.
Like I was a dirty Red or somethin'.
Then how could you be here?
Well, maybe I'm not, Pop.
This ain't real, what's happenin'.
You're having a dream.
Wake up, Pop. You're snoring.
You're right.
You shouldn't have been deported.
You should've been exterminated.
Rocco...
I must apologize for Mr. Temple.
He doesn't know what he's talking about,
or, who to.
Sir, Johnny Rocco was more than a king.
He was an emperor.
His rule extended over beer,
slot machines, the numbers racket,
and a dozen other forbidden enterprises.
He was a master of the fix.
Whom he couldn't corrupt, he terrified.
Whom he couldn't terrify, he murdered.
You filth. You city filth.
Oh, Mr. Temple, you're
hopelessly old-fashioned.
Your ideas date back years.
You're still living in the time
when America thought
it could get along
without the Johnny Roccos.
Welcome back, Rocco. It was all a mistake.
America's sorry for what it did to you.
On the level, boss, were you that big?
On the level, are you that dumb?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's me.
Sure, I was all of those things.
And more.
When Rocco talked,
everybody shut up and listened.
What Rocco said, went.
Nobody was as big as Rocco.
It'll be like that again, only more so.
I'll be back up there one of these days.
And then you're gonna
really see something.
If the time ever comes when your kind
can walk a city street in daylight
with nothing to fear from the people...
The time has come, Mr. Temple. It's here.
Okay.
You know all about me.
Now, what's with you, wise guy?
Well, give.
- In the war, weren't you?
- Yes.
- Get any medals?
- A couple.
- Brave, huh?
- Not very.
- Why'd you stick your neck out?
- No good reason.
What are you saying, Frank?
I believed some words.
Words? What words?
Well, they went like this,
"But we are not making all this sacrifice
"of human effort and human lives
"to return to the kind of a world
we had after the last world war."
Huh.
"We're fighting to cleanse
the world of ancient evils.
"Ancient ills."
What's that all about?
I remember those words.
Well, that makes two of us.
We rid ourselves of your kind
once and for all.
You ain't comin' back!
Who's gonna stop me, old man?
If I wasn't a cripple...
You wouldn't be talking this way.
Right, Pop?
Filth! You filth!
Get him, will you!
- Sic him, Pop!
- Stand your ground!
"Stand your ground."
You're killing me, Pop.
Come on. Come on, Pop.
You're not quitting, are you?
My boy, George, never quit,
and I ain't quitting.
That's the spirit, Pop. Never say die.
You little wildcat.
Smelled blood, huh?
Got your appetite up, huh?
Hey, boss.
Miami wants you on the phone.
A whole bunch of people out on the porch,
look like Indians.
- What do they want?
- They want in.
- What for?
- The hurricane.
All right, keep them out.
Hello?
Yeah, this is Mr. Brown.
Hello? Oh, hello, Ziggy. How are you?
I recognized your voice, yeah.
Swell hearin' it again.
How's every little thing?
- Maybe it's the law.
- Right. Show him in.
Hey, that's swell.
This end, too.
Look, when are you coming down?
What hurricane? That right?
- I want to see the boss.
- It's the skipper!
- Mr. Temple, Mr. Temple, please!
- Well, look, uh...
You're only a couple of hours away.
You can beat the hurricane out.
No, it's gotta be tonight.
Yeah, see you in a couple of hours.
Bye.
Storm warning. Big blow on the way.
- So what?
- This coral reef not safe.
Got to make for deep water right away.
That boat stays right here.
Too dangerous. Boat break up on reef.
I tell you when to move that boat.
I am skipper.
Now, look.
I paid you.
- Now, you do what I say.
- Please, señor.
You want half money back? I give.
But got to move boat.
Give me your rod.
See this?
You move that boat,
I'll blow your brains out.
Okay, okay.
We'll be out of here in a couple of hours.
I'll be ready.
Go out and move that car around the back.
I come back here looking
for those Osceola boys.
I knew they were somewhere around here.
Down the lobby,
I ran up against these two.
They didn't look right to me,
so I asked them a few questions.
By the way they answered me,
I knew there was something fishy.
So I put in a call to Ben Wade,
but, before I can get through,
the lights went out on me.
I woke up in there.
Rocco was standing over me.
I recognized him right away
from the pictures.
I made a break for the door,
and the lights went out again.
I'm the electrician.
Angel. Shave.
What did Miami have to say?
Everything's okay.
How soon will they be down?
They were leaving right away.
How're you feeling, copper?
I'll say one thing, you sure can take it.
By the way Toots poured it on,
I'm surprised you ever woke up.
Phew. Boy, sure is hot.
Not too close.
So I won't get away with it, huh?
How many times I heard that
from dumb coppers. I couldn't count.
I still say it.
You'd give your left eye
to nail me, wouldn't you, huh?
You can see the headlines, can't you?
"Local Deputy Captures Johnny Rocco."
Your picture would be in all the papers.
You might even get to tell on
the newsreel how you pulled it off.
Yeah.
Well, listen, hick.
I was too much for any big-city
police force to handle.
They tried, but they couldn't.
Took the United States government
to pin a rap on me.
Yeah, and they won't make it stick!
You hick!
I'll be back pulling strings to get guys
elected mayor and governor
before you ever get 10-buck raise!
Yeah.
How many of those guys in office
owe everything to me?
I made them.
Yeah, I made them, just like a tailor
makes a suit of clothes.
I take a nobody, see, teach him what to
say, get his name in the papers.
I pay for his campaign expenses.
Dish out a lot of groceries and coal.
Get my boys to bring the voters out.
And then count the votes,
over and over again
till they added up right,
and he was elected.
Then what happened?
Did he remember when the going got tough?
When the heat was on?
No, he didn't want to.
All he wanted was
to save his own dirty neck.
Yeah, that's enough of that.
Give me a towel, will you?
Yeah. "Public Enemy," he calls me!
Me, who gave him his public,
all wrapped up with a fancy bow on it!
Angel, lay my clothes out.
- What suit?
- The gray one.
- What color shirt?
- A white one, of course.
Some little wildcat.
I knew one like you a long time ago.
Scratched, kicked, bit.
Regular hellion.
She even stuck a knife in me once.
Irish kid.
Little and kind of skinny she was
but a real fireball.
Her name was Maggie Mooney.
But for professional reasons,
I had her change it to Gaye Dawn.
She was a knockout in those days.
Hold on.
Why, you...
Go ahead, boss, smack her.
Get it out of your system.
Look at him. The great Johnny Rocco
with Nora's spittle hanging from his face!
Shut up, old man!
Come over here. I'd like to spit on you.
Give me. Give me!
Nothing to stop me from
wiping you all out.
What good will that do, boss? Forget it.
Her kind's a dime a dozen.
I say smack her and let it go at that.
Oh, that'd be right for you, Toots,
not for him.
I need your advice, I ask for it.
The Roccos don't,
or they wouldn't be Roccos.
No, Toots. Smacking her isn't enough
for such an insult. He'd have to kill her.
Then he'd have to kill
the rest of us because we witnessed it.
Not just Mr. Temple and me,
but all the witnesses.
It's kill us all or nothing.
He needs you and Curly and Angel.
So it'll be nothing.
Wise guy.
Unlock this door!
Unlock this door! I want out!
Let her out.
I take off my hat to you, soldier.
It's good thing you said what you did when
you said it, or he'd have started shooting.
Close shave for you folks.
Closer than the one he got from Angel.
Where is everybody? Downstairs?
Oh... Hello, everybody.
Hi, fella.
Where's Johnny?
He's in there getting dressed.
I need a drink.
What's everybody doing upstairs?
Honey?
Have you been crying?
Why? Has somebody been mean to you?
Him? Did you make her cry?
If you did, you ought to be ashamed.
- How about a little drink, huh?
- No, thanks.
- Oh, come on. It'll chase the blues away.
- No.
- I'll have one.
- The boss said...
I don't care what the boss said.
I need a drink.
- Good evening, Mr. Temple.
- Miss.
You got a cigarette?
Thanks.
Did your horse win?
- Uh, my horse?
- Mm.
Oh, no, I'm afraid he
ran out of the money.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh...
I think I'll go to my room.
I feel faint.
What I need is a drink.
That's what I need.
Say, how about it, you?
How many times do I have to tell...
The boss say you get no more drink.
Oh, he did, did he?
Well, this is a free country.
If I want a drink, I can have one.
I can buy my own. There!
Sorry.
- The boss say...
- The boss! The boss! He can go to...
Oh, hello, darling.
How come it's hotter at night
than in the day?
And when it's raining than when it ain't?
Huh, wise guy?
I don't know.
You don't know.
I thought you knew all the answers.
I thought you was a wise guy
from way back.
Darling, you've hurt yourself!
Your face! How in the world...
Oh...
- What's funny?
- Nothing.
Then, why'd you laugh?
I don't know.
Dumbbell.
What's worse, Curly?
A dumbbell or a wise guy?
A wise guy, I guess.
Got a million dollars?
No.
- How much?
- Nothing.
But you're a wise guy.
Well, you see, I was educated
only in impractical things.
With you, it's just the opposite.
I'm afraid. I hate thunder.
Is this it? Is it?
- It's the beginning.
- I'm afraid!
Well, can cars get through
during a hurricane?
Maybe. Maybe not.
I think I'll have a...
- A scotch and water, please.
- No.
- Please, darling.
- No!
You know, what you were saying,
that's the truth.
Only you don't believe it.
I can see right through you.
What you really think is
"I'm better than Rocco.
"He's filth!"
Like the old man said, right?
Right.
"He's got a gun, you think,
and I haven't."
You figure it's the gun.
Well, listen, soldier.
Thousands of guys got guns,
but there's only one Johnny Rocco!
How do you account for it?
Well, he knows what he wants.
- Don't you, Rocco?
- Sure.
- What's that?
- Tell him, Rocco.
Well, I want, uh...
He wants more. Don't you, Rocco?
Yeah, that's it. More.
That's right, I want more.
Will you ever get enough?
Will you, Rocco?
Well, I never have.
No, I guess I won't.
You, do you know what you want?
Yes, and I had hopes once,
but I gave them up.
Hopes for what?
A world in which there's
no place for Johnny Rocco.
Yeah?
Okay, soldier.
Here's your chance.
Give me.
Okay, soldier, you can make
your hopes come true.
But you gotta die for it.
See where I'm aiming? Right at your belly.
Go ahead, shoot.
- Get away, sister.
- Get away, Nora.
Shoot!
All right, you got a gun now.
You gonna use it or not?
Kill him, Major!
Yeah, kill him, Major.
Go ahead, show them
how you're not afraid to die.
Shoot!
Looks like you don't want it enough,
what you want.
Tootsy laughs when something's
funny for a change.
One Rocco more or less
isn't worth dying for.
Give me that gun.
Oh, no, I'm afraid you'd use it.
One old man more or less
isn't worth dying for.
What's the matter, sister?
You look like you lost somebody
near and dear.
A live war hero.
Now I know how you did it.
Hey, Curly, Gaye, anybody!
Want a hero?
Here's one for sale, cheap.
All right, Rocco.
All right!
Let's you and me play that game now!
You can stop me from going out that door.
But you gotta die first.
If he shoots me, you still get it.
Get out of my way.
Get away from that door!
The gun wasn't loaded.
He didn't have a chance.
Murderer.
Had to do it, old man.
Or he would've been
out that door and gone.
He's gone now.
That's right, sister.
The gun wasn't loaded.
But our hero didn't know it.
You knew the gun was empty,
didn't you, son?
You could tell by the weight.
No, sir. I didn't know.
He just didn't have the nerve, Pop.
Let's face it.
You were smart, fella.
What happened to him
would've happened to you.
It's better to be a live coward
than a dead hero.
Oh, excuse me.
You weren't afraid, son. We all know that.
Oh, yes, I was afraid.
But that's not why
I didn't pull the trigger.
What do I care about Johnny Rocco,
whether he lives or dies?
I only care about me. Me and mine!
Rocco wants to come back to America,
let him. Let him be president!
I fight nobody's battles but my own.
I can't see it your way, Frank.
Sawyer didn't either.
He was a fool.
Me, die to rid the world
of a Johnny Rocco?
No, thanks.
If I believed your way,
I'd want to be dead, too.
It's true.
You are a coward.
What you're saying now is only
to save your coward's face.
Now, Nora.
Maybe Frank's right.
Maybe he's right.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Hey, what's the idea, Ziggy?
Why ain't you started yet?
So what?
Huh?
What's the matter, you guys?
Didn't I take chances?
Now listen, I make the run from Cuba.
I risk my neck, my boat and the shipment,
and you won't come out in the rain?
Well, you listen to me. Either you
show tonight or the deal is off.
Well, I know a dozen guys who'd just break
their necks
to get their mitts on this shipment.
Look, my watch says 8:00.
I give you two hours.
You ain't here by 10:00, the deal is off.
Hello?
Hey!
Oh!
Downstairs, everybody.
Hey.
Didn't I say no drinking?
Oh, please, honey. Just one?
Bring down the shipment.
In there.
Mr. Temple.
Wait.
Is that someone calling?
There were some Indians at the door.
I sent them away.
You had no right.
Oh...
Listen to it.
"The upstairs shutters gotta be closed,"
she said.
If they ain't, the roof might come off.
Go close them.
One thing I can't stand
is a dame that's drunk.
What I mean, they turn my stomach.
No good to themselves or anybody else.
She got the shakes, see?
So she has a drink to get rid of them.
That one tastes so good
so she has another one.
First thing you know, she's stinko again.
You gave me my first drink, Johnny.
Oh, so it's all my fault now?
Everybody has their first drink,
don't they?
But everybody ain't a lush!
If I'd known you was gonna act this way,
I wouldn't have come here.
If I'd known what you're like,
you wouldn't have been asked.
Eight years since I seen her.
You wouldn't know it was the same dame.
You certainly haven't changed one bit.
Meaning what?
Nothing.
Gee, honey, you're as mean as can be.
Mean as can be.
Now what does that remind me of?
Well, don't you remember?
That was in a song. She used to sing it.
Yeah, that's right.
I gave her her first chance, took her out
of the chorus, made her a singer.
Mention that while you're at it.
Why ain't you a singing star
instead of a lush?
Gee, Johnny, I didn't mean anything.
Yeah, she could've had a future.
That's right. She had everything.
Voice, looks.
Plenty of class.
I was the rage.
Gee, honey.
Now, look, Gaye.
Why don't you give us your old song, hmm?
- You mean, right now?
- Yeah.
- I can't.
- Ah, sure you can.
Please, Johnny, don't make me.
I won't make you do anything.
Tell you what,
I got a proposition for you.
Now, you sing us your song,
you can have a drink.
Can I have the drink first?
No! The song.
Then the drink.
Without any accompaniment?
Now, look, do you want a drink
or don't you?
All right.
Well?
My gowns were gorgeous.
Always low-cut. Very décolleté.
I wore hardly any makeup.
Just some lipstick, that's all.
No lights, just a baby spot.
I wouldn't have any entrance.
They'd play the intro in the dark
and a spot would come on and there I'd be.
Well, go ahead. Sing.
Oh.
- Give me that drink now, Johnny.
- No.
- Johnny.
- No!
- But you promised.
- So what?
- You said that...
- But you were rotten.
Oh, no.
Thanks, fella.
You're welcome.
- Play a little gin?
- Okay.
- For how much?
- You name it.
Nickel a point.
Hey, old man.
How bad can it get?
I asked you a question! Did you hear me?
Well, worst storm we ever had
was back in '35.
Wind whipped up a big wave and sent it
busting right over Matecumbe Key.
Eight hundred people
were washed out to sea.
How far away was that from here?
A few miles.
Listen to it.
I'm sorry about the things
I said upstairs.
I know they aren't true.
Will you forgive me, Frank?
Of course.
He might've killed you, but that made
no difference, you had to help her.
Your head said one way,
but your whole life said another.
The other things, maybe they're true.
Maybe it is a rotten world.
But a cause isn't lost as long as
someone's is willing to go on fighting.
Well, I'm not that someone.
But you are.
You may not want to be,
but you can't help yourself.
Your whole life's against you.
What do you know about my life?
A whole lot.
From the way you look and talk,
and from things George wrote me.
Most of his last letter was
all about you and him on the phone.
Only he had it the other way.
You were the one on the hill.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Why is everybody so quiet?
Come on, talk, why don't you?
Well?
You, Curly, say something.
- What do you want me to say?
- Oh, anything, just so it's talk.
- Go ahead!
- I'm trying to think.
I bet you two or three years,
we get Prohibition back.
Go on.
- This time we make it stick.
- Yeah.
I bet you two or three years,
Prohibition comes back.
Absolutely, yeah.
The trouble was, see before, I mean,
too many guys wanted to be top dog.
That was the trouble, yeah.
One mob gets to massacring another.
The papers play it up big. Big, see?
- So what happens?
- So what?
Naturally, the papers play it up big,
and the public, they get the idea
that Prohibition's no good.
That if they can get rid of it.
- Prohibition, I mean...
- I don't believe it.
Eight hundred guys getting washed
out to sea. You're a liar!
Nobody would live here
after a thing like that happened.
Would they, Curly?
I remember reading about it
in the papers at the time.
A relief train was dispatched from Miami.
The barometer was down to about 26 inches
when that train pulled into Homestead.
Engineer backed his string
of empty coaches
into the danger zone
and the hurricane hit.
Knocked those coaches right off the track.
200 miles an hour, that wind blew.
A tidal wave, 12 feet high
went right across the Key.
Whole towns were wiped out.
Miles and miles of track
were ripped up and washed away.
Nothing was left.
More than 500 bodies were
recovered after the storm.
And for months afterwards,
corpses were found in the mangrove swamps.
You don't like it, do you, Rocco?
The storm?
Show it your gun, why don't you?
If it doesn't stop, shoot it.
So the public votes out Prohibition.
And that's the end of the mobs.
Next time, it'll be different, though.
We learned our lesson, all right.
Next time, the mobs'll get together.
Make a big wave.
Send it crashing down on us.
Destroy us all, if need be.
But punish him.
Oh, shut up, old man!
I'm warning you, shut up!
Hear me. Hear me.
- I'll kill you!
- Rocco!
Make a big wave.
Send it against us. Take us all.
But destroy him.
Rocco.
Mr. Temple!
The storm's passing.
A torn shutter or two,
some trash on the beach.
In a few hours, there'll be little
to remind you of what happened tonight.
Will we ever see you again, Frank?
Yeah, the storm.
It's passing.
- Will we?
- I hope so.
Why don't you stay right on
here with us, Frank?
You're most welcome.
Go on, tell him, Nora.
If he decides to stay here with us,
we'd be most happy.
Go on, tell Frank.
Have you any folks?
No.
I'd be proud to have you
regard us as your family.
Maybe that isn't what Frank wants.
Oh, I don't mean to set onto you, son.
Think it over.
Don't give your answer right away.
Hey, boss! Hey, hey, boss!
- What's the matter?
- The boat's gone!
What?
He did it.
I told him I'd kill him,
but he did it just the same.
Maybe he'll come back
now the storm's over.
- No.
- Why not?
Because he believed me
when I told him I'd kill him.
Well, what are we gonna do?
- We can't stay here!
- Can we?
Hey, boss?
Your mistake, sister.
- We're not in any trouble.
- Got something?
There's another boat out there.
It ain't much, but it'll get us to Cuba.
Who's going to run it?
Him.
Mr. Temple! You not good man!
You not let nobody in! That's no good!
Tom Osceola.
- Tom, Tom...
- Oh, shut up!
You leave women and baby out here
in storm? That no good!
You no more friend, my brother and me.
We no do like you say anymore!
No go Ben Wade!
You no good friend to Indian!
Tom, Tom!
You told me you sent them away.
You lied to me.
They were outside
my door during the whole storm.
- So what?
- Well, they might've died out there.
And who cares?
You filth.
What he said, you can run a boat.
That's a fact, huh?
His first sweetheart was a boat.
You're taking us to Cuba.
Why should I?
Because you know
what'll happen to you if you don't.
I won't take you.
You mean, you'd rather die than take us?
- I didn't say that.
- Hmm?
You won't kill me because I'm your
only chance of getting away from here.
There's other ways of getting at you.
Right, Toots?
Right.
- Maybe I'm up to them.
- Oh, no, you wouldn't be.
After a few minutes of Toots, here, you'll
begin to ask yourself questions like,
"What if I come out of this a cripple?"
And uh, "Do I care whether they make
their getaway or don't?"
All your answers would be right ones.
- I'm not so sure.
- I am.
Of course, if you're anxious
and want to find out
just how good you are at taking it,
we'll accommodate you.
But let me warn you.
Toots hasn't had much practice.
Kind of rusty. Might slip.
And that'd be too bad.
Because you made real sense
upstairs when you said that, uh,
"One Rocco more or less
ain't worth dying for."
Ziggy!
Yeah.
Mr. Temple!
The law.
One wrong word out of anybody
and he gets it the same as Sawyer did.
Temple!
Understand me, old man?
Now, you, sister, let him in.
Hey, Temple!
Good evening, Ms. Temple.
I'm looking for Sawyer. Is he here?
No.
Has he been here?
That's funny. He put a call into me
from here about 7:00.
- Did he?
- Yeah.
- Good evening, Temple. Folks.
- Ben.
- Pretty good blow, huh?
- Yeah.
Did some damage, I see.
Power lines are down
in a couple of places.
- How's the road?
- Passable.
I'm trying to locate Sawyer.
Seen him, anybody?
Have you seen Sawyer?
No.
Well, he was here, I know
because he called me from here.
About 7:00.
I called back a few minutes later.
Somebody answered. Was it one of you?
I did.
Oh, you?
I just come down from upstairs
when you called.
There was nobody around, so I answered.
Probably he stopped in to make his call.
Then he went on and got caught
in the storm.
He's stalled someplace along the road
right now, probably.
Well, he ain't between here
and Palm Grove.
And he wouldn't have called me
unless it was something special.
Seen anything of the Osceola brothers?
- Have you?
- No.
I figured that was what was all about.
His call, I mean.
The Osceola brothers.
Couple of Indians busted out of jail,
and we're looking for them.
Oh.
I'll take a run down Matecumbe Way.
If Sawyer shows up, tell him to wait.
I'll be back.
See you later.
First visit to the Keys, Mr...
- Brown.
- Yeah.
Late in the season for a storm like this.
They usually hit the early part
of the summer.
Oh, is that so?
- Been doing any fishing?
- Yeah.
Well, there's no better fishing
anywhere than on the Keys.
See you later.
It's him!
Sawyer!
He's murdered!
Well, look, I didn't wanna say anything.
After all, it's not my business.
But those Indians you were
talking about, they were here.
The Osceolas?
Yeah, they were here all during the storm.
They left only a couple of minutes ago.
Stop!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Watch yourselves. Stay in line.
He's dead.
Your Indians murdered Sawyer.
You lied to me, Temple.
You said you hadn't seen the Osceolas.
You lied, didn't you?
I knew Sawyer had been here.
That's why he called me.
Because he'd found the Osceolas.
They thought they could hide it
by sinking his body,
but they couldn't. The storm tore
his body loose and threw it up.
Right at your door.
And that's where the crime belongs,
at your door.
You probably knew they killed Sawyer.
I wouldn't put it past you!
And I'm gonna lay charges
naming you as accessory.
What was the shooting?
The Osceolas, they tried to get away.
I killed them both.
Brown, what's your first name?
Howard.
Address?
Hotel Central, Milwaukee.
- How long you gonna be here?
- A week.
Haven't I seen you someplace before?
I don't think so.
You.
Hoff. Richard.
Hotel Central, Milwaukee.
We're all together.
Your full name.
Frank McCloud. No address.
What are you doing here?
Passing through.
You.
Bass. Edward Bass.
Hotel Central, Milwaukee.
We're all together.
How far to Key West?
About 100 miles.
Some hurricane.
Thought it would blow us
right out into the ocean.
Had to pull up on the road for
a couple of hours till it blew over.
That's some hurricane.
I'll be back in the morning.
Can we get something to eat?
Can we?
In there, everybody.
Hi, Ziggy!
Johnny-boy, how are you?
Well, well, well. What do you know?
You're a sight for sore eyes!
Come on in.
Hey, boys. Ziggy!
It's sure great to see you again,
Johnny pal.
Well, it sure is swell.
Hey, Rocco. You put on a little weight.
Well, now wait a minute.
Look who's talking!
Oh, look out!
- Say, guess who's here?
- Who?
Gaye!
Gaye, where are you?
Gaye Dawn? Don't tell me!
Well, I'll be...
- Say, she's as pretty as ever.
- Yeah.
Where you been all the time
Johnny was away, huh?
Around.
If I'd have known that, I'd have
tried to beat Johnny's time.
Same old Ziggy, huh?
All right, baby.
I know you fellas are in a hurry, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, uh, Curly.
Lou.
Paper has a good feel.
Lathe work's okay.
Portrait's good. No breaks in the lines.
- Serial numbers check out?
- Yeah, naturally.
Back color's okay.
High-class merchandise.
- Okay.
Hey, fella, what are you gonna do?
Don't go with them.
They'd wait till you get them
inside of Cuba, then they'd kill you.
You'd never walk off that boat.
She's right, Frank.
Tell them you'll go, or they'll hurt you.
Then when you get outside in the dark,
make a break, run. Try to get away.
It's your only chance, fella.
Frank, what are you thinking?
You were right.
Your head says one thing
and your whole life says another.
Your head always loses.
Out there in the dark,
make a break for it.
Run, fella!
Yeah, that's what my head says.
You gonna make a fight of it, Frank?
I've got to.
Not that one Rocco more or less makes
any difference in this world.
What I said upstairs still goes.
I haven't changed my tune.
It's just that I've got to.
Well, if you're a fighter,
you can't walk away from a fight.
That's the answer, I guess.
Here you are, Curly.
Well, Johnny pal.
When are you coming back again?
It won't be long now.
With you back again,
it'll be like old times, huh?
- You know something?
- Yeah?
I bet inside of two years
we have Prohibition back again.
- Only this time, it's gonna be different.
- Right.
- The mobs will be together.
- Yeah.
- No more blasting each other.
- You said it.
- So long, Johnny pal.
- So long, Ziggy.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- See you when.
Let's get started.
Bring everything down.
The soldier's stuff, too.
Oh, soldier?
Give Ralph a hand.
Coming with us?
Yes or no? I'm in a hurry.
Toots, go to work on him.
You win.
I thought you'd change your mind
the last minute.
Well, what's the damage, old man?
That ought to take care of it.
Want to come along, sister?
All right.
Okay, boys.
Give me.
Where are my things?
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
You're not coming.
Here, on this, you can
stay drunk for a month.
- Johnny, please take me with you.
- Let go.
- Get away!
- You got to, Johnny. You got to, please!
- Come on.
- I'll stop drinking. I'll do anything.
Only take me with you.
- Please, Johnny. I love you! I need you!
- Let go of me, will you?
I'll kill myself, I will! Johnny, please!
Please!
Listen, I'll be good to you,
like I was before.
I won't let you go without me!
You've got to take me with you!
- You've got to, you've got to!
- Get away from me!
Come on, soldier!
Get going, soldier.
Good luck, son.
Yeah, good luck.
Why doesn't he run?
Run, fella, run!
Will you cast off that bowline?
Stand by that stern line.
Okay, let her go.
That was his only chance.
He didn't take it.
He should've run.
The lines are dead.
How we doing?
We're right on course.
Well, keep us that way.
How you feeling, Toots?
Oh, I feel awful.
Why don't you go downstairs?
It's too hot down there.
What time is it?
A little after four.
We're not halfway there, yet.
- Johnny's sleeping?
- Yeah.
Dog, Unit, Man, Roger.
Numeral 0-2-2-4-0-0-Z.
Man, Roger, X-ray, George.
Group numerals 4-5.
Missing fishing boat Santana
is being taken to Cuba. X-ray.
Sea search of area B immediately. X-ray.
Is us they are talking about on the radio?
Oh, let them.
In a fog like this, they couldn't find
the Queen Mary.
Hey, Curly!
What time is it?
- A little after four.
- Oh.
- Say, Johnny.
- Yeah.
- I've been thinking.
- Yeah?
- About Gaye.
- What about her?
Do you think it was such a good idea
not to bring her?
- She's pretty sore.
- Oh, so she's sore.
Yeah, but she might squeal.
Just for spite.
On Ziggy, I mean.
Well?
Oh.
I get it.
There's only one Johnny.
Hey, you.
Take a look over the stern.
See if we picked up any kelp.
Oh.
I feel awful.
Toots, help!
Curly?
What's the matter?
My gun. It's gone.
Gaye.
Toots.
Ralph.
Soldier.
Hey there, soldier!
Soldier?
Curly.
- Angel, you go up.
- Huh?
Go on! Do you hear me?
I'll get killed.
You gonna go up there? Are you?
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Toots killed him, he's dead.
Then you go check.
Soldier.
Listen to me.
Angel and Curly are dead.
There's just me and you.
From now on, we'll be partners.
Everything will be 50-50.
What do you say?
Can you hear me?
What do you say? Is it a deal?
I know what you're thinking.
You get rid of me and have all
the money for yourself, is that it?
Is it?
Answer me!
I'll tell you what.
Suppose I say the money is yours.
Yeah!
Here, look!
It's yours.
All yours, soldier.
Plenty more when we get to Cuba.
Okay, soldier?
You hear me?
I'll make you rich!
Soldier!
You're not big enough to do this to Rocco.
I'll kill you!
You'll never bring me in. Never!
Look, soldier, I know what it is.
You figure I got a gun,
so you can't trust me. Right?
Okay.
Look!
See?
I'm leveling with you.
Okay, soldier?
I'm coming out.
I got no gun and I'm coming out.
Soldier!
Mayday. Mayday.
Mayday.
Calling Nan, Mike, Abel.
This is Abel, Sugar, Abel, Nan.
Abel, Sugar, Abel, Nan.
Calling Nan, Mike, Abel.
Come in, please.
This is Nan, Mike, Abel.
This is Nan, Mike, Abel. Go ahead.
This is Abel, Sugar, Abel, Nan.
The Santana.
My name is Frank McCloud.
I'm about 12 miles off
Boot Key Harbor, on my way in.
Over.
Are you all right?
Are you all right? Over.
Yes, but I need medical attention. Over.
Continue on course.
Stand by on this frequency.
I'm standing by.
Will you put me through to
the Largo Hotel?
Stand by.
State police picked up that fellow Ziggy
and his men crossing into Georgia.
You'll have to go up
and identify 'em, miss.
Mr. Temple.
I'm mighty grateful to you
for saving my life and all
but those two boys, the Osceolas.
I'd rather been killed than have
innocent blood on my hands.
Oh, I'm the one to blame.
If they hadn't trusted me,
they wouldn't have turned up here
and they'd still be alive.
It seems we can't do anything
but harm to those people
even when we go to help them.
No, Mr. Temple, it wasn't you.
It wasn't the law or anybody.
It was only Johnny Rocco.
Nobody in the whole world is safe
as long as he's alive.
We better go, miss.
Hotel Largo.
Frank.
Oh, thank God.
He's all right, Dad.
He's coming back to us.