Psagmeno.com | No1 Subs iNFO
If you must blink,
do it now.
Pay careful attention to
everything you see and hear,
no matter how unusual
it may seem.
And please be warned,
if you fidget,
if you look away,
if you forget any part
of what I tell you,
even for an instant,
then our hero
will surely perish.
His name is Kubo.
His grandfather
stole something from him.
And that really
is the least of it.
Ow!
Well, hello, Kubo.
How was it today?
It wasn't a bad crowd.
I got two pennies
and a lint ball.
This is pretty good lint.
And what have you got
planned for today?
Oh, you know, the usual.
Monsters?
Of course.
You think you can work in
a fire-breathing chicken?
The chicken again?
The chicken is funny.
A touch of comedy to balance
the whole thing out.
They're gonna be throwing money at you.
I just know it.
Uh, they'll throw something at you.
I don't know.
Okay, I'll
see what I can do.
And do you plan on finishing the
story this time, young man?
If you must blink,
do it now.
Yay!
Pay careful attention to
everything you see and hear,
no matter how unusual
it may seem.
And please be warned,
if you fidget,
if you look away,
if you forget any part
of what I tell you,
even for an instant,
then our hero
will surely perish.
Hanzo was a mighty samurai,
but he was alone.
His family taken from him,
his kingdom in ruins,
and his army destroyed
by the dreaded Moon King.
You may recall,
Hanzo was roaming
the distant Far Lands
in search of
a magical suit of armor.
The only weapon
in the whole world
that could protect him from
the power of the Moon King.
This armor was
made up of three pieces.
The first...
Oh! I know! I know!
The sword unbreakable.
The second...
The breastplate...
Impenetrable.
Impenetra-bubble!
Yeah!
And finally,
the third weapon,
the final piece
of the armor...
I know this one. Pick me!
The helmet invulnerable!
Before Hanzo
could claim the armor
and unite the pieces
to reveal their true power,
he was attacked by
the Moon King's beast.
Oh, yes!
Kill the chicken!
Rip it to pieces.
Oh, my.
Hanzo was filled with rage.
His soul tormented
by the grief of
a family stolen from him!
At last, our hero was
face-to-face with his nemesis,
the Moon King.
So, be sure to
come back tomorrow.
What? Oh, come on!
People like an ending.
Where are you going?
No, you can't...
You can't leave!
Kubo.
- Kubo.
- Yes, Mother.
I'm here.
Hungry?
And even though
he could barely see
his own hand in
front of his face,
Hanzo and his
army of loyal samurai
pressed on
through the blizzard.
And suddenly, as quickly
as it had started,
the storm cleared
before him.
Hanzo breathed a sigh of
relief, for he was home.
His fortress?
The Beetle Clan castle!
Yes.
At the very edge
of the Far Lands,
hidden from the Moon King
by powerful magic.
And then what happened,
when he got to the castle?
When who got
to the castle?
Hanzo! My father!
Hanzo”.
Hanzo was at the castle?
He...
Just give me
a second. I'm...
No.
It's gone. I can't...
I'm sorry, Kubo.
Perhaps I could recall
a different story.
Mother, what was
Father like?
Oh.
This one is easy.
Hanzo was a mighty warrior,
skilled with sword and bow.
No, what was he
really like?
When he wasn't fighting,
when he was with us.
He was just like you.
Like me?
Yes.
Strong, and clever,
and funny,
and, oh, so handsome.
Ugh. Mother.
Come on!
Never forget how much
he loved you, Kubo.
He died protecting us.
Did the Moon King...
Uh.
Your grandfather.
Did Grandfather and your
sisters really kill my father?
It can't be true, can it?
They're family.
No, they are monsters.
Grandfather and my sisters
stole your eye, Kubo.
They must never
find you again. Never!
You must always stay hidden
from the night sky,
or they will find you
and they'll take
you away from me.
Promise me you will
never let this happen.
Promise me, Kubo!
Don't be sad, Kubo.
Kubo?
Remember what you must do,
Remember?
Keep you with me
at all times, Mr. Monkey.
And?
And keep Father's robe
on my back at all times.
Yes, Kubo.
And there's
one more thing.
Never, ever
stay out after dark.
Huh?
Remember?
Yes, Mr. Monkey.
Good boy.
Bedtime.
Mother, wake up.
You're dreaming.
No. Kubo.
Kubo, is that you?
Yes, Mother. I'm here.
Kubo, what happened
to your eye?
Paper boy!
Here, here!
Come on. Come on.
Come sit next to me.
I got us a good spot here.
What do you think?
I got myself all spruced
up for the big day.
Mmm.
I do so love the festival.
A time to celebrate.
You know, it's a shame
you never stay past sundown.
There's fireworks,
and singing, and dancing,
and feasting, of course.
But the best part of all...
Do you see those
lamps and altars?
We use those to speak to the
loved ones that left us behind.
We listen to their tales,
and guide their safe return
to the blissful pure land.
Really?
Did you speak to someone?
Yes, I did. My husband.
His voice was
as clear and loud
as the one you use
for your stories.
In 72 years, he never
had a thing to say.
Now he's gone,
I can't shut him up.
You have someone
you wanna talk to, huh?
Very much.
Well,
what's stopping you?
Don't I need a lamp?
Well, I'll bet you could
make a really nice one
with that paper
folding thing you do.
You see,
not just a pretty face, huh?
Now, hurry along.
Go! There's still
time before dark.
Go! Get out of here.
Place the lamp
at the altar.
Very good.
What do we
do next, Daddy?
Now we pray.
We ask her spirit
to honor us with its light.
Grandma, will you
please honor...
Shh.
Softly, softly.
Hello, Father.
I hope you're well.
I mean, I know you're dead,
but I hope
everything is okay.
Look, it's your robe.
Mother says
I'll grow into it.
She says you were
a great leader
who died protecting me.
Saving one of my eyes.
Two would have been ideal,
but thanks anyway.
Father, I'm worried
about Mother.
With every day that goes by,
she drifts further away.
She talks a lot
about you, but...
But I just don't know.
I don't think she remembers
what's real anymore.
I don't know
I just wish you were here,
so I could talk
to you, see you,
find out what I should do.
Daddy, Daddy, she's here!
Grandma is here!
Now it's time
for the final part.
We have to help her
get back to the spirit world.
But she just got here.
Come on.
Father? Hello?
Anytime.
Fine!
I don't need you anyway.
Kubo.
I'm sorry.
Little boy.
What happened to your eye?
Who are you?
How do you know my name?
We are your family, Kubo.
Your mother's sisters.
And we've been looking
for you for so long.
It's so lovely
to meet you, Kubo.
Face-to-face.
Come, Kubo.
Come to your aunties.
No reason to be afraid, Kubo.
We just need
your other eye.
Your grandfather
admires it so.
Help! Help!
Somebody help!
Help! Look out!
Run!
We're here, Kubo.
Your family has
come for you.
Kubo.
Mother.
Kubo, you must find the armor.
It's your only chance.
Remember this.
Mother! Mother! No!
Mother!
Kubo.
Kubo!
Can you hear me, Kubo?
I said your mother
is gone.
Your village is destroyed.
Burned to the ground.
We landed here
in the Far Lands.
Your enemies
aren't far behind.
We must search for shelter
before your grandfather comes.
We need to go now.
Come on,
get up, let's go.
Once we're inside,
you might be tempted
to complain about the odor.
Keep in mind
my sense of smell
is 10 times
stronger than yours.
You have questions,
I can tell.
Who...
You get three.
I think I have more.
Three, but first
you're gonna eat.
Why only three?
Okay, that was your first question.
What?
I don't understand
what's happening!
Who are you?
You don't recognize me?
All these years, you had
to keep me in your pack.
Well, now you know why.
But you were a wooden charm.
You were this big.
I called that charm
"Mr. Monkey."
And if I were
alive at that point,
I might have
found that insulting.
Look, your mother used the
last of her magic to save you
and bring me to life.
Here. Drink.
It smells.
Everything in here smells.
Drink it.
I don't want it.
I said drink it.
You're a mean monkey,
aren't you?
Yes. Yes, I am.
And that's three.
You're out of questions now,
so just listen.
I'm here
to protect you, Kubo.
And that means
you have to do as I say.
So, if you don't eat,
you'll be weak.
If you're weak,
you'll be slow.
If you're slow, you'll die.
It's too hot!
Drink.
Oh, excuse me.
Okay, you better start
taking this seriously, Kubo.
This is real.
This is not a story.
Those things, your aunts,
they never get hungry.
They never sleep.
They will find you!
And if we're not prepared,
they'll kill me
and take your other eye.
What are we gonna do?
We're going to
find the armor.
It's the only thing
that can protect you.
So it's real. Really real.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to keep it.
I pulled that
from her head.
I didn't mean to.
Your mother
was very powerful.
She blessed your robes
so that when the need was most,
they would fly you away.
She used the last of that
power to bring me to life.
This bracelet,
her hair, it's a memory.
And memories are
powerful things, Kubo.
Never lose it.
One more question?
Last one.
Do you know where it is?
The armor?
No. No, I don't.
Now, go to sleep.
Goodnight, Monkey.
Kubo.
You were
talking in your sleep.
You were dreaming,
calling out to your father,
and then the paper flew out of
your bag and folded itself into
him.
He's been standing there for
hours, quietly judging us.
I'm not even convinced
this counts as origami.
I could swear
scissors were involved.
Ow.
Back home in the cave,
my mother's dreams did this,
and the paper always
unfolded itself by morning.
What's that about?
What are you doing?
I guess this is how my
father answered me. Hmm.
I'm tempted to say
that entrusting our fate
to the guidance
of a small paper man
seems like a bad idea.
But it's the best
bad idea we have.
You're growing stronger.
You might not wanna look
quite so pleased about that.
We grow stronger, the world
grows more dangerous.
Life has a funny way
of keeping things balanced.
Monkey, do you ever say
anything encouraging?
I encourage you not to die.
"I encourage you not to die."
Mosquitoes. Annoying.
Wasn't me, I swear.
Paper runs out,
as does patience.
I didn't ask them
to do that.
The second time.
I didn't!
At least, not exactly.
I mean, I felt it, but...
Magic is not
meant to be easy.
You need to
learn control.
Concentrate on what you're
doing, and always remember,
don't mess with the monkey.
Tread carefully, Kubo. This
isn't one of your stories.
How do you know?
Maybe it is.
And I'm the valiant hero
and you're the mean monkey.
Heroes come and go.
Any moment, something terrible
could come out of nowhere and...
Monkey!
Kubo!
Monkey, wait.
He wasn't trying to hurt me.
He just wanted...
Hanzo.
Hanzo?
I still think
I'm gonna stab him.
Why must you always
assume the worst?
Oh! Oh! Pardon me for not trusting
this giant, spiky, insect-monster
that just kidnapped you.
Hanzo. Yes,
I remember him.
I think, maybe,
he was my master.
What?
What did you say?
We had a crest.
A samurai crest.
Have you seen
this crest before?
This is a miracle.
You have our robes.
You're wearing our robes!
Why are you
wearing our robes?
He doesn't have to
answer your questions.
Anyway, who are you?
Many years ago,
I was cursed.
Trapped in this
cursed state.
Cursed to wander
the Far Lands.
Cursed or curs-ed.
No comrades, no master.
Not even a name
or a single memory
of the noble warrior
I once was.
You used to be a man?
No, not just any man.
A samurai.
I mean,
I'm pretty certain.
Look, I had the stuff.
I mean, I'm either a samurai
or a really bad hoarder.
Either way, inside my thorax
beats the heart of a warrior.
If you have no memory, how can
you be certain of anything?
Because I get flashes.
They come about from objects
I find on my travels.
Sometimes it's a sound.
Or a smell.
You must get
a lot of flashes.
The memories, they fade.
And all I'm left with
is the sense that I was
once part of
something much greater.
Monkey, can I tell him?
I really don't think
that's a good idea.
He has a right.
Absolutely not.
But... I...
No "buts." No!
What? Tell me what?
Hanzo was my father.
Kubo!
This is a miracle.
I have found
the son of my master.
Don't even.
Oh.
Whatever brings you to these
lands, whatever your quest,
it is now my quest, too.
I will join you, and I will give
my life for you, if necessary.
Wow. You will?
What? Do you think
that's possible?
Look, kid, I mean, I know how these
quests go. People die all the time.
They drop like flies.
That doesn't matter.
'Cause I have a feeling
this is my destiny.
No, it isn't!
We can't trust
anything you say,
because you can't
trust anything you say.
We don't know anything about you.
Monkey,
you said it yourself.
Our quest
is a difficult one.
A samurai, even a cursed one with
no memory, that looks like a bug,
could be helpful.
Yes, I am certain
I could be helpful.
Indispensable.
In what way?
Firing an arrow into a wall
is hardly what I call...
Impressive.
Oh, look at that.
Literally, the first
time I've ever done it.
Just tell me of our quest,
and I will quickly demonstrate
my numerous indispensabilities.
Well, that's kind of
a long story.
You've got my attention.
I promise I won't even blink.
I actually don't think
I even can blink.
- Do I have eyelids?
- Fine.
Walk and talk.
Hanzo has found a path.
So, you used
to be a toy monkey.
Kubo, I really don't see how
this part is important to our story.
I kept her in my pocket. She was only
like this big.
Okay, Kubo, that's enough. Tiny.
And she was called
"Mr. Monkey."
I wasn't a toy.
I was a charm.
Of course you were.
That doesn't look good.
Don't touch anything.
He did it.
Okay.
No. No. No.
Yes.
Kubo, look.
The sword unbreakable.
It could be a trap.
Allow me.
What, it's not a trap
if you do it?
Stealth is my middle name.
You don't even
have a first name.
Don't worry. I got this.
The mighty
Beetle is victorious!
I don't got this.
I don't got this!
Oh, for crying out loud!
I invoke
the sword unbreakable!
It broke.
So, does it just
mean the handle or...
I'm a little disappointed
with this magic sword.
It's not the right sword,
you idiot!
Look!
The sword!
It's in his head.
Hey! I've got
a bone to pick with you.
See, because
he's made of bones.
You're an embarrassment.
Uh...
This is problematic.
Enough with the arrows!
Oh, foot!
You can fly?
Apparently, yes!
Are you sure it isn't
the sword unfindable?
I think I found it!
A hand here. Anyone?
Anyone else?
Kubo!
Monkey!
Whoa!
No!
Kubo!
Huh.
Yes!
Thank goodness that's over.
Everything turning black.
Then open your eyes.
Oh.
I can't feel my wings.
You didn't even know you
had them five minutes ago.
Stop wriggling.
Here.
Is that feeling better?
Oh, yeah.
A little to the left.
Down, just a bit.
Right there. That's good.
Wait, you're being
nice to me.
Shh. Don't tell anyone.
We did it, Beetle.
We got the sword.
Whoa. Put that down,
it's sharp!
Ooh. Mmm.
Okay, we're done here.
Get up.
We have a lot
of walking to do.
You can't be serious.
I'm always serious.
Are you two going
to fight, again?
Of course not. We're having
a grown-up conversation.
You're going to
fight again.
Kubo, just go over there
and play with something.
Not that!
Monkey, this is
the Long Lake.
We can't walk around it.
We need to swim across.
I can carry Kubo.
"Carry Kubo."
That's your better idea?
Look, I appreciate
your help. I really do.
But when it comes
to the boy,
I know what's best.
Oh, is that right?
And what's best is not to be fielding
ideas from a talking cockroach.
This coming from
a talking monkey.
I can still
hear you, you know.
Then play louder.
This conversation is over. Monkeys
don't swim.
- Not to worry. Monkey see, monkey do.
- Oh.
How long have you
been waiting to say that?
Ever since
I met you.
Hey, what were we grown-up
conversation-ing about? Oh!
You're ridiculous. You're
just absolutely ridiculous.
Ridiculous!
Crossing the lake
is a ridiculous idea.
It's not your fault. There's
no sense left in your head.
I think I resent that.
I may not know everything...
Anything.
But I do know Kubo is more
capable than you think he is.
You're being a tiny
bit overprotective here.
I'm being a lot
overprotective here.
It's my job to make sure Kubo
is safe, and that is not safe.
You... You are not safe.
Kubo is just a child.
And an incredibly gifted one.
He just saved our lives.
Yes, he's very powerful, but
he still has much to learn!
What?
Well,
fast learner.
Did you know
you could do that?
Show off.
Okay, now take
a deep breath.
Clear your mind.
Guess I got that part covered.
Now, draw back slowly.
That's it.
Close one eye. Guess you
got that part covered.
Concentrate on what is
directly in front of you.
Let everything else
fall away.
And release!
Yeah!
Perfect shot!
Not bad.
And what's your plan for getting
the fish into the boat,
so we can actually eat it?
Well, I said I was teaching
him how to shoot, not fish.
Fishing is
tomorrow's lesson.
Give me that.
Whoa.
Grabby monkey.
Now try it.
Pull back and...
Whoo-hoo!
A rope.
It's a pretty good idea.
Hmm. And you're not
an awful shot.
Okay, now you two
are being weird.
Um...
We're going to need
something to cut this with.
Sword unbreakable.
Must you play
with your food?
Yes.
What's the matter, Kubo?
You act like you've
never had a meal
sitting between a monkey
and a beetle before.
I've never had a meal sitting
between anyone before.
Come on, eat.
You need energy.
And this is much better
than whale soup.
Kubo, question.
Before you started on your heroic
quest, what were you like?
Well, I looked
after my mother mostly.
And I told stories
about mighty
warriors seeking revenge
with battles, and
monsters, and magic.
I was pretty good
at telling them.
Not so good
at ending them.
Sometimes I would tell my mother
stories about little things.
Like skimming
rocks across the river
or catching fireflies
in the mulberry fields.
And when I told
those stories,
I could see her eyes
were mostly clear.
I could tell she saw me.
Really saw me.
I could see her, too.
Her real self.
Her spirit trying
to fight its way out.
It was beautiful.
You know something, Kubo?
Back when you
just told stories,
before you went on
this great adventure,
you were still
very much a hero.
We're gonna have
to head for shore.
Find a hiding place and...
The second piece
of armor.
The breastplate.
It's down there?
Okay, I got it.
Beetle, wait!
No, don't worry.
Beetles can hold their breath
under water for a very long time.
What? Since when?
It's a well-known fact,
Monkey.
So, you don't remember anything
at all, but beetles swimming?
That's what
sticks in there?
No, Beetle.
My mother told me
a story about the Long Lake.
There's something
under the water.
Oh, yeah?
Um...
What kind of something?
She said there was
a garden of eyes,
eyes that stare into you,
into your soul.
They show you secrets, things to
keep you down there with them.
Forever.
Okay.
Well, I won't look
directly into anyone's eyes,
even if I'm being
incredibly sincere.
You're gonna miss me, Monkey.
Be careful.
He's searching for the armor
just like his insolent father.
Yes, sister.
Then we must ensure he does
not find what remains.
Monkey,
I think he's in trouble!
We should help him.
Kubo, your aunts are still out there.
I'm sorry.
But we have to head for shore.
Kubo!
Kubo.
Look at this.
I come fishing and all I
reel in is a stinking ape.
How pathetic that
this filthy creature
is all that's left
of my sister's magic.
This filthy creature
will tear you apart!
Kubo.
Kubo?
I have crushed creatures who could
fit this world on their fingernail.
This victory
brings me no honor.
Imagine how you're going
to feel when you lose.
I felt loss only once.
Eleven years ago,
I lost my sister.
She fell in love with a fool
and betrayed our father!
She was an
ungrateful coward!
Who's the coward now?
I got it! I got it!
Beetle, what happened?
Where's Kubo?
Um...
Uh-oh.
Get back down there!
He's in trouble!
I got it.
Mother. Mother.
Mother.
It never fails to amaze me
how the creatures down here fight
so hard just to die another day.
Down here, there are
days worth fighting for.
There is nothing down
here worth anything!
It's pathetic what
happened to my sister.
I looked up to her.
She was so strong.
And love made her weak.
No!
It made me stronger.
Over here.
The eyes...
It was the eyes.
They had him in a trance.
Oh, no.
No.
Come on. Come on, Kubo.
Wake up. Please wake up!
Please, please wake up.
It's gonna be all right.
I'm here.
I'm right here.
I saw...
What? What did you see?
Mother.
My son.
So, you must look
more like your dad, then?
You're staring.
Let me guess.
You have questions.
Why...
I'll start.
First question. If I'm
Beetle and you're Monkey,
why isn't he called "Boy"?
Oh, boy.
Questions can wait.
We need sleep.
Tell us your story,
then we can sleep.
Please?
Okay.
Perhaps you can help me.
The night I met
your father...
Mother.
My sisters and I went to the
Temple of Bones to kill Hanzo.
Oh, right.
At the bidding
of the Moon King,
my sisters and I had come
down from the night sky
and killed many
noble warriors.
Your grandfather told us
that any man who
found the magical armor
would grow too powerful
and be a threat
to the heavens.
That night, I arrived at
the temple before my sisters.
And there he was,
the mighty Hanzo.
"You have offended
my father," I told him.
"Now you must die."
Yeah, that's so you.
Beetle. Shh!
We fought.
Hanzo was strong.
But then he stopped.
He looked into my eyes and
uttered four simple words.
These words
changed everything.
"I love you,
"Monkey"?
"You are my quest,"
he whispered.
I had seen the wonders
of the universe,
but the warmth of his gaze
as I looked into his eyes...
That...
That I had never known.
It was his humanity I saw.
And it was more powerful
than anything
in my cold realm.
In recognizing
his compassion,
I recognized my own.
I spared his life.
He gave me mine.
And...
And then he gave me you.
But your grandfather
found us.
His rage at my betrayal
shook the heavens.
Your father and his army
gave their lives,
allowing me to escape
with you in my arms.
Why does Grandfather
hate me?
Oh, Kubo...
He doesn't hate you.
He wants to make
you just like him.
Blind to humanity,
as I once was.
Only then can you take
your place beside him
as part of his family.
Cold and hard.
And perfect.
I'll never be like him,
never.
I know.
He's exhausted.
Mmm.
Me, too.
I'm not tucking you in.
You're hurt.
It's just a scratch.
Monkey, why didn't you tell him
sooner who you really are?
The magic that keeps
me here, it's fading.
Soon I'll be gone.
And then Kubo
will be alone again.
Not alone.
He is the son of Hanzo.
I will do everything I can
to keep him from harm.
Thank you, Beetle.
To know Kubo has someone to
watch over him when I'm gone.
That would be a fine way
to end my story.
Your story will never end.
It will be told by him and by
the people he shares it with.
And by the people
they share it with.
they share it with,
and by the people
they share it with.
And by the people...
Beetle.
The point is
your story will live on
in him.
Hello, my young friend.
Why don't you
join in my song?
But how did you...
You're...
Even blinder than you?
Twice as much,
to be precise.
Which means I see
double the truth.
This is all a dream.
Is this a good dream
or a bad one?
See for yourself.
My father's fortress.
Yes.
The last piece
of the armor.
It's here?
Follow the setting sun
and you'll find it,
in the place that
might have been your home.
Claim your birthright, Kubo.
Give this story
a happy ending.
Mother! Beetle! Wake up!
I'm up. I'm up.
Well, I'm down.
Off.
I think I slept
on something.
Sword uncomfortable.
The helmet,
I know where it is.
I saw it in a dream, Beetle.
A dream?
Well, it doesn't mean
anything in particular.
I mean, I dreamed I fought a giant
skeleton with swords in its head.
That really happened.
Oh, yeah.
Beetle.
Come on, this way.
I spy with my one eye
something beginning with "S".
Snow?
No.
Snowflake?
Okay.
Oh. Pfft.
Snow covered trees.
Nothing to do with snow.
How about "serious"?
Stupid.
Okay, I got it.
Snow.
He said it wasn't "snow."
It's a song.
Well, that's not fair.
How do you see a song?
You look.
Golden heron.
It's believed they hold the
souls of the departed,
carrying them over
to wherever they need to go.
Hmm.
What are they singing?
It's beautiful.
Many say the song's about
what happens when we die.
How we don't
just disappear.
We don't?
Uh, so, what happens to us?
Well, like Kubo's paper,
we shift.
We transform so we can
continue our story
to another place.
The end of one story is merely
the beginning of another.
I remember this place.
This was where my father
prepared for his quest.
There's something
I don't understand.
Why would the helmet
be here?
Kubo!
Release us!
Oh, sister.
I remember how we
looked up to you.
Of all of us,
you shone the brightest.
Such a waste.
All we ever wished was to be a
family in our home among the stars.
I think we have very different
definitions of family.
Don't you touch him,
you witch!
And then there's you,
the thieving insect
who stole my sister's soul.
What?
Oh, this is precious.
You've been
together all this time
and you haven't
even realized?
You took her from us.
It was only fitting
we took something from you.
How swiftly those memories
spilled from your head,
wiping out all recollection
of your obscene union.
Hanzo.
What?
Hanzo?
I... I didn't know.
No!
I'm forgetting
what I came here for.
Mother!
Shh. It's okay. I'm here.
Father?
My son.
Seems I'm married to a bug.
Yeah.
But a samurai bug.
You are my quest.
You always have been.
Hanzo, keep him safe,
no matter what.
I promise I will.
No!
Fly home, Kubo.
Kubo? Is that you?
You have to
leave this place.
The Moon King, he's coming.
Grandfather!
It's me, Kubo!
I know you can see me!
Hello, grandson.
It's so good to
see you at last.
Soto speak.
And I see you found
the armor.
Seems your mother
had a reason
to bring you to this
dreadful place after all.
I see.
I know you do.
That's how this all began.
You finally saw me.
It was my fault. I should've
listened to my parents.
Kubo, we both want
the exact same thing.
You want to take my other eye.
That's what you want!
Well, yes. But do you
know why I want it?
Because you're old,
and mean, and cruel.
Oh, now,
that's a little harsh.
As long as you cling
to that silly, useless eye,
you can't come up
to live with me.
In the heavens.
You'll be stuck
down here in this hell,
staring with that lonely eye
at hate and heartache
and suffering and death.
Where I want to
take you,
we have none
of those things.
It'll just be you
with your family.
Where you belong.
My family is gone.
You killed them.
No...
They brought their
fates upon themselves!
They disgraced me and upset
the order of everything!
That's how
your story goes.
Oh, Kubo...
When you're up there with me,
you will be beyond stories.
You will be immortal.
You will be
infinite.
No. You're wrong,
not infinite.
All stories have an end.
Is that right?
And how does
this story end?
I kill you.
Oh.
Very well.
Is this your wish,
to do battle with a hideous
monster who ruined your life,
to prove your worth
like your doomed father?
How mortal.
You want to be human?
Then share their weakness!
Suffer their humiliation!
Feel their pain!
This is the end
of your story.
Now, take one last
look with that lonely eye,
one last look at this
wretched place you call home.
I'm not leaving.
For every horrible thing
down here,
there's something
far more beautiful.
My mother saw it.
So did my father. I see it.
Even with just one eye.
Then I'll just have to rip
it out of your head again,
won't I?
If you must blink,
do it now.
I know why
you want my eye.
Because without it,
I can't look into the eyes of
another and see their soul.
Their love...
Everything you loved is gone!
Everything you knew
has been taken from you!
No.
It's in my memories.
The most powerful
kind of magic there is.
It makes us stronger
than you'll ever be.
These are the memories of
those we have loved and lost.
And if we hold their stories
deep in our hearts,
then you will never
take them away from us.
And that really
is the least of it.
Where am I?
Hello, Grandfather.
Oh, hello.
What happened to your eye?
Don't you remember?
No, I... I'm sorry,
young man.
But I seem to have
forgotten my story.
Can you help me?
I'll tell him.
No, we'll all tell him.
We'll tell him
everything he needs to know.
You are the kindest,
sweetest man
to ever live
in this village.
Oh. Oh, really?
Yes.
Uh... Uh...
Every day,
you walk around smiling
and handing out
coins to children.
Like me!
And old women.
Oh.
You... You taught
my kids to swim.
What?
And you give
blankets to the poor.
You're a good man.
You fed the hungry. You
always lend a helping hand.
You're a great
example.
It turns out
I'm pretty selfless.
That's why we love you.
You know, we have
something in common.
We both adore
your grandson.
His name is Kubo.
Kubo?
I'm sorry.
But I...
But I don't remember.
Well...
Your grandson's
a storyteller.
He'll tell you all the
stories you've forgotten.
Really?
Of course.
Hello, Mother.
Father.
I know my stories can tend
to get a little, um, long,
so I'll keep this brief.
I'm very grateful I've had
the chance to meet you both,
hear your wisdom,
feel your kindness,
even eat a meal
sitting between you.
This was a happy story.
But it could still be
a whole lot happier.
I don't know exactly
what the rules are
or how this works,
but if there
were any way to...
You know, I still need you.
So I can say this
has been a happy story,
or I could feel it.
We could all feel it.
Then we could
end this story.
Together.
The end.