Right, let's sort the buyers from the spyers,
the needy from the greedy,
and those who trust me from the ones who don't.
Because if you can't see value here today,
you're not up here shopping,
you're up here shoplifting.
You see these goods?
Never seen daylight, moonlight, Israelite
or Fanny by the gaslight.
Take a bag.
Come on, take a bag.
I took a bag home last night,
and it cost me a
lot more than £10,
I can tell you.
Anyone like jewelry?
Look at that one there.
Handmade in Italy,
hand stolen in Stepney.
It's as long as my arm.
I wish it was as long
as something else.
Don't think 'cause these boxes
are sealed up they're empty.
The only man who
sells empty boxes
is the undertaker.
And by the look of some of you lot here today,
I'd make more money
with me measuring tape.
Here, one price.
£10.
Did you say £10?
BACON: Are you deaf?
That's a bargain.
I'll take one.
Squeeze in if you can.
Left leg, right leg,
your body will follow.
They call it walking.
You want one
as well, darling?
You do. That's it,
they're waking up.
Treat the wife, treat somebody else's wife.
It's a lot more fun if you don't get caught.
Hold on, you want one as well?
Okay, darling, show me a bit of life then.
It's no good standing out there
like 1:00 half struck.
Buy them, you better buy them!
These are not stolen,
they just haven't
been paid for.
And we can't get them
again, they've changed
the bloody locks.
Here, one for you.
It's no good
coming back later
when I've sold out.
"Too late,
too late!"
will be the cry
when the man with
the bargains has
passed you by.
And if you've got no money on you now,
you'll be crying
tears as big as
October cabbages.
Bacon, cozzers.
BACON: Shit.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
ALAN: Ed can hustle
a few quid here and there,
but his real talent
lies in cards
and gambling with cards.
Bacon could see that his days of selling
moody goods on street corners are numbered.
It's time to move on and he knows it.
TOM: And I'm 6'1 ",
that's perfect for
my height, all right?
NICK: All right, you take
a photo. You're catching
up with me, you are.
Look, what are you
talking about? I'm
bloody skinny, pal.
Yeah, yeah, of
course you are.
All right?
Nick the Greek, always a pleasure.
Tom, what have you been eating?
I've been
telling him this. ..
Enough already.
You two, join me in my office.
So, how much is it then, Tom?
You know how much it is, Nick.
And that includes the amp, yeah?
No, that does not include the amp.
Shit, Tom, I thought it included the amp.
Well, it doesn't.
I'll throw in one
of these telephones
if you like,
but it does not include the amp.
Very nice.
I hope it includes the speakers.
It doesn't include the speakers,
it doesn't include the amp,
and it's not supposed to include me
getting the hump with your stupid questions.
Now you want it, Nick, you buy it.
What else do I get with it?
You get a
gold-plated
Rolls-Royce,
as long as you pay for it.
Don't know, Tom.
Seems expensive.
Seems? Well, this
seems to be a
waste of my time.
That is 900 nicker in
any shop you're lucky
enough to find one in,
and you're complaining about 200?
What school of finance did you study?
It's a deal, it's a steal.
It's the sale of the
fucking century.
In fact, fuck it, Nick, I think I'll keep it.
All right, all right, keep your Alans on.
Here's a ton.
Jesus Christ.
You could choke a
dozen donkeys on that.
And you're haggling over £100?
What do you do
when you're not buying
stereos, Nick?
Finance revolutions?
£100 is still £100.
Not when the price is £200, it's not.
And certainly not when
you got Liberia's deficit
in your sky rocket.
Tighter than a duck's
butt you are.
Now come on,
let me feel the fiber of your fabric.
ALAN: The skinny one is Tom,
and he's the entrepreneur of the bunch.
He's got a couple of dirty
little fingers in a couple
of dirty little pies.
Nick, here, however, has made it his business
to have all 20 fat little fingers and toes
in every dirty bent and stolen pie in London.
Between the two of them,
there ain't much
you can't get ahold of.
(SNIFFS)
That's my 25 grand, it's all there.
It took me a long time
to earn that, so you
treat it with respect.
What about the chef?
TOM: What have
you come as?
Cupid, stupid.
That's the last time
I'm getting any more
fruit off of you, Tom.
Do you call that fresh?
There was more small, hairy armored things
in your fruit than there was fruit.
You should open a butcher's, not a grocer's.
Well, if you will order stuff from Katmandu,
don't be surprised
if it picks up a
few tourists en route.
Anyway, enough about that.
Where's the money?
Oi!
Keep your fingers out of my soup.
ALAN: Soap is called Soap
because he likes to keep
his hands clean
of any unlawful behavior.
He's proud of his job
and even more
proud that it's legal.
He represents the more
sensible side of the four.
You sure you can afford 25?
That depends on how you look at it.
I can afford it as long as
I see it again, if that's
what you mean.
Got the rest from the fat man and Bacon?
Fat man, Bacon and myself.
Looks like it's
time to make
that call to Harry.
Who's this fat man then, eh?
Eh?
Do you want a sandwich, Bacon?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
ALAN: It's not easy
to take a seat at
this card table.
The amount of money involved
has to be 100 grand upwards,
and there's no shortage of punters.
The man who decides whether
you can play or not
is this man, Harry.
Or as some, including himself,
like to call him,
Hatchet Harry.
You got it all?
100 grand.
Well, if you got it, you got it.
Now, if you
don't mind. ..
What's this Eddie like, then?
He's a fucking thief.
ALAN: Harry has a colleague,
a monster of a man,
Barry the Baptist.
The Baptist got his
name by drowning
people for Hatchet.
Are you gonna
fucking pay?
Yeah, I'll pay!
How are you gonna
fucking pay?
I'm gonna pay it.
ALAN: Barry makes sure the
administrative side of the
business runs harmoniously.
The boy's got a rare ability.
He seems to make cards transparent.
He's got. ..
All right, all right, so we can say he's good.
Oh, no, he's better than good.
He's a fucking liability.
Here, hold on.
What do you think
of these?
We're selling hundreds.
Very nice, Harry.
What's it for?
Oh, don't play
innocent with me,
Bazza. Spanking.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
There's 25 from me, Tom, Soap and yourself.
That's 100 grand to the pound.
So why the fuck are you counting it?
Because I like to.
So, a reasonable return
should be in the
region of 120 grand.
That's for 25 grand
invested, going on
previous experience.
Going on optimism.
Whatever it's going on,
it should be enough to send
you on a cooking course.
You're not funny, Tom.
You're fat.
And look as though
you should be,
but you're not.
Fat? Who are you
calling. . . Jesus!
It's good in here, isn't it?
Handy for the tube, great electrics.
I can see why you moved in.
Don't knock it, it's cheap like the budgie.
And nobody wants
to live next to the
people we live next to.
(CHUCKLING)
A bit anti-social
to say the least.
What do you mean?
He means they're thieving bastards.
I mean, when they're
not picking peanuts
out of poop,
they rip off unfortunate
souls of their
hard-earned drugs.
Not exactly thick, these walls.
MAN: Nice work, John.
Get yourself a drink.
Is that it?
How many times do I have to tell you, Plank?
You find us a job
worth doing, you'll find
your share improving.
Now, have you got a problem with that?
(REGGAE MUSIC PLAYING)
You know, Charles,
this gear is
getting heavier.
(COUGHS)
I have a strong suspicion
we should've been
rocket scientists
or Nobel Peace Prize winners
or something.
Peace Prize?
Be lucky to find your
penis for a piss the
amount you keep smoking.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Who the hell's that?
All right, Willie?
Does it look like I'm all right?
Take this.
I'm in danger of breaking sweat at any second.
WINSTON: Charles, why
have we got that cage?
Security?
That's right.
That's right, security.
So what's the point in
having it if we're not
gonna fucking use it?
Well, I would have
used it, Winston,
but this is Willie.
And Willie lives here.
Yes, Charles, but you didn't know it was Willie
until you opened the door, did you?
Chill, Winston.
It's me.
Charlie knows
it's me.
What's the problem?
The problem is, Willie,
that Charles and
yourself are not the
quickest of cats
at the best of times.
So just do as I say
and keep the fucking cage locked!
What is that?
That's Gloria.
Yes, I know
that's Gloria.
What's that?
Fertilizer.
You went out six
hours ago to buy
a money counter,
and you come back with
a semi-conscious Gloria
and a bag of fertilizer?
Alarm bells are ringing, Willie.
We need fertilizer, Winston.
We also need a money counter.
This money's gotta be out by Thursday.
I'm buggered if I'm gonna count it.
And if you do have to buy sodding fertilizer,
could you just be a little more subtle?
What do you mean?
We grow copious amounts of ganja, yeah?
Yeah.
And you're carrying
a wasted girl and
a bag of fertilizer.
You don't look like
your average
horti-fucking-culturalist.
That's what I mean, Willie.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
How long's he been in there, Son?
About 20 minutes.
He's on his own?
Yeah, just carrying a bag.
All right, let's pay
him a little visit
then, shall we?
ALAN: Big Chris settles
debts for Harry.
The only thing he cares
more about than
an unsettled debt,
is his son and heir, Little Chris.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Shh!
This is one of them
high-powered
jobs, isn't it?
(GROANING)
Got some bad news for you, John.
What the fuck. ..
You mind your language in front of the boy.
Jesus Christ.
That includes blasphemy as well.
Now tell me, John, how can you be concentrating
and it is a lovely tan by the way,
when you've got
more pressing
priorities at hand?
Tell Harry. ..
I mean Mr. Harry,
I've been busy.
I'm nearly there.
Check his locker, Son.
JOHN: I don't suppose
there's any chance
of you lifting this
sun bed up, Chris,
is there?
He's not poor.
He's got over a monkey here,
and that's just in his wallet.
Fucking hell, John,
you always walk around with that in your pocket?
Oi!
You use language like
that again, Son, you'll
wish you hadn't.
Sorry, Dad.
Right, well, put the rest of the stuff in that.
You can go home in a plastic bag tonight, John.
You owe what you owe,
and by the time this tan's faded,
you wanna have paid.
You never would have paid.
Who would pay for shit?
Yeah, exactly.
I mean we ain't
too certain. ..
Well, what the hell are you doing here?
Why, what's up?
Let me guess.
My foot in
your arse.
Game of cards?
Hatchet Harry?
You're supposed
to be getting your
rest in, boy.
You playing cards tonight, Son?
With Harry?
Don't be silly, Dad.
I wouldn't have anything to do with that.
HARRY: Where did he
get 100 grand?
He's got some adhesive mates.
I mean they're like brothers.
They've tossed up between them.
And JD is his dad and owns the whole property?
No mortgage, no debts.
Lock, stock, the fucking lot.
Don't you worry, Harry.
I've got it under control.
Good. You can get this
under control now.
It seems that
Lord Appleton Smythe
has run out of money.
And these little beauties are up for auction.
But I'm not paying
a quarter of a
million quid for them,
if you know what I mean, Barry.
Make sure we get
everything from inside
the gun cabinet.
I don't wanna know who you use,
as long as they're not complete muppets.
And don't tell them what they're worth, Barry.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Right, where was we?
Shotguns? What,
like guns that
fire shot?
You must be the brains, then.
That's right, guns that fire shots.
Make sure you bring
everything from inside
the gun cabinet.
There'll be a load
of old guns.
That's all I want.
Everything else outside the cabinet,
you can keep.
It's yours.
Thank you very much.
There'd better be something there for us.
It's a fucking stately home.
Of course there'll be something there.
DEAN: Like what?
Like fucking antiques.
Antiques?
What the fuck do we
know about antiques?
We rob
post offices.
And steal cars.
What the fuck do we know about antiques, mate?
If it looks old,
it's worth money.
Simple.
So stop fucking moaning and rob the place.
So who's the guv?
Who are we
doing this for?
You're doing it for me, is all you need to know.
You know because you need to know.
I see.
One of those
on-a-need-to-know-basis
things, is it?
Like one of those James Bond films.
Careful, remember who's giving you this job.
Right, I'm off.
Call me when
you're done.
Ta-ta.
Fucking Northern monkeys!
I hate these fucking Southern fairies.
ALAN: Ed has been
playing cards since
he could lift them up,
and he soon discovered
that he had
a big advantage.
It's not that he's good
with cards or even
good at counting them.
It's that he's good with
reading people's reactions,
no matter how subtle.
And everybody has reactions,
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
especially when
it comes to money.
Invitations.
Invitations?
Yeah, invitations.
You know, four pretty
white pieces of paper
with your names on them?
Well, we've got 100,000 bits of paper
with the Queen's head on them.
Will that do?
All right, just you.
The others, they can
wait next door
in Samoan Jo's.
Samoan Jo's?
You mean the pub?
Hold on. ..
Hold on to your
fucking tongue,
and I will hold onto my patience, okay, sonny?
No one in here tonight
but card players,
and I do mean no one.
Evening, Frazer.
Don, Phil.
It's a bit dramatic, isn't it?
Is this supposed to be symbolic?
Apparently, it's for security.
Yeah? I'd have
brought me gloves
if I'd have known.
You must be Eddie, JD's son.
You must be Harry.
Sorry, didn't know your father.
Never mind, son.
You just might meet
him if you carry
on like that.
Evening, Tanya, been a while.
All right, Ed?
(SCREAMING)
Right, we call each other Kenny, okay, Gary?
All right, Kenny.
You gonna put your stocking on, or what?
I've just spent 220 quid on me hair.
If you think I'm pulling a stocking over it,
you're very much mistaken.
You're gonna have to put something on.
This is three card brag, gentlemen.
That means three three's are the highest,
then three aces, then running down accordingly.
Then it's a running
flush, a run, a flush
and then a pair.
An open man can't see a blind man,
and it will cost you
twice the ante to
see your opponent.
Now don't fuck around,
fellas. You all know
the rules,
and you know I won't stand for it.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(SOFTLY) What are you doing?
Put that back.
We're here to rob the guns.
Put it back.
It's crap anyway.
Come on.
Come in.
(CHATTERING ON TV)
What sort of pub is this, then?
It's a Samoan pub.
What's that?
It's a cocktail.
You asked for
a cocktail.
No, I asked you to give me a refreshing drink.
I wasn't expecting a fucking rain forest.
You could fall
in love with an
orangutan in that.
You want a pint, go to the pub.
I thought this was a pub.
It's a Samoan pub.
Well, whatever it is,
can you get your man
to turn the TV down?
You can ask him if you like.
If I was you, I'd leave
him well alone.
Here, get rid
of that. Bring
us a Diet Coke.
Excuse me, can you turn that TV down?
No.
(ALL WHOOPING)
(GROANING)
DEAN:
Whoa, whoa, Kenny!
What are you doing?
I am trying to find
out where they keep
their money!
You twat, can't you
see these people
have got no money?
They can't even afford new furniture.
We've got the guns.
What's the matter
with you?
Every time we do a job,
you have to go
burning people's feet.
What's wrong with you?
You wanna be more careful, old fella.
You very nearly took
my man's head
clean off with that.
You all right, Kenny?
Kenny?
10 grand, blind.
20 grand, open.
Deep end, eh?
Fold.
BARRY: Gotcha.
20 grand, open.
I'll fold.
Don't go spending that all at once, boy.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, bloody hell.
What?
I thought you said there'd be no staff, Barry.
Did you get those guns?
You wanna see what they did to poor Gary?
Gary. Gary.
I said, did you get those guns?
Yes! We got them!
Good. I'll speak
to you later.
Gary, if you can hear
me, get back in the car
now, mate, okay?
Barry. Barry.
Fucking Southern
shandy-drinking
bastard ! Gary!
(ROCK AND ROLL MUSIC PLAYING)
Give me my money!
Give me back my money, you fucking snake!
You give me my money!
Give me back
my money!
Give it back!
Wankers!
Come on, you.
Not now, please.
Not now.
Oh, you fucking bastard.
(EXCLAIMING)
You bastard.
Oh, my good God.
We'll take you to the cleaners.
20 grand, open.
£30,000.
Back to you already, Eddie.
50 grand.
80 grand.
100 grand.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Look, fellas, I know. ..
I know you're not in.
Which means no one cares what you know.
250.
That's quite a raise.
That's 150 on my 100.
Yeah, and is there anything else you wanna say?
As you know,
this puts us in an
awkward position.
I don't have enough to continue.
We will have to see both your cards
if no one loans Eddie the money to continue.
It's a loan or we see both your cards.
I will.
You will what?
I will loan you the money.
No, I think I'd rather just turn them over.
I'm not interested in what you would rather.
I wanna keep going.
I'm also offering you the money.
So we don't have to
turn them over, because
you can borrow.
I need 250 grand.
No, you need 500 grand to see me.
That's if I want to see you.
Well, you're gonna
have a problem
carrying on, ain't you?
I'll see you.
Okay, before I loan you this
I expect, if you lose, of course,
my money back
within a week.
Crystal?
That's Sunday, okay?
Is that it?
Now let's see his fucking cards.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(RETCHING)
Hello, boy.
Feeling a bit
poorly?
I know your friends are responsible
for most of the cash.
So, I'm gonna give you one week to find it.
Otherwise, I will take a finger
off each of you and your friends' hands
for every day that passes without payment.
And then when you run out of digits,
your dad's bar, and who knows what then.
All right, my son?
This doesn't look good.
ALAN: He then
proceeded to explain
the unfortunate position they were in.
Harry was going to start
sizing up all their
fingers in a week,
because he knew there was
no way Ed could settle
that debt on his own.
Harry saw it as their money
on the table, so it was also
their debt off the table.
Ed would hate admit it,
but he could have kissed
the old bastard for that.
If he said he wanted to
settle the debt on his own,
it would have been a lie.
Now, I wish to Christ he
would have let me settle
the debt on my own.
I'm gonna kill him!
Stop fucking about, Tom,
and think about what
we're gonna do.
Now sit down.
What's all the fuss about Harry?
Why don't we just boycott the payment?
Let me tell you about Hatchet Harry.
BACON: Once there was
this geezer called
Smithy Robinson
who worked for Harry,
but it was rumored that he was on the take.
Harry's invited
Smithy round for
an explanation.
Smithy didn't do
a very good job.
Within a minute,
Harry's lost his rag,
reached out for the
nearest thing at hand,
which happened to
be a 15-inch
black rubber cock.
He then proceeded to
batter poor Smithy
to death with it.
Now that was seen as a pleasant way to go.
Hence, Hatchet Harry
is a man you pay
if you owe.
Don't worry, I'll think of something.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
"Golf. The best
way to spoil a
good walk."
Winston Churchill said that.
I say it's a
dog-eat-dog world,
and I've got bigger teeth than you two.
(GORDON GRUNTING)
I think our friend
is trying to tell
us something.
Perhaps not. Perhaps I
should take another swing
just to make sure.
Give me a five iron, John.
Certainly, Dog.
Now, keep still.
Yes, Gordon, is there
something you'd
like to tell us?
It's in the fireplace.
Shut it, you idiot!
Yes, Gordon, you were saying?
It's in the fireplace.
Just pull it out.
It's in the bottom.
It's in the fireplace,
Plank. Just pull it out.
It's in the bottom.
Oh, Dog, I think
you want to have
a look at this.
You gonna let me down now?
DOG: No.
I'm not finished with you yet.
Steel.
Help, help, help!
Oh, Dog.
WOMAN ON TV: It's all up
to you, audience.
You have to decide, yes, you have to decide
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
who the winner is going to be.
Who the hell's that?
It's only 12:00.
Use the cage, that's what it's there for.
Who is it?
We have got security for a reason, Willie.
Chill, Winston.
It's only Plank.
This weed's getting
quite a rep,
you know, fellas.
All right?
Easy. Jesus!
Never saw you there.
Hello, love.
Enjoying yourself?
Is she compos?
What do you think?
Boo!
PLANK: Fuck me.
Clean that up, Charles.
Sod you. You
clean it up.
Sorry, fellas, but that
stupid cow scared the
fucking life out of me!
Never mind.
Can you just
sit down?
Stay out of the way?
Look, how much is it you want?
I'm after a half weight.
Right, well, that's £1,500 then.
Pass the scales, Willie.
Give us some gear, J.
Any chance of actually seeing the money?
The odds
are 100-to-one.
All as we need is 5 grand.
I'd rather put my money
on a three-legged
rocking horse.
The odds are 100-to-one
for a good reason,
Bacon.
You won't win.
Where's Eddie?
Where do you think?
The bottom of a
bottle. And has
been for two days.
It's hit him hard.
Yeah, it's hit us all hard.
Yeah, but he's got
to tell his dad he's
about to lose his bar.
Listen to this one.
You open up a company
called Arse Ticklers
Faggots Fan Club.
You what?
You take out an advert
in the back page
of some gay mag,
advertising
the latest in
arse-intruding dildos.
You sell it with, I don't know,
"Does what no other dildo can do until now.
"The latest and greatest in sexual technology.
"Guaranteed results
or your money back."
All that bollocks.
Now these dills cost 25 quid a pop.
That's a snip for the
amount of pleasure they're
gonna give the recipients.
But they send their
checks to the
other company name,
nothing offensive,
Bobbie's Bits, or
something, for 25 quid.
You take that 25 quid,
you stick it in the
bank until it clears.
Now this is the smart bit.
You send back
the check for £25 from
the other company name,
Arse Ticklers Faggots Fan Club, saying,
"We're sorry, and we
couldn't get the
supplies from America,
"because they've
run out of stock."
Now you see how many people cash that check.
Not a single soul.
Because who wants their bank manager to know
they tickle arse
when they're not
paying in checks?
So how long do you
have to wait till
you see the return?
Probably no more than four weeks.
A month?
So what fucking good
is that if we
need it in six. ..
No, five days.
Well, it's still a good idea.
He may know
we smoke a lot and
burn a bit of profit,
but he can't have any
idea how much hard
currency we've accumulated.
I don't know.
Do you know?
We can just slice it off the top.
WINSTON: You guys
gotta realize who
this chap is.
He might look
a bit silly, but he's
a fucking lunatic.
And if he gets the
slightest inkling we're
not throwing straight dice,
then you and me are gonna
know what the sharp side
of a kebab knife feels like.
So you know these geezers well?
PLANK: Well enough.
I've been buying gear
off one of them for
a couple of years.
So, what are they like then?
Poofs. Nothing heavy.
Four public schoolboys.
Soft as shite.
PLANK: They ponce around
in funny hippy clothes
all day, talking bollocks.
They're just good at growing weed, that's all.
Business has got bigger
than what they
can keep up with.
DOG: Well, they
can't all be stupid,
can they?
Think about it.
They've got a container
load of cash in shoeboxes.
They're selling
class-A gear.
Don't you think there
might be someone
sensible involved?
What about security?
PLANK: There's one steel
gate as you go in, but
they never lock it.
What do you mean, never lock it?
What have they got it there for then?
I must have been
there 50 times.
It's never locked.
They're not suspicious.
Everyone who goes there's a toff.
They're all into that karma crap.
"If I don't harm nobody,
nobody harms me" stuff.
No way they can get back to you?
Even if they could,
they'd be too shit scared.
I'm a geezer.
They got no muscle.
Gutless faggots.
Fancy one?
What's all the flapping about?
You told the old man yet?
Hoping I won't need to.
I've got a plan.
Now listen carefully.
Hello, boys.
Harry.
Do you want a drink?
Hello, my son, do you want a lolly?
Piss off, you nonce.
Oi ! Watch it.
No thanks, Harry.
We're both all right.
Nice shooter.
Yeah, one of a pair.
Holland & Holland.
Do you want
to hold it?
No, not my thing.
Thanks, Harry.
Business good?
I imagine that's
why I'm here.
Four young fellas
got in deeper than
they could handle.
They owe me half a million pound.
LITTLE CHRIS:
How much?
Half a million.
I'm game.
Me, too.
Oh, God.
Right.
We hit them as soon as they come back.
We'll be prepared, waiting.
And they're armed.
What was that?
Armed?
What do you mean, armed?
Armed with what?
Bad breath,
colorful language,
feather duster. ..
What do you think they're gonna be armed with?
Guns, you tit.
Guns? You never
said anything about guns.
A minute ago this
was the safest job
in the world.
Now it's turning into a bad day in Bosnia.
Soap, stop being such a mincer.
I've thought
about that and. ..
And what exactly?
And all we have to
do is find out
who's carrying them.
Carrying them? Well,
they could all be carrying
them for what we know.
No. Only one of
them carries them
going to the job.
So I assume the same one will be carrying them
when they come back from the job.
Oh, you assume, do you?
And what do they say
about assumption being the
brother of all fuck-ups?
It's the mother
of all fuck-ups, stupid.
Well, brother, mother, any other sucker,
it don't make any difference.
They're still fucking
guns, and they still
fire fucking bullets.
Soap, if you have a better idea
how to get £500,000
in the next few days,
let us know.
In the meantime, Tom,
you talk to Nick the Bubble
about shifting the weed.
Weed?
No, it's not
normal weed.
It's some
fucked-up-skunk,
class-A,
I-can't-think-let-alone-move
shit.
Doesn't sound very good me.
No, neither me.
But it depends
what flicks your switch.
And the light is on
and burning brightly
for the masses.
Anyway, do you know anyone?
I know a man, yes.
Rory Breaker.
Not that madman with an Afro?
I don't want anything to do with him.
You won't have to.
Just get me a sample.
No can do.
What's that?
A place near Katmandu?
Meet me halfway, mate.
Look, it's all completely chicken soup.
It's what?
It's kosher
as Christmas.
Jews don't celebrate Christmas, Tom.
Yeah, well, never
mind that. I'm gonna
need some artillery, too.
Couple of
sawn-off shotguns.
This is a bit heavy.
This is London,
not the Lebanon.
Who do you think I am?
I think you're Nick the Greek.
Hold those two.
I don't normally have
anything to do
with weed, Nick.
But if it is what he says it is,
I'll take it off him
for 3.5 grand a key.
That is if it is what he says it is.
I don't want to see it after a sample,
I don't want to touch it after a sample.
I'll leave you in
the capable hands
of Nathan here.
He'll sort out the details.
But just let me tell you one thing.
If the milk turns out to be sour,
I ain't the kind of pussy to drink it.
Do you know what I mean?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Rory Breaker.
Rory? Yeah,
I know Rory.
He's not to be underestimated.
He's a funny looking fucker, I know.
But you've got to look
past the hair and the
cute cuddly thing.
It's all a deceptive facade.
A few nights ago, Rory's Roger iron rusted.
He's gone down the
Battle Cruiser to watch
the end of a football game.
No one's watching
the custard, so he
switches the channel over.
A fat geezer's north opens.
And he wanders up and turns the liza over.
"Now fuck off
and watch it
somewhere else."
Rory knows claret is
imminent, but doesn't wanna
miss the end of the game.
So calm as a coma,
picks up a
fire extinguisher,
walks straight past
the jam rolls who are
ready for action
and plonks it outside the entrance.
He then orders an Aristotle
of the most ping-pong
tiddly in the nuclear sub
and switches back to his footer.
"That's fucking it," says the geezer.
"That's fucking what?"
says Rory.
And he gobs out a
mouthful of booze
covering Fatty.
He flicks a flaming match into his bird's nest,
and the geezer's lit up like a leaking gas pipe.
Rory, unfazed, turns
back to his game.
His team's won, too.
Four-nil.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Oi!
Is your hair supposed to look like that?
All right, short stuff?
Never mind
"short stuff."
Listen, the next time we do a job like this,
we're gonna want more money, Barry.
Or we're going back
to post offices and
cars. Fuck that.
Where's the others?
There was no others.
Stop fucking
around. The others,
the old ones.
I don't know what you mean.
There were two old guns there.
Where are they now?
Not in the cabinet, there wasn't.
There was a couple of
old hammer-lock muskets
the butler was carrying.
But they were ours, we sold them.
Well, you better unsell them, sharpish.
We had to sell them.
We needed the money!
I'm not fucking interested!
If you don't want to be
counting the fingers
you haven't got
I suggest you get those guns, quick!
Jesus.
If I pick them up, will they stay in one piece?
Where'd you get them?
I got contacts.
Listen, Tom, you point them at me,
I'll shit myself or do whatever you say to do.
Either way you get the desired effect.
Oh, they look very nice, I agree,
but they're lacking
in criminal credibility,
ain't they?
I might get laughed at.
How much do you want for these muskets?
£700 each.
What's that?
A pound for every year
they've been about?
I know they're antiques,
but I ain't paying
antique prices.
They're a bit long, ain't they?
Sawn-offs are out.
People want a bit more
range these days.
Range?
I don't want to blow
the arse out of this
country, granted.
But I don't want anyone
blowing a raspberry
at me, either.
I want to look fucking mean.
Of course you'll look mean.
You'll look really scary.
Anyway, enough about that.
What about this geezer who sells drugs?
Rory Breaker's standing by.
You stand to make a lot of money, tubby Tommy.
BIG CHRIS: I understand
if this has come as
a bit of a shock,
but let me tell you how
this can be resolved by
you, the good father.
Go on.
He likes your bar.
Yes?
He wants your bar.
And?
Do you want me to draw you a picture?
Look, that boy doesn't
know his arsehole
from his ear hole.
This is my bar.
It's got nothing to
do with him.
What, and I care?
Remember, you do have the luxurious advantage
of being able to sustain your son's life.
And you do have a
reputation, so I'll choose
my words very carefully.
You tell Harry to go fuck himself.
Now,
I'll put that
down to shock.
Only once.
Only once can I
or shall I let you get
away with that.
Your son's got three days to find half a mil.
But make up your mind which you prefer,
your bar or your son.
DOG: Plank goes in first.
There's a cage, but it's never locked.
DOG: Is it, Plank?
Never.
DOG: It don't wanna be.
All right, once he's got
himself set, he gets
the rest of us in.
(FEEDBACK SCREECHING)
Now we get nasty
with a couple of them.
Shit them up, gag them, whatever.
Now these wankers
shouldn't give us
any problems.
But like any cowboys,
there'll be a few
tools lying around.
When the job's done,
we come straight back
here and unload.
And Robert's your father's brother.
Everyone savvy?
ALL: Sweet.
Have a look at these.
And what are we supposed do with these?
Put them on your head, stupid.
Christ.
If you think I'm gonna
turn up there clean-shaven
and greet them
with a grin on
my face, you got
another thing coming.
Now these fellas, they're your neighbors.
I thought it might be
a good idea to disguise
ourselves a little.
Right. Yeah, good
thinking, Soap.
Well done.
I brought weapons as well.
Weapons? What do
you mean, weapons?
(CLEARS THROAT)
These.
(EXCLAIMING) Jesus.
Let's keep them covered up, eh?
Couldn't you have got anything a bit bigger?
What, like that?
What do you think?
I think you need help.
Bar steward, can
we have a couple
of drinks, please?
Have you seen
your dad? Hatchet sent
one of his men around.
Oh, shit. When?
Crazy. ..
Where did you
get these?
A fucking museum?
Nick the Greek.
How much did you part with?
£700 for the pair.
Drachmas, I hope.
I'd feel safer with a chicken drumstick.
These are gonna do more harm than good.
Jesus, Tom, do these work?
Don't know.
Look nice though,
don't they?
I rather like them.
That's top of the list of priorities, that is.
EDDIE: Ladies,
back to more
important issues,
if you don't mind.
We have only got two real guns.
Apparently, that's what they are.
So we find a good place to hide next door,
we wait till it sounds like the right time,
then we
jack-in-the-box,
look nasty and stuff,
cocoon them
in gaffer tape,
nick their van, swap the
gear into the new van and
bring it all back here.
As long as we're
all out of our hiding
places quickly,
it's the last thing they're gonna expect.
Oh, and if Tom or anyone else for that matter
feels like giving them a bit of a kicking,
I'm sure it won't do any harm.
Yeah, little bit of pain never hurt anybody,
if you know what I mean.
Also, I think knives are a good idea.
Big, fuck-off,
shiny ones.
Ones that look
like they could
skin a crocodile.
Knives are good
because they don't
make any noise.
And the less noise they make,
the more likely we are to use them.
Shit them right up.
Makes it look like we're serious.
Guns for show, knives for a pro.
Soap, is there
something we should
know about you?
I'm not sure what's more worrying,
the job or your past.
Come on, girls.
Where the fuck
are they going?
Shift a piano?
I thought this was meant to be a robbery.
Where did they get those outfits?
BOTH: Not a
bad idea, that.
All right,
it's Plank. Is
Willie there?
No. I'm afraid he's not.
He's out at the moment.
PLANK: Perhaps
you can help.
Well, perhaps
I can't, Plank, if you
know what I mean.
Look. If you
could just
open the door,
so I could talk without shouting.
J: I can't help
you, Plank.
I think you'll find it is in your interest.
Hold on, okay?
Look, Willie, it's Plank outside for you.
He says it's in our interest.
Listen, I don't
care if it's
King-fucking-Kong!
He's not coming in here, not today.
Hold on. We are
in business, and
correct me if I'm wrong,
but that is business.
Corrected. That's a
walking accident that
we can do without.
Jesus, he's okay.
He knows only to
buy weights now.
We're looking at at least a couple of thou.
What do you think, Winston?
Willie, this is the last time, all right?
But you and the money are going out the back.
If he knows you're here, he'll be all day.
Now just clear this shit up.
What, now?
Yes. Now!
Just get rid of him quick.
All right, just coming.
What the fuck is he doing?
Come on, I can't wait out here all day.
J: All right,
just coming.
I thought you was
gonna leave me
out there all day.
I didn't know you were a removals man, Plank.
Lives and learns, don't you?
You keep the gates locked now, do you?
Sorry, gotta do business like this now.
Can't be too careful these days.
I know. Shut it!
You say a fucking word, the right ear goes.
Another one, then your left.
What are you doing, Plank?
What do you think I'm doing?
Hang on, what are you doing?
Unlock the gate.
All right, I said unlock
the fucking gate!
That's it!
Go, go, go!
Fucking move!
What the fuck's going on?
Just hang on, I've got the keys.
The gate's locked!
I don't believe the
fucking gate's locked!
What have you done to Fauntleroy?
I didn't touch him.
He just passed out.
Don't just stand
there. Get that
fucking door shut.
You want the world to see us?
(MEN ARGUING)
What's going on down there?
Shit.
Charles, get the rifle out.
We're being fucked.
It must be this one.
Hold that gun.
Plank, give me
the keys. Give
me the keys, Plank.
Don't point it at me,
bollocks, point
it in there.
DOG: Planks of wood.
I'm working with
fucking planks of wood.
Shit.
What the fuck is that?
What the fuck's that?
It's me Bren gun.
Don't you think you could
have brought something
a little bit more practical?
Don't none of you
slags move. I'll kill the
fucking lot of you!
Who are you gonna
kill, Plank? There's no
one fucking there.
(SCREAMS)
They fucking shot me.
Well, shoot them back.
Jesus, Plank.
Couldn't you have got
smokeless cartridges?
I can't see a bloody thing.
(GROANS)
Shit.
I've been shot.
I don't fucking
believe this.
Could everyone stop getting shot?
DOG: John, sit down
and patch yourself up.
You tart, it's a fucking air rifle.
What the fuck was that?
Well, that was the Bren gun.
If you fire that gun again,
you're a dead man.
Understand? Dead.
No ifs, no buts, you're a fucking dead man!
All right, all right.
I've got the bollock
ache with this. Where's
me fucking gun?
All right, now that I've got your attention,
firstly I'm gonna blow his toes off.
(GUN FIRING)
(WHISPERING) Shit.
DOG: There go
his toes.
Now if you want
me out of here in
five minutes flat,
open the fucking gate,
'cause I'm gonna blow his leg off.
They're gonna fucking kill us if we do, man.
Poor J will certainly
get it if we don't.
He's serious.
I'm losing patience.
Hurry up, girls.
WINSTON: It's all right.
All fucking right.
Willie, he
doesn't know
you're here. Just. ..
Sort something out.
And all your friends, there's a good lad.
There's only three of us here.
I don't believe you.
Fuck it, I'm gonna
blow his leg off.
I mean it.
It's only three of us.
DOG: Plank?
Yeah. One
of them is out.
Now open the gate.
(SIGHS)
(GROANING)
Up, up, up.
There's a
good lad.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
John, get them tied up.
Plank, where's the money?
There. In those
shoeboxes.
Where?
Out the back.
And the weed?
Point.
With what?
Your fucking hands, now.
I'm tied up.
Well, nod your head or something.
Check it out.
Plank, get Paul out
of that van, lively.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMS)
(GUN FIRING)
Knife.
I'm gonna cut him.
Make sure he
knows he's dead.
How you doing, Mick?
How do you think
I'm doing?
He's fucking nearly chopped me arm off.
Jesus Christ.
Lenny, what the fuck's been going on here?
Shut up, you idiot.
It's Hanukkah.
Well, don't just stand there.
Have you got
the bags? Can
you fit it all in?
It's a lot.
I can't get Epping Forest in my van.
Can't? I don't
wanna hear "can't."
Bollocks to can't.
You'll fit it all in
if you have to
make two trips.
Bollocks.
You've got a ticket already.
And if you don't
move it, we will
move it for you.
I'll only be a minute.
You've already been 15.
Look.
Come and have a look.
At what, exactly?
Well, the
van's half full.
So?
So, all I've got to do is fill it up,
put you in it. ..
What?
And I'm off.
Do you think you
can carry more than
one bag this time?
I can't.
My neck, Dog.
How many more bags?
JOHN: Just a couple.
Mick, you dead yet?
I'll be all right
once I've dealt with
that lanky prick.
DOG: Do it quietly.
It's time I say,
"Good night,
nurse."
(GUN CLICKING)
(SCREAMING)
Where the fuck did she come from?
(PANTING)
That is it. Tie her up.
We're out of here.
What are you doing, Ed?
Do you want one?
No, I fucking don't.
You cannot make
a cup of tea, Edward.
The entire
British Empire was
built on cups of tea.
SOAP: Yeah, and look
what happened to that.
And if you think I'm
going to war without one,
mate, you're mistaken.
Going to war with what?
Have you forgotten those guns, you dozy prat?
You won't get away with this.
Paul, what's that?
It's a traffic warden.
I can see it's a fucking traffic warden.
What's he doing in the back of the van?
He was gonna call the cozzers.
Fair enough, we'll deal with him later.
How are we doing, Tom?
Right as rain.
I'm just gonna take care of the cabs.
Keep us posted.
All right, mate, do you do airports?
Where the hell are we gonna hide?
Don't complicate
things. Just hide.
We're on.
Cor, they weigh a pound or two.
Shut up and back up!
(WHISTLES)
Spin round, big boy.
What the fuck?
Stay down.
Stay down!
Tie them up, tape them up, hands and face.
On the floor!
Bend over the fucking desk.
Keys. I want
keys. Now!
I'll find you.
Course you will, sweetheart.
What do you think
this is, fucking
hide-and-seek?
That one.
Search that one.
Right, I'll see you
in the van when you've
finished with handsome here.
Jesus, that wasn't too bad, was it?
When the bottle in my
arse has contracted,
I'll let you know.
Bacon, see what we've got.
Let's have a butchers, eh?
We've hit the jackpot, lads.
We've got God knows
how much of this
stinking weed,
a shit load of cash
and a traffic warden.
What?
Jesus, Ed, we got a traffic warden.
I think he's still alive.
He's got claret coming out of him somewhere.
What did they want with a traffic warden?
I don't know, but I don't think we need him.
Knock him out and dump him at the lights.
Knock him out?
What do you mean,
knock him out?
Knock him out with what?
I don't know!
Use your imagination!
(GROANING)
Don't touch him up.
Knock him out!
I'll knock you out in a minute.
Look, you want to knock him out,
you knock him out.
I fucking hate traffic wardens.
It's about time you
gave my young
friends a visit, Chris.
Tomorrow's the day and mum's the word.
Now I can't have that, can I, Baz?
No, Harry, you can't.
I mean, it's a liberty.
And I can't have a liberty taken, can I, Chris?
No, Harry, you can't.
I mean, it's enough to give me the arsehole.
And I can't have the arsehole, can I, boys?
BOTH: No, Harry, you can't.
EDDIE: Right, that's it.
We're done.
We're off.
Here, Ed.
Are you sure it's
a good idea taking
this back to yours?
Well, it's the only place we can take it,
and it's the last place they're gonna look.
Anyway, fuck it!
The battle is over and the war is won.
Now, Tom.
You take this
to Nick the Bubble,
then we get rid of it quick.
It's skunk, and it's as good as it gets.
All right, we'll take it.
Half price.
I don't think he'll like that.
You said 3.5 a key,
and you know that's
a good price.
It was yesterday I said three and a half,
and now it's today if I'm not mistaken.
We'll take it tomorrow, half price.
If he wants to get rid of it quick,
he'll have to take it.
Now look,
I've got a race coming up in a minute,
so if you'd just be
kind enough to. ..
Lenny, take that round
to Snow White and
the three little chemists.
They should have a gander of that.
I want a second opinion.
LENNY: Hang on
a minute, Nathan.
Something stinks.
NATHAN: Yeah, your
fucking aftershave.
LENNY: Fuck you,
funny man.
For God's sake.
Help me.
I'm in pain.
I'm in so much
pain ! Jesus.
Go in slowly, Nathan.
Fuck you, funny man, you go first.
Just get the fuck in there, will you?
I want this house searched for bugs.
I mean, I want it stripped.
Where's the point in that?
Even if there was a
bug, they'd have
taken it with them.
It's a bit late
for you to start
thinking, John.
If it's a possibility,
that's good
enough for me.
And when you've stripped this place,
I want every slag this
side of Ceylon pulled in
and tortured badly.
I want to know who's responsible for this.
Otherwise, I'm gonna hold you responsible.
EDDIE: Not a bad day.
That pile takes care of Harry.
What's left over?
Give me half a chance to count it.
What about this gear then, eh?
What, you want a toke on that?
No, I don't think
I want any of that
horrible shit.
Can we lock up and get drunk now, please?
We shot one of them in the throat.
What do you want, a medal?
I'll shoot you in the
fucking throat if I don't
get my ganja back.
RORY: The one you
shot, is he still
in there now?
No, it was another one.
That's more like it.
Where is he?
Well, they took him with.
No, he's still alive.
What did you
shoot him with?
An air gun?
Look, we grow weed.
We're not mercenaries.
You don't say.
Who could it be?
Where do we start, Rory?
Mr. Breaker.
Today my name
is Mr. Breaker.
You think this is a coincidence?
This white shite steals my things
and thinks that he can sell it back to me!
He's got less brains than you, Lenny!
Get Nick,
the greasy wop. ..
Greek bastard
round here now.
If he's still
stupid enough to be
on this planet.
(ROCK SONG PLAYING)
Your stupidity might be your one saving grace.
Uh?
Don't "uh" me, Greek boy!
How is it your
fucking stupid,
soon-to-be-dead friends
thought that they
might be able to
steal my cannabis,
and then sell it back to me?
Is this a declaration of war?
Is this some white
cunt's joke that
black cunts don't get?
'Cause I'm not fucking laughing, Nicolas!
I know you couldn't have known my position,
'cause you're not that stupid that if you did,
you wouldn't have
turned up here
scratching your arse
with that, "What's going on here" look
slapped all over your Chevy Chase.
But what you do know is where these people live.
If you hold back anything, I'll kill you.
If you bend the truth,
or I think you're
bending the truth,
I'll kill you.
If you forget anything, I'll kill you.
In fact, you're gonna
have to work very hard
to stay alive, Nick.
Now, do you understand everything I've said?
Because if you don't, I'll kill you.
Now, Mr. Bubble
and Squeak, you
may enlighten me.
So we've got a bit of a problem, ain't we?
Well, yeah.
Yeah, we do.
Yeah, yeah, we do.
In fact, it's a little bit
more than a little bit
of a problem, isn't it?
On a scale of things, you could say
it's the Mount fucking Everest of problems.
And the reason it's such
a mon-fucking-strosity
of a problem is,
you don't even got
a first idea who did
this to us, have you?
Dog, we've been up
all night. It's no one
from round here.
We've had them all lined up against the wall.
If he was a toe-rag
from out of manor,
we'd know.
We'd know.
You'd know?
You'd fucking know?
You wouldn't know
if it was the next door
fucking neighbors!
Now get out there and
find them ! I'm sick of the
fucking sight of you!
Get out of my
fucking sight! You
little shit!
Scarface.
I've watched Scarface.
If you want to know
how to do a drug deal,
you watch Scarface.
That really inspires confidence, that.
This guy
Rory Breaker. ..
Rory Breaker?
Psychotic black
dwarf with an Afro?
That'll be the same man, yes.
I heard about him.
He's a fucking lunatic.
Well, he can afford
to do the deal at the
price we're selling.
It's not worth him giving us any trouble,
because he knows we'll be a pain in the arse,
and who needs a pain in the arse?
I'll take a pain in
the arse for
half-a-million quid.
You'd take a pain in the arse for air miles.
Tom, the fatter you get, the sadder you get.
Will you two stop flirting for a minute?
After we pay Hatchet, this deal puts us up
nearly £200,000 each.
That's not bad for
a morning's work,
I think you'll agree.
So they had the cash.
And the puff.
Cheeky bastards.
Count it.
Shit, Dog, there's a lot.
Don't you want to
do it next door?
We're not going
next door till we've flayed
them dead men walking.
We'll count it upstairs.
I don't want them
to see you fingering
their money
when they walk through the door.
But, Dog, look. ..
Give us it here, dozy bastard.
Check your guns.
Get yourselves
well hid.
You wait till they get right inside the door,
then you give it to them.
Give me them shooters, you can use your own.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
That's no way to answer the phone.
(EXCLAIMS)
Is that you, Dean?
No, it's Lord fucking Lucan.
Who do you think it is?
What can I do for you?
You know those
guns I sold you?
I need them back.
Not likely, I'm afraid.
I don't think I'll be
seeing them again.
Look, I've got the money to pay for them.
I'm sure you do,
but I don't think
you understand.
I ain't gonna be seeing them or the guns again.
Can't get them.
If we can't get them, we can't get them.
Well, you'll have to fucking get them.
Look, we made the
fucking deal for everything
inside the cabinet.
Inside-out-fucking-side.
I don't give a shit.
You get those guns,
because if you don't. ..
Oh, yeah, Bazza, or what?
Have you heard of Harry Lonsdale?
Otherwise known
as "Hack you up with
a hatchet Harry?"
Well, this is
James Bond,
need-to-know time.
When you dance with
the devil, you wait
for the song to stop.
Know what I mean?
I mean, find them, torture them and kill them.
And bring back what belongs to me.
Because if you don't,
your family's
bang in trouble.
Who was that?
(SIGHS)
That was Harry Horrible Hatchet.
Jesus, I've heard of him.
DEAN: We're in shit.
They were his fucking
guns we sold.
We've got to find them.
Now, no fucking about
now, Nick. Where can
I find those guns?
Six black cocks and
a little white kitten sitting
on the side of the road.
We're gonna do a proper decoration job.
I want the gray skies of London illuminated.
I want that house painted red.
(ALL LAUGHING)
All right.
There's this brass
standing on
the corner, right.
Dwarf walks up to her carrying a suitcase.
Winston, there, is gonna
come along and see if he
recognizes any of them.
Now watch out for these fellows.
They've got a bit of an arsenal,
and they don't mind using it.
And I'm taking down her panties.
Now, does everyone
here know what
they've got to do?
Yeah.
What the fuck is going on?
(GUNS FIRING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
You got something here for me, have you?
Come on,
chop-chop.
Thank you very much.
He's got the guns.
Go ahead,
you get them.
Why me?
You're supposed
to be the
hard case. ..
You go and
get the guns!
I drive the car!
Good boy.
Oh, get the fucking guns!
I'm not going to get the fucking guns!
You get the fucking guns!
You fucking. ..
(MOCKING LOUDLY)
All right, wrap them guns up.
Count the money.
Put your seat belt on.
GARY: Fucking guns!
We've got to get the
fucking guns, or
we're dead!
(STARTING CAR)
So I made sure
I fucked the one that
was coughing.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Get out of the car, you yuppy fucker!
(DOG SHRIEKING)
He's the one we shot in the neck.
Is that right,
Mr. Botanical?
(GUNS FIRING)
(EXCLAIMING) Jesus.
I don't believe this.
What the fuck has
happened here?
Jesus.
The money.
The gear.
This is fucked.
No money.
No weed.
It's all been replaced by a pile of corpses.
All right, don't panic.
Let's think about this.
No, fuck that.
You can think about
it. I am panicking
and I'm off.
How did you get your hands on these then?
The boys had them.
I know you like these sort of things.
Wondered if you wanted them.
Yeah, I'll have them.
Was it hard work getting the money?
Not especially.
Upset a few characters though.
You counted it?
Yeah. It's all there,
to the pound.
And they were gonna pay?
Looks like it, but who knows?
The opportunity was there.
In my experience,
it's best to take
that opportunity
if it's there.
Good work, Chris.
DEAN: We've got to
get those guns.
This is dangerous
shit, Dean. We don't even
know who lives there.
Listen, I don't care who lives there!
All's I know is that
it's preferable to
death by Hatchet.
GARY: Fair enough.
Let's go.
I don't think it's the right move.
It's either that,
the old boy's place
and we lose a digit daily.
I'm gonna phone him.
As if he'll care.
He'll care all right.
That was supposed
to be his money.
Whether he cares about us or not is different.
Pass me the phone.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
That you, boy?
It's Ed, if that's what you mean.
Pay day, isn't it?
Yeah. I wanted to
talk to you
about that.
I'll bet you do.
I've got half-a-million
nickers sitting here,
which means some poor sod doesn't.
You've been upsetting a few people, boy.
But that really isn't my concern, is it?
What does concern me is the guns you had.
And I want to talk to you about that.
So get your arse
over here now,
and I do mean now.
Bastard ! You
fucking bastard!
Fucking bastard!
(SCREAMS)
What the fuck are you doing here?
Job well done.
We made a few quid
out of that one.
Son?
Made a few quid, did you?
Where's what I want?
You all right down there, mate?
Very fucking funny.
Where's what I want?
I've just left it in the office.
We better go to the office and get it then.
That's if you want
your son to see
his next birthday.
Now chop-fucking-chop.
All right, fair enough.
Where are you going?
It's a 30-second
drive or a five-minute
walk.
And I couldn't have parked outside.
I'd have got a ticket.
I suppose that don't matter now, does it?
Just be careful.
Right.
You and me.
You and who?
You know where the door handle is, Tom.
Oh, no, not again!
That's it. I'm off.
Tom, that is our bag.
Ed.
Hold on.
This is our bag.
That's it, we're off.
I'll see you in the
car. I'm gonna
take these guns.
Tom, don't fuck about!
I'll see you in the car.
Tom.
It'll only take
a minute.
What is going on?
I don't know.
But what I do know is
there's no more Harry,
which means there's no more debt.
And if there's no
more debt, there's no
more problem.
And there's no problem
with the neighbors,
because they're all dead.
And I think, if I get this right,
we haven't done
anything wrong,
and we're in the clear.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Never ever has anyone ever
been as fucking rude to me
as you did!
Fucking bastard!
You all right, mate?
Cheeky bastard.
ALAN: Now this was an
embarrassing position
for Tom to be in.
But Chris had to respect the fact
that he was holding what
appeared to be a pair
of loaded shotguns.
And Tom had to respect
the fact that they
were not loaded.
So, without anybody losing too much face,
Tom left through a side door,
and Chris left with the money.
And everybody else got arrested.
He's not one of them.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
I think your dad
would like a word
with you, Ed.
Where are the others?
They got out
yesterday. They're
back at the bar.
All right, Dad?
I'm all right.
How about yourself?
Oh, I'm all right.
Could do with a drink, though.
All in good time, all in good time.
So you in the clear?
More importantly, am I?
It appears so.
Appears?
You'll have to do
better than fucking
appears, my friend.
Well, everybody's dead,
Dad. I think that's about
as clear as you can get.
How about that drink?
You know where the bar is.
Hey?
Don't make yourself
too comfortable.
Alan's got to sit there.
Alan!
You're lucky you're
still breathing, let
alone able to walk.
I suggest you take full advantage of that fact.
You took your time.
Where the hell have you been?
Sit down, I'll tell you.
So the traffic warden
identified the
neighbors' bodies,
which sort of puts us in the clear.
The only thing connecting
us with the case is
those shotguns.
And Tom took care of them.
SOAP: You did take care
of the shotguns,
didn't you, Tom?
I wanted to talk to you about that.
Well, talk.
Well, actually, no.
I've got them sitting in the car.
I was gonna sell them back to Nick the Greek,
but I'm having a bit
of trouble getting
hold of him.
You dippy bastard.
So,
the only thing connecting us with the case
is in the back of
your car, which is
parked outside?
They cost us 700 quid.
I'm not gonna
throw them away.
And they're hardly
likely to trace them
back to us, are they?
Do you really think
it's worth taking
the risk for £700?
Tom, you're a dick.
Now you take those guns,
and you throw them
off a bridge.
And throw yourself off while you're at it.
Now, Tom.
Look, all I'm. ..
ALL: Now, Tom!
Can I have a beer, please, Dad?
I'm busy.
Get it yourself.
It seemed Hatchet underestimated you lot,
and it seems to have cost him.
Well, I ain't gonna
make the same
mistake now, am I?
So I've decided to bring your bag back.
I think the word you're
looking for, gentlemen,
is "thank you."
Thank you.
Now you've presented me with a problem.
I've lost my employer.
So I've taken care of meself and me son.
Now if you think that's unfair,
you come and pay me a little visit.
But you better be waving a white flag
high and clear, so as I can see it.
Or it'll be the
last little visit
you ever make.
You understand?
That's all I've come to say.
There is one more thing.
It's been emotional.
We are now officially
in the money-lending
business.
You all right, Son?
Put your seat belt on.
We're out of here.
It's empty.
ALL: What's his number?
Don't, don't!
You'll jam the line!
I'll call him.
My fucking battery.
Oh, you. ..
Give me
the phone!
No, fuck off!
I'll dial it!
Give me the phone!
Just be calm for a minute.
All right, shut up and tell
me the number!
Fuck you!
Give me
your phone!
You'll break it!
Just calm down!
Give me the phone!
Look, you'll
break it, and it'll be
fucked, won't it?
Will you shut?
It's fucking ringing!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)