They are coming to get you, Barbara.
Stop it!
They are coming.
They don't like being awakened this way.
Why do you have to be so mean?
Hey, I'm your older brother.
Being mean and heartless
is part of my job.
They're going
to get you, little sister.
Johnnie, now you're being silly
and I don't want to hear it.
Will you cut it out,
right now?
You never know
when to stop, do you? Never!
What's the matter, Barbara?
You gettin' scared?
You're still scared
of her, aren't you?
That's why
we're here, isn't it?
No, that's not
why we're here.
Tell me somethin', will ya?
Why do we have to put ourselves
through this... charade?
Because she is
our mother!
Can't you at least give her
one day out of your life?
One day? This is the fourth
time we've been up here...
in the three months
since she died.
I'm spending more time with her
now than when she was alive.
And you know why?
Don't start.
She couldn't possibly
be buried in the city.
No. That would
have been much too easy.
She knew I'd have to be
the one to drive you up here.
That's why she had herself buried 200
miles from the nearest glass of beer.
Johnnie, now we're here. Will
you just please stop it?
Stop what?
The truth?
She drove our father
to an early grave.
She drove
me away from home,
and she damned near drove you into a convent.
That's not true.
When's the last time you had a date?
That is none of your business!
The one thing
she never, ever drove...
was 200 miles
to visit anything.
Johnnie, please. Now, I need
you to stop talking like that.
Don't talk like that.
Not here.
What do you mean,
“not here”?
Not here. Not in the middle of-
Of what?
Show some respect.
Ha! You're afraid,
aren't you?
You really are afraid of this place.
God, you never stop!
For the love of God, Johnnie.
Bastard!
Jesus, you're weird. Let's just
get through this, can we, please?
Just get it over with.
They're coming
to get you, Barbara.
- Barbara-
- For the love of God, Johnnie.
They're horny, Barbara.
They've been dead a long time.
Look! Look!
There's one of them now.
He wants you!
He's getting closer.
Dangerously closer!
Stop it. John!
He's going to hear you!
It doesn't matter.
He knows we're here.
It's too late now.
There's no escape!
No, Mother!
You bastard.
Johnnie-
I'm sorry. Very sorry.
Hey! I'm sorry.
Hey, man, are you okay?
Is there something
we can do to help?
It's weird, huh?
Aaah.
- Aaah!
- Uh, uh- Oh-
Oh-
Johnnie!
Help! Help!
Please, my brother's hurt!
Hey! Hey, mister! Hey!
Please, we need help.
Please, mister, help us.
Oh, sh-
No! No!
Hey. Hey!
Hey! Is there anybody here?
Hey!
Hello?
Hello.
Oh, no!
Oh-
Anyone else inside?
Huh?
You got any shotguns in there?
Hunting rifle, anything.
I don't know.
What?
I don't-
You don't know?
No.
Hey. Hey.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Hey, come on! Come on!
Come on!
Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Come on!
No! Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on!  No!
Die! Damn it!
Who is he?
Do you know him?
It's all right. it's all right.
Did what you had to do.
Do you know any of them?
Ones outside?
This isn't your house?
You don't live here?
Look. Talk to me, girl.
Do you have a car?
Huh?
Yes. I- No. My brother-
The windows. They're not strong
enough to break through the door,
but they can get through
the window glass.
Goddamn you!
Goddamn all of you!
Truck's on empty.
We can't take the chance of running
dry out in the middle of nowhere.
We'll hole up here.
Hope that some help comes.
My name is Ben.
What's your name?
- Barbara.
- Yes.
- Now look here, Barbara.
I don't need you falling apart on me.
You understand?
I see what you did over there. I
know you can fight when you have to.
Well, you have to now.
Right now.
Fight what you're thinkin'.
Fight what you're feelin'.
The fight'll keep you strong,
keep you thinkin' straight.
What's happening?
I don't know.
Nobody knows.
Radio in the truck.
All I heard was trash talk.
Same as always.
People tryin' to sound
like they know what's goin' on.
They don't really know shit!
Same as always.
One guy saying it's...
escaped prisoners on the loose
from up at Hennessey.
Another guy saying it's...
some kind of chemical spill
makin' everybody go crazy.
They don't know shit.
How do they explain...
a man walkin' around
with his neck broken?
A man shot full of holes...
and still comin' at you?
Assholes... down in Evans City
out for a good time...
with their guns
and their six-packs.
Assholes tryin' to round them up
and put them in the back of trucks.
Like they know what
they going to do with them.
They had 10, 20 of them
in the back of this panel truck.
They opened the door
to let another one in.
They come spillin' out of there...
like bugs.
I was at a diner.
Windows shot out.
Lady next to me shot dead.
Others too.
I saw six or seven go down.
Car exploded outside.
My car caught on fire.
It was like- like a war.
Some of those things
made it inside the diner.
Started comin' after us.
Some good ol'
boy comes chasin' him.
Mean son of a bitch
got some kind of...
hot-shit gun,
like an M-16 or somethin'.
He starts-
shooting wild.
Bullets tearin' up the place.
I saw one of those things
take 30 hits and keep on comin'.
The damn thing had to be dead,
but it kept on comin'...
till it took a hit in the head.
That brought it down.
The only way to stop 'em-
You got to-
You got to...
get 'em in the head.
Look, I don't know what's goin' on,
but I sure as hell know
that it ain't no prison break.
It ain't no kind of chemical that I ever
heard about can make a dead man walk.
This is something that nobody has ever
heard about and nobody's ever seen before.
This is hell on earth.
This is pure hell on earth.
Damn!
Doesn't take long for the world
to fall apart, does it?
There's got to be guns
in this house.
Maybe upstairs.
I'm going to go
take a look around.
You all right down here alone?
There's something up there.
What?
What is it?
It's all right.
It's nothin' to worry about.
- What is it?
- It's nothin'. It's nothin'.
It's all right.
Ben!
It's all right. Don't shoot.
Don't shoot, mister!
- It's just us!
- Who the hell is “us"?
- Tom Bitner, sir. That's me.
Harry, what's going on?
This here's Harry Cooper.
That's his wife callin'
down in the cellar.
They got a sick little girl
down there too.
My woman's down there too,
that's Judy Rose Larson.
Um, that's all of us.
Do you mind if we ask
who the hell you are now?
- Girl's Barbara. I'm Ben.
- You damned near broke my arm, Mr. Ben.
Harry, for God's sake!
- Aren't you going to answer her?
- Harry, please answer me!
Uh, it's all right.
We're all right.
- There's some people up here.
- Didn't you hear all the noise up here?
We could've used some help.
Hey, maybe you can see through walls.
I can't.
We heard some
bangin' around up here.
It could've been those things
for all we could tell.
We just heard
some bangin' around is all.
No, no, that ain't right.
We heard the girl callin' out,
askin' if anyone was here.
We was just scared, that's all.
Want to know the truth?
We was scared to hell.
You live here, Tom?
No. This is my Uncle Rege's house.
Him and my cousin Satchel.
Ol' Uncle Rege, he's dead.
I seen him. I swear to God.
I touched him.
He was stone cold dead.
He died today.
- And that's the truth!
- Harry, please!
Let's go. We can talk in the cellar.
Me and Judy Rose,
we walked on over to be
with Satchel, you know?
Radio said there was some kind of trouble.
We didn't see nothin'.
We didn't see nothin'. Home to
here, we didn't see nothin'.
Damn it!
We have heard all this before!
I didn't hear it before, Cooper.
Go on, Tom.
Well, me and Judy Rose,
we walked on over like we said.
We wasn't here more than 10
minutes when Mr. Cooper there,
he come bangin' on the door.
How'd you get here?
You don't look like neighbors.
Oh, what? You tryin' to figure
out if somebody's got a car?
You don't think we've
all been through this before?
Mine is broken down
on the interstate,
and the kid here doesn't own one,
if you can believe that.
Damn!
What about you, Mr. Ben?
You don't exactly look
like neighbors yourself.
Truck- outside, out of gas. Gas?
Evans City is five miles away.
Hey, we can make five miles on freakin' fumes!
Yeah, what if
we don't make it?
You willin' to take that chance?
Besides,
Evans City's a war zone, man.
I know. I been there.
It's going to take us a hell of a lot more
than five miles before we find any real help.
There's a gas pump out by the shed.
Huh?
But Uncle Rege,
he keeps it locked.
Do you know where the key is?
No, but I could hunt for it.
We will, but not now.
It could take too long.
Besides, we might never find it.
We got to figure out
what we're doin' first!
- Finish your story, Tom.
- This is bullshit.
If we're going to do something,
let's do it.
If we're going to stand around and
bullshit, let's do it in the cellar...
where it's safe. I'm not so sure goin'
down in that cellar is a smart move.
What do you mean?
I mean I'm not so sure...
lookin' ourselves down in that
cellar is such a smart move!
I'm not goin' down there until
I know what all the options are.
What damned options?
And who the fuck gave you the right
to decide for the rest of us?
I'm not deciding for you
or anybody else, Cooper.
I'm thinkin' about my own ass!
Now, you want to go down in that cellar, go!
Nobody's stoppin' you.
For God sakes, Harry, what's going on?
Damn it, Helen!
Will you quit yelling at me?
I can't think straight
with you yelling at me!
You know, I've only been
around you a minute or two,
but that's enough time for me
to know that I don't like you.
I'm sure you feel the same
about me, so let's just...
try to stay out of each
other's way, all right?
Go on, Tom.
What else you got to tell?
Well, like I said,
Judy Rose and I, we wasn't here
more than 10 minutes, and...
Mr. Cooper, he come bangin'
on the door, you know.
We let him in,
him and his wife,
and I seen
their little girl was hurt,
so I, uh-
I tried to call for help, you know.
The phone's makin' this funny sound.
Tried and tried,
and I couldn't call nobody.
That's when Uncle Rege, uh,
he come walkin' out
of the bedroom, you know?
He was dead a minute before.
I swear to God.
He was not dead.
He couldn't have been.
Y-You were wrong.
You made a mistake. That's all.
He was dead.
I know he was.
What happened?
Uncle Rege, he went
after my cousin Satchel.
H-He- He went
after him like, uh-
I don't know.
Anybody else in the house?
No, just them.
Tom, I'm afraid
your cousin is dead.
Uh-huh. I know he's dead.
Shot himself.
I mean, Uncle Rege comin'
after him and all, you know?
I run down here and got the
shotgun, but what could I do?
I couldn't imagine
shootin' Uncle Rege.
Couldn't imagine
doin' a thing like that.
And that's when I told everyone
to go down in the cellar.
Goin' down in the cellar,
that's my idea.
- It was a good idea.
- Look. Look outside.
- Into the cellar, quick.
- No, that cellar's a death trap.
Those things don't have much strength,
but get enough together. they may
be able to break through the door.
Be cornered down there.
No way out.
We'd do better fightin' 'em off here
where there's still some way to escape.
A way out is a way in.
T-The windows-
Maybe we can board 'em up.
There's no time.
Those things are- Look, there's
only three of them, man.
I've handled more than that by myself.
We found these two guns.
I'm worried about more of 'em comin'.
That cellar door won't hold 'em.
- Oh, and the windows will.
- Look, I don't need this!
I told you before, you want
to go downstairs, go on. Get!
You can be boss down there.
I'm boss up here.
What you going
to do, Tom?
Judy Rose, come on up.
We need your help.
You're crazy!
You're out of your minds.
This here's Judy Rose.
Go get them old shelves out of the kitchen.
What are we doin' now?
We're going to board up them windows.
Tommy!
Board up the windows? Are you
sure we're going to be all right?
There are more of them things out there.
More of them things like Uncle Rege.
Tommy!
Go on. Do what I tell ya!
I shut this door, I'm not openin' it until
somebody comes who can get us out of here.
If somebody like that comes,
we'll try to remember to call you.
Idiots! You lamebrains!
You're going to die up here.
You're going to die.
You're going to be fine.
We're all going to be fine.
Daddy's found someone,
and we're going to get some help.
What's happening? They
decided to stay upstairs.
What about us?
it's safer down here.
- What about Sarah?
- It's safer down here, Helen.
There's just that one hammer.
Here. Use this.
Nail 'em up quick and dirty.
Get the windows covered
as fast as you can.
We'll go around later
and reinforce them.
Anybody find any keys,
hang on to 'em.
How many people are up there?
There's two more.
- And they've got the gun.
- No, they've got two guns.
They might have a hundred
guns, for all I know.
But it doesn't matter,
because it's safer down here!
We're going up.
We've got to get help for Sarah.
I'm not opening that door,
Helen, and neither are you.
And if you try, so help me I'll kill you.
You'll what?
That is your daughter lying there.
We have got to
get her to a doctor!
There's no doctors
upstairs, Helen.
And there's
no way out of here!
None of those yo-yos has a car!
What a place to be stuck!
Middle of nowhere.
Bunch of yo-yos.
Judy Rose, help me here!
That's it. Grab this. Perfect.
Fever's gotten worse.
Look, she's going
to be all right.
Somebody'll come.
We'll get out of here.
We're all going to be all right.
Did you find anything?
I'm done over here.
They're crazy.
They're out of their minds.
You bunch of yo-yos!
This is the last of the big stuff, huh?
Not going to do it.
Hey, Tom, give me a hand.
Turn it over.
Come on. Come on.
Get the legs off. Shit!
All right. We'll leave our gun here.
I'll be back.
Come on, come on, come on!
Get over here.
Okay, great.
Bring my gun when you come back.
Come on. Nail it up.
Just get it up.
We'll reinforce it later.
They're so slow!
We could just walk right past 'em.
We wouldn't even have to run.
We could just walk
right past 'em.
We have the guns.
If we're careful,
we can get away.
You told me to fight.
Well, I'm fighting.
I'm not panicking.
This place is not safe,
not upstairs or down.
We should leave
before it's too late.
Look, I know you want
to get out of here,
and so do I,
and we're going to do it.
We're going to figure out a way to
get to that gas, and we'll be gone.
Now, you're doin' fine, all right?
I'm doin' fine.
We're all doin' just fine.
We're going to make it,
if we're careful.
Like you said,
we've got to be careful.
Get them doors down and nail 'em up!
That's it! Nice goin'!
Is she crazy or what?
Oh, my God.
Tommy!
Easy- Easy.
Wait for Tom. Wait.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
All right. Nail it up.
Nail it up! Come on. Come on.
Just get a few nails in.
Okay. Get some in the table top.
All right?
It's all right. Come on.
Keep nailing. Keep pounding.
Get a hole for that one. Come on, Tom.
Tom! Oh, yeah, another door.
Let's get this baby off.
That's good.
Easy, easy, easy.
All right.
Hit it.
Come on!
Hey, we're goin'
upstairs for a minute.
We're going to leave
the weapons here, all right?
Hey, hey, Tom. Tom.
Wait a minute.
Don't go up.
It's all right.
Come on. Don't look at it.
What is this?
All new stuff in here?
Uncle Rege was
fixin' up the place.
- No good.
- it's better than nothin', Ben.
No good.
Hey, Tom.
Television.
Check it out and see
if anything's on.
Tellin' you what to do,
I think.
Damn. This must really be big.
Station's in Zelienople.
it's only about 20 miles from here.
Might as well be a hundred.
- Says they're going to come on live.
- Yeah? Well, we can't wait.
Give me a hand with some
of that lumber over there.
We can use some of this stuff
to cover the windows downstairs.
I'm some kind of stupid.
What?
Them old doors, the ones we took
down, they're all in the cellar.
Heads up down there!
- Idiots!
- What's happening up there?
How do I know what's
happening up there?
Said they were going
to board it up.
- Board it up, please.
- And you refused to help them.
That's right, Helen.
I refused.
Right! I refused.
You know why?
Because they're wrong.
it's a stupid idea.
The cellar is the only
safe place in the house.
You watch.
You just watch.
They're going to come begging for us to let
them in down here before this is all over.
And what will you do then?
- Will you open the door then?
- Mr. Cooper?
Harry.
Mr. Cooper, we need the doors that's down
there so we can board up the windows.
- For God's sakes, Harry!
- Then fuck him!
Mr. Cooper,
can you hear me?
Cooper! You open
this door right now!
We need those doors,
Cooper!
I got a shotgun out here. Open this door,
motherfucker, or I'll blow it to shit!
What are you doing? Cooper
Open this door, now!
What do you hope to accomplish?
Shut up, Helen!
I'm counting to three,
then I'm coming through.
We're going to open!
I'm counting.
That's one-
What you going to do, Cooper?
That's two!
Better open this door
right now, Cooper!
Get your hands off of me.
Look. From now on,
you leave that door open!
We may want to get down there. We may need
to get down there if those things break in.
Yeah, sure. You want
the best of both worlds.
You get caged in up here, you want
to be able to run downstairs.
That's not the way
it's workin', pal.
You want to get in that cellar, you get
in there now or you can forget it!
I'm not boxin' myself in down there until
there's absolutely no other choice.
And I'm not gamblin'
with my daughter's life!
You want to stay up here, that's your
decision, but don't count on me to help you.
Look, I am not counting on you for shit.
That's why I'm not going to let you-
If you're going to keep on
fighting, then get out!
This is our house.
This is Tommy's house.
You're just all playin'
rooster with it.
I'd like to know where you'd all
be if we didn't let you in here.
Where would you be
if we kicked you the hell out?
We're not going to kick anyone out, Judy Rose.
We're not going to do anything like that.
Now, come on. Let's try to work together
and get some of this damn shit done!
You ought to keep her covered.
Get some blankets
from upstairs or somethin'.
How'd she get hurt?
One of those people
bit her on the arm.
What? You want
this one too?
We have to get help.
We have to get a doctor for Sarah.
We're going to try.
Since you ain't doin' nothin', maybe you
want to start lookin' for those keys.
What keys? Keys to the
gas pump out back.
You mean, there's a car?
It's a truck!
The gas pump
is locked.
The keys could
be anywhere!
You know where- keys- I'm-
I'm looking for-
Oh, my God.
I need the hammer in here.
Bring the hammer-
Tommy!
Helen, we ought
to get downstairs quickly!
Damn.
Cooper, get me them nails
over there and that wrench!
Helen!
I can't let go.
You got to help me out.
Get me the wrench and nails, man!
Helen!
Cooper!
This is definitely not going to work.
We've got to get
downstairs quickly.
Take your hands off of me.
Take your hands-
Take your hands off of me!
Damn it!
No!
No, don't shoot it.
It's Mr. Magruder from the Legion Hall.
You shot Mr. Magruder!
Look at his back.
- You shot him!
Look at his back. I didn't do that.
Look there.
Barbara.
Just like Uncle Rege. They're dead,
but they're coming right for us.
No. That's impossible.
That just can't be.
Grab him. We'll throw him
up and out the window.
Is he dead?
Is he dead? You're all seeing this.
Stop it! You're losing it, girl.
You are losing it!
You think so?
Whatever I lost,
I lost along time ago.
And I do not plan on
losing anything else.
You can talk
to me about losing it...
when you stop screaming at each other
like a bunch of two-year-olds.
You all right?
Hey, hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Look at me.
It's going to be all right, okay?
How many bullets
does this thing hold?
Fifteen. There's more in the desk.
Look, we have a few more
windows to cover up, all right?
Why don't you grab some of that
lumber over there and get started.
It's going to take us a while.
Okay?
Tommy. Tommy.
Hospitals are deluged
Random acts of violence are being committed
by people in a trance-like or hypnotic state.
They've lost their ability to communicate
and reason, and they do not respond...
to command or authority.
Civil forces and the military have been
mobilized but the violence is so widespread...
that it is impossible for rescue
services to respond with any efficiency.
People left to defend themselves are
caught in a river of...
Citizens faced with the collapse of
local police and fire departments...
have taken the law
into their own hands.
Civil and social services have
been disrupted or suspended
Most communities
are without telephones.
Many are without power,"
some are without gas and water
The scientific community
is focusing on the phenomenon.
Specifically, on that trance-like state
that seems to characterize the assailants-
clearly a behavioral disorder.
But what could have caused...
so widespread and dramatic a condition
as the one we are facing tonight?
We've heard speculation on everything from
the ozone layer and chemical weapons...
to, uh,
voodoo, mysticism and organisms from space.
Biologists in Stockton, California,
have released a report...
stating that the, uh,
bodies of
the recently dead are...
returning to life,
driven by an unknown force that enables
the brain to continue to function.
Doctors at the Center for Disease
Control in Atlanta reject that theory,
calling it "preposterous
beyond belief"
They feel that the only
reasonable explanation...
is a germ- uh, a bacteria
or a virus that has...
a mind-altering effect
on its victims,
though how such a germ could have
been delivered so quickly...
and over such a vast area
does remain a mystery.
It's being called "Judgment Day"
by religious lea-
Hey, man. Where you takin' that? Huh?
What the hell-
That stays up there, pal. Will
you get off my back, Goddamn it!
Damn it!
Damn it! Nice going, asshole!
You smashed it!
You were taking it downstairs!
I was not!
You stupid-
You fuck-
Damn you!
I'll kill you.
You son of a bitch!
That was our only way
of finding out what was going on,
and you smashed it!
I wasn't taking it downstairs!
You can't get any reception
in a basement, dickhead!
What the hell
is she doin'? Hey!
Is that your Uncle Rege?
Looks like him.
Do you think he might have
a set of keys in his pocket?
We've got to get the keys.
Damn it, stay back here!
We can get away.
No, it's too dangerous.
I'm telling you,
we could make it!
Five miles. We got that kid.
Cooper's kid.
- Leave him. We'll bring help.
- We better make some kind of damn move.
We're drawing a crowd here.
You know I'm right.
Like I told you,
we can walk right by them.
I got 'em. I got the keys.
We got to get to the gas.
It's our best chance.
All right. Everybody,
back inside quick!
Damn it! Get in here!
I want you to stay inside. What?
Keep the rifle. You can't
go out without the guns.
We have Tom's gun. If something
happens, I want that rifle in here.
- I don't want any locked doors between me and this guy.
- Oh, for crying out loud.
Do you think that-
- Shut up, Cooper.
I don't want to hear another word.
The only way I'm going out there is with
you and that rifle keepin' things straight.
Tom, let's go.
it's you and me.
I'm coming with you.
I can drive.
No, you're staying here.
Somebody's gotta drive,
somebody's got to do the gas, and
somebody's gotta ride shotgun.
That means three of us goes out. Tommy,
tell them I know how to drive. I can do it!
Her daddy's got trucks. She's been
driving since she was little.
All right. Is that shotgun loaded?
Yeah, I got shells in my pocket.
Can't tell how many
are on the porch.
Probably be the toughest
getting past those.
Once we get to the yard, we oughta be all right.
Not too many out there.
There's no way.
This is crazy.
We're never going
to make it.
Hah!
You keep an eye
on us outside.
When we get that gas and start driving
back, get that kid up there fast.
Judy, get in that truck, all right?
Get in; get it started.
Don't stop, no matter what happens.
Tom and I will keep those things off of you.
You just move!
Heads up!
Go! Come on!
Get in the truck!
Get in!
No! Oh, God!
Oh, God!
Damn it!
Shut the door!
Darn you piece of shit!
Start!
Come on! Come on! Wait! Wait!
Ben, come on!
What's happening?
Ben!
Judy Rose, slow down!
We lost Ben!
Judy Rose, stop!
Stop the car!
We lost Ben!
Go back!
Judy!
Ben!
We lost Ben!
What?
We lost Ben! Oh, my God.
Why didn't you tell me?
I was hollering at you!
Go back and pick him up!
Tommy, here he comes! What should I do?
I don't wanna leave you!
Go down there
and get him, Judy Rose!
- These are the wrong keys!
- What?
These are the wrong damn keys!
Tom! What the hell
are you doing?
I want you down
in that cellar, Helen!
There's nothing more we can do up here.
Not now.
Do what he says. We're
gonna try to get to town.
At least I am. I f I can find
any help, I'll be back.
Come on.
We mustn't leave Ben!
But we should wait until Ben gets back.
I'll wait as long as I can.
Right now, I want you in
that cellar where it's safe.
But maybe we should-
Into the cellar, Helen. Now.
Your daughter needs you.
Sarah?
Oh, my baby!
I want that gun.
God. You go to hell.
I want that gun. Give it up, Cooper!
just crawl back into-
Help me! No!
Cooper! Cooper!
Open this door,
Goddamn it!
Son of a bitch, Cooper!
Open it up!
Cooper!
Cooper! Open this door!
Goddamn it!
Barbara!
Give that to me!
Cooper! Son of a bitch!
Let me in!
Cooper!
Open the door!
Let me in!
Cooper!
- Go on! Push!
- I'm trying!
Push!
Let him in!
The gun! Get his gun!
S-Sarah?
Shoot it.
No.
Shoot it, Cooper.
No, I-
But... it's my-
No!
Ohh.
Stop it! Ben, are you crazy?
Stop it!
Cooper, no!
Cooper!
No! God!
Madness.
They're coming.
No.
- We can still make it.
- No, I can't.
I'm hurt bad.
Go on.
Get out of here. Go!
I'll bring help if I can.
Go!
Oh, God!
Do not attempt
to reach friends or family
Do not attempt to reach
any of the rescue stations...
identified in previous advisories.
They may no longer be in operation.
Repeating this advisory number nine from
the Office of Emergency Preparedness...
dated 11:00 p.m. August 23, 1989.
It has been confirmed
that the bodies of the dead...
are being reactivated
by forces as yet unknown.
Got that right.
These reactivated
bodies are weak and uncoordinated
but are capable of inflicting
damage on people and on property.
They are to be considered
extremely dangerous,
especially when encountered
in large numbers.
These bodies can be disposed of
in only one known manner-
that is by incapacitating the brain.
They got that right too.
These reactivated bodies...
will attack warm-blooded animals
of all species,
including human beings,
without pro vocation,
and will devour flesh of any prey.
It's been confirmed that acts
of homicide and cannibalism...
reported through the afternoon and evening...
of August 23, 1989...
are attributable,
at least in part,
to these reactivated bodies.
Don't shoot!
Johnnie!
Jesus Goddamn holy-lovin' shit!
What in the name
of Jupiter's balls...
are you doin' out here
alone, little lady?
...they're hangin' out down there.
'Cause me and the boys
must have dragged out...
at least seven, eight
of them down there already.
Very interesting. Tell me,
Chief, are these things slow-moving?
Yeah, they're dead.
They're all messed up.
Ward, puttin' on a little
extra weight, aren't you, buddy?
They're us.
We're them, and they're us.
Say what?
Nothing.
No more
beer for you, man!
- Having fun?
- Give me a break.
Whoa.
Drag that outta here.
I'm goin' in there. Watch your back.
There may be more of 'em.
All right.
Oh!
You came back.
There's another one for the fire.