Huhh!
Get a break, boss?
No break...
Huhh!
Pick up that hammer there, boy.
Yes, sir, boss.
Huhh!
Come on, get it! Go!
Say...
any of you boys smithies?
Or if not smithies per se...
were you otherwise trained
in the metallurgic arts...
- Aah!
- Before straitened circumstances...
forced you into a life
of aimless wanderin'?
Jesus! Can't I count
on you people?
Sorry, Everett.
Well, all right.
If we take off through
that bayou...
Wait a minute.
Who elected you leader
of this outfit?
Well, Pete, I figured
it should be the one...
with the capacity for
abstract thought.
But if that ain't the
consensus view...
then hell, let's put it to a vote.
Suits me!
I'm votin' for yours truly.
Well, I'm votin' for
yours truly, too.
Okay. I'm with you fellas.
Mind if we join you, old-timer?
Join me, m' son.
Join me.
You work for the
rail road, grandpa?
I work for no man.
Got a name, do you?
I have no name.
Well, that right there
may be the reason...
you've had difficulty
finding gainful employment.
You see, in the mart of
competitive commerce...
You seek a great fortune...
you three who are now in chains.
You will find a fortune...
though it will not be
the fortune you seek.
But first...
First you must travel...
a long and difficult road...
a road fraught with peril. Mm-hmm.
You shall see thangs...
wonderful to tell.
You shall see a... a cow...
on the roof of a cotton house. Ha.
And, oh, so many startlements.
I cannot tell you how long
this road shall be...
but fear not the obstacles
in your path...
for fate has...
vouchsafed your reward.
Though the road may wind...
yea, your hearts grow weary...
still shall ye follow them...
even unto your salvation.
No, the treasure's still
there, boys, believe me.
But how'd he know
about the treasure?
I don't know, Delmar.
The blind are reputed to
possess sensitivities...
compensating for their
lack of sight...
even to the point of
developing paranormal...
psychic powers.
Now, clearly, seeing
in the future...
would fall neatly
into that category.
It's not so surprising. Then...
that an organism deprived
of its earthly vision...
He said we wouldn't get it.
He said we wouldn't get
the treasure we seek...
on account of our obstacles.
What the hell does he know?
He's an ignorant old man.
Jesus, Pete. I told you
I buried it myself.
If your cousin still has
this here horse farm...
and a forge and some
shoein' impedimenta...
to restore liberty of movement...
Hold it right there!
You men from the bank?
You Wash's boy?
Yes, sir. Daddy told me...
I'm to shoot who's
ever from the bank.
Well, we ain't from the
bank, young feller.
Yes, sir. I'm also supposed...
to shoot folks servin' papers.
We ain't got no papers. Neither.
I nicked the census man.
Now, there's a good boy.
Is-Is your daddy about?
Hello, Pete.
Who are your friends?
Pleased to make your
acquaintance...
Mr. Hogwallop.
My name's Ulysses
Everett McGill and...
And I'm Delmar O'Donnel.
How you been, Wash?
Been what, 12, 13 years?
Yeah.
I expect you want them
chains knocked off.
They foreclosed on Cousin Vester.
He hanged hisself a year come May.
And Uncle Ratliff?
The anthrax took most of his cows.
The rest don't milk.
He lost a boy to mumps.
Where's Cora, Cousin Wash?
Couldn't say.
Mrs. Hogwallop up
and R-U-N-N-O-F-T.
She must have been
lookin' for answers.
Possibly.
Good riddance, as far
as I'm concerned.
I do miss her cooking, though.
This stew's awful good.
You think so?
I slaughtered this
horse last Tuesday.
I'm afraid she's startin' to turn.
Well, that winds up tonight's...
Pass the Biscuits Pappy
O'Daniel Flour Hour.
This is Pappy O'Daniel...
hopin' you folks been enjoyin'
that good old-timey music.
And remember...
when you're fixin' to fry
up some flapjacks...
or bake a mess of biscuits...
use cool, clear water...
and good, pure Pappy
O'Daniel flour.
Well, guess I'll be turnin' in.
Say, uh, Cousin Wash...
I suppose it'd be the, uh,
acme of foolishness...
to inquire if you had a hair net.
We got a bunch in yon bureau.
Mrs. Hogwallop's, as
a matter of fact.
Help yourself.
I won't be needing 'em.
All right, boys!
Unh. How's my hair?
It's the authorities!
We got you surrounded.
Damn. We're in a tight spot.
Just come on out and grabbin' air!
And don't try nothin' fancy.
Your situation is
pretty nigh hopeless.
Damn! We're in a tight spot!
What in the Sam Hill?
Pete's cousin turned
us in for the bounty.
What the hell are you saying?
Wash is kin!
Sorry, Pete!
I know we're kin, but they
got this depression on.
I got to do for me and mine.
I'm gonna kill you...
Judas Iscariot Hogwallop!
- You miserable,
horse-eatin' son of a-
Damn! We're in a tight spot!
Damn his eyes!
Pa always said, "Never
trust a Hogwallop."
Come and get us, coppers!
You boys is leavin'
us no choice...
but to smoke you out.
Damn! We're in a tight spot.
Light her up!
Hold up, boys!
Ain't you ever heard
of negotiatin'?
Bet we could talk this thing out.
I hate fire!
You lousy, low-down,
yellow-bellied goat-
Pete, we got to speak
with one voice here.
Careful with that fire, now, boys!
Light the loft, son.
Aah!
I hate fire!
Gapped-toothed. Carpetbaggin',
motherless spawn of hell!
Step back. Damn it. Look out.
Holy St. Christopher!
Get away from that vehicle, chaps!
She's liquid fire!
Take cover, boys!
That ain't popcorn!
Let's get the hell out of here!
Scatter, boys!
Goddamn it!
Get in, boys!
I'm gonna R-U-N-N-O-F-T!
Come on, boys, come on! Come on!
What are you doing here?
You ought to be in
bed, clump snatcher.
You ain't the boss of me!
You candy-butted.
Car-thievin' so-and-so's!
I curse your name!
Go back home and mind your pa!
What's the damn problem?
I can get the part from Bristol.
It'll take 2 weeks.
Here's your pomade.
Two weeks?
That don't do me no good.
Nearest Ford auto man's Bristol.
Hold on, now. I don't
want this pomade.
I want Dapper Dan.
I don't carry Dapper Dan.
I carry Fop.
Well, I don't want
Fop, goddamn it!
I'm a Dapper Dan man!
Watch your language, young fella.
This is a public market.
Now, if you want Dapper Dan,
I can order it for you.
Have it in a couple of weeks.
Well, ain't this place
a geographical oddity.
2 weeks from everywhere.
Forget it.
Just a dozen hair nets.
Well, didn't look like
a one-horse town...
but try finding a
decent hair jelly.
Gopher, Everett?
And no transmission belt
for 2 weeks neither.
Huh? They dam that
river on the 21 st.
Today is the 17th.
Don't I know it.
We got but 4 days to
get to that treasure.
After that, it'll be at
the bottom of a lake.
We ain't gonna make it walkin'.
That's right.
Gopher, Everett?
But the old tactician
has got a plan.
For the transportation, that is.
I don't know how I'm gonna
keep my coiffure in order.
How's this a plan? How
we gonna get a car?
Sell that. I figure
you can only have...
painful association for Wash.
"To Washington
Bartholomew Hogwallop."
From his lovin' Cora.
"Amor Fidel... is."
It was in his bureau.
I reckon it'll fetch
us enough cash...
for a good used auto voiture...
and a little leftover besides.
Whoo! You got some light
fingers, Everett.
Gopher?
You miserable little snake.
You stole from my kin!
Who was fixin' to betray us.
You didn't know that at the time.
So I borrowed it till I did know.
That don't make no sense!
Pete, it's a fool who
looks for logic...
in the chambers of
the human heart.
What the hell is that singing?
Appears to be some kind of a...
congregation.
Care for some gopher?
No, thank you, Delmar.
A third of a gopher would
only arouse my appetite...
without beddin' her back down.
Oh, you can have the whole thing.
Me and Pete already had one.
We ran across a whole
gopher village.
Well, I guess hard times
flush the chumps.
Everybody's lookin' for answers.
Where the hell's he going?
The Father, the Son,
and the Holy Ghost.
Well, I'll be a son of a bitch.
Delmar's been saved.
Well, that's it, boys.
I been redeemed.
The preacher done washed away...
all my sins and transgressions.
It's the straight and
narrow from here on out.
And heaven everlasting's
my reward.
Delmar, what are
you talkin' about?
We got bigger fish to fry.
The preacher said all my
sins is washed away...
including that Piggly Wiggly
I knocked over in Yazoo.
I thought you said you was
innocent of those charges.
Well, I was lyin'.
And the preacher said...
that that sin's been
washed away, too.
Neither God, nor man's
got nothin' on me now.
Come on in, boys.
The water is fine.
Come on, boy. There, boy.
Good doggy.
All right, boys, we got the scent.
The preacher said it absolved us.
For him. Not for the law.
I'm surprised at you, Pete.
I gave you credit for
more brains than Delmar.
But there was witnesses
seen us redeemed.
That's not the issue, Delmar.
Even if it did put you
square with the Lord...
the state of Mississippi's
a little more hard-nosed.
You should have
joined us, Everett.
It couldn't have hurt none.
Hell, at least it would
have washed away...
the stink of that pomade.
Joining you two ignorant fools...
in a ridiculous superstition...
Thank you, anyway.
And I like the smell
of my hair treatment.
The pleasin' odor's
half the point.
Baptism!
You two are just dumber
than a bag of hammers.
Well, I guess you're
just my cross to bear.
Pull over, Everett.
Let's give that
colored boy a lift.
You folks going past Tishomingo?
Sure, hop in.
How you doin', son?
Name's Everett.
These two soggy sons of bitches...
are Pete and Delmar.
Keep your fingers away
from Pete's mouth.
He ain't had nothing
to eat for 13 years...
except prison food, gopher,
and a little greasy horse.
Thanks for the lift, sir.
My name's Tommy. Tommy Johnson.
How you doin', Tommy?
Say, I haven't seen a
house out here for miles.
What are you doin' out in
the middle of nowhere?
Well, I had to be at that there
crossroads last midnight.
Sell my soul to the devil.
Well, ain't it a small world?
Spiritually speakin'.
Pete and Delmar just
been baptized and saved.
I guess I'm the only one
that remains unaffiliated.
This ain't no laughin'
matter, Everett.
What'd the devil give you
for your soul, Tommy?
Well, he taught me to play
this here guitar real good.
Oh, son...
for that you traded
your everlasting soul?
Well, I wasn't usin' it.
I've always wondered.
What's the devil look like?
Well, of course, there
are all manner...
of lesser imps and demons, Pete...
but the great Satan hisself...
is red and scaly with
a bifurcated tail...
and he carries a hay fork.
Oh, no. No, sir.
He's white. As white as you folks.
With empty eyes and a big.
Hollow voice.
He loved to travel around
with a mean old hound.
That's right.
And he told you to
go to Tishomingo?
Well, no, sir. Why,
that was my idea.
I heard there's a man down there.
He pays folks money
to sing into his can.
They say he pays extra...
if'n you play real good.
Tishomingo, huh?
How much he pay?
All right. Boys, follow my lead.
Hello?
Who's the honcho around here?
I am. Who are you?
Well, sir, I'm Jordan Rivers...
and these here are the
Soggy Bottom Boys...
out of Cottonelia, Mississippi.
Songs of salvation
to salve the soul.
Uh, we hear that you
pay good money...
to sing into a can.
Well, that all depends.
You boys do Negro songs?
Um... well, uh, sir,
we are Negroes.
All except for our
accomp-our accomp...
Uh, the fella that
plays the guitar.
Yeah, well. I don't
record Negro songs.
No, I'm lookin' for some
old-timey material.
You see, people can't seem
to get enough of it...
since we started
broadcasting it...
on The Pappy O'Daniel
Flour Hour...
so thank you for stopping by.
But...
Sir, uh, the Soggy Bottom Boys...
have been steeped in
old-timey material.
Heck, we're silly with
it, ain't we, boys?
That's right.
That's right. We ain't
really Negroes.
All except for our accompanist.
Whoo! Hot damn. Son!
I believe you did sell
your soul to the devil!
Whoo-ee!
Boy, that was some mighty
fine a-pickin' and a-singin'.
I'll tell you what.
Ahem. You come on in here, you...
You sign these papers here.
I'm gonna give you $10 apiece.
Uh, uh, okay, sir, but
Mert and, uh, uh...
Aloysious'll just have to sign Xs.
Only 4 of us can write.
That'd be fine.
Ha ha!
Whoo!
Hey, mister, I don't mean...
to be tellin' tales
out of school...
but there's a fella in there
who'll pay you $10...
if you sing into his can.
I'm not here to make a record.
You dumb cracker.
They broadcast me
out on the radio.
That's Governor Menelaus...
"Pass the Biscuits"
Pappy O'Daniel.
And he'd sure appreciate it
if you ate his farina...
and voted him a second term.
Finest governor we ever
had in Mississippi.
In any state.
Oh, Lord, yes. Every
parish or precinct.
He was makin' the bigger point.
Well, ain't you gonna
press the flesh, Pappy?
Do a little politicking?
I'll press your flesh,
you dimwitted sumbitch.
You don't tell your pappy how
to court the electorate.
We ain't one-at-a-timin' here.
We're mass communicatin'!
Oh, yes. That's a
powerful new force.
Mm-hmm!
Shake a leg, Junior.
Thank God your mammy
died givin' birth.
If she'd have seen you,
she'd have died of shame.
Well, hi there! How you doin'?
Let's bed down here for the night.
Yeah, it stinks in that old barn.
Suits me.
Pretty soon it'll be nothin'
but featherbeds and silk sheets.
Million dollars.
Million-point-two.
500,000 each.
400, Delmar.
Pete, what are you gonna do...
with your share of the treasure?
Go out west somewhere.
Open a fine restaurant.
I'm gonna be the maitre d'.
Greet all the swells.
Go to work every day
in a bow tie...
tuxedo.
And all the staff say
"Yes, sir" and...
"No, sir..."
and "In a jiffy, Pete."
And all my meals for free.
What about you, Delmar?
What are you gonna do with
your share of that dough?
I'm gonna visit them
foreclosin' son of a guns...
down at the Indianola
Savings and Loan.
Slap that money on
the barrel head...
and buy back the family farm.
You ain't no kind of man
if you ain't got land.
What about you, Everett?
What you have in mind...
when you stole it
in the first place?
I...
didn't have no plan.
Well, that hardly sound like you.
All right, boys! It's
the authorities!
Your situation is
purty nigh hopeless!
Damn. They found our car.
We ain't got the time...
and nary the inclination...
to chat with you boys any further.
Damn. We got to skedaddle.
I left my pomade in the car.
Maybe I can creep up.
Don't be a fool, Everett.
We got to R-U-N-N-O-F-T.
Where's Tommy?
Already lit out.
Scared out of his wits.
Let's go!
Well, hell, it ain't square one.
Ain't no one gonna pick up...
3 filthy, unshaved hitchhikers.
And one of them a know-it-all...
who can't keep his trap shut.
Pete, the personal rancor
reflected in that remark...
I don't intend to
dignify with comment.
But I would like to address
your general attitude...
of hopeless negativism.
Consider the lilies
of the goddamn field.
Or, hell, take a look
at Delmar here...
as your paradigm of hope.
Yeah. Look at me.
Now, you may call it an
unreasoning optimism.
You may call it obtuse...
but the plain and simple fact
is that we got close to...
3 days before they...
dam that river.
Is this a road to Itta Bena?
Uh... Itta Bena?
Itta Bena?
Isn't that... Isn't that, uh...
Stay on this here road.
Nah, that ain't right.
I was thinking of. uh...
Take this road...
Nah, nah, nah. That ain't right.
It seems to me there's a road-
cow road that used to
lead all the way...
Well, most of the way.
That ain't right, either.
Hop on in while you
give it a think.
Right. Delmar.
Any of you boys know your way...
around a Walther P.P.K.?
Well, see, that's where
we can't help you.
I don't believe it's
in Mississippi.
Friend, some of your folding
money has come unstowed.
Just stuff it down that
sack there, will you?
You boys aren't bad
men, I take it?
Well, it's funny you should ask.
I was bad till yesterday...
but me and Pete here been saved.
I'm Delmar, and that
there is Everett.
George Nelson.
It's a pleasure.
Grab the tiller, will you, buddy?
Hand me that chopper. Ha ha ha ha!
Say, what line of
work you in, George?
Ha ha ha ha!
Come and get me, coppers!
You flatfooted, lame-brained,
soft-ass sons of bitches!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
No one can catch me!
I'm George Nelson!
I'm bigger than any
John, live or limp!
I'm 101/2 feet tall!
Cows.
I hate cows worse than coppers!
Oh, George. Not the livestock.
Come on, you miserable,
salaried sons of bitches!
Come and get me!
Come on, boys, we're
going for the record.
3 banks in 2 hours!
Okay. Folks, hold the applause
and drop your drawers.
I'm George Nelson...
and I'm here to sack
the city Itta Bena!
He's a live wire, though.
Ain't he?
All the money in a bag.
What are you lookin' at, grandpa?
Pardon me, George...
you got a plan for
gettin' out of here?
Sure, boys.
Here's my plan. Ha ha ha ha!
They ain't never seen
ordnance like this!
Thank you, folks.
And remember, Jesus saves...
but George Nelson withdraws!
Ha ha ha ha!
Go fix the auto voiture, Pete.
Is that Babyface Nelson?
Who said that?
What ignorant,
lowdown, slanderizin'
son of a bitch said that?
My name is George Nelson. Get me?
She didn't mean nothin'
by it, George.
George Nelson!
Not Babyface!
You remember!
And you tell your friends!
I'm George Nelson.
Born to raise hell.
Well, that was some fun.
Now, wasn't it, George?
Yeah.
Almost makes me wished I
hadn't have been saved.
Jacking up banks.
I can see how a fella'd derive
a whole lot of pleasure...
and satisfaction out of it.
It's okay.
Hoo, dawgies!
Well...
I'm takin' off.
You boys might as well...
keep my... share of the riches.
Well, where are you going, George?
I don't know.
Who cares?
Now, what do you suppose
is eatin' George?
Well, Delmar...
they say that with the
thrill-seeking personality...
What goes up must come down.
On top of the world one minute,
haunted by meekness the next.
Yes, sir, it's as if our
old friend, George...
is a alley cat and his
own damn humors...
are swingin' him by the tail.
I wouldn't worry, Delmar.
He'll be back on top again.
I don't think we've seen
the last of George Nelson.
Don't be saps for Pappy.
Homer Stokes for governor.
Let's sweep this state clean.
Vote for Stokes, brother.
Aw, shh shh. Hang on!
I'm gonna slap one on here.
Folks, here's my
cousin Ezra's niece...
Eudora from out of Greenwood,
doin' a little number...
with her cousin Tom-Tom...
which I predict you
gonna enjoy thoroughly.
Now, what can I do
you for, Mr. French?
How can I lay ahold of
them Soggy Bottom Boys?
Soggy Bottom.
I don't precisely recollect them.
They cut a record in
here a few days ago...
with an old-timey harmony thing...
with a guitar
accompany-accompany...
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I remember them.
Colored fellas, I believe.
Yes, sir, they a
fine bunch of boys.
They sang into yonder
can, then skedaddled.
Well, that record...
is just goin' through
the goddamn roof.
They playin' it as
far away as Mobile.
No.
Whole damn state's goin' apey.
Well, it was a powerful air.
Hot damn. We got to
find them boys...
and sign 'em to a
big fat contract.
Hell's bells, Mr. Lund,
if we don't...
the goddamn competition will.
Oh, mercy, yes, we got to
beat that competition.
- Yes, sir.
Delmar. Over here.
Do you have the Soggy
Bottom Boys...
performing "Man of
Constant Sorrow"?
No, ma'am. We got a new
shipment in yesterday.
Sorry, but we just can't
keep 'em on our shelves.
How are you?
Delmar, come on. Go. Go.
Shut up, Delmar.
Uhh! Ohh!
Pull over! Pull over!
Guess old Pete's got the itch.
Howdy do, ladies?
Name of Pete.
Ain't you gonna
introduce us, Pete?
I don't know their names.
I seen 'em first!
Ladies, my name is Ulysses
Everett McGill...
and, well, you three
ladies are about the...
the prettiest...
water lilies, uh...
Corn liquor.
Everett.
My hair!
Look at this.
Pete!
Where the heck are you?
We ain't got time
for hide-and-seek!
Now, we ain't got time
for your shenanigans!
Sweet Jesus, Everett.
They left his heart.
Aah! Aah!
What the-Delmar, what the
heck's got into you?
Can't you see it, Everett?
Them sirens did this to Pete.
They loved him up...
and turned him into a...
horny toad.
Pete!
Pete! Pete!
Pete, it's me-Delmar.
It's me-Delmar.
Everett.
Delmar, what the...
What are we gonna do?
I'm not sure that's Pete.
Of course it's Pete. Look at him.
We got to find some kind of...
wizard can change him back.
I'm just not sure that's Pete.
You can't display a toad...
in a fine restaurant like this.
Why, the good folks here'd
go right off their feed.
Hey. I just don't
think it's right...
keeping him under wraps...
like we was ashamed of him.
Well, if it is Pete,
I am ashamed of him.
The way I see it, he
got what he deserved.
Fornicating with some
whore of Babylon.
These things don't happen
for no reason, Delmar.
It's obviously some kind of
judgment on Pete's character.
Well, the two of us was
fixin' to fornicate.
You're gonna have to excuse
my rusticated friend...
unaccustomed as he
is to city manners.
Hmm?
I guess we'll have ourselves...
a couple of steaks...
and some, uh, gratine potatoes...
and wash it down with some
of your finest bubbly wine.
Oh, and I don't suppose
you have any...
Maybe the chef could prepare...
Just bring us a couple of
leaves of raw cabbage.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
That kind of barnyard language...
I don't believe I've seen you
boys around here before.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Name of Daniel Teague...
known in these precincts
as Big Dan Teague...
Or to those who are
pressed for time-
Big Dan tout court!
How you doin', Big Dan?
My name's Ulysses Everett McGill.
This is my associate
Delmar O'Donnel.
I detect, like me...
you're endowed with
the gift of gab.
I flatter myself that
such is the case.
In my line of work,
it's plumb necessary.
The one thing you don't want...
is air in the conversation.
Once again we find
ourselves in agreement.
What kind of work you do, Big Dan?
Sales, Mr. McGill. Sales!
And what do I sell?
The truth, every
blessed word of it.
From Genesis on down
to Revelations.
That's right, the Word of God...
which, let me tell you, there
is damn good money in...
during these times
of woe and want.
People are lookin' for answers...
and Big Dan sells the
only book that's got 'em.
And what do you do...
you and your, uh,
tongue-tied friend?
We, uh...
we're adventurers, sir.
Currently pursuing a
certain opportunity...
but we're open to others as well.
I like your style, young man...
so I'm gonna propose
you a proposition.
You cover my bill, so I don't
have to run back upstairs...
get your waitress to wrap
your dinner picnic-style...
And we shall retire to
more private environs...
where I will tell you how there
are vast amounts of money...
to be made in the service
of God almighty.
Well, why not? If nothin' else...
I can use some civilized
conversation.
Don't forget your
shoe box, friend.
Languishin'!
Goddamn campaign is languishin'!
We need a shot in the arm.
You hear me, boys?
In the goddamn arm!
Election held tomorrow...
that son of bitch Stokes
would win it in a walk!
Well, he's the reform
candidate, Daddy.
Yeah?
A lot of people like that reform.
Maybe we should get us some.
I'll reform you, you
soft-headed son of a bitch.
How we gonna run reform when
we're the damn incumbent?
Is that the best idea you
boys can come up with?
Reform?!
Weepin' Jesus on the cross.
That's it!
You may as well start drafting
my concession speech right now.
Okay. Pappy.
I'm just making a point.
You stupid son of a bitch.
Give me back that hat! Hurry up!
Pappy's just makin' a point.
Shut up!
Thank you, boys, for
throwing in that fricassee.
I'm a man of large appetites...
and even with lunch
under my belt...
I was feeling a mite peckish.
It's our pleasure, Big Dan.
Thank you as well for the
conversational hiatus.
I generally refrain from
speech during gustation.
There are those who attempt
both at the same time.
I find it coarse and vulgar.
Where were we?
Making money in the
Lord's service.
You don't say much. Friend,
but when you do...
it's to the point and
I salute you for it.
Yes, Bible sales.
Now, the trade is not
a complicated one.
There are but 2 things to learn...
One being where to
find a wholesaler...
the Word of God in
bulk, as it were.
Two-how to recognize
your customer.
Who are you dealing with?
It's an exercise in
psychology, so to speak.
And it is that which I propose...
to give you a lesson in right now.
Why, I like to think I'm a
pretty astute observer...
of the human scene, too, Big Dan.
No doubt, brother.
I figured as much back
at the restaurant.
That's why I invited
you all out here...
for this advanced tutorial.
Unh!
What's going on, Big Dan?
It's all about the money, boys!
That's it!
Gol... durned... money!
I don't get it, Big Dan.
Raah!
I just take your show cards.
Yaah!
And whatever you got in the hole.
What the...
there ain't nothin'
but a damn toad.
No, you don't understand.
That's Pete.
Pete.
You know these things
give you warts?
End of lesson.
So long, boys. Hee hee hee.
See you in the funny papers.
Y'all seen the end
of Big Dan Teague.
Where are they?
Talk, you unreconstructed
whelp of a whore!
Where they headed?
Aah!
Your screams ain't gonna
save your flesh...
Aah!
Only your tongue is, boy.
Where they headed?
Aah!
Lump, I.O.
Sweet summer rain.
Like God's own mercy.
Your two friends have
abandoned you, Pete.
They don't seem to
care about your hide.
Okay.
Stairway to heaven.
We shall all meet by-and-by.
Goddamn it!
God forgive me!
Hold.
Believe me. Delmar, he would
have wanted us to press on.
Pete, rest his soul...
was one sour ass son of a bitch...
and not given to acts of
pointless sentimentality.
It just don't seem right...
digging up that
treasure without him.
Maybe it's for the
best he was squished.
Why, he...
was barely a sentient being and...
well, as soon as we get
ourselves cleaned up...
and we get a little
smellum in our hair...
why, we're gonna feel 100%
better about ourselves...
and about... life in general.
Must be near Parchman Farm.
Sorry sons of bitches.
Seems like a year ago
we busted off the farm.
Pete got a brother?
Not that I'm aware.
Heat must be getting to me.
That was wonderful. That sure was.
Yes.
Now, I know the Sunnysiders
would agree with me...
when I say the great
state of Mississippi...
cannot afford 4 more
years of Pappy O'Daniel!
4 more years of cronyism!
Nepotism! Rascalism!
Of service to the interests!
Now, the choice,
she's a clear 'un.
Pappy O'Daniel, slave
of the interests.
Homer Stokes, servant
of the little man.
Ain't that right, little fella?
He ain't lyin'!
Ladies and gentlemen. The
little man has admonished me...
to grasp the broom of reform...
and sweep this state clean!
It's gonna be, "Back to
the flour mill, Pappy!"
The interests can take
care of themselves!"
come Tuesday...
we're gonna sweep the rascals out!
Clean government is
yours for the asking!
Folks, now the
little Wharvey gals!
Wharvey gals?
Did he just say
little Wharvey gals?
Come here, girls.
What y'all gonna sing for us?
"In the highways."
Goddamn it all!
You know them gals, Everett?
Hey, girls!
- Daddy!
Ha ha ha!
Daddy? He ain't our daddy.
Hell, I ain't. What's
this Wharvey gals?
Your name's McGill.
No, sir. Not since you
got hit by that train.
What are you talking about?
I wasn't hit by any train.
Mama says you was hit by a train.
- Blooey!
- Nothin' left.
Just a grease spot on the L & N.
Damn it, I wasn't
hit by any train!
That's why Mama's got
us back to Wharvey.
That's her maiden name.
You got a maiden name, Daddy?
No, Daddy don't have a maiden name.
See...
That's your misfortune.
That's right, and now
Mama's got a new beau.
He's a suitor.
Yeah, I heard about that.
Mama says he's bona fide.
Mmm.
He give her a ring?
Yes, sir. A big 'un.
- Gotta gem.
- Mama checked it.
It's bona fide.
He's a suitor.
What's his name?
Vernon T. Waldrip.
Uncle Vernon.
Till tomorrow.
Then he's gonna be Daddy.
I am the only daddy you got.
I am the damn paterfamilias.
But you ain't bona fide.
Where's your mama?
She's at the five-and-dime.
Buying nipples.
Daddy!
Hello, sugar! Ha ha!
How's my little girl?
Hi.
Who the hell's that?
Starla Wharvey.
Starla McGill, you mean.
How come you never
told me about her?
'Cause you was hit by a train.
That's another thing.
Why are you telling our
gals I was hit by a train?
Lots of respectable people
been hit by trains.
Judge Hobby over in Cookville
was hit by a train.
What was I supposed to tell 'em...
that you were sent
to the penal farm...
and I divorced you from shame?
I take your point.
But it does put me in a
damned awkward position...
vis à vis my progeny.
Hello, Penny.
Is this gentlemen bothering you?
You Waldrip?
Uh-huh. That's right.
Hmm.
You been using my hair treatment?
Your hair treatment?
Excuse me.
I got news for you.
In case you hadn't noticed.
I wasn't hit by a train...
and I have traveled
many a weary mile...
to be back with my wife
and my 6 daughters.
Seven, Daddy!
That ain't your daddy, Alvinelle.
Your daddy was hit by a train.
Penny, you stop that!
No, you stop it! Vernon
here's got a job.
Vernon's got prospects.
He's bona fide.
What are you?
I'll tell you what I am...
I am the paterfamilias,
and you can't marry him!
I can, I am, and I will. Tomorrow.
I got to think about the
little Wharvey gals.
They look to me for answers.
Vernon can support 'em...
and buy 'em lessons
on the clarinet.
The only good thing you
ever did for the gals...
was get hit by that train!
Why, you lying
unconstant succubus.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You can't swear at my fiancee!
Oh, yeah?
Well, you can't marry my wife!
Unh! Unh!
Who is that man?
He's not my husband.
Just a drifter, I guess.
Just some no-account drifter.
Aah! Unh!
And stay out of Woolworth's!
I'll bet she does imitations, too.
Deceitful, two-faced she-wolf.
Never trust a female, Delmar.
Remember that one
simple precept...
and your time with me will
not have been ill-spent.
Okay. Everett.
"Hit by a train."
Truth means nothing
to a woman, Delmar.
Triumph of the subjective.
You ever been with a woman?
Well, I've...
I-I got to get the
family farm back...
before I can start
thinking about that.
That's right. If then.
Believe me. Delmar, a woman
is the most fiendish...
instrument of torture
ever devised...
to bedevil the days of man.
Everett, I never figured
you for a paterfamilias.
Ohh, yes. I have spread my seed.
And look what it's...
Goddamn it. What the
hell's going on?
Okay, boys. Enjoy
your picture show.
Do... not... seek the treasure.
Do not...
seek the treasure.
It's a bushwhack.
They're fixin' an ambush.
Do not seek the treasure.
We...
We thought you was...
a toad.
We... thought...
you... was... a toad.
Do not seek the treasure.
Quiet there! Watch the picture!
I signed that bill.
I signed a dozen
agriculture bills.
Everyone knows I'm a
friend of the farmer.
What do I gotta do, start
tending livestock?
We can't do that, Daddy.
We might offend our constituency.
We ain't got a constituency!
Stokes got a constituency!
Well, it's a well-run campaign.
Midget and broom and whatnot.
Devil his due.
Hell of an organization.
Say, I got an idea.
What's that, junior?
We can hire us a little fella...
even smaller than Stokes's.
You slump-shouldered sack of nuts!
Why, we'd look like a bunch
of Johnny-come-latelys...
breakin' out our own midget.
Don't matter how stumpy!
And that's the goddamn
problem right there.
People think Stokes
has got fresh ideas.
He's au courant and
we're the past!
It's a problem of...
- Perception.
- That's right.
Reason why he's pulling
our pants down.
Gonna paddle a little behind.
Ain't gonna paddle it. Gonna kick it.
Real hard.
No, I believe he's
gonna paddle it.
I don't believe that's
a proper description.
Well, that's how I'd
characterize it.
I believe it's more of
a kickin' situation.
God-God forgive me.
I could not gaze
upon that far shore.
Pete.
Hold still!
Can't... stand much longer.
It was-it was a
mo-moment of weakness.
Quit yer babblin', Pete.
We gotta skedaddle.
That's all I got.
They lured me out for a bathe...
and then they dunked me,
trussed me up like a hog...
and turned me in for the bounty.
I should have guessed it.
Typical womanly behavior.
We're just lucky we left...
before they came back for us.
We didn't abandon you, Pete.
We just thought you was a toad.
No, they never did
turn me into a toad.
Well, that was our mistake then.
And we was beat up by
a bible salesman...
and banished from Woolworths.
I don't know, Everett.
Was it the one branch
or all of them?
Well, I ain't had it
easy, either, boys.
Frankly, uh, well, I...
I spilt my guts
about the treasure.
Huh?
I'm awful sorry I
betrayed you, fellas.
Must be my Hogwallop blood.
That's all right. Pete.
Awful white of you to take
it like that, Everett.
I feel wretched.
Spoiling your play for a
million dollar point two.
It's been eatin' at my guts.
Oh, that's all right.
You boys are true friends! Ohh!
You're my boon companions.
Pete, I don't want you...
to beat yourself
up about this, eh?
I can't help it...
but that's a-a wonderful
thing to say.
Yeah.
Pete, uh...
the fact of the matter is...
damn it.
There ain't no treasure.
Fact of the matter
is there never was.
But...
So where's all the money
from the armored car job?
Never knocked over no armored car.
Sent up for practicing
law without a license.
But...
Damn it, I had to bust out.
My wife wrote me she
was getting married...
I gotta stop it.
I had 2 weeks left on my sentence.
I couldn't wait 2 weeks.
She's getting married tomorrow.
My added time for the escape...
I don't get out now till 19... 87.
I am sorry about that.
I'll be...
84 years old.
I guess they'll tack on
50 years for me, too.
Boys, we was chained together.
I had to tell you something.
Busting out alone
was not an option.
I'm sorry.
84 years old.
Well, I'll only be 82.
You! You ruined my life!
Unh!
You ruined my life!
I do apologize about that, Pete.
84 years old!
I'll be going...
Delmar!
Now, boys. Boys.
That's Tommy. They got Tommy.
Noose.
Sweet Jesus, we got to save him.
The color guard.
Brothers!
Oh, brothers!
We have all gathered here...
to preserve our hallowed
culture and heritage...
from intrusion...
inclusion...
and dilution...
of color, of creed...
and of our old-time religion.
We aim to pull evil
up by the root...
before it chokes out...
the flower of our
culture and heritage.
And our women.
Let's not forget those
ladies, y'all...
looking to us for protection...
from darkies...
from jews...
from papists...
and from all those
smart-ass folks...
say we come descended
from monkeys.
That's not my culture
and heritage.
Yes!
Is that your culture and heritage?
No!
And so...
we gonna hang us a Negro.
Hooray, hooray!
I ain't never harmed you...
Neither of you gentlemen.
Uh...
Mm-hmm.
I ain't never harmed nobody.
Hey, hey, Tommy.
Huh?
Tommy, we come to rescue you.
That's mighty kind of you boys...
but I don't think nothing's
going to save me now.
The devil's come to
collect his due.
Don't be crazy, Tommy.
You don't want to get hanged.
Well, nah, I don't reckon I do...
but that's the way it
seems to be working out.
Listen, Tommy, I got a plan.
No!
The color guard is colored.
Who made them the color guard?
Run, boys!
Whoa!
No, no, son!
Can't let that flag
touch the ground!
Ooh.
Heh heh.
Leave me alone. Get
your hands off me.
I can do this myself.
Get away from me.
I'm saying we should
hire this man away.
That's a good idea, Pappy.
Hell of an idea.
Can't beat 'em. Join 'em.
Have him join us.
Run our campaign...
instead of that egghead's.
Enticements of power,
wealth, et cetera.
No one says no to Pappy O'Daniel.
Oh, gracious, no...
Not with his blandishments.
And powers of persuasion.
What's his name again?
The campaign manager?
Yes.
Waldrip.
Vernon Waldrip.
Vernon T. Waldrip.
Hmm.
It's an invitation-only affair.
We'll have to sneak in...
through the service entrance.
Hold on.
Wait a minute.
Who elected you leader
of this outfit?
Since we've been
following your lead...
we got nothing but trouble.
I've gotten this close
to being strung up...
and consumed in a fire
and whipped no end...
and sunstroked and soggied.
And turned into a frog.
He wasn't turned into a frog.
Almost loved up, though.
So, you're against me now, too?
Is that how it is, boys?
The whole world...
and God almighty...
Now you?
I guess I deserve it.
Boys...
I know that I made some
tactical mistakes...
but if you just stick with me...
I got a plan. Believe me. Boys...
we can fix this thing...
and I can get my wife back...
and we can get out of here.
Goddamn disgrace!
Made a travesty of
the entire evening.
Ohh.
What I wouldn't give to get
ahold of those agitators.
I mean, whoever heard
of such behavior...
even amongst the colored?
Or mulattos, maybe.
I suspect some miscegenation
in their heritage.
How else you going to explain it?
Using a confederate
flag as a missile...
Crazy! No one's ever
going to believe...
we're a real band.
No. It's going to work.
I just got to get close
enough to talk to her.
Taking off with us has
got more future...
than marrying some
guy named Waldrip.
I'm goddamn bona fide.
I got the answers.
Everett, my beard itches.
Hey. Hey.
"In the Jailhouse Now," fellers...
neighborhood of "B."
Psst!
Penny.
Ahem.
It's me.
No.
Honey, honey.
We're leaving the state.
Pursuing opportunities
in another venue.
I got big plans.
Not minstrels... this
here's just a dodge.
I'm going to be a dentist.
I know this guy who'll
print me up a license.
Why, that is an
improper suggestion.
I-I-l can't switch sides...
in the middle of a campaign...
Especially to work for a
man who lacks moral fiber.
Moral fiber?
Why, you little
pasty-face sumbitch.
I invented moral fiber.
Pappy O'Daniel was displaying...
rectitude and high-mindedness...
when that egghead you work for...
was still messing his drawers.
Psst! Honey.
Go away.
I want to be what you
want me to be, honey.
I want you and the
gals to come with me.
What. Dear?
What are you doing here, Pappy?
Well, I guess someone let on...
we was giving out liquor.
Yeah, well. You'll be laughing...
out the other side of
your face come November.
Pappy O'Daniel will
be laughing then.
Not out the other side of his face.
Though.
Oh, no, no, no. Just
the regular side.
They're my daughters, too, Penny.
Ain't you ever heard
of amor fidelis?
Hot damn! It's the
Soggy Bottom Boys!
Oh!
Whoo!
Holy moley!
These boys are a hit.
But, Pappy, they's integrated.
Wait a minute.
Well, I guess folks don't
mind they's integrated.
You's miscegenated.
All you boys is miscegenated!
Give me the microphone!
These boys is not white.
Hell, they ain't even old-timey.
Look, I happen to know,
ladies and gentlemen...
that this band of
miscreants here...
this very evening...
interfered with a lynch mob...
in the performance of its duties.
Oh, yeah, it's true.
See, I belong to a
certain secret society.
I don't believe I got to
mention its name, you know?
Let 'em play! Go on!
Hmm.
And these boys here...
they trampled all over our
venerated observances...
and rituals.
Now, this here music
is over, all right?
And I have-No! Hey!
Hey, I ain't... listen to me.
Folks, listen to me. I...
These boys desecrated
a fiery cross.
We was all havin' a good time!
And they's convicts, folks...
Fugitives escaped off the farm.
Now, folks, these boys
got to be remanded...
to the authorities.
Criminals!
And I have it from the
highest authority...
that that Negro sold
his soul to the devil!
Ohh!
Wait, wait, wait a
minute, now, folks.
No! It's true!
It's true.
Wait a minute. Wait
a minute, folks.
Is you is, or is you
ain't my constituency?
No!
Is you is, or is you ain't...
my constituency?
No!
Is you is...
Is you is, or is you ain't...
My constituency?
Oh, come on, folks.
No. It's Homer now.
Come on. I'm a friend
of the little man.
- Ha ha ha ha!
- Waah!
This is not fair!
Hey! Come on!
Come on, now, folks...
we got a little
misunderstanding here.
Goddamn!
Goddamn! Opportunity knocks.
Get out of my way!
That's fine.
That's fine!
Ladies and gentlemens...
here and listening at home...
the great state of Mississippi...
Pappy O'Daniel, governor...
Wants to thank the
Soggy Bottom Boys...
for that wonderful performance.
And it looks like...
the only man in
this great state...
who ain't a music lover...
is my esteemed opponent
in the upcoming...
Homer Stokes.
Yeah, well. There ain't
no accounting for taste.
He sounded to me like
he was harboring...
some kind of hateful grudge...
against the Soggy Bottom Boys...
on account of their
rough and rowdy past.
Looks like-
Looks like...
Homer Stokes is the
kind of fellow...
wants to cast the first stone.
Well, I'm with you, folks.
I'm a forgive and
forget Christian...
and I say if their
rambunctiousness...
and misdemeanoring
is behind them...
It is, ain't it, boys?
Yes, sir, it is.
Well, then. I say...
by the power vested in me...
these boys is hereby pardoned.
And furthermore...
in the second Pappy
O'Daniel administration...
these boys is going to
be in my brain trust.
What's that mean, Everett?
Well, Delmar, it means
that you and me...
and Pete and Tommy
are going to be...
the power behind the
throne, so to speak.
Oh, okay.
So, without further ado...
and by way of endorsing
my candidacy...
the Soggy Bottom Boys...
is going to lead us
all in a chorus...
of "You Are My Sunshine."
Ain't you, boys?
Governor. It's one
of our favorites.
Son...
you're going to go far.
I guess Vernon T. Waldrip...
is gonna be going on relief.
Maybe I can throw a little
patronage his way...
Get him a job digging ditches...
or rounding up stray dogs.
So, is the marriage off,
then, Miss Wharvey?
It's McGill.
No. The marriage will
take place as planned.
With a little change of cast.
Me and the little lady are
going to pick up the pieces...
and retie the knot,
mixaphorically speaking.
You boys are invited, of course.
Hell, you're the best men.
I already got the rings.
Where's your ring, honey?
I ain't worn it since our
divorce came through.
It must still be in the
roll-top in the old cabin.
Never thought I'd need it.
Vernon bought one
encrusted with jewels.
Now's the time to buy
it off him cheap.
We ain't getting
married with his ring.
You said you'd changed.
Honey, it's just an
old pewter thing.
Ain't going to be no wedding.
It's just a symbol, honey.
No wedding.
We'll go fetch it
with you, Everett.
It's just a... Shut up, Delmar.
It's just a symbol.
I've spoken my piece
and counted to 3.
She counted to 3.
Goddamn it.
Son of a bitch!
You have any idea how
far that cabin is?
George?
Hello, boys!
Well, these little men...
finally caught up with the
criminal of the century.
Looks like the chair
for George Nelson.
Yup, gonna electrify me.
I'm going to go off
like a Roman candle.
Ha ha ha!
20,000 volts...
chasing a rabbit
through yours truly.
Gol damn...
gonna suck all the power
right out of the state.
Gonna shoot sparks out
the top of my head...
and lightning from my fingertips!
I'm George Nelson...
and I'm feeling 10 feet tall!
Looks like George is
right back on top again.
Cow killer!
Well, at least you
boys get to see...
the ancestral manse...
The home where I spent
so many a happy day...
in the bosom of my family...
refugin', if you will...
With a mighty oak
tree out front...
and a happy little
tire swing on it.
Where's the happy
little tire swing?
End of the road, boys.
No. Wait a minute.
Let's go. Boys.
It's had its twists and turns.
Now it deposits you here.
Wait a minute.
You have eluded fate...
and you have eluded me...
for the last time.
Tie their hands, boys.
You can't do this, now.
Didn't know you'd be
bringing a friend.
He'll just have to
wait his turn...
share one of your graves.
You can't do this.
We just got pardoned by
the governor hisself.
It went out on the radio.
Is that right?
Well, we ain't got a radio.
God have mercy.
It ain't fittin'.
It ain't the law.
The law?
The law is a human institution.
Perhaps you should start
making your prayers.
Oh, my God.
Everett?
Tommy, I'm sorry we
got you into this.
Good Lord...
what do we do?
Oh, Lord...
please look down and recognize...
us poor sinners.
Please, Lord.
I just want to see
my daughters again.
I've been separated from
my family for so long.
I know I've been
guilty of pride...
and sharp dealing.
I'm sorry that I
turned my back on you.
Forgive me.
We're helpless, Lord.
For the sake of my family.
For Tommy's sake.
For Delmar's and Pete's.
Let me see my daughters
again, Lord.
Help us, please.
Ahh. Ahh.
A miracle.
It was a miracle!
Delmar, don't be ignorant.
I told you they was
flooding this valley.
No! That ain't it!
We prayed to God and he pitied us!
Well, it never fails.
Once again, you two
hayseeds are showin'
how much you want for intellect.
There's a perfectly
scientific explanation...
for what just happened.
That ain't the tune
you was singin'...
back there at the gallows!
Well, any human being
will cast about...
in a moment of stress.
No, the fact is, they're
flooding this valley...
so they can hydroelectric
up the whole durn state.
Yes, sir, the South
is gonna change.
Everything's gonna be
put on electricity...
and run on a paying basis.
Out with the old
spiritual mumbo jumbo...
the superstitions, and
the backward ways.
We're gonna see a
brave new world...
where they run everybody a wire...
and hook us all up to a grid.
Yes, sir, a veritable
age of reason.
Like the one they had in France.
Not a moment too soon.
Hey, there's Tommy.
Tommy, what you ridin' there?
Unh! Whoa.
Roll-top desk.
"All's well that ends
well." some poet said.
That's right, honey.
Don't mind telling you
I'm awful pleased...
my adventuring days
have come to an end.
Time for this old boy
to enjoy some repose.
That's good, honey.
You were right about
that ring, too.
Any other wedding
band wouldn't do.
This here was fore-ordained.
Fate was a-smilin' on me.
That's not my ring.
What? Not your ring?
That's one of Aunt Hurlene's.
You said it was in
the roll-top desk.
I said I thought it was
in the roll-top desk.
No, you said...
Or under the mattress.
Or maybe in my chifforobe.
I don't know.
Well, I'm sorry, honey.
We need that ring.
That ring is at the bottom
of a pretty durn big lake.
Uh-uh.
A 9,000-hectare lake.
I don't care if it's 90.000.
That lake was not my doing.
Of course not, honey...
I counted to 3, honey.
No, wait, honey.
Finding one little
ring in the middle...
of all that water is one
hell of a heroic task!