Whoo-hoo!
G-a-b, hey! G-a-b, hey!
It's so much soul
Who's got the souls
of Rolling Stones?
On the road that's cold
What do we do? We G-a-b
With the groove, with the vibe
With the rhythm completely
Jump on the mike, I bet
We got soul, and don't you forget it
So come, come, come,
come, come again
I'm rocking on the mike
So much soul
We're young, we're hip
Get up, get up, get up,
get up, get up...
Come on, man. Let's go.
We've got soul
Uh, uh, uh, uh-huh
I got it, you got it
He's got soul
Here we go, here we go
You got it
1, 2, here we go again
Your mouth's ready to blow again
Making sure, jack...
"Reihi was a Taniwha.
"She lived at the bottom
of a huge lake.
"She spent most of her time
"taking care of a greenstone wall.
"The wall stopped the water
"from flooding over the people
"who lived by Reihi's lake.
"Once a month, the people would bring
"a huge piece of greenstone
to help Reihi keep the wall strong. "
especially if you drive around
the big towns, people.
Hope you love my wife, you know...
I was just checking out
the weather situation.
A few showers as well
and light winds at first,
but it's going to be getting better
throughout the day and the night...
A bit of cloud
and a bit of rain as well.
People, I've just had
a phone call from Darren.
Now, apparently, Darren's
just lost his girlfriend.
Brother...
I'd say we are in business, my man.
What's happening, everybody?
Aah!
Settle down!
"Then the children
would run and laugh
as they collected all the fish
Reihi had left for them. "
Was it a good story, kids?
Well, I liked it.
No. It's dumb.
What's a Taniwha?
It's a creature
that looks after people.
Where the fuck is everyone?!
What are you doing home?
I got something for you.
Come on, Hu, let's go!
Go on, open it.
What do you reckon, kids?
- Yeah!
Oh, yum!
- Oh, Jake!
- Look at all the kai moana!
Bloody oceans of the stuff!
- I'm hungry!
- Me, too!
Go on, kids. Grab some.
Take it outside.
Come on, Hu.
Got to eat them outside.
Where the fuck you off to?
Come have a feed, boy.
No.
Fuck him.
Jake, not on the table, hon.
Oh, why not? I want a feed.
Well, the kids might come in.
Well, what about the chair?
Remember?
So...
where did all the seafood come from?
I got lucky.
I got laid off.
What?
Whoa, whoa, woman. Let me finish.
Jake Heke, you've got
a family to feed.
- You've got bills.
- Look, I've signed up for the dole.
It's only 17 bucks a week
less than my wages.
Well, don't look like that.
It's not the end of the world.
What about our house?
We got a house,
and the government ain't
going to kick us out.
The rent's cheap.
I want us to have
our own home, Jake.
Damn you. We can't make
bloody ends meet as it is.
Forget the bloody house.
Let's talk about the bedroom.
Oh, don't, Jake!
You fucking got to spoil
everything, don't you?
Fuck you!
Ooh, yeah, ooh, yeah, ooh, yeah
Scoo da da do wa oh
Ooh, I left this mark
on this world
Ooh, yeah, ooh, yeah, ooh, yeah
Scoo da da do wa oh
Yo, Toot.
Yo, G.
What you up to?
Oh, you know, a bit
of this and the other.
You never know when
the Queen might drop by.
Well, if she does,
here's something to feed her.
Bloody Santa Claus!
Do you think we'll ever
get out of here, Toot?
I don't know.
Maybe.
You know, when I'm old enough
to get the dole,
I might just do this baby up
and drive on out.
Can I come, too?
Of course. You're my best mate.
Hey, Gracie, did you
bring your book?
Oh, I forgot.
I just finished a new story, too,
but I can remember most of it.
Choice!
The story was about a Taniwha.
Do you know what a Taniwha is?
Well, Reihi was a Taniwha.
She lived at the bottom
of this lake.
Now, she spent most of her time
looking after this huge
greenstone wall.
The wall stopped the water
from flooding over the people
who lived by Reihi's lake.
Once a month, the people would bring...
Beth Heke?
What now?
Been keeping bad company.
Was that before or after
you picked him up?
So what's the charge?
Oh, he's lucky this time.
Two older boys stole the car.
He's just hanging around
with the wrong crowd.
Still, it's not going
to look good tomorrow
when he appears in court
on those other charges.
You think you know everything
about us, don't you?
It's my job.
Is she a Taniwha, Mom?
No, son.
Well, we'll leave
Boogie with you, then.
- Mark.
- Pardon?
My son's name is Mark.
Well, that's not
the name he gave us.
You get those lonely, lonely
Lonely, lonely blues
When you're on your own.
Mm-hmm
So all you've got to do
Is call up on the phone
No need to be alone.
Mm-hmm
And if you lose your way
And you've got nowhere to go...
The usual.
What's your fucking problem?
Check that out, bro.
The man can sure pack a punch.
He's been behind bars, I bet.
Yeah, right. Bloody zoo.
If I wanted to drink with women,
I'd drink in the bloody
lounge bar, huh?
I've had women up to here.
Come on, Polly. Help your sister.
Set the table, girl.
There are reports that they've had
at least one sighting of the Virgin.
Oh, no wonder we got it...
Why, Boog?
Don't know.
You don't know?
Do you know you
have to go to court tomorrow?
Do you remember what Bennett said?
Jeez, Boog, what's
bloody wrong with you?
Don't know.
When you were a kid,
you wouldn't even take
a piece of fruit without asking.
You're going to come
tomorrow, aren't you, Mom?
Yes, we'll be there. Will you?
Yeah. Just keep your hands
in your pockets there, brother.
Come on, bro. I'd just
like to see them smile.
Oh, you mean like this?
You dirty bastard.
I can make mine smile all right.
I just can't make the woman happy.
I took a big feed
of seafood home today...
bloody everything.
Just wanted to put
a smile on her face.
You think she'd let me? No chance.
All I told her was I got laid off.
Anyone would have thought I told her
that my prick dropped off.
Laid off twice in one day, eh, bro?
Poor bastard.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
You're leaving home in the morning
You come on home in the night
Ooh, babe...
Fucking beautiful.
And when I ask you, babe
You just say, you're right
But you don't know
What my heart's been going through
Staying up late
Just waitin' on you
When will you be the one for me?
Oh, yeah, without your love
I can't make it
You're all...
Gee, where did you
get those muscles from?
Bro, you've been lifting
those weights, huh?
What, you've done lag?
Am I right?
You want to fuck with me?
You should learn
to pay your respects.
In case you want
to know, it's Jake...
Jake the Muss.
Mmm, loving you is all I need, boy
I was right... too much weights,
not enough speed work.
Useless prick.
Cheers.
Into me
Am I not enough for you...
Party at my place tonight, boys.
Come on, Poll. Bed.
Come on, Hu.
Hurry up, Polly.
Thanks, Bub.
- Good night, Mum.
- Night-night, Polly.
You, too, mister.
You've got a big day tomorrow.
You won't forget, eh, Mum?
How can I forget
with you reminding me
every 5 minutes?
Good night, son.
Good night, Mum.
Whoo-hoo!
Your old man was
sure swinging tonight.
He'll be swinging, all right,
by the time I've finished with him.
Did you hear he got the sack?
Doesn't surprise me, girl...
days he took off.
Beth, babe.
Dooley!
You should have seen
the Muss in action.
It was beautiful.
He decked a bloody gorilla.
He was big. Man, was he big.
Fucking huge.
It has to be said...
almost as big as that
thing in Bully's pants.
Notice he said almost, ladies?
Yeah, right.
Hey, girl, you should have
seen him, though.
Dool's right... big...
and bloody ugly.
Well, he didn't get
everything right, though.
Well, it's just that Bully
isn't that big, girl.
- Whoo!
Mmm, you're hot tonight, girl.
Yeah, ever since Jake
put his hand halfway up my skirt.
Ooh, I might have to
go home early tonight.
Yo, Mave. Give us a song.
Come on, Mave!
How about you and Beth sing for me?
- Yeah!
OK, OK, OK.
Give us a G. Give us a G.
Well, I've tried
- Whoo!
As hard as I can
Just to make you
Understand
'Cause the world
It won't stop
It keeps goin'
Goin' round and round
I guess the nature
The nature of love
Hurts always, always
What are you doing?
Couldn't you sleep, either?
Aren't they beautiful
when they're like that?
I wish I could see them.
I remember
They're just drunk. That's all.
All those yesterdays
People show their true feelings
when they're drunk.
Understanding
Man, Gracie, you've got
some far-out ideas.
I thought Mum said
you were growing up.
At least I'm not going
to court tomorrow.
Oh, sorry, Boog.
I didn't mean it.
Oh, what the hell.
What's the worst that can happen?
The nature of love
And it's always,
always been this way
So, now, my lover
There'll be no other
The stars in the heavens
Will shine forever
Moments we treasure
You and I in love
So, darlin'
Here is my heart
Ohh
Yeah
- Whoo!
You're a hard lady, Bethie.
And you're a hard man, Jakey.
Play another one, someone.
Next time, watch what you say
in front of the fucking women!
How's that for true feelings?
Oh, don't play that shit, friend.
Play something we all know.
Later!
Have a feed. Have a feed.
Have a feed.
Hey, Mavis, come have
a drink with me, mate!
What's up with bloody Millie?
Is she spoiling the party, or what?
Too much gin and not enough sex.
Hey, hey, hey.
I'm not going to miss out tonight.
Dooley, eh?
Strike when the pants
are ready to drop.
Looks like they've
already dropped, Mave.
Bloody bastard!
Never mind him, Mave.
Come have a feed.
There's still a bit left
in the bottom.
Dooley, what the fuck
are you doing?
You're with me!
Got any money?
Money?
What for?
You don't need money.
You got everything
you want right here.
You got booze, food.
The old man.
Don't give me your bullshit excuses!
Come on. Let's go.
Have a drink with me, son.
Remember how we used to
talk and laugh?
We could talk and talk,
you and me.
Remember?
You're drunk.
I'm not drunk.
I'm happy.
Then you're out of your fuckin' head.
Oh, I'm so sorry, babe.
I didn't... hang on.
Hang on, son. I got some money.
Hey, cook us some eggs, eh, Beth?
Ooh, and some bacon.
Fuck off!
What the fuck's going on?
I asked for some eggs, but...
Cook the man some eggs.
You want eggs?
Well, have the bloody lot of them!
It's OK, man.
Cook the man some fucking eggs.
Do it yourself, Jake!
I'm not the fuckin' slave
around here, Jake!
No, you can...
You're a fuckin' coward!
Leave her alone,
you fucking bastard!
Stop it! Stop it!
It's OK, Poll.
Shh! Shh!
Shush, Hu.
Shh!
I want Mummy!
Shush, Hu.
It's OK, Poll.
Your fuckin' mouth!
You do as you're fucking told!
Fuck. Last time, I got 20 bucks.
So what are you up to, Gracie?
You could help.
Not me. Waste of bloody time.
You should leave it.
There'll be plenty of time
for you to clean up
after drunken fucking parties.
What do you mean?
When you get married, girl.
Who said I want to?
It's just the way things are.
No. The fellas around here
are too ugly.
It's just a matter of time, Gracie.
Who did the prick smack over?
Grace?
The fuckin' bastard!
Where are you going?
Out of this fuckin' hole!
They've eaten the whole lot.
I'm hungry.
How about some Chinese?
Yuck!
Where's Mum?
Well, she's not bloody here, is she?
Look, there's one more pea.
Mum?
Yeah, I know, Boog.
Do you want an aspirin?
Listen, Boog...
Grace can go with you, eh?
Give a good impression.
I'm not feeling the best, son.
Just give me time to wash up.
Nothing that a good
coffee won't fix.
I'll catch a later bus.
OK, Boog?
Ya, sure.
We love the reggae girls,
we love the reggae girls
The reggae music make you
jump and stomp, yes
dance and prance, yes
So everybody come
and shake your butt, yes
'Cause this the music,
and I'm the best, yes
And this is something
that they must confess, yes...
Do you reckon we should go in?
Nah. Wait for Mum.
Come on, son. We're running late.
Didn't I tell you I was
picking you up this morning?
Forgot.
Come on.
Bit of trouble
at your place last night.
Look, Mark, I have to be honest.
You're on remand.
The cops say they
found you on the streets.
They're going to try
and persuade the judge
that your parents can't control you.
I've seen your mother.
I don't think she's going
to make it here this morning.
She's going to catch a later bus.
- Morning.
- Hi.
Mark, you ready? Better go in.
Come on.
Nig Heke, eh?
Son of Jake the Muss.
You a bit of a chip off
the old block, boy?
I'm nothing like him.
Yeah, we'll see.
So today's the day, boy.
Judgment day.
How bad do you want in?
Didn't hear you, boy.
I want a patch.
You hear that, brothers?
He wants a patch.
You'll have to get through me first.
Do all right with women, boy?
I do all right.
Must be your flashy smile, eh?
Value your teeth?
You like your pretty-boy face.
Call you Michael Jackson,
except we'll rearrange it for free.
You think about that, boy,
before you think about any patch.
Is that right, Mark?
You admit to the burglaries?
And what about these
motor-vehicle charges?
Will you be withdrawing those?
Yes, your honor, but we recommend
that Mark goes into
social welfare custody.
Take your hat off, please, sergeant.
We picked him up yesterday.
Sir, it's pretty clear
that his parents
can't look after him.
And, um...
what do you two have?
I'm in a difficult position.
I've had no contact
with Mark's parents, and...
Yes, well, I was hoping
the boy's mother would be here today.
I was around there this morning,
and after what I saw...
I don't think Mark
should be at home.
Yes. Yes. All right.
Things seem to be going
from bad to worse
for you, don't they, Mark?
Under the circumstances,
if your parents can't control you,
I'll have to remand you
in social welfare custody.
Nig Heke's brother.
Looks like a fucking poofter to me.
Baby, you can fuck
with me any day.
Now, you can either
do this the hard way,
or you can make it work for you.
- It's your choice.
- What do you mean?
You can let me help you,
and you might learn something,
or you could end up in jail.
Because that's where you're heading.
Sorry to interrupt.
Can I see you a moment?
Uh, yeah. I'll see you outside.
Please try, Boog.
It can't be that bad, eh?
At least you'll be doing
something different.
Hey, I could even write to you.
I've never had anyone
to write to before.
Gee, girl, you started without me.
Jeez, woman, is that the result
of one hell of an orgasm or what?
What the hell happened?
Same old story.
Never learn to keep my mouth shut.
Help yourself to a beer.
Ah, what the hell.
Surprised there's any left.
Well, you know the rules, girl.
Keep your mouth shut
and your legs open.
Didn't get to court, then, eh?
Like this?
Do more harm than good.
Welfare came round this morning.
Promised Boog I'd be there for him.
That boy's got to learn
to stand on his own two feet.
You're going to
have to take a chain saw
to those apron strings, girl.
He's not strong
like the others, Mave.
Ah, shit. I remember
when he was a wee fella.
Couldn't tear him off you.
He'll be all right.
It's Nig I'd worry about.
It doesn't seem
like that long ago
that Nig was a baby.
Well, he's not a baby anymore,
that's for sure!
Jeez, you should have
seen Jake, Mave,
boasting about his baby boy...
till Nig started crying at night.
That's about when those
two parted company.
Ain't that the truth?
Bloody men.
Jeez, he was a beautiful baby, Mave.
Oh, enough bloody talk, girl.
Hit the fella over the head!
Tell him to wake his ideas up.
Bloody gangs.
Kati!
So how you doing, boy?
The brothers can't hear you, boy.
Timata!
Kati!
Brother,
now you've met your new family.
Grace!
I wanted to be there, Grace.
I couldn't.
They'd have sent him away.
You've seen the state of me, Bub.
They did.
They did, Mum.
They sent Boog away.
But how can they do that...
just take someone's son away?
It's OK, Mum.
Boog seemed OK.
He should be at home with us.
Can't a man get some
fuckin' sleep around here?
Fuck, woman, you look fucking awful.
Go clean yourself up.
This is as cleaned up
as I get, you bastard.
Tried getting cleaned up
all morning
so I could go to court with our son.
Our son, Jake!
What the fuck's Nig been up to?
You have no idea, do you?
Boogie!
Boogie? Is that right?
He's gone, Jake.
He's gone to welfare, and you slept
through the whole bloody thing.
Is that all?
Is that what all this
slamming of fucking doors,
crying, and carrying on is about?
Fuck!
The boy is soft.
It'll toughen him up.
Anyone would think
he bloody died or something.
Hey, so go do something
about the way you look.
You're starting to
make me feel fucking sick.
You did this to me, you bastard.
I hope you spew your guts out.
You know your fucking
problem, eh, woman?
You're too bloody lippy,
too bloody smart-mouthed.
You're a bad example
for the fucking kids.
Always writing, aren't you?
Too fucking smart.
You'll end up like
your mother here.
I hate him.
Bring your book here, Bub.
What you been writing?
I was going to write to Boog.
You got a good nature, girl.
Mr. Bennett said we could visit.
It's all right for those fellas.
They've got everything
at their fingertips...
flashy car, plenty of money.
Easy for them.
Knew we couldn't.
I didn't say we couldn't.
It just won't be easy.
Got to find the money.
Do you think we could?
Yes. Yes, I do.
I promise.
I love you, Mum.
I love you, too, Bub.
Come and suck on this.
You fellas are too ugly.
Did you hear? Boog got sent away.
Yeah, I heard.
- Boys' home, right?
- Ya.
- You want a puff?
- Nah.
Well, yeah. Why not?
He's going to be OK, though.
And you know why?
Because Mum said we can visit...
you know, as a family.
Isn't that choice?
Yeah. Yeah. Choice.
What do you think
it'll be like?
What? The boys' home?
Got to be better than this car.
You going to hold on to that
till it goes out?
Oh. Sorry.
You're the only one
I can talk to.
You know that, Toot?
Yeow, G. Best mates...
forever.
250 smackeroonies.
Fuckin' beautiful.
Fuckin' tin-ass.
Must be your shout, eh, bro?
Yeah, all right, all right.
Well, bloody hell.
I should have brought
the video camera.
Get out and stay out,
you fucking bastard!
Hey, Muss.
Have a win on the Gigis, Muss?
Look at the bloody
state of you, man.
You're a fucking mess.
Don't you ever speak
to me again, you hear?
You might spoil my night.
Good evening, ladies.
I've just had a bit of a windfall,
and since you're looking
so bloody beautiful,
I thought I might buy
you gals a drink,
especially the one
standing here
in his fucking party dress.
Barman, 6 milk shakes, eh?
Easy on the ice cream.
Ooh. Forget it, lady.
You looked better
before you turned around.
Fuck, boy, you're too much.
If you want to be
like your old man,
learn how to stand
on your own two feet.
Fuck. Is that your old man?
Piss off.
I don't have an old man.
You're still a bloody
attractive woman.
You mean after you
take to me with your fists?
You make me sick.
Oh, hon, you still
on about the other week?
I told you, I'm sorry.
And I told you
when I get like that,
get out of my way.
But you have to get
all lippy on me.
I got a temper on me,
but who hasn't?
You're priceless.
Well, at least I try
to make it up to you.
Get off me, Jake.
Oh, you're a hard lady.
Hey, where do you think
you're going?
Sit down and keep a man company.
I've got things to think about.
Like what?
Since when were you interested?
Well, if you can't tell
by the way I just grabbed you,
I must be losing my touch.
If you're not gonna take me
seriously, Jake...
Take it easy. Talk to Jakey.
It's just...
It's just what?
Jeez, you're pretty.
I want us to visit Boogie.
Is that all?
Go together, as a family.
You know, make a day of it,
take up a nice picnic lunch.
Maybe we could rent
a car for the day.
Oh, yeah. Maybe we could
fuckin' fly.
It's not impossible, Jake.
I've worked it out.
There's the money Auntie Matawai
sent me at Christmas.
If I put a bit aside each week
from the housekeeping,
in a month, maybe we could go.
Please, Jake?
And this whole day
means a lot to you, huh?
Yes.
Book the fuckin' limousine.
Horses, babe.
Honest.
Now, will you come here?
Tell Jakey you love him.
That's the trouble,
Jake. I do.
- What's going on?
- It's Heke, sir.
He's got your taiaha, sir.
If you want to smash things, boy,
you start with me!
You think you're man enough
to hold a taiaha, boy?
I hate this fucking place!
You're not supposed to like it!
Let me go, you black bastard!
We are the same color, boy!
The British used to think
the bayonet was the most lethal
of all hand-to-hand
combat weapons,
till they came across our warriors,
who fought with a taiaha.
You think your fist
is your weapon?
When I have taught you,
your mind will be.
You'll carry your
taiaha inside you.
Come on.
Whoa, this is the life, eh, kids?
Don't even have to change gears.
Want to come and visit
your brother, son?
Nah. Got something else on.
Oh, come on, son...
as a family.
What? Too fucking busy
to visit your own brother, boy?
Rather be with a pack of wankers.
He would have come, Jake,
if you would have waited.
He would have.
Visits don't start
till after lunch.
We may as well take
a drive, eh, kids?
- Yeah!
What's the time, Mr. Wolf?
What's the time?
I said 1:00
2:00
3:00
4:00
5:00
6:00
Spooly, spooly,
spooly ooly dooly booly
7:00
8:00
9:00, widdly widdly widdly,
wee, wee, oh
What's the time, Mr. Wolf?
What's the time?
What's that place over there, Mum?
Taku Whenua Tuturu.
My piece of dirt.
That's where I was
brought up, kids.
What's that big house
over there, Mum?
That's the Wharenui.
It was a lot different
when I was a girl.
It was always impressive.
What's impressive?
Choice.
It was always choice.
And inside are the most
choicest carvings.
Go on, mum.
Oh, and inside are photos
of the old people
and the Tukutuku panels.
You know, I used to help Nannie
and Auntie Matawai repair them.
Well, why don't we
ever go there, Mum?
One day we'll all end up there.
See over there to the right?
That's the Urupa...
the family cemetery.
All my family are buried there.
I'd love to go and see them.
Not before me, you don't.
Your father and I
were going to get hitched there.
Except we didn't.
I wasn't bloody good enough...
not for their royal highness.
Tell them everything,
why don't you?
Your mother was beautiful...
pride of the fucking tribe...
And this old black-ass comes along
and steals her away.
And you know where
I come from, kids?
A long line of slaves.
Fucking slaves.
I'd like to see those wankers
call Jake the Muss that now.
Ah, this place gives me the creeps.
Come on, kids.
Doesn't give me the creeps.
You never met my grandmother.
Eh, Jake?
Jake?
Just want to show
our flash car to my mates.
Whoa, bro, you know what
the penalty is for car theft?
Just one beer, huh?
One, Jake.
Just the one.
Promise?
Cross my heart.
Cheer.
Ah, cheer.
Cheer, bro.
Cheer.
How long is Dad gonna be?
I'd get that tone out of your voice
if I were you.
How many times have
you seen your father
like today, Grace?
Never... that's how many,
so just give him a chance, eh?
Now running on the track,
it's Robin the Fair...
Bethie! Name your poison.
Oh, no, thanks, Dooley.
Jake and I are going to
visit our son Boogie.
- Aren't we, Jake?
- Yeah, yeah. Just a minute.
I'm trying to listen
to the horse race.
You promised, Jake.
Shut up, woman.
You'll make me miss
who won the fuckin' race.
The kids are hungry.
Well, feed them.
You got bootloads of the stuff.
We'll be waiting.
Come on, come on.
Come up, come up.
So he's not coming?
Oh, he's coming, all right.
You're hopeful.
No, Grace.
It's just a woman's
lot, that's all.
One day you'll understand.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Stop, stop.
It's good, but it's
not good enough!
I've told you fellas
time and again,
this haka won't work
until you get the first action right!
You're reaching up
for all these ancestral lines,
and you're pulling them
down into your body!
The weight of your ancestors.
Some of you look
as though you're reaching
for butterflies or something.
Now, let's do it again...
and wake up!
And I in love
So, darling, here is my heart
Give me the keys, Jake.
I said, give me the keys.
What for?
I'm going to visit Boogie.
Bad idea.
The problem is
you've spoiled the boy.
You've got to toughen him up.
Give me the bloody keys!
That's it, woman. Just fuck off!
Take a bloody taxi.
You got all my bloody money.
Fuck.
I remember
All those yesterdays
Come on kids.
We'll walk around
to the taxi stand.
Taxi? What for?
We're going home.
No. We're going to see Boogie.
You promised.
Please, Grace, try to understand.
I don't want to listen
to any more of your lies.
I hate you! I hate you both!
Come on, kids.
Boogie? Son?
We were on our way.
We rented a car for the trip.
We had a bit of an accident, son.
Oh, well, you know
what your father's like
when he gets behind the wheel.
Had a picnic lunch all prepared.
Stayed up all last night.
I got in just what you like.
It was just a stupid accident.
Whoa. Party at my place tonight, boys.
- Hello!
- Hey!
Fuck. I need to piss.
Thanks, mate.
We really needed to know that.
Bethie, you awake?
Come party with us.
No.
No more, Jake.
I could tell straightaway
it was a holding.
What's more, it's
my mate's holding.
Next thing I know,
I give him a smack.
Oh, if it isn't Gracie.
Hu wanted some water.
Come and give your uncle a kiss.
You're growing up fast, girl.
Where's mum?
She's in bed, where you should be.
What happened then, Jake?
He comes back at me
with this crowbar.
Yeah? And then what?
I take the crowbar off him
and give him another smack.
Good night, Hu.
Night-night.
Shh. Shh. It's OK, Gracie.
Uncle Bully is going
to be gentle with you...
as gentle as a lamb.
Shh.
Shh. Shh.
Your mum and dad are going to be
real angry at you,
turning me on like that...
coming downstairs in nothing
but that flimsy little nightie.
Shh, shh, shh.
It's our secret, hey, Gracie?
You hear me, girl?
Keep your mouth shut.
Did Huata wet the bed again, Bub?
You should have left it.
I'd have done that.
Just go away.
Go away.
Look, I don't blame you, Grace.
I wanted to see Boogie
as much as you.
You don't care about any of us.
That's not true.
I love you all.
But you're a liar!
Go on...
got your period, Bub.
It's bound to make you
a bit uptight...
Get out! Get out!
What's for breakfast?
You want something to eat,
fix it yourself.
Give me a coffee.
Go and have a wash, Jake.
Clean your ears out
while you're at it.
What the fuck's up with you?
I'm not going to
take this anymore.
Do you hear me, Jake Heke?
No more.
We never got to see Boogie.
I don't want any more
of these drunken parties
or your bloody ugly
mongrel mates coming around.
It's no good...
no good for the kids,
especially now Grace is growing.
Who the fuck do you
think you are, eh?
Sitting there like
Lady Bloody Muck,
telling me in my own house
who I can and can't have here.
Well, I've asked
them back tonight,
and you'd better be ready for it.
Do you hear me?!
Now, get off your fat ass
and get busy.
Oh, Grace!
Leave that kid alone!
You know, that's your problem.
You spoil the lot of them!
No wonder they're all
so fucking screwed up!
It's got nothing to do with you,
eh, Jake Heke?
You're such good father material!
You chased Nig off!
You couldn't give a damn
about Boogie!
You're not gonna
hurt my babies anymore...
not while I can do
something about it.
Oh, you want something to eat?
Learn how to cook.
Grace!
What's up?
What?
I said, what's up?
How long have you
been sitting there?
Why is everything so black, Toot?
Don't know.
Maybe 'cause we're all bloody Maoris.
You got something...
you got something to sniff?
Yeah. A couple of old socks.
What's going on, G?
I thought you said
we were best friends.
If you're too bloody mean,
just forget it.
Hang on. Hang on.
No glue, OK? OK?
But I've got some dope.
You want some of that?
Ya.
What's going on with you, Bub?
What colors are you seeing now, G?
Still all black?
Not an old black in sight.
Notice how you never see black
in a rainbow, do you?
Just bright colors.
Must be their pot.
You know, the pot at
the end of the thing.
Oh, dumb.
Pot... the end of the thing.
You're shit!
You're just like
everyone else around here.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
You're just a stupid kid
that lives in an old wreck of a car.
G! G! Come back, G!
G, come back! What did I do?
Please, G!
I'm sorry!
Please.
This is the day
that the Lord has made
That the Lord has made
We will rejoice
We will rejoice and be glad in it
And be glad in it
Whoa, for this is the day
That the Lord has made
We will rejoice and be glad in it
This is the day, this is the day
That the Lord has made
This is the day
that the Lord has made
That the Lord has made
We will rejoice
We will rejoice and be glad in it
And be glad in it
This is the day
That the Lord has made
We will rejoice and be glad in it
This is the day, this is the day
That the Lord has made
Shit. It's nearly on empty.
I've got money.
Forget the money. It's just no good.
We've been driving around for hours.
When was the last time
you phoned home?
Uh, about 9:00.
Jeez. It's nearly 11:00.
I've got those
Lonely, lonely, lonely,
lonely blues
I've got those
Lonely, lonely, lonely,
lonely blues
Lonely, lonely blues
Look what she done,
what she done, my baby
- Bring your ass in here, girl!
- Look what she done...
I said in here! Move!
Your mother's been out
all day, half the fucking night!
Now, where the fuck you been?
Come on, bro, she's home now.
Let the kid go to bed.
Come on, Jake.
Play the guitar, man.
Go on. Piss off to bed.
Hey, come on, give your Uncle Bully
a kiss good night.
I don't want to.
What? I didn't hear you.
I said I don't want to.
What, you got
a hearing problem, girl?
Hey, no. Leave it.
Daddy, no!
Daddy!
I told you about this thing, eh?
No fucking wonder you don't do
what you're fucking told!
Take it easy, Jake.
She's just a kid.
Fuck! Get out of here!
Bully, play us a song.
Go on, dude.
Look what she done,
what she done, my baby
Look what she done...
Where is she?
Stop your panic, woman.
She's home.
She won't be taking off anymore.
Where is she, Jake?
She pissed off out the back.
What the fuck?
Aah! Aah! Oh! Oh!
Some-someone help me
get her down!
Please! Please!
Come on, baby. Come on, girl.
It's all right, baby.
Mummy's home. Mummy's home.
Come on, Grace. Oh, God.
We've got to do something.
Jake!
My baby!
I'll get help.
No, Grace!
Don't cry, Mavis.
Doesn't do any good.
Auntie Matawai?
It's Beth.
Ka mata oku tamahine...
last night.
I want to bring her home, Auntie.
Will you come and get us, please?
Thank you.
We're going to play spacies.
Come on, you two.
Oh, where's Gracie?
She's having a long sleep.
No, she's not. Her bed's empty.
That's enough, Polly. Come on.
What the fuck's going on here?
I want us to take Grace back home
to the Marae.
This is her fucking home.
No, it's not.
This was never her home...
never.
And that fucking place is?
Fucking Maoris who think they're better
than the rest of us?
I hate them.
Bastards living in the fucking past.
It's our past, too, Jake.
What's that supposed to mean?
I want Grace to be with her people.
We should have gone back
a long time ago.
Fuck off!
You're not taking her anywhere.
I'm taking her, Jake,
with or without you.
I wasn't there
when Grace needed me.
This time I'm going to do
the right thing by her,
and you're not going to stop me.
You fucking do,
and I won't be here
when you get back.
Well, go on, then.
Go! Get the hell out of here!
I'm taking her.
I'll kill you first!
Well, go on. Do it.
You're still a slave, Jake...
to your fists, to the drink,
to yourself.
Well, go on.
Kill the bloody lot of us!
Stay out of my fucking way...
or I'll kill you.
You've come home, Grace.
We're home.
Oh, my baby.
Am I that much of a bastard, eh?
You're my mates. You tell me.
It's not too late
if you want to go to the Tangi.
We'll drive you.
Fuck off.
I'm not going to give them
the satisfaction.
I was never fucking good enough,
not for their Beth.
I'll knock her bloody head in.
Never mind, bro.
What's the key to her, man?
You think I was tough on the kid?
Na... it wouldn't have been
just that, mate.
Bull, what do you think?
You think I was tough on her?
Fucked if I know, bro.
I'll try and tell you
a story, eh, Gracie?
The story about a young girl
growing up in this beautiful place.
She was given an honor.
She was made Puhi of the Marae.
The special one.
Well, you see, the girl fell in love,
as all young people do.
But you see, the problem was...
the old people
wouldn't agree to the fella.
The girl, being headstrong,
went with him anyway.
Her father said she'd be back...
that when everything
went to hell, she'd be back.
So the girl...
made a promise to herself
and said she wouldn't.
No matter what, she wouldn't.
You see, Grace...
I did know how to keep a promise.
I did.
I'm so sorry, Bub.
I'm so sorry.
I should have been
there for you, sis.
You were always there for us.
Oh, son.
Hey, G.
Best friends... forever.
Remember?
That's all I meant. Honest.
But you were right.
I'm just a stupid kid
who lives in an old wreck of a car.
She loved you, man.
She loved you.
What's the time?
What's the time, Mr. Wolf?
What's the time? Say, it's 1:00
Have you ever seen so much piss?
That's because they love you, man.
Yeah.
Yeah. Why not?
I'm a lovable chap.
Jake the Muss.
What's the time, Mr. Wolf?
Ohh ohh
There's Mr. Daddy-Longlegs
Crawling onto the ceiling
The sun don't shine,
the sun don't shine
The sun don't shine...
Where the fuck are you?!
You bastard!
Fucking bastard.
Don't forget your hat, eh, uncle?
Hey, uncle, did you
get all the ghosts?
I sure did.
Got the whole lot of them.
You come and stay.
Bring the kids with you.
We've got a lot of work
to do back home.
And here, too, auntie.
You sort out here first.
Be strong.
Good-bye, auntie.
You made me real proud today, son.
Me, too, eh, Mum?
I made you proud today.
You sure did, Bub.
Well, I suppose I'd better
be taking off, then.
Take off? Where to?
I don't know.
Probably back to my car.
I like it there.
Well, do you think
you could like it here, with us?
Because we like having you.
Don't we, kids?
Ya!
Well, whatever you say, Mrs. H.
I mean, if you need me,
that'll be great.
I do need you.
Need you all.
Well, we'll say grace.
Grace!
Thank you for my family,
and thank you for the food. Amen.
Good look, bro.
Would you like one, bro?
No, thanks, man.
I wear mine on the inside.
Don't you think you should
take the car back, son?
In the morning.
Your mates did you proud today.
There.
Mrs. H, could you read me
one of G's stories?
I can't. That's why she reads to me.
I mean used to.
Yeah, the one about the Taniwha.
OK.
What's wrong, Mum?
Toot, put the kids in the car.
Thanks, bro.
Same place... same fucking place
same thing happed with me.
Anyway, this fucking ape
comes over to me,
takes off his shades,
and says the classic line.
The classic line! Wait for it.
Waiting, waiting, waiting.
"What the fuck you staring at, man?"
So I say to him, cool-ass,
"Well, not you, mate.
Your spunky missis. "
Trouble is, she was
fucking uglier than him.
- Then all hell broke loose.
- Old Jimmy, eh?
Hey, you can stay at
my place tonight, mate.
Yeah, fuck it. Why not?
Beth! Bully, give the lady a seat.
You fucking animal.
What the fuck?
Women and children, eh?
You fucking coward!
Please, control your
missis there, mate.
Who the fuck do you think you are
coming in here
mouthing off at my mates?
Get the fucking hell out of here
before I kick your bloody head in.
That's always your
answer, eh, Jake?
Violence.
It's bad enough that you did it here,
but you brought it home with you
and I damn well let you.
What the fuck are you on about now?
It was violence
that killed my Grace.
She didn't have an ounce
of violence in her, Jake,
but we made damn sure
it was all around her.
She killed herself!
You bloody bastard!
It was your bloody mate
who handed her the rope!
Hey, I don't have a clue
what you're on about.
- You fucking child...
- Shut up, Nig!
You animal.
You raped a 13-year-old girl,
then sat here drinking
with her father
while the rest of us buried her.
She's off her fucking head, man.
Sneaking around my house
and laying your dirty, filthy,
fucking hands on my baby!
My Grace!
Hey, you're not
on the fucking Marae now,
so don't come in here
accusing my mates of shit!
Hey, come on, man.
Look, no one's thinking straight.
We're family. Right?
Beth. Sit down. Have a drink.
I won't drink with
you fucking animals!
Read it.
Uncle Bully.
Uncle fucking Bully!
Let's go, son.
You dumb bastard, Bully!
Fuck you, Beth. Where are you going?
I found something better, Jake,
and I'm going to make damn sure
my kids have it all.
From now on,
I make the decisions for my family.
Fuck off, then!
You'll get nothing from me.
You've got nothing I want.
Our people once were warriors,
but not like you, Jake.
They were a people
with mana, pride.
People with spirit.
If my spirit can survive
living with you for 18 years,
then I can survive anything.
Maybe you taught me that.
Oh, you are fucked, lady!
Really fucked!
You think I need you
and your fucking spirit?
Fuck off! Go on, go!
I don't want you, ever!
I'll knock your fucking head off!
Fuck you! You'll be back.
Fuck this warrior shit.
You'll be back!
Fuck you, Beth!
Do you hear me, Beth?!
Fuck you!
Where are we going, Mum?
We're going home.
Oh, fuck all that
fucking warrior shit!
You'll be back! You'll fucking see.
You'll need me!
You'll fucking want me!
You'll be back. Fuck you, Beth!