Subtitles by explosiveskull
PASTUZO:
Our last rainy season.
LUCY: Just think, Pastuzo,
this time next month
we'll be in London.
Where the rivers run
with marmalade
and the streets are paved
with bread.
Did you read the book
about London?
I skimmed it.
Oh, Pastuzo.
Well, reading makes me sleepy.
But any city that can
come up with this
is all right by me.
(LUCY SIGHS)
Ooh, Pastuzo, look!
PASTUZO: It's... It's a cub.
Lucy!
Lower me down.
Be careful.
(CUB SCREAMING)
Lower, Pastuzo. Lower.
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
(YELPS)
(LUCY PANTING)
PASTUZO: Lucy?
Lucy!
I'm afraid we're not going
to London after all.
PASTUZO: Why not?
We've got a cub to raise.
- PASTUZO: What's he like?
- LUCY: Rather small.
(SNEEZES)
And rather sneezy.
But he likes his marmalade.
- PASTUZO: That's a good sign.
- (BURPS)
LUCY: Oh, yes, Pastuzo.
If we look after this bear,
I have a feeling he'll go far.
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
PADDINGTON: Dear Aunt Lucy.
I hope all is well
in the Home for Retired Bears.
Life in London has been
better than ever this summer.
I've really got to grips
with how things work.
- (WHIRRING)
- (SIGHS)
And it seems there's something
new to do every day.
- Guess what, Paddington?
- Hmm?
The steam fair
is coming to town.
I'm going along tonight
to write about it
- in my newspaper.
- Ooh.
Who's going to want
to read about that?
Everyone. They travel the
world in an old steam train.
- I thought you'd love it.
- I do.
Don't tell anyone, okay?
Not cool.
- Why don't we all go?
- PADDINGTON: Good idea.
Your father's a dab hand
at the coconut shy.
"Bullseye Brown"
they used to call him.
Not anymore. Coconuts are
a young man's game.
Well, I think you're in great
shape for a man your age,
- Mr. Brown.
- Ah, thank you, Paddington.
Hang on,
how old do you think I am?
Oh, er, about 80.
- 80?
- At least.
- Just a minute, young bear.
- Hmm?
Thought I told you
to wash behind your ears.
Oh, but I did, Mrs. Bird.
I...
I wonder how
that got in there.
(BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
I really feel at home
in Windsor Gardens.
Bonjour, Mademoiselle.
Good morning, Paddington.
- I brought you breakfast.
- Thank you.
Your sandwiches always
put me in a good mood.
Morning, Doctor Jafri.
You haven't forgotten
your keys, have you?
Keys? Keys!
Oh. Oh! (SIGHS)
PADDINGTON: Well caught.
- Thank you, Paddington.
- You're welcome.
Glorious day, Colonel.
Is it?
How absolutely thrilling.
How was your date,
Miss Kitts?
Well, he wasn't the one,
but you know what they say.
- Plenty more fish in the sea.
- Exactly.
Thank you.
(MUSICAL TRUCK HORN PLAYING)
- Morning, Paddington.
- Morning, Mr. Barnes.
- Bye, Paddington.
- Au revoir, mademoiselle.
Right, test me.
What's the quickest way
from Baker Street to Big Ben?
Ah, an easy one.
Turn right
onto Portman Square...
PADDINGTON: Everyone has
been so kind and welcoming
even though they're very busy.
Mrs. Brown is planning to
swim to France.
It seems an awful lot
of hard work
when you can go by boat
or plane or even train.
But that's not the point.
She's been cooped up
all summer
illustrating a series
of adventure stories
and has decided
she wants one of her own.
Whoo-hoo!
PADDINGTON: Judy has been
suffering from a broken heart.
I'm dumped? I think you'll
find you're dumped, Tony!
PADDINGTON: Her first
reaction was to become a nun.
But she soon got over that
and has thrown herself
into a new hobby.
She found an old
printing press at school
and is starting a newspaper
with no boys.
Now all we need is some news.
PADDINGTON:
Jonathan is joining her
at big school this year.
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
- He spent the holidays
building a fully-working
steam engine,
but I'm not supposed
to talk about that
- as it's "not cool."
- (BLOWS TRAIN WHISTLE)
He's got a whole new look,
and if anyone asks,
he's now called J-Dog,
and he's definitely not
into steam trains.
But Mr. Brown has been
busiest of all.
He recently had a surprise
at work.
CEO: I am delighted
to announce,
our new Head of Risk Analysis
will be
Mr. Steve Visby.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
PADDINGTON: And
this has prompted
what Mrs. Bird calls "a
full-blown midlife crisis."
It involves
blending his food,
painting his hair,
and engaging in a process
called "Chakrabatics."
INSTRUCTOR: Open your mind
and your legs will follow.
(YELPS)
- Thank you, Paddington.
- Keep up the good work.
Oh, Aunt Lucy, you sent me
to London to find a home,
and it's worked out better
than I ever imagined.
I have a wonderful family.
(WHISTLES)
And have made friends
in all sorts of places.
Here, boy.
There you go, Wolfie.
I do hope if you could see me,
you'd be pleased.
Lots of love from Paddington.
- Mr. Gruber?
- (STORE BELL JINGLING)
GRUBER:
Ah, Mr. Brown, come in.
I just had a visit
from Madame Kozlova
who runs the fair.
Oh, yes?
They were having a clear out
and found all these old crates
stuffed full with memory-bilia
they thought
- had been lost forever.
- Oh!
She asked me
if I would sell it
for them while
they're in town.
And it struck me there might
be something in here
for your auntie's birthday.
Oh, good idea.
- (BUZZING)
- (GASPS)
Ah, look at this!
(TOY MONKEY GIBBERING)
It's very nice, Mr. Gruber,
but...
I know, I know,
it has to be perfect.
Well,
since Uncle Pastuzo died,
I'm the only relative
she's got left.
And it isn't every day
a bear turns 100.
Quite so. Ah!
How about these rolling shoes?
Please, Mr. Gruber,
be serious.
Perhaps your auntie's
rolling days are behind her.
I think you might be right.
Oh, what's this? (BLOWS)
Ah, that must be
the popping book.
Very interesting.
Really?
You see, Madame Kozlova's
great-grandmother,
who started the fair,
was also a brilliant artist.
And every time
they visited a new city,
she made a popping book
to remember it by.
Oh!
And this is London.
PADDINGTON: Oh, Mr. Gruber,
it's wonderful.
Aunt Lucy always dreamed
of coming to London
and never had the chance.
But if she saw this,
it would be like
she were finally here.
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
- (SHIP HORN BLARING)
- (PASSENGERS CHEERING)
PADDINGTON:
Aunt Lucy! Aunt Lucy!
LUCY: Paddington!
Oh!
Come with me, Aunt Lucy.
Oh, yes, please.
I want to see everything.
NEWS VENDOR: Get all
your racing news right here.
- Well, what do you think?
- It's wonderful.
All aboard.
- One and a half bears, please.
- Mind your step, madam.
LUCY:
What a polite young man.
(PIGEON COOING)
What a polite young pigeon.
(BIG BEN TOLLING)
Oh, Paddington, you've made
an old bear so very happy.
This is perfect.
- Oh.
- Huh?
We have a snag.
Do we?
You see, this popping book
is the only one of its kind,
and they want rather
a lot of money for it.
Oh, well, Mrs. Bird found this
coin in my ear at breakfast.
Perhaps there's more.
(CHUCKLES) It would take more
than an earful, Mr. Brown.
I'm afraid you would need
a thousand of those coins.
Oh.
Let's take another look
at the monkey.
I think he's super-duper.
- (TOY MONKEY GIBBERING)
- Oh!
I can fix that.
That's very kind, Mr. Gruber,
but Aunt Lucy did so much
for me when I was a cub,
and this could be my way
of saying thank you.
I'm going to get a job
and buy that book.
Back in a few minutes,
Paddington.
- Ciao ciao.
- Ciao ciao, Mr. Giuseppe.
Good afternoon. Welcome to
Giuseppe's grooming salon.
What can I do for you
today, sir?
A shave? A light pomade?
Or is it just a brush?
- (STORE BELLS JINGLE)
- (GASPS)
Quick trim, barber.
Oh, I'm not the barber.
I just tidy up.
That's all I want.
Tidy up the back and sides,
nothing off the top.
Yes, but...
No buts.
Come on, man, chop-chop.
If you say so, sir.
Hmm.
Ah.
Hmm...
- (WHIRRING)
- Oh. Whoa!
(SNORING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(VIBRATING) Giuseppe's?
Would you mind
if I call you back?
I think I may be about to
shave a customer.
Oh, thank goodness.
(YELPS)
Just putting you on hold.
(SCREAMING)
But I don't want to.
(SIGHS) It's only a
haircut, Nelson.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
Come in. Take a seat.
We'll go somewhere else.
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
Oh, that's not good.
Oh... Um...
No.
Um...
Ah.
(CUSTOMER MUTTERING)
Just giving you
some product, sir.
Ah, jolly good. Carry on.
PADDINGTON: All done.
I must say, it's turned out
a lot better than I expected.
What... What the devil's that?
It's, er, marmalade.
Marmalade?
Hairy marmalade.
Well, get it off!
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
Oh, yuck!
What is the matter with you?
- Paddington!
- Mr. Giuseppe. I can explain.
It's really not as bad
as it looks.
(FIRE ALARM BEEPING)
Have you ever been fired,
Mr. Brown?
Well, no,
but are you quite sure
you're ready for
the workplace, Paddington?
It's a tough,
competitive world out there,
and I worry
a good-natured little bear
might get trampled underfoot.
He's right, you know?
You can't trust anyone.
That's why
I'm doing my newspaper alone.
MARY: Darling,
is this about Tony?
JUDY: No!
JONATHAN:
Everything is about Tony.
And the only reason no-one's
helping with your paper
is because it's so lame.
Well, at least
I'm not pretending
to be someone I'm not.
Nor am I. G-Man.
- J-Dog.
- BOTH: Spud bounce.
But Aunt Lucy said,
"If we're kind and polite,
the world will be right."
At least
someone's making sense.
Sorry. You're kind, Mr. Brown,
and you made it to the top.
I'm nowhere near the top.
I peaked in the middle.
Now my hair's gone grey,
my belly's popped out,
and I've started to creak.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Oh, doesn't that man live in
the big house on the corner?
JONATHAN:
It's Phoenix Buchanan.
Dad's 'celebrity' client.
He's one of
our Platinum Club members.
And a very famous actor.
Or used to be.
Now he just does
dog food commercials.
Mrs. Bird doesn't like him
because he can never remember
her name.
Now then,
simmer down, simmer...
All right, little bit more.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
That's enough.
I'm sorry, I'm at my worst
tonight. I really am. I am
tickled the deepest shade
of shrimp
to have been asked here
tonight
to open this
wonderful old steam fair.
But you know,
when Madame Kozlova created
this thing
all those years ago,
she most certainly was not
thinking of people like me,
whatever I am,
'VIP, ' 'celebrity.'
I hate all that stuff.
No, no... 'West End legend, '
- that's another one.
- (CROWD LAUGHING)
No, no, she was thinking
of you guys, huh?
The ordinary people.
So, I'm gonna ask
one of you to
come up here
and open the fair.
Volunteers? Anyone.
ALL: Me. Me.
Eeny, meeny, miney...
(GRUNTING)
...bear!
Let's have the young bear.
Why not?
- Come, come, young ursine.
- Thank you.
Up here, my furry friend.
Very good, very good.
- Now, your name is?
- Paddington Brown.
Oh, well, of course it is.
You are my new neighbor.
You live with
Henry and Mary
and the great Mrs...
- (MUMBLES)
- (SIGHS)
Now then, I suppose you know
who I am?
Oh, yes,
you're a very famous actor.
- Oh, pooh. (CHUCKLES)
- Or used to be.
Now you do
dog food commercials.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
- Well, a man has to eat.
- What, dog food?
(ALL LAUGHING)
(STRAINED LAUGHING)
Very, very funny.
Anyway, they do say that
at Madame Kozlova's,
all your dreams come true.
So, if you had one wish
tonight, what would it be?
Oh, that's easy.
I'd like to get my Aunt Lucy
a birthday present.
- ALL: Aww.
- Aww. Darling.
I've got my eye on
an old pop-up book of London.
Made by Madame Kozlova,
as it happens.
The only problem is
it's rather expensive.
So I need to get my paws on
an awful lot of money.
Well, I'm not sure that
we can offer you that.
But we can of course
offer you
oodles of fun.
So, if you would like to
lend me a paw,
we now declare
Kozlova's Steam Fair
- open!
- (ALL CHEERING)
Thank you,
thank you very much.
- (CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
- Wonderful, thank you.
- Mrs. Brown?
- Just one moment.
- A word in your ear.
- Hmm?
This, er, this pop-up book.
- Do you know it?
- I know of it.
But I was led to believe
it was lost.
Where on earth
did you find it?
Oh, at Mr. Gruber's
Antique Shop.
He's keeping it to one side
for me,
but I really need a job.
I don't suppose you have
any advice, do you?
No. No. No.
I imagine you just have to
start at the bottom
of the ladder
and work your way up.
(CHUCKLES)
Do you know what,
Mr. Buchanan?
Hmm?
You've just given me
the most brilliant idea.
Have I?
I'm going to be
a window cleaner.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS) Hmm...
Ah.
(EXHALES)
(GRUMBLES)
Ah.
Hmm?
Oh... Oh, dear.
Um...
(YELPING)
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Hmm...
Ow.
(GRUNTING)
Hello? Anyone?
Hmm?
(DOORBELL RINGS)
- Hello? Window cleaner.
- LANCASTER: No, thank you.
Sure, Colonel?
They're awfully dirty.
I don't care
and I'm not paying.
Perhaps I'll do them anyway.
(PULLEYS CREAKING)
(LANCASTER SIGHS)
(PADDINGTON YELPS)
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Good afternoon, Colonel.
Are you aware
there's a bear on your roof?
Yes, he seems to be
cleaning my windows.
Shall I do your gutters
while I'm up here?
Um, yes. Thank you.
Well, of course it's not
for me to say, Colonel,
but I wouldn't care to have
an undesirable
crawling all over my premises.
And as Commander of your
Community Defense Force...
Is that an official position,
Mr. Curry?
Or have you just bought
yourself a yellow coat?
Got my eye on you, bear.
Oh. Sorry.
MAN:
♪ Here's a little song
♪ To help you get along
♪ Get you out the door
♪ To do a tiny chore
♪ Take some soap and water
Mix it up together
♪ Splash it on the window pane
♪ Scrub it left to right
Till it's shiny bright
♪ Rub with all your might
♪ Left and right
Make it right
♪ Rub and scrub
With your tub
♪ Left and right
Rub and scrub
One more day, Aunt Lucy.
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- Hmm?
Mr. Gruber?
Eh?
You're not Mr. Gruber!
- Clear off!
- Oh, no, you don't.
(LADDER WHIRRING)
(ALARM RINGING)
Stop! Thief!
(PANTING)
Come back with that book!
(SIREN WAILING)
Robbery in progress
at Gruber's Antiques.
Suspect is
a small bear wearing
a red hat
and blue duffle coat.
PADDINGTON: Stop!
Come back!
(GASPS)
No!
(WHISTLES)
(BARKING)
Come on, Wolfie.
Oi!
- Oi! Get off it!
- PADDINGTON: Give that back!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- (LAUGHING)
- No!
- THIEF: Nice try, bear.
- Whoa, Wolfie.
(BICYCLE BELL RINGING)
Toodle-oo.
Oh. Um...
(BOAT HORN HONKING)
- (HOWLING)
- Giddy-up!
Ow.
Come on, boy.
- (BIRDS SQUAWKING)
- (PADDINGTON YELPING)
Excuse me. Coming through.
Who are you? (GRUNTS)
Oh, dear.
Strike a light! Oh!
(GROANING)
That book is reserved
for Aunt Lucy!
(SQUAWKS)
- Hello there.
- (HISSES)
Oh! Ow. Not the snout!
- Wolfie!
- (BARKS)
(SCREAMING)
Thank you, Wolfie.
Come on. Attaboy.
(PANTING)
All right, all right.
You got me.
Hand over that book.
'Fraid I can't do that.
Cheerio.
- (WHIMPERS)
- But
where did he go?
Hold it right there.
Oh, thank goodness
you're here, Officer.
Put your... paws in the air.
But I'm not the thief.
I was chasing the thief.
And then he... He...
Disappeared in
a puff of smoke?
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- Well, yes.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
- JONATHAN: Paddington!
- MARY: Oh, no!
- HENRY: What's going on?
- OFFICER: Hold it there.
Hang on. Hang on. We're
taking him into custody.
- There must be some mistake.
- No mistake, sir.
What's happened?
- Caught red-handed.
- What?
Robbing Gruber's Antiques.
CURRY: Well, well, well.
The truth is out.
We opened our hearts
to that bear,
we opened our doors.
Well, you did.
I kept mine triple locked
in accordance
with the guidelines.
And all along,
he was robbing you blind.
(POLICE VAN ENGINE STARTS)
MARY: Paddington!
- Oh, no!
- ALL: Paddington!
Oh, dear!
THIEF: A nice little haul,
and no mistake.
Turned out to be quite
a stroke of luck,
that bear turning up
when he did.
Coppers think he done it.
We're in the clear.
(LAUGHING)
Indeed, Magwitch.
And we gave quite
a performance, you and I.
Just like the old days.
Why the lemon face, Hamlet?
If you have something to say,
I beg you,
share it with us all.
It is not,
nor it cannot come to good.
Oh, really. You and your
dreary conscience.
Tell me this.
Which would you rather?
That you stand here,
gathering dust
while I humiliate myself
in a spaniel's costume
on television
or that we all return in glory
in the greatest one-man show
the West End has ever seen?
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Oh, thank you, my darlings.
Thank you. Thank you.
Blessings upon you all.
Deepest of bows. Thank you.
I know what you're thinking,
Scrooge.
It will cost a fortune,
but if I'm right,
that is exactly
what this book will provide.
This is no dusty antique.
Hidden on every page,
a little lady
pointing to a clue.
Find all the clues,
we're rich again,
and our dog food days
are done.
BUTLER: (ON VIDEO)
Dinner is served, Master.
Thank you, Simkins.
If, like me, your doggie likes
to maintain standards,
can I recommend
Harley's Gourmet Dindins.
More taste,
more goodness, more,
dare one say, class.
Mmm.
NARRATOR:
Harley's Gourmet Dog Food.
- Woof.
- Not to be consumed by humans.
BAILIFF: Court will rise.
Deep breath, Paddington.
Remember what Mr. Brown said.
"You're young. You've done
nothing wrong. You'll be fine.
"So long as you get
a fair-minded judge."
Order! O... Order.
Oh, dear.
You'll now hear the case of
the Crown versus Paddington
Brown.
(GULPS)
Oh, yes, he loved the book.
His heart was set
on top of it.
So you discussed
how expensive it was?
Yes, but he was earning
the money.
I refuse to believe that
young Mr. Brown
would ever burglarize my shop.
ALL: Exactly.
FORENSIC INVESTIGATOR:
Paw prints were found
here, here, and here.
And a substance, later
identified as marmalade,
was found here.
And is this
the same marmalade?
Yes, it is.
(ALL GASPING)
Phoenix Buchanan, do you
swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth?
May my entrails
be plucked forth
and wound about my neck
should I deceive.
I do.
Prison is no laughing matter.
And I should know, I spent
three years in Les Misérables.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Mr. Buchanan,
you live on the same street
- as the defendant?
- I do.
And you were an eye witness
to the events that night?
Indeed I was.
I was up late, when I became
aware of a hullabaloo
in the street below.
I went to my awards room,
which is a large room
overlooking
the newspaper kiosk,
and I saw young Paddington
riding a rather
disreputable-looking hound.
Mary Brown drew this
based on
the bear's description
of the man he claims
he was chasing.
Did you see him on the street
that night?
Oh, a handsome devil,
isn't he? Hmm?
- Dazzling eyes.
- Yes, but did you see him?
Your answer will tell us
whether the bear is guilty.
Did you see this man?
Alas,
I did not.
(ALL GASP)
PHOENIX: But perhaps
he'd already vanished.
I beg you, have mercy on him.
He is but a cub.
GUARD: Paddington Brown.
Ten years for grand theft...
Oh, but, I...
...and grievous barberly harm.
- (DOOR BUZZES)
- Follow me.
Oh, um...
Mrs. Brown usually reads me
a story before bed.
I don't suppose...
Sorry, son.
No bedtime stories in here.
Oh.
(DOOR LOCKS)
Dear Aunt Lucy.
A great deal has happened
since I last wrote.
There's been a bit of a mix-up
with your present,
and the upshot is
I've had to leave
Windsor Gardens and move
- somewhere else.
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
It isn't quite as charming
as the Browns' house,
but it's not all bad.
It's a period property.
In fact, it's one of
the most substantial
Victorian buildings
in London,
and the security arrangements
are second to none.
I'm only allowed to see
the Browns once a month.
I wonder
what they're doing now.
I do hope
they don't forget me.
Of course they won't,
Paddington.
This is the Browns
you're talking about.
They'll sort everything out,
and I'll be able to go home
and get your present,
and everything will be
right as rain.
I just need to hold on
till then.
(WHISTLING)
D.
The hunt begins.
(DOOR BUZZES AND OPENS)
GUARD: 325, 326, 327...
Here goes, Paddington.
Manners.
GUARD: Fall in.
Good morning.
How would you like to start
a gardening club?
How would you like to be
buried in a very deep hole?
After you.
Spooner, R. Workshop.
Brown, P. Laundry duty.
Right, laundry.
Laundry, laundry?
Ah! Laundry!
(BUZZING)
(GRUNTS)
Ugh!
Oh!
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, it's only one red sock.
What's the worst
that can happen?
Afternoon, chaps.
(GROWLS)
If you ask me, the pink really
brightens the place up a bit.
If you ask me, you should pipe
down and enjoy your dinner,
because it might be
your last.
Okay.
(TRAY CLATTERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SNIFFS) Ugh.
Don't worry. I used to be
a restaurant critic.
- It's not as bad as it looks.
- Oh.
(GAGS)
It's worse.
What is this?
Nobody knows.
But we've been eating it
three times a day
for the past ten years.
Why doesn't someone have
- a word with the chef?
- (COUGHS)
- With Knuckles?
- (GROWLING)
Two things to remember if you
want to survive in here.
Keep your head down
and never talk to Knuckles.
Thank you.
Well I think
it's a great idea.
Tell you what, son,
you get Knuckles to change
the menu and
we might forget about you
making us
look like
a bunch of pink flamingos.
- All right then, I will.
- PHIBS: You don't wanna
- do that.
- Aunt Lucy said,
"If you look for the good
in people, you'll find it."
She obviously
never met Knuckles.
Um, excuse me.
Mr. Knuckles?
Yes?
I just wondered
if I could have
a quick word about the food?
Send a medic to the canteen.
You want to
complain?
Oh, no,
I wouldn't say complain.
Oh, that's a shame.
Because I just love it
when people complain.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
Oh.
Well, in that case,
it's very gritty.
- Oh.
- And lumpy.
And as for the bread...
(PRISONERS GASP)
Need I say more?
I think we need to completely
overhaul the menu.
Now I know we're working to
a tight budget,
but we could at least
add some sauce.
(PRISONERS GASP)
Oh. Sorry about that.
I'll just...
Hmm. No,
that's just rubbing it in.
(GROWLS)
Don't worry. I know
what gets ketchup stains out.
Hang on, was it mustard?
No.
That's just made it worse!
Does anyone know
what works on ketchup?
Chaps?
(PRISONERS GASP)
Forget the medic.
Better send a priest.
You listen to me,
you little maggot.
Listening.
Nobody criticizes my food!
- Right.
- Nobody
squirts condiments
on my apron.
- Got it.
- And nobody
bonks me on the head
with a baguette.
No bonking.
I'll overhaul
the menu all right.
- Really?
- Dish of the day.
- Yes?
- Bear pie.
I don't like it.
What is this?
It's a marmalade sandwich.
Marmalade?
My Aunt Lucy taught me
to make them.
You mean, you can make this?
- Well, yes.
- Stand aside.
Get up off the floor,
you bunch of yellow-bellies!
Listen to me.
This bear is now
- under my protection.
- Oh.
Anyone who touches a hair
on his back
will answer
to Knuckles McGinty.
That's Knuckles with
a capital 'N.'
- Thank you, Mr. McGinty.
- Don't thank me yet.
I don't do nothin'
for no one for nothin'.
Beg your pardon?
You get my protection
so long as you make
that marmalade. Deal?
(SPITS)
Deal. (SPITS)
Somebody's got to recognize
him sooner or later.
(GRUBER GRUNTS)
You all right, Mr. Gruber?
There's something about
this whole business
that has been tickling
my brainbox.
What is it?
On the night of the robbery,
when young Mr. Brown
called out,
the thief took to his heels
and ran down the stairs.
MARY: Came straight through
the shop
and out the front door,
setting off the alarm.
Ah. But that's the thing.
He didn't go straight through
- the shop.
- No?
GRUBER: He came all the way
over here
to get the popping book.
Why not some jewelry
or a vase?
They're much closer.
Far more valuable.
He can't know much
about antiques.
No.
Unless
he knows something about
that book that we don't.
You may find this hard
to believe, Madame Kozlova,
but Paddington is innocent.
And we think that
the real thief
may have broken
into Mr Gruber's
just to steal your
great-grandmother's pop-up book.
- The pop-up book?
- I know it sounds far-fetched.
But is there anything you could
tell us about that book?
Anything at all
could be helpful.
- That's quite a story.
- Oh, really?
Come with me.
I'll show you
where it all happened.
You see, my great-grandmother,
who started this fair,
was the finest show woman
of her generation.
She could tame lions,
breathe fire, swallow swords,
but she was most famous
for the trapeze.
They called her
the "Flying Swan."
Wherever she went,
she was showered with gifts,
and made a fortune.
But where there is a fortune,
there is also jealousy.
The magician
wanted it for himself.
And the "Flying Swan"...
(AUDIENCE GASPING)
...became the "Dying Swan."
He went to her caravan
and opened her strongbox.
But instead of her treasure,
all he found was
one of her pop-up books:
- Twelve Landmarks of London.
- (MAN SHOUTING)
They had him cornered,
but he vanished.
And neither he,
nor the treasure,
were ever heard of again.
I knew
there was something special
- about that pop-up book.
- HENRY: Hmm?
Well, why else would she have
kept it in her strongbox?
You're not telling me you
believed all that guff, are you?
Madame Kozlova drew 12 London
landmarks in that book.
Yes?
Well, what if they're not
just landmarks.
What if they're...
I don't know...
- ...clues!
- Clues?
- To where she hid her fortune.
- You mean a treasure map?
- Exactly!
- (SIGHS)
And that's why the thief
took it from Mr Gruber's.
First thing tomorrow we need to go
to every landmark in that book,
see if we can sniff out
anything suspicious.
Too many adventure stories,
Mary.
What?
She's a fortune-teller.
She spun you a yarn.
It's what they do.
Honestly, Henry, you're
so close-minded these days.
What's that supposed to mean?
What happened to the man
I married?
He'd have believed me.
- Oh, him. He's gone.
- What?
I'm afraid your husband's
just a creaky old man,
- he's not Bullseye Brown.
- (MARY GROANS)
WOMEN:
♪ I'm crazy like a fool
♪ What about Daddy Cool?
♪ Daddy, Daddy Cool
Bullseye.
Oh, Henry.
MALE SINGER:
She's crazy about her daddy
Henry? Henry!
Anyway, the point is,
we're not going to
help Paddington
by going on
a wild goose chase.
We're looking for this
scruffy chancer,
not some
swashbuckling pirate
hunting for buried treasure.
I think there's more to him
than meets the eye.
I think he somehow knew
the story
of the Kozlova fortune
and is out there right now
trying to find it.
Well, Grandfather,
tonight we go in search
of clue number two.
The setting,
St. Paul's Cathedral.
But how to slip in unobserved?
Enter Sister Isabella.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SNORING)
- KNUCKLES: Wakey-wakey.
- (GASPS)
Marmalade time.
GUARD: There you go, lads.
Good luck.
- Um, Mr. McGinty...
- What do you want?
Well, the thing is,
I'm actually innocent.
And I wondered
if you had any advice
on how to clear my name?
Now that we're friends.
KNUCKLES: Friends? I'm
your boss, not your buddy.
Oh. Well, after you.
Why? So you can stab me
in the back?
No. Because it's polite.
Aunt Lucy said,
"If we're kind and polite,
"the world will be right."
(SCOFFS) You were ahead of me
and now you're behind.
That makes you a sap.
- Ingredients are over there.
- Um...
- Aren't you going to help?
- Nope. Now get on with it.
But there's 500 hungry prisoners
coming for breakfast,
so we'll need
1,000 juicy oranges and...
Oh, and rule number one:
no talking.
(GRUNTS)
(HUMMING)
Rule number two:
- no humming or singing...
- But... I...
...or any other expression
of bonhomie.
(EXHALES)
(UTENSILS CLANGING)
(GRUNTING)
Ooh, that's heavy.
Come on,
put your back into it.
Help.
These sacks are awfully heavy.
Well, take them
one at a time, then.
Right. One at a... time.
One juicy orange.
Two juicy oranges.
Three juicy oranges.
- Now what are you doing?
- Taking them one at a time.
One sack at a time!
I'm sorry, I'm finding this a very
stressful working environment.
Aunt Lucy said...
Aunt Lucy! I've had it up to
here with Aunt Lucy!
- (GRUNTS)
- She sounds like
- a proper old bag to me.
- (GASPS)
I beg your pardon?
I said,
your Aunt Lucy sounds like
one of the most naive,
gullible, mushy-brained...
What's going on?
Why are you looking at me
like that?
It's awful hot in here.
Are you hot? I'm hot.
(PANTING)
Did I leave the oven on?
It's called a hard stare.
Aunt Lucy taught me to do them
when people had forgotten
their manners.
You don't have to tell me
about hard stares,
I practically invented them.
Pretty good for a bear though,
I'll give you that.
Now, Mr. McGinty,
I may look like
a hardened criminal to you,
but I really am innocent.
And if you're not going to
help me clear my name,
you could at least help me
make this marmalade.
(SIGHS)
All right, I'll help.
Thank you.
Not gonna be much use
to you though.
These weren't exactly made
for cooking.
Oh, I don't know.
Looks to me like
you've got yourself
a fine pair
of orange squeezers.
Orange squeezers?
(SNIFFING) Good.
No.
Better.
Tomato.
Lovely.
Yes. Spot on.
Now, we have to be
very careful with knives.
Aunt Lucy said that
sensible bears...
(CHOPPING QUICKLY)
Where on earth did you learn
to use a knife like that?
You don't wanna know.
Well, it's jolly good.
(SNIFFS)
Now?
Now.
- Right, it's time for the sugar.
- Okay.
That's what turns the juice
into marmalade.
- How much?
- Ooh, a lot.
(SNIFFING)
Same again.
Ah.
A squeeze of lemon.
A pinch of cinnamon.
And just a bit more sugar.
Well, is it good?
Oh, it's too soon to tell.
We'll only really know
once it's set.
Designed
by Sir Christopher Wren,
St. Paul's Cathedral is
one of London's
most famous landmarks.
Sadly the Great Dome is
closed to visitors today
as one of its statues
was destroyed in a bizarre
accident last night.
But if you follow me...
Excuse me?
What happened here?
- A nun went berserk.
- JUDY: Really?
It happens.
The police have rounded them
all up for questioning.
Hold it there, Sister!
You're going nowhere till
the detective says so.
Spin it around!
Mind you, if you ask me,
the real culprit
slipped the net.
What makes you say that?
Because I saw her,
that's what.
I was on patrol
in the Upper Dome,
watching the nuns parade
far below,
when something caught
my eye.
One of them broke free
from the herd
and made her way
to the Whispering Gallery.
Only the good Lord knows
what she was doing up there.
PHOENIX: "C."
But she was never gonna
get away with it.
Not while I'm Vice Deputy
Head of Security.
Oi!
Attention all units.
An unusually attractive nun
is causing mayhem
in the cathedral dome.
Activate emergency protocol.
Stop that stunning Sister.
- I set off at lightning speed.
- (SLURPING)
But by the time
we'd locked the place down,
she'd vanished into the night.
- Good evening, my son.
- Oh, good evening, Your Grace.
Good evening.
(INHALES)
Most beautiful woman I've seen
in a long time.
Do you think you might
be able to describe her?
It would be my pleasure.
(CHUCKLES)
(SLURPS)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (BANGS GONG)
Gentlemen.
For breakfast this morning,
Chef McGinty would like to
propose an orange marmalade
served on a bed of
warm crustless bread,
topped with another piece
of warm crustless bread.
Bon appetit.
Two choices:
take it or leave it!
Are you all right, Knuckles?
Yes!
Why don't you come
and join the others?
Don't want to.
Are you scared
what they might think?
No!
What do they think?
Did they like it?
Did they say anything?
What did they say?
- Well...
- They hated it! I knew it!
My father always said
I'd amount to nothing,
and he was right!
Knuckles. Knuckles!
What?
Come and look.
PRISONERS: Mmm, mmm!
Mmm.
Come on.
(PRISONERS APPLAUDING)
Paddington.
I've a strange, warm tingle
in my tum-tum.
I think that's called pride,
Knuckles.
Well, I don't like it.
PHIBS: Um, have you got
anything else?
What?
You know, for, um, pudding?
- No!
- Fair enough.
I'm afraid we only know
how to make marmalade.
But if you have any recipes...
This lot? You're wasting
your time there, Paddington.
They wouldn't know their
pectin from their paprika.
Well, my grandmother used to
do a lovely chocolate roulade.
I think
I can remember the recipe.
Oh.
Charley Rumble makes
a mean apple crumble.
(GROWLS IN AGREEMENT)
And I can make
a strawberry panna cotta
with a pomegranate glaze.
Oh, I like the sound of that.
Don't you, Knuckles?
Yeah!
Come on then,
let's get cooking.
MAN:
♪ If this little proverb
♪ You will understand
♪ You will lend your brothers
a helping hand
Ooh, nice roulade, Spoon.
Thank you, Phibs.
- There you go, Paddington.
- Ooh, Knuckles.
I want those petit fours now!
♪ So whether you agree
Or you shall disagree
♪ You cannot disregard
the truth of this philosophy
♪ Singing life will be easier
Time would be breezier
♪ If you love your neighbor
Excuse me, Professor.
What would Aunt Lucy say?
- "Always use a cake fork."
- Well then.
- Care for a taste, Warden?
- Thank you, Paddington.
♪ So if the choice of a heaven
you wish to party
WARDEN: Mmm! Butterscotch!
♪ This is an example
you should try to emulate
♪ Resist all temptation,
restrain from strife
♪ I try to live a normal
and an upright life
♪ And this too you must learn
Make the best of what you earn
♪ Strictly learn to leave
your brothers' property alone
♪ And life will be easier,
time will be breezier
♪ If you love your neighbor
(CONTINUE PLAYING MUSIC)
WARDEN: (ON PA) "...and
it turns out the monster
"wasn't such a monster
after all,
"and they all became
the best of friends.
"The end."
PRISONERS: Aww.
Uh! Time for bed, you lot.
You need your beauty sleep.
It's visiting day tomorrow.
Visiting day.
I do hope you have good news.
MARY: In the past month,
these 3 shadowy individuals
have all been seen
snooping round
3 London landmarks.
JUDY: We think
the thief you saw
is part of a criminal gang.
Using the pop-up book as
a treasure map.
Well, it's a theory.
Have you found out
who they are?
Not yet, dearie.
Maybe I should take a look.
I'm sorry, this is
a private conversation.
Oh, it's all right,
Mr. Brown,
- this is my friend, Knuckles.
- (PRISONERS GREETING)
And this is Phibs. Spoon.
Jimmy the Snitch.
T-Bone. The Professor.
Squeaky Pete.
Double Bass Bob. Farmer Jack.
Mad Dog.
Jonny Cashpoint.
Sir Geoffrey Wilcott.
I hope I can rely
on your vote.
And Charley Rumble.
Oh, it's so wonderful
to meet you all.
I must say, it's
a great relief to know that
Paddington's already made
such sweet friends.
Would you excuse us a moment?
- What are you doing?
- Talking to the nice men.
"Nice men"? Mary,
we can't trust these people.
I mean, look at them.
Talk about a rogues' gallery.
Hideous.
And as for that bearded baboon
in the middle,
he's hardly got two brain
cells to rub together.
We can still hear you,
Mr. Brown.
(ALL AGREEING)
That was the light
you turned off.
The microphone is on
the other side.
It's got "microphone"
written on it.
Gentlemen, if I have
offended you in any way...
KNUCKLES:
Don't worry about it.
We're fond of
the little fella.
And let's face it,
if anyone can recognize
a criminal gang, it's us.
(ALL AGREEING)
We'd be grateful for any help.
Please.
Well? Knuckles.
I'm afraid I don't recognize
any of them. Lads?
ALL: No.
I'm afraid
I couldn't possibly comment.
Oh.
KNUCKLES:
Sorry to say it, kid,
but your friends are barking
up the wrong tree.
A nun, a beefeater and a king?
Sounds more like a fancy dress
party than a criminal gang.
PADDINGTON: Then,
what are we going to
do now?
- (BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
- Oh!
- Watch where you're going.
- So sorry. Sorry.
Sorry, I get grumpy
when I haven't had breakfast.
Keys. Keys. Keys!
Bottoms!
You can't park here!
I'm not parked,
I'm doing the bins.
You're not doing the bins,
sunshine,
you're studying
on council time.
I'm gonna report you.
And your hat.
- Morning, Miss Kitts, Colonel.
- Oh, morning, Mrs Brown.
Judy asked me
to drop these off to you.
CURRY: Propaganda!
You are wasting your time
trying to peddle that rubbish.
Everyone round here knows
it was your bear that done it.
And this street is a far,
far better place without him.
- What?
- (WOLFIE BARKING)
Oh, it's that mangy dog!
You are going to the pound,
my son.
Barking without a license
in a built-up area.
Give them here, Mary.
I have to sell them
under the counter,
for obvious reasons,
but people are buying them.
Really?
It's a bloomin' good read.
Made a few people round here
think twice
about your young bear.
You just need to find
that thief.
Oh, we're trying.
Don't suppose you know where
he is, do you, Feathers?
He's behind you.
Sorry, what?
PHOENIX: Coo-eee!
- Mary?
- Oh, hello, Phoenix.
Why don't you come on in?
I want to hear all about
the investigation. Yeah?
Mysterious things have been
happening all over town.
- Oh, yes?
- Strange characters
turning up at every landmark
in that book.
Are they?
I don't know.
Perhaps
it's just a coincidence.
Henry says I let my imagination
get the better of me.
Well, you're an artist, Mary,
like me.
Our imaginations run free
like bison upon the plain.
But can I just say,
in this particular case,
I think dear old Henry might
have a point.
Do you?
But I do have a little bit
of good news
that might turn your frown
upside down.
Oh, yes?
It looks, fingers,
fingers, fingers,
as though the funding
may be coming through
for my one-man show.
Oh. Right.
It's an evening of monologue
and song,
featuring some of
my better known characters.
Would you like
a little preview?
Um...
Picture this scene. Darkness,
then suddenly spotlight, me,
ping!
♪ Listen to
the rain on the roof
♪ go pit pitty pat,
pit pitty pat sit...
Oh, Mary, you look sad.
You don't like musicals?
No. No, no, no.
I suppose
it seems so unfair
Paddington is in prison
and yet
- life carries on.
- Oh, I know.
It must be so hard to accept
that he won,
that man with the dazzling
blue eyes. (CLICKS TONGUE)
(SIGHS)
I beg your pardon?
The man in the poster.
Your wonderful drawing.
Yes, but... how do you know
he had blue eyes?
Hmm?
It's just a pencil sketch.
Ooh.
Well, then I must have
colored him in. (CHUCKLES)
HENRY: Phoenix Buchanan?
He's a master of disguise.
- She's gone mad.
- MARY: Think about it, Henry.
Someone out there knows about
the Kozlova fortune, right?
Alleged fortune.
And Knuckles said we weren't
looking for a criminal gang.
Knuckles?
- Because there was no gang.
- It was one man.
Feathers knew all along.
- Feathers? Who's Feathers?
- Hmm?
The parrot at the newsstand?
No...
Can we just return
to Planet Earth for a moment?
Phoenix Buchanan is
a highly respected,
award-winning actor,
and a member of
our Platinum club.
- He is not a petty thief.
- Hang on a minute, Henry.
But let's just assume
I'm wrong, shall we?
Okay.
And that the fortune-teller,
career criminal
and parrot are right.
May I remind you that you
don't actually have any proof.
Now, if anyone wants me,
I shall be putting up posters.
He's right.
MRS. BIRD:
Well, I believe you, Mary.
Actors are some of
the most evil, devious people
on the planet.
- Are they?
- They lie for a living.
Crikey.
- If we're gonna catch one...
- Yes?
...we're gonna need
a foolproof plan.
- (KNOCKING ON METAL)
- Hmm?
- KNUCKLES: Paddington?
- Oh.
KNUCKLES: Paddington.
Knuckles?
KNUCKLES: Got a proposition
for you, kid.
Me and the boys have
been talking, and
seems to us,
if you're gonna clear
your name,
you're gonna need our help.
The Browns may mean well,
but...
It takes a thief
to catch a thief.
Oh.
KNUCKLES: Now, if we could
figure a way out of here
and hit the streets,
we'd find this guy
soon enough.
But that would mean... escape.
KNUCKLES: It certainly would.
And we got a plan.
But it's a four-man job,
so we need your help.
What do you say, kid?
It's very kind of you,
Knuckles,
but I don't think
Aunt Lucy would like
the idea of us breaking out
of prison.
The Browns will find
the real thief.
I just need to be patient.
You may not wanna hear this,
kid,
but sooner or later
the Browns, well,
they'll forget you.
PHIBS: They always do.
SPOON: They'll miss one visit.
Then two.
KNUCKLES:
Before you know it,
you won't have a home
to go back to.
You're wrong, Knuckles.
You're all wrong.
The Browns aren't like that.
They'll come tomorrow
and they'll have good news,
you'll see.
WOMAN: (ON INTERCOM) Hello?
It's Judy Brown
from the Portobello Express.
Come in.
So what's this for, darlings?
School newspaper?
Yes. We thought the agent
of the Phoenix Buchanan
would be really interesting.
And you'd be right.
But I've got two minutes,
so we better make it snappy.
And I've only given you that
because you've brought
breakfast.
Nice buns, by the way.
Here he comes.
- Hello, Joe. What a surprise.
- (JOE CHUCKLES)
What are you doing here?
JOE: Oh, you know,
posting letters.
How's Paddington?
Oh, he's a tough wee bear.
Yeah, he is.
Well, send him my best.
Yes, I will.
Thank you, Joe. Bye-bye.
Mr. Buchanan.
So, when can we expect to see
Mr. Buchanan back on stage?
Phoenix? Oh, I wouldn't
hold your breath, darling.
(CHUCKLES) No, no, no,
don't get me wrong.
He's a terrific actor,
but there is a teensy
little problem.
Really?
He won't work
with other people.
Thinks they dilute his talent.
Miss Fanshaw.
Oh, I must scoot.
We're having lunch
with a big Broadway producer.
- Oh, where are you going?
- The Ritz, darling!
Really nice buns.
PHOENIX:
Well, good heavens. Come.
(PHONE RINGING)
MRS. BIRD: The package
has been delivered.
Repeat, the package
Barkridge's, no less.
Lucky, lucky Phoenix.
Whoo!
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- FELICITY: Phoenix.
Felicity!
What a lovely surprise.
I was beginning to think
you'd lost my number.
I've got two minutes,
so we better make it snappy.
Okay.
We're having lunch
with a big Broadway producer.
Well, wonderful news.
Yes, yes. Where does one go?
The Ritz, darling!
I am on my way.
Nice buns, by the way.
I beg your pardon?
(TAPE REWINDING)
Really nice buns.
Thank you, darling.
I've never had any complaints
about
Mr. and Mrs. Botty-cheek.
Yes.
Gloves. Keys.
And exit.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Mary?
(GASPS)
(KNOCKING ON WINDOW)
(MOUTHING) Open the window.
- Hello, darling.
- Have you gone insane?
I know it's Phoenix
and I'm going to prove it.
This is breaking and entering.
We haven't broken anything.
Why would Phoenix want
to steal a pop-up book?
He's a millionaire!
That's where you're wrong.
He owes money
all over town. Look.
So he's got a few bills.
I mean, everyone...
Good grief, the man spends
a lot on face cream.
He hasn't got
a penny to his name.
Now come on. Let's find
that book and get out of here.
(GASPS) Cravat.
- Well?
- Nothing.
We must be missing something.
Unless there's nothing
to find.
Now can we please go?
- Oh. Look, Henry.
- What?
The carpet.
Yes, it's lovely.
I'll order a swatch.
- Give me a leg-up.
- Oh...
Quick, quick, quick.
(GRUNTS)
Yes!
A secret room.
- It's an attic.
- Secret attic.
It's an ordinary attic.
Every house in the street
has one.
I mean, look, it's just
a perfectly normal...
Oh, my God, he's a weirdo.
Look, Henry. The nun.
The thief. The king.
We were right!
Sorry. "We"?
- Well, I mean, I never...
- (DOOR OPENS)
(MARY GASPS)
- Quick!
- (WHISPERING) Get down. Get down.
Quite frankly ravishing.
Hello?
Who goes there?
Reveal yourself.
Henry?
Hello, Phoenix.
What on earth
are you doing here?
I might ask you
the same thing.
Well, I live here.
It's my house.
And I
insure it. And for our
Platinum Club members,
we perform an annual
free home inspection
to verify your
security arrangements.
In your pajamas?
Mmm-hmm.
With your wife?
So that all seems
pretty secure.
- Oh, hello, Phoenix.
- Mary.
Didn't hear you come in.
She helps out when we're busy.
Oh, well, that sounds
entirely plausible.
Does it? Great.
Well, I'm delighted to say
that everything
seems tickety-boo.
- Wonderful.
- (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
HENRY: So, I'll nip back
to the office
and get the boys
to type that up ASAP.
And we'll hope
to see you soon.
Indeed.
Perhaps next time
not in your pyjamas?
(ALL LAUGH)
- He's such a silly one.
- Ciao, now.
Oh, thank Larry it's there.
Thank Larry, Johnny and
all the ghosts of the avenue.
(IN COCKNEY ACCENT)
Yeah, well, that was close,
weren't it?
(IN SCOTTISH ACCENT) Aye!
Too close, if you ask me.
(NORMAL ACCENT)
Hold your nerve, MacBeth!
Screw your courage
to the sticking place!
We are so nearly there.
I have followed this lady
through the whole of London
and collected every one
of her clever little clues.
(IN SCOTTISH ACCENT)
Aye. But what do they mean?
(IN COCKNEY ACCENT) It's just
a jumble of letters, ain't it?
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(IN BELGIAN ACCENT) Uh-huh.
They are not letters at all.
They are musical notes.
(NORMAL ACCENT) Indeed,
Poirot. And I believe I know
just where to play them.
- (ALL CHATTERING)
- Hold it!
That is an amazing story.
But all you can actually prove
is Phoenix Buchanan
keeps his old costumes.
- (ALL PROTESTING)
- Bring me some hard evidence.
Bring me the book
with his fingerprints on,
and then you've got a case.
But until then, there's
nothing I can do. I'm sorry.
Where is she go...
Where's she going?
What do we do now?
I don't know.
Well, at least we can tell
Paddington we know who did it.
- Oh, no.
- What?
- We've missed visiting.
- Oh!
MARY: Paddington.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DOOR BUZZES)
(SNIFFLES)
(GASPS)
- (INSECTS CHITTERING)
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
LUCY: Paddington!
(GASPS) Aunt Lucy?
- Aunt Lucy!
- Paddington.
What are you doing here?
I thought you'd be at home.
I'm afraid
I don't have one anymore.
You see, I'm in prison.
And even the Browns
have forgotten me.
(KNOCKING ON PIPE)
KNUCKLES: Paddington?
Knuckles.
Tonight's the night.
We leave at midnight.
You wanna clear your name,
it's now or never.
- You in?
- (SIGHS)
I'm in.
WARDEN: Right. Time to call it
a night. (CHUCKLES)
Not much going on here anyway.
They've been good
as gold recently.
Lights out.
(GRUNTS)
(YELPS)
(GRUNTING)
Ah!
Oh, sandwiches.
KNUCKLES: Paddington.
Coming.
(WHISTLING)
(GASPS)
Good luck, little bear.
KNUCKLES:
This is the life, lads.
(ALL WHOOPING)
Freedom!
Bring her down, Spoon.
KNUCKLES: There she is, boys.
Our ticket out of here.
What do you mean?
Where are we going?
Might as well
tell him, Knucks.
PADDINGTON: Tell me what?
Aren't we going to clear
my name?
Sorry, kid. Change of plan.
What?
- We're leaving the country.
- And you're coming with us.
But... you lied to me.
Oh, hey, now,
it wasn't like that.
We were doing you a favor.
If we told you the truth,
you'd never have come along,
and it's better this way.
We are gonna make
marmalade together.
But I don't want to, Knuckles.
I want to clear my name
and go home.
And you said you'd help.
You promised.
Sorry, kid.
No can do.
- (GROWLS)
- SPOON: Paddington!
Let him go.
If he wants to get
himself arrested,
that's his choice.
- (SNIFFLES)
- (SIRENS WAILING)
JONATHAN: Hello.
JUDY: You've reached
the Brown residence.
JONATHAN:
We're not here now...
JUDY: ...but leave a message.
(BEEPS)
Hello, it's me. Paddington.
I hope you don't mind
my calling.
I just wanted to let you know
I've broken out of prison
and, well,
I suppose I'm on the run.
I didn't really mean to,
but Knuckles said
that if we broke out
he'd help clear my name,
and then I could come home.
But he's gone now
and I'm on my own.
I don't really know why
- I'm calling.
- (PHONE BEEPING)
I suppose
I just wanted to say...
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
...goodbye.
(SNIFFLES)
- (PHONE RINGING)
- (GASPS)
- Hello?
- MARY: Paddington?
Yes. Yes, it's Paddington.
I'm so sorry I escaped,
Mrs. Brown,
but I thought
you'd forgotten on me.
We'd never
forget you, Paddington.
- Paddington?
- MARY: You're family.
And we know who the thief was.
It's Phoenix Buchanan.
Mr. Buchanan?
MRS. BIRD: But he's
disappeared into thin air.
We've been looking for him
at every landmark
- in that book.
- JUDY: Every last page.
"Where all your dreams
come true."
Why do you say that?
Oh, it was written on the
last page of the pop-up book.
Always made me think
of Aunt Lucy.
- Very bizarre.
- Is it?
I found that exact same phrase
on a scrap of paper
in Phoenix's house.
Really?
I'm sure
I've seen that before.
Look. "Where all your dreams
come true."
HENRY: The organ?
That must be where Madame
Kozlova hid her fortune.
Let's get to the fair.
It's too late.
They're leaving today.
JONATHAN:
From Paddington Station.
MARY: At 6:35.
There's still time.
Paddington, head for
the station.
If we can find Phoenix
and get hold of that book,
his fingerprints
will prove everything.
But that's miles away,
Mr. Brown. I'll...
(MUSICAL HORN PLAYING)
I'll see you there.
- (HORN HONKING)
- MR. BARNES: Clear the road.
This is a refuse emergency.
- (BRAKES SCREECHING)
- PADDINGTON: Sorry!
Fellow citizens, I've just
received intelligence.
The bear has escaped
and may be heading this way.
I have raised
the neighborhood panic level
to "wild hysteria."
Get out of the way,
Mr. Curry!
JUDY: Paddington's not coming
this way!
He's gonna clear his name.
And we're gonna
bring him home!
We don't want him here.
No, of course you don't.
You never have.
As soon as you set eyes
on that bear,
you made up your mind
about him.
Well, Paddington's
not like that.
He looks for the good
in all of us,
and somehow he finds it.
It's why he makes friends
wherever he goes.
And it's why Windsor Gardens
is a happier place
whenever he's around.
He wouldn't hesitate
if any of us needed help.
So stand aside, Mr. Curry,
because we're coming through!
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(SPUTTERING)
(ENGINE STALLING)
CURRY: Nice try, Brown.
Your plan
seems to have stalled.
Like your vehicle.
Try the choke. Go on, try the choke.
You're flooding it.
Clutch down, second gear,
Mr. Brown.
What?
- DR. JAFRI: After three. Three.
- CURRY: What's going on?
You are illegally perambulating
on a public highway.
LANCASTER:
Put your backs into it.
- Do not push that vehicle.
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- Bring Paddington home.
- Thank you.
(ALL CHEERING)
Right, Paddington, stay low,
and remember, you're a bin.
PADDINGTON: You're a bin.
You're a bin.
Just an ordinary bin
going for a walk.
(GASPS)
- PADDINGTON: Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Nothing to see here, Officer.
Just a bin.
- Hmm.
- (PADDINGTON SLURPS)
Quite good being a bin.
(WHISTLING)
PHOENIX: Gentlemen.
(CONDUCTOR BLOWS WHISTLE)
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
- (GASPS)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
HENRY: Paddington!
Mr. Brown!
Quickly, he's on board.
(GROANS)
Don't worry,
I'll handle it myself.
We've gotta catch up
with that train.
- But how?
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
I've got an idea.
Good morning, madam. Sir.
Welcome on board.
Morning. Thank you.
May I offer you a glass
of champagne?
Oh, thank you so much.
That's very kind.
Very civilized, yes.
Nice to have a break
after all I've been through
with that beastly bear.
Boiler pressure, 225.
Water, half a glass.
Air brake, off.
Nice work, J-Dog.
My name's not J-Dog.
It's Jonathan Brown.
And I like steam trains.
- Oh, for goodness' sake.
- I'm so sorry.
- Get off. Stop it.
- (SHUSHING)
Don't shush me, Gertrude.
I have just been spilled upon
by a chilled liquid.
Gerald, I want you to shush.
Yes, Gertrude.
REPORTER: (ON RADIO)
...seven o'clock.
Here's the news from the BBC.
Four convicts
made a daring escape
from Portobello Prison
last night.
The prisoners all appear to
have vanished
- without a trace...
- (KNUCKLES CACKLES)
...except Paddington Brown,
who was seen boarding a fair
train bound for Bristol.
Police are closing in
and expect to make
an arrest soon.
(TURNS RADIO OFF)
Poor little fella.
Must be somewhere down there
right now.
SPOON: Shouldn't we help him,
Knuckles?
KNUCKLES: How?
We go back down there,
they won't just lock us up,
they'll throw away the key.
I know but he's our friend.
Stick to the plan.
I don't do nothin' for no one
for nothin'.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
Well, Grandfather,
the moment of truth.
D.
- D.
- (NOTE PLAYS)
(GASPS)
A.
PADDINGTON: The book.
(GASPS)
Ah.
- What's he doing?
- JUDY: I don't know.
- Paddington!
- He can't hear us.
Can this thing go any faster?
I can try
but I need more coal.
I'm on it.
Pull alongside.
I'm going across.
- I'll come with you.
- Judy...
Just you try and stop us!
Come on then!
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(SNEEZES)
- Ready?
- Yep.
Go!
(GRUNTS)
(YELPING)
INSTRUCTOR:
Open your mind
and your legs will follow.
(SCREAMS)
Mr. Brown!
Mrs. Bird.
C.
And finally E.
(NOTE PLAYS)
- (CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
- It works.
(GASPS)
(PHOENIX EXCLAIMING
IN DELIGHT)
Ooh.
Hello.
Aren't you pretty.
West End here I come.
(SQUISHING)
- Morning.
- (GASPS)
No!
- What was it? D. F.
- (NOTES PLAY)
D.
Come back with that book.
(GRUNTS)
Where do you think
you're going, bear?
It's a train. It comes to
an end, like all of us alas.
(GASPS)
PHOENIX: Whoops.
Exit bear,
pursued by an actor. (YELPS)
Phoenix Buchanan.
Mrs. Bird?
Oh, so now you remember me?
Well, I never. The cavalry.
An old crone, a little girl
and an insurance man.
What am I going to do?
I'll tell you exactly
what I'm going to do.
- Mmm?
- I'm going to bloomin' well
biff you on the nose.
Not a very good idea.
(BOTH GASP)
Stage combat, level four.
Well, where I come from,
laddie,
they teach you never to bring
a knife to a gunfight.
(COCKS RIFLE)
I think you'll find
that fires plastic darts.
So it does.
Whereas this sword looks
very sharp.
Back you go.
All of you, back.
And for you, sir,
the jumbo pavlova.
- Ah.
- Enjoy.
Oh, hello, Your Honor.
The hair is looking lovely.
MARY: Paddington!
Mrs. Brown!
I've got an idea.
Good. Good. Excellent.
Now for your furry friend.
(EXHALES)
Slow down, Jonathan.
PHOENIX: Coo-ee!
What a clever little bear.
(GRUNTING)
Don't worry.
I know a wee trick
Harry Houdini used to do.
(GRUNTING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Jump, Paddington!
I'll catch you.
No!
- Whoa!
- (GRUNTS)
- (GROANS)
Bye-bye, bear.
Bullseye!
Stop the train, Jonathan!
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(PLANE APPROACHING)
(SPLASHES)
KNUCKLES: Let's go, lads.
(ALL GASP)
Knuckles, you came back.
Can't make marmalade
on my own now, can I?
Thank you, everyone.
Paddington?
He's burning up.
Better get
the little fella to bed.
- JONATHAN: Mom!
- JUDY: Paddington!
MARY: He's not well.
KNUCKLES: Don't worry,
he's gonna be fine.
Aren't you, little buddy?
JONATHAN: Paddington!
- Where am I?
- Take it easy now.
You gave us a wee scare,
but you're home now.
- Home?
- That's right. Look.
The police realized they'd
made a terrible mistake.
HENRY: Phoenix Buchanan
has been arrested, and,
I might add, is no longer
a member of our Platinum Club.
- Then...
- You're a free bear.
- How long have I been asleep?
- JONATHAN: Three days.
Three days! But that means...
It's Aunt Lucy's birthday.
And I never sent her anything.
It's all right, Paddington.
But it isn't all right,
Mrs. Brown.
You see, Aunt Lucy did so
much for me when I was a cub.
Without her I'd never
have come to London.
And I suppose
all I ever really wanted
was to make her proud.
But now she's going to wake up
on her birthday
with no present
and think
I've let her down completely.
Oh, you great goose,
she won't think that at all.
Won't she?
Come with us.
- Here he is!
- (ALL APPLAUDING)
- What are you all doing here?
- We wanted to say thank you.
PADDINGTON: Thank you?
For everything
you've done for us.
(ALL AGREEING)
If it wasn't for you,
we'd never have met.
You helped me pass my exam.
I would be permanently locked
out of my house.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'd say you've rather a lot
to be proud of.
GRUBER: And when we heard
that the police wanted
the popping book
for evidence,
we thought we'd find
Aunt Lucy another present.
DR. JAFRI: So we all
clubbed together.
I pulled in a few favors
from my old Air Force chums.
And we think
she's going to love it.
But... what is it?
You wanted to get that book
so Aunt Lucy could see London,
didn't you?
It was always her dream.
Well, we thought,
why look at London in a book
when she could see
the real thing?
- (DOORBELL RINGS)
- (GASPS)
Why don't you go
and answer that?
(GASPS)
Oh...
Paddington.
Happy birthday, Aunt Lucy.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
MAN:
♪ Shake, shake, shake, Senora
♪ Shake your body line
Shake it all the time
♪ Work, work, work, Senora
Work your body line
♪ Shake, shake, shake, Senora
Shake it all the time
♪ My girlfriend name is Senora
♪ I tell you friends,
I adore her
♪ And when she dances,
oh brother
♪ She is a hurricane
in all kind of weather
♪ Jump in the line
♪ Shake your body
and jump in the line
♪ Jump in the line
♪ Shake your body
and jump in the line
♪ Shake, shake, shake, Senora
Shake your body line
Shake it all the time
♪ You can talk about cha cha
Tango, waltz or the rumba
♪ Senora's dance has no title
♪ Jump in the saddle,
hold on to the bridle
♪ Jump in the line
♪ Shake your body
and jump in the line
♪ Jump in the line
♪ Shake your body
and jump in the line
Phoenix Buchanan,
you have proved yourself
to be a heinous criminal
and a disgrace to the noble
profession of acting.
- (SOBS LOUDLY)
- I sentence you to ten years,
and I suggest that you use
your time behind bars wisely.
I shall.
♪ Listen to the rain
on the roof go
♪ Pit pitty pat, pit pitty pat
Pitty
♪ Sit kitty cat
We won't get home for hours
♪ Relax and listen to the rain
on the roof go
♪ Plunk planka plink,
plunk planka plink
♪ Planka
♪ Let's have a drink
And shelter from the showers
♪ Rain, rain, don't go away
Fill up the sky
♪ Rain through the night
We'll stay cozy and dry
♪ Listen to the rain
on the roof go
♪ Pit pitty pat, plunka plink
Plank
♪ Pity that it's
not a hurricane
♪ Listen plink
to the lovely rain
(ALL CHEERING)
Thank you. Thank you.
Well, it seems I didn't need
the West End
after all. Just
- a captive audience.
- (CHEERING CONTINUES)
What am I like?
Guards, lock me up!
Oh, wait, you have.
(CHUCKLES)