Reynolds has made
my dreams come true.
And I have given him what
he desires most in return.
And what's that?
Every piece of me.
He's a very
demanding man, isn't he?
Must be quite a challenge
to be with him.
Yes.
Maybe he's the most
demanding man.
Morning, ladies.
- Morning.
- Morning, madam.
Good morning, ladies.
- Morning, Biddy.
- Morning, Mr. Woodcock.
- Morning, Nana.
- Pippa.
- Morning, sir.
Try these.
Reynolds. They're delicious.
Remember I told you, Johanna“.
No more stodgy things?
I didn't know that.
You may have told it
to someone else.
- Morning.
- Morning, my old so-and-so.
Where have you gone, Reynolds?
There's nothing I can say to get
your attention aimed back at me.
Is there?
I cannot begin my day
with a confrontation, please.
I'm delivering the dress today.
And I can't take up space
with a confrontation.
I simply don't have
time for confrontations.
Good morning, Countess.
Good morning, Cyril.
Good morning, Peter.
Who is this beautiful stranger?
I need to see you
far more often, Henrietta.
- I am very excited.
- I am, too. Come in.
Exquisite.
Yes?
Let's take it for a walk.
Beautiful work, ladies.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
It's beautiful, Reynolds.
Worth everything
we've been through.
I feel like it will
give me courage.
Ladies and gentlemen,
take your seats, please.
- Evening, Stephen. Is she here?
- Yes, sir.
What do you want
to do about Johanna?
I mean, she's lovely,
but the time has come.
And she's getting fat,
sitting around waiting for you
to fall in love with her again.
I'll give her the October dress.
If that's all right.
I have an unsettled feeling,
based on
nothing I can put my finger on.
Just butterflies.
Been having the strongest
memories of Mama lately,
coming to me in my dreams,
smelling her scent.
The strongest sense that
she's near us.
Reaching out towards us.
I very much hope that she saw
the dress tonight. Don't you?
Yes.
It's comforting to think the dead
are watching over the living.
I don't find that spooky at all.
Why don't you go
to the country tonight?
I'll follow tomorrow.
Good idea.
I like that idea very much.
My old so-and-so.
Mr. Hansford?
- Mr. Hansford?
- Hello?
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- Fill it up, please.
- I will do.
Check the oil and the tires.
Lovely. Thank you.
It's a hard frost this morning.
It's cold, isn't it?
It's very bitter.
Ugh.
Excuse me. Could we have
a bit more toast, please?
Yes.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
What would you like to order?
A Welsh rarebit...
With a poached egg
on top, please.
Not too runny.
And bacon,
scones,
butter, cream,
jam,
not strawberry.
No.
Raspberry?
What else?
Coffee or tea?
Do you have Lapsang?
I'll have a pot
of Lapsang, please.
Good choice.
And some sausages.
Show me.
Will you remember?
Yes.
I'm keeping this.
And now?
Will you have dinner with me?
Yes.
For the hungry boy,
my name is Alma.
- Am I late?
- No.
What do you think?
Hmm.
I like the sauce.
Custard.
It's quite good.
Mmm-hmm.
May I, Alma?
I like to see
who I'm talking to.
Here.
Mmm.
There you are. That's better.
Does your mother
have brown eyes?
Green.
Do you look very much like her?
I don't know, I think so.
Do you have a photograph?
Yes.
- Would you let me see it?
- Not here, at home.
Carry it with you.
Always carry her with you.
Where's yours?
Your mother.
She's here in the canvas.
- What do you mean?
- Hmm.
You can sew almost anything
into the canvas of a coat.
Secrets,
coins,
words, little messages.
When I was a boy,
I started to hide things
in the linings of the garments,
things that only I knew
were there.
And over my breast, I have a
lock of my mother's hair,
to keep her close to me always.
She was quite
a remarkable woman.
She taught me my trade.
So I try to never be
without her.
You must love her very much.
Hello.
This is Alma. Say hello to Alma.
This is Alma.
Come say hello to Alma.
- Come on, come on.
- Hello.
Shall we show her
the house, lads?
I made this dress for
her when I was 16 years old.
It's beautiful.
'Twas for her second
husband, for the wedding.
My father had died
many years before.
Our nanny,
the evil Miss Blackwood...
Black Death, we used to call her.
Because of superstition, she
refused to help me sew the dress,
as she believed it would
bring her bad fortune,
to never be a bride.
Not that anyone
would have had her.
And she seemed ancient to us, I have
no idea how old she actually was,
and monstrously ugly.
So...
I worked alone
for months and months,
hunched over,
sewing and sweating and sewing.
And the Black Death
never married anyway.
All the help I could
have had from her.
'Twas my sister, Cyril, came
to my rescue in the end.
There are endless superstitions
when making a wedding dress.
Young girls afraid they'll
never marry if they touch one.
Or models afraid
they'll marry only bald men
if they put one on.
And where's the dress now?
I have no idea
what happened to it.
No idea.
Most probably
turned to ashes by now.
Fallen to pieces.
And your sister?
What?
Did she ever marry?
No.
C'mon, boys, let's have a fire.
If you want to have a staring
contest with me, you will lose.
Hmm.
You're a very handsome man.
You must be around
many beautiful women.
Yes.
So, why are you not married?
I make dresses.
You cannot be
married when you make dresses?
I'm certain I was
never meant to marry.
I'm a confirmed bachelor.
I'm incurable.
Hmm.
Marriage would make me deceitful
and I don't ever want that.
You sound so sure about things.
I'm sure about that.
I think you're
only acting strong.
No, lam strong.
For who? Not for me, I hope.
I think it's the expectations
and assumptions of others
that cause heartache.
Would you help me
with something?
- Yes.
- Come on.
Good. Just jump up
on the box for me.
I think we're going to try and
pull this back for you.
Pretty good.
One moment.
We'll save that one
for another time.
Quite nice.
But, um...
Mmm.
Bit serious.
This one.
Do you like it?
- Yes.
- It's very good.
That's it.
Let's get that off you, and then
I'd like to take your measurements.
Is that all right?
And who's this lovely creature
making the house smell so nice?
Hello, I'm Alma.
I'm Cyril.
Sandalwood and rose water.
Mmm. Sherry,
and...
Lemon juice?
Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
We had fish for dinner.
My old so-and-so.
Would you mind?
Can you step
towards me? Ready?
Thirty-two.
Thirty.
Thirty-one.
Thirty-five and a half.
Fourteen and a half...
Seventeen...
Twenty.
- Can you just stand normally?
- Yes.
- I stand normally.
- Like before.
- What do you mean?
- Straight.
- Like that.
Yeah, you didn't say that.
Sixteen and a half.
Eight and a half.
You have no breasts.
Twenty-two.
- Yes, I know.
- Thirty-two and a half.
You can drop your arm now.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, you're perfect.
My job to give you some,
if I choose to.
Ten.
Nine.
Six and a half.
Twenty-five.
And 45. That's it.
- Would you try something else for me?
- Yes.
You have the ideal shape.
- I do?
- Mmm-hmm.
He likes a little belly.
I never really liked myself.
I thought my
shoulders were too wide,
my neck was skinny like a bird,
that I had no breasts.
I felt my hips were larger
than needed,
and my arms too strong.
I feel as if I've been looking
for you for a very long time.
You found me.
Whatever you do,
do it carefully.
But in his work,
I become perfect.
And I feel just right.
Good evening,
Mr. Woodcock, sir.
Maybe that's how
all women feel in his clothes.
You look beautiful, really.
Very beautiful.
You're making me
extremely hungry.
- Thank you.
- I ordered you a steak tartare.
Oh, perfect. Thank you.
My little carnivore.
I've just been on the telephone
to your favorite client.
Mmm-hmm.
Barbara Rose
is getting married again.
Oh, goody.
All right. Well...
Think I'd better have another one of these.
That's your room.
I'm right next door.
Get your rest.
We'll start early
in the morning.
How early?
I'll wake you.
Good night.
Sometimes
we wake up
at 4:00 in the morning,
after we've gone
to bed at midnight.
And then he's ready
to start again.
And I can stand endlessly.
No one can stand
as long as I can.
What is it, Alma?
What are you looking
so forlorn about, hmm?
I don't know, I...
I think I don't like
the fabric so much.
Well, Alma,
this fabric is adored
by the women
who wear our design.
It's perfect for this dress.
Cyril is right.
Cyril is always right.
It's not because the fabric is adored
by the clients that Cyril is right.
It's right because it's right.
Because it's beautiful.
Maybe one day you'll
change your taste, Alma.
Maybe not.
Maybe you have no taste.
Maybe I like my own taste.
Yes, just enough
to get you into trouble.
- Perhaps I'm looking for trouble.
- Stop!
You know, at the big races and
the Derby and, uh, those“.
- Yes?
- Excuse me, Mr. Woodcock.
I would like to say that I hope one
day I could wear one of your dresses.
Oh, thank you.
If that's your wish, I hope
it comes true for you.
She really means it.
She told me she wants to be
buried in a dress that you make.
Hmm.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, ladies, for your kind words.
Good night.
- Thank you.
- Thank you!
- Good night. Thank you very much.
- Good night.
You'd dig her up and sell the
dress again, wouldn't you, Nigel?
Well, otherwise it would
seem to be going to a waste,
but, yeah, I mean,
one but can try.
Nigel, why aren't
you eating your profiteroles?
What?
Have you had enough to eat?
You seem thirsty.
Morning, Reynolds.
Mmm-hmm.
- Morning, Cyril.
Please, don't move
so much, Alma.
I'm buttering my toast,
I'm not moving too much.
Well, it's too much.
It's a distraction,
it's very distracting.
Maybe you pay
too much attention to it.
It's hard to ignore.
It's as if you just rode
a horse across the room.
This is too much movement.
It is entirely too much
movement at breakfast.
Perhaps you should
take your breakfast after him.
Or in your room.
I think he's being too fussy.
His routine, when he's in
it, is best not shaken.
- Well...
- This is a quiet time,
not to be misused.
If breakfast isn't right,
it's very hard for him to recover
for the rest of the day.
I didn't know that.
No, of course you didn't.
But you do now.
Still I think he's too fussy.
Well, that's as may be.
This is Flemish bobbin
lace from the late 1600s.
It's very rare, very precious.
I rescued it from Antwerp
during the war.
I've been waiting
for the right moment to...
To make something with it.
Hold it.
- That's very nice. That's beautiful.
- That's good.
- Best yet. Beautiful.
- Very nice. Turn towards the light.
Um, just look towards
the window, please, Alma.
Amber, could you just
lift the bodice,
a little bit?
It keeps dropping down.
We need to get that adjusted properly.
It's ridiculous.
- Just get it fixed.
- Yes, sir.
Should've been
ready today, quite honestly.
Keep your eye on that.
- Together.
- I'm not sitting on the floor.
Sit on the floor.
You're lovely.
Ah, it's great.
That's great.
Okay, hold that
while I change the film.
Have I finished yet?
All right, that's it.
I need to do some work.
Hell.
Yes?
May I come in?
I'm working.
Do you need anything?
It's fabulous on the shoulders.
Shoulder drapes, and then you
can put it on completely.
Okay?
Good, good, good.
Alma? Is she ready?
Nearly.
Come on, please.
Mmm-hmm.
Ingrid.
Uh, cape's wrong.
Let me do it.
Ellie, you ready?
Let's have a look at you.
Stand here, please.
Mmm.
All right.
Off you go. Thank you, Pippa.
Ingrid, you ready?
Let me do it, let me do it.
Damn it.
You're no good to me
just standing there, Pippa!
- I need your hands on this.
- Sorry, sir. Sorry. Yes.
Just go. Go, go!
I'm sorry.
Let me drive for you.
You see, when you...
When you love your work
and you can give like he does...
You need to come down
again.
And then he's...
He's a baby.
Like a spoiled little baby.
When he's like this,
he's very tender.
Open.
How long will these
episodes last?
Only a few days,
and then he's well again.
- No. Alma, what are you doing?
- There's tea for you.
Don't put the tray on the table, please.
Just take it off.
I didn't ask for tea.
No, but...
Can you take it out, please?
Yes, I can take it out.
- It's a bit late now, isn't it?
- I'm taking it out.
Yeah, but it's a bit
late now, isn't it?
But I'm taking it out.
The tea is going out, the interruption
is staying right here with me.
What if they are yellow
underneath and white on top?
The poison ones have gills.
Look at the book in the kitchen.
We cook them in fat?
No, we'll cook them in butter.
But not too much.
Mr. Woodcock detests
too much butter.
There's a very good chance Barbara Rose
will ask you to attend her wedding.
What do you want me
to do with that?
Accept her invitation.
If you can stomach it.
I really wish I hadn't heard
this till later on, Cyril.
It's very unsettling.
Well,
chin up.
Barbara Rose pays
for this house.
All right?
Morning, Barbara.
Morning, Cal.
Morning, Tippy.
- Good morning,
- Mr. Woodcock.
Reynolds.
Let's get started.
Put it in there.
Thank you.
I'm just going
to lift this up, Barbara.
Oh.
I know you're doing
the best you can.
Don't do that.
- Take your hand away, please.
- I'm still so ugly.
Barbara, I'm trying to make
you a beautiful dress.
I need your help.
Uh, please.
Reynolds, will you come?
Just stand still, please.
It's really not my place,
Barbara.
This is what I do.
This is my place, here.
I'm afraid I must insist
that you come.
George Riley, News of the World.
- Who'll be the attendant at the wedding?
- My son, Cal.
My Cal, my son.
He's so wonderful, he's so
in favor of this marriage.
John Evans, Daily Mail.
And what of your holdings,
Miss Rose?
Do they become
Dominican property?
- I don't know, I don't think so.
- If I may say,
we are being married
under Dominican law,
but in my country,
her money belongs to her
and my money belongs to me.
Anyway, why would I need her money?
I have enough of my own.
What's Barbara brought into your life?
I brought sincerity
into his life.
- Sincerity?
- Then one kiss for the cameras.
Go on, give us a kiss
for the cameras, Miss Rose.
The answer to the question
- is sincerity.
- Let's give them a kiss...
Rubio, tell us about selling visas
to the Jews during the war.
Thank you.
Visas? Jews?
- Thank you very much, gentlemen.
- Thank you for that.
Jews, visas?
That dress doesn't belong here.
- Don't start crying.
- I'm not crying.
I'm angry.
- Well, don't start blubbering, Alma.
- I'm not blubbering.
She doesn't deserve it.
It's your work.
Come on.
Tippy?
Mr. Woodcock.
- What is it?
- I would like the dress back.
Miss Rose is sleeping.
Well, that's got nothing
to do with the dress.
Can you go and get it
for me, please?
She's sleeping.
In the dress?
Well, yes.
Go and take the dress off her
and bring it to me right away.
- I don't think so.
- Take the fucking dress off Barbara
and bring it to me
or I'll do it myself!
I beg your pardon?
Alma.
- Hello, Mr. Woodcock.
- Cal.
I...
It's no business of ours
what Mrs. Rose decides
to do with her life.
But she can no longer
behave like this
and be dressed
by the House of Woodcock.
Thank you.
I love you.
- Pedigree. That's for mother.
- Racy.
Uh, she'd like
something like that, but...
- Thank you, dear.
- It's Mona's day.
- Yes, it is.
- So I'd like to wear something for her.
- Yes, of course.
- She mentioned that last time.
- Did she?
- Yeah.
- Did she really?
All right.
- Julie.
- Yes, sir.
- Do we have porridge?
- Yes, we do.
- Um, do we have cream?
- We do, yes.
- Thick cream?
- Oh, yes.
That's what I'd like
for breakfast, please.
- All right, sir.
- Don't forget the salt this time.
- I shan't, I shan't.
- Oh, Alma, would you like some porridge...
- Yes.
- This morning?
- Some for Alma as well, please.
- Right away.
- And, um, bacon and eggs with that.
- All right, sir.
Morning.
I'm so hungry.
Delighted that we have
cream in the house.
- Yes.
- Makes all the difference.
It's essential with porridge.
A little bit naughty though.
- Dear Reynolds.
- Your Royal Highness.
- Hello.
- How beautiful you are.
- How nice to see you again.
- Your Royal Highness.
- Cyril!
- Your Highness.
- Hello.
- How lovely to see you.
Good morning.
When you dream about your
wedding dress, what is it that you dream?
I dream that it's
the most beautiful wedding dress
in the world.
Naturally.
Perhaps the only wedding dress
in the world.
Yes.
Or to take it just
a little step further,
perhaps the only wedding dress
that was ever made.
Oui.
Is Your Royal Highness a gold
person or a silver person?
- Silver.
- Good.
Lace or pearl?
Lace.
Very good.
Merci.
I want to wish you
good fortune for your wedding.
Thank you.
Je m'appelle Alma.
Lovely to meet you, Alma.
I live here.
Come in.
Alma.
Good morning, Cyril.
I wanted to ask your help in a gift
I wanted to make for Reynolds.
I want to make him a surprise.
If everyone left the house
when he takes his walk
on Thursday,
I will cook for him, dinner.
And when he comes back,
no one will be there but me.
I'll be waiting for him,
I will surprise him and we
can have dinner together,
just the two of us.
Do you like this idea?
Would you help me?
It isn't his birthday.
I know.
I would advise
against this, Alma.
- Why?
- Because he doesn't like surprises.
- He does.
- Well, he won't like this one.
I'm trying to surprise him
and love him the way
that I want to.
Well, if you're looking
for something kind to do,
perhaps you could think of
something else.
No, I really must advise
against this, Alma.
I don't think there could be a more
inappropriate time to try something new.
This is what I want to do,
and I think
it will be very nice.
I respect your advice, Cyril.
But I have to know him
in my own way,
and this is what
I want to do for him.
Good night.
- Good night.
- Good night, madame.
Good night, madame.
Good luck.
Oh, Alma. What is this?
I love you, Reynolds.
Yes, but what is this?
It's a surprise.
Are you hungry?
Where is Cyril?
I've sent everyone home.
She's left.
What time did she leave?
This afternoon.
I've made us dinner.
Let me collect myself
for a moment.
I'll just have a bath, I think.
This is very kind of you, Alma.
- Would you like a champagne or a martini?
- No, thank you.
Oh, is that your dress?
It's finished.
Let's have a look at it.
Hmm.
It's rather interesting.
Very good work.
I'll just have my bath now.
When will Cyril get back?
Mmm, tonight?
How was your appointment
with the princess?
She's very beautiful, like
a sculpture of some kind.
Mmm-hmm.
So will you
make her a wedding gown?
I have made her baptism,
her First Communion
and confirmation dresses.
I made the dress
for her presentation at court,
indeed the entire wardrobe
for her coming out season.
It's only right that I should make her
wedding dress, wouldn't you think?
- Christ.
- No.
But this is not
what I wanted to say.
I'm sorry, I don't know
what I said, I...
This is meant
to be a nice evening.
Let me serve you.
Do you like it?
I do.
No, you don't.
You don't like it at all.
Usually, you always
tell me what you think.
What is this?
You're lying.
As I think you know, Alma,
I prefer my asparagus
with oil and salt.
And knowing this, you've prepared
the asparagus with butter.
Now, I can imagine
in certain circumstances
being able to pretend
that I like it made this way.
Right now, I'm just admiring
my own gallantry
for eating it the way
you've prepared it.
I don't know
what I'm doing here.
I'm just waiting around
like an idiot for you.
This was an ambush, Alma.
To what purpose?
This is not...
I know it's not going
as I expected.
I didn't mean
these things to come out.
I'm sorry, but it was
meant to be nice.
Well, what did you expect?
I wanted time with you. I
wanted to have you to myself.
- You have me all the time.
- No.
- What on earth are you talking about?
- I don't!
There are always people around.
And if not, then there's
something between us.
- Something between us?
- Yes.
- What?
- Some...
- Distance!
When did this happen?
What happened to make you
behave like this?
Is it because you think
I don't need you?
- Yes.
- I don't.
Well, that's
very predictable of you.
Don't act so tough.
I know you are not.
Yeah, that's right. That's right.
If I don't protect myself
somebody will come
in the middle of the night
and take over
my corner of the room
and ask me about
their fucking asparagus!
- Don't be a bully. You're being a bully.
- There are other things
- I'd like to do with my time. It's my time!
- I have no idea
- what I'm doing here in your time!
- My time!
What am I doing here?
I'm standing around like
an idiot waiting for you!
- Waiting for what?
- Waiting for you.
Waiting for what?
Waiting for you
to get rid of me.
To tell me to leave.
So tell me.
So I don't stand around
like a fucking fool.
Asparagus, is this all about
your asparagus?
- No, it's not about asparagus.
- Then what the hell is it about?
Are you a special agent
sent here to ruin my evening
and possibly my entire life?
Why are you so rude to me?
- Why are you talking to me like this?
- Is this my house?
- This is my house, isn't it?
- Yes, this is your house.
- Is this my house?
- Of course it's your house.
- Or did somebody drop me on foreign soil.
- What a question!
Behind enemy lines?
- It's you who brought me here.
- I'm surrounded on all sides.
It's you who brought me here.
When the hell did this happen?
Who are you?
Do you have a gun?
You here to kill me?
- Why are you...
- Do you have a gun?
- Stop it!
- Where's your gun?
- Stop being a child.
- Stop playing.
- Show me your gun.
Stop playing this game!
- I am not.
- I'm not playing a game.
- Yes. Mmm-hmm. Uh-huh.
- What game am I playing?
What game? What precisely
is the nature of my game?
- You tell me.
- Oh, this whole...
- What?
- All your rules and your walls
and your doors and your people
and your money and all these
clothes and everything!
This, this, this game!
Everything here!
The whole... Pfft!
Nothing is normal
or natural or...
Everything is a game!
"Yes, mister!
No, madam! Yes."
Well...
- if it's my...
- "I don't eat this. I don't drink that.
- "I don't..."
- If it's my life that you're describing,
it's entirely up to you whether
you choose to share it or not.
If you don't wish
to share that life,
as apparently it's so disagreeable
to you in every respect,
why don't you just fuck off
to back where you came from?
Yeah.
Sometimes it's good for him to
slow down his steps a little.
Would you like me
to ask Alma to leave?
No. Why?
Well, if you're going
to make her a ghost,
go ahead and do it.
But, please, don't let her
sit around waiting for you.
I'm very fond of her.
Oh, you're very fond of her, are you? In that case...
No, don't turn it on me. I don't
want your cloud on my head.
- Oh, shut up, Cyril.
- No, you can shut right up.
Don't pick a fight with me, you
certainly won't come out alive.
I'll go right through you and it'll
be you who ends up on the floor.
Understood?
- Morning, Pippa.
- Morning, sir.
- Pen, book and glasses?
- Yes, they're all there for you, sir.
- Morning, ladies.
- Good morning, sir.
Excellent work, ladies. Um...
It's just not very good, is it?
It's ugly.
You all right, sir?
Reynolds?
Reynolds, are you all right?
Mr. Woodcock,
he seems to be ill.
Who seems to be ill?
Mr. Woodcock, he's fallen over
and he's damaged the dress.
I'm sorry, Biddy.
Who's fallen over?
Mr. Woodcock, he's fallen over
and he's damaged the dress.
There's stains
on the front of the skirt
and there's a hole
in the lace on the bodice
and there's shoe polish
on the front of the dress.
Shoe polish from what?
From his shoe.
I'm fine.
Oh, I don't know what
the hell came over me.
Must be something I've eaten.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, God.
- You should lie down now.
- No, I'll be fine in a minute.
- Please lie down.
- No, really, don't fuss, Alma, please.
Just don't fuss.
Whatever it is, if you fuss,
I'll die right here.
I promise I won't fuss.
Let me do that, please.
- I have to take these off.
- Yes, I'll take them off.
Alma? Alma?
Yes?
Um...
Would you tell them
I'll be down shortly?
Yes, of course.
Hello, Cyril.
Hello.
What is it?
I don't know what the
bloody hell came over me.
I'll be all right in a moment.
Oh, you don't look all right.
Where does it hurt?
Hurts all over.
I've never really felt
like this before.
Is it your stomach?
Is it something you've eaten?
No, I don't think so.
Just sore, really.
So please tell them
I'll be with them in a minute.
No, you're not going anywhere.
You're to stay here and rest.
Would you like me
to do anything?
Just give me silence.
- Shall I call the doctor?
- No, Cyril, you certainly will not, please.
- All right.
- Um...
- Exhausted yourself.
- Just give me silence.
- Burning up.
- You take care of the dress for me.
Yes, of course I will.
It's all right.
I just...
I just want...
That's it.
Come on, Alma.
I think I may be sick again.
We're gonna have
to do a lot of work
to get this dress ready
for tomorrow, you know.
We're gonna have to undo the front
of the dress and replace the skirt.
We're gonna have to cut
a new panel of the satin
and then there's also the
organza that needs to be...
Yes, I'll deal with that
in a minute, Biddy. Thank you.
You're soaked. We need
to change your pajamas.
I'm scared, Alma.
Yes, of course you are.
Do you think
I'll ever get better?
Of course.
I'll take care of you.
Madam, there's a telephone call.
He's settled now, sleeping.
- The doctor's here.
- What doctor?
The doctor I sent for.
- Oh, no, but he doesn't...
- He needs to be examined.
- No.
- Yes!
No, he's not dying.
He needs to be examined.
He's sleeping now.
That's what he needs.
Let me be unambiguous.
Come out of the room
and downstairs immediately.
All right.
Alma, this is Dr. Hardy.
How do you do, Mrs. Woodcock?
How do you do?
How's he feeling?
He's better.
He's sleeping.
Is he able to keep
anything down yet?
He hasn't tried yet.
Uh, I was going
to make some soup.
And his fever?
It has gone down.
- Uh, would you like me to see him?
- Yes.
- Is that all right, Mrs. Woodcock?
- Yes, it is!
Reynolds, Lady Baltimore has
sent her godson to see you.
Dr. Hardy.
Hello, Mr. Woodcock.
May I examine you?
Keep your hands off me.
- I'd just like to take your temperature.
- Alma,
there's a strange boy in the room.
Can you get him out, please?
- I admit I do look young, but I...
- Fuck off.
Reynolds, please,
just let him examine you.
Yes, fuck off.
- I think this is clear.
- Hmm.
He wants you to fuck off.
I'm so sorry, Doctor.
- I'm very sorry.
- Not to worry.
I'll drop by tomorrow morning
to see how he's coming along.
- 9:00 a.m.?
- Yes.
If his fever increases during
the night, you'll telephone me?
Of course, Doctor.
- Good night, Mrs. Woodcock.
- Good night, Doctor.
Follow me.
When will it be ready?
I don't know.
Let me put it another way.
This dress will be ready by 9:00 a.m.
because that's when it leaves for Belgium.
Ladies, I'm very sorry, but I'm afraid
you'll have to work late this evening.
The dress needs to be ready by 9:00 a.m.
to make its journey to Belgium.
Do expect to be here
for quite some time.
If you need to use the telephone,
please use the one in my office...
- Nana and Biddy...
- ...to alert your families.
What can I do to help?
Could you pin the ribbon on
the hem there, please? Thank you.
Ladies, I'm very sorry, but I'm afraid
you'll have to work late this evening.
The dress needs
to be ready by 9:00 a.m.
and I know there's rather
a lot to do on it still.
So please do expect to be here
possibly for most of the night.
If you need to make telephone calls,
do so from my office. Thank you.
Are you here?
Are you always here?
I miss you.
I think about you all the time.
I hear your voice
say my name when I dream.
Then when I wake up, there are
tears streaming down my face.
I just miss you,
it's as simple as that.
I want to tell you everything.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
I can't hear your voice.
Your fever's gone down.
I love you, Alma.
I don't ever want
to be without you.
I love you.
I have things I want to do.
I had thought my days
were unlimited.
The mistakes I've made
and made again,
they can no longer be ignored.
There are things nagging at me.
Things that now must be done.
Things I simply
cannot do without you.
To keep my
sour heart from choking.
To break a curse.
A house that doesn't
change is a dead house.
Alma, will you marry me?
Will you marry me?
What the bloody hell
are you thinking about?
Will you marry me?
No?
Yes.
Will you marry me?
Yes, I will.
Reynolds to Alma, when you say these
binding and contracting words,
you'll be looking at each other.
After all, it is each other
you are marrying and not me.
Reynolds... I call upon
these persons here present...
I call upon these persons
here present...
To witness that I,
Reynolds Jeremiah Woodcock...
Do take thee, Alma Elson...
To be my lawful wedded wife...
To be my lawful wedded wife.
Alma... I call upon
these persons here present...
I call upon these persons
here present...
To witness that I, Alma Elson...
Do take thee,
Reynolds Jeremiah Woodcock...
To be my lawful wedded husband.
And it now gives me
great pleasure to say...
Congratulations.
You are now husband and wife.
And you may kiss the bride.
- An hour?
- Uh, an hour? That's okay.
Cuckoo.
- I'll see you later.
- See you later.
- Have a good time.
- You, too.
You, too, have a good time.
Not for me, thank you.
Dr. Hardy?
- Dr. Hardy?
- Oh! Hey. Sorry, excuse me.
Reynolds, do you
remember Dr. Hardy?
- Good evening, Mr. and Mrs. Woodcock.
- Oh, hello.
How do you do, Mr. Woodcock?
How are you feeling?
I think we met in a puddle
of sweat, didn't we?
Yes, that's right.
I probably owe you
an apology of some kind.
- I seem to remember barking at you.
- There's no need.
- I've been laid siege by much worse.
- Oh, really?
You look very healthy.
How are you feeling?
Didn't I tell you to fuck off?
Yes. Yes, you did.
Dinner is served, everybody!
Come along.
That's your shifty-eyed godson?
Shifty-eyed?
He's got perfectly normal eyes.
I'm rather less fat, I think,
than when you last saw me.
- Really?
- Yes.
Thank you very much indeed.
It's fallen off me.
Ooh! I'm so sorry.
...there are secrets nobody tells.
Your wife has got that gorgeous
glow you get with a first marriage.
How long will you be here for?
Seems my godson's rather
enjoying that glow as well.
So, what are your plans
for New Year's Eve?
Oh, um...
We don't have any.
Well, you should come out for
the Chelsea Arts Club Ball.
- I don't know what that is.
- It's not something I'd suggest
if I didn't think you'd have
a wonderful time.
It's really something
to be seen.
I'll pass it on to my husband.
But I think we'll stay in.
Change your mind.
Or get him to change his
mind, or whatever it takes.
Now, please come. I promise you
the time of your life.
How do you know
how my life has been?
I don't.
You're right.
I think this would be quite a
fine time, if you'd like to come.
She's barely looked at you
this evening, has she?
I think they're well
and truly shaken now.
What on earth are you doing?
- I rolled a three.
- Yes, but that's the four pip.
- Go back to the bar where you belong.
- Oh, sorry.
Let's not start cheating
at this stage, Alma.
I'm not cheating.
I don't need to cheat.
Oh, good. You do need to be able
to count, on the other hand.
Backgammon, by the way,
I get treble the score
because you haven't gotten
any checkers off the board.
Oh.
Stupid game anyway.
Well, maybe it seems stupid to you
now as you're currently losing,
but I dare say
if you were victorious,
I'm confident you'd see it
in a different light.
Now, they need your chair
for my next opponent. Next.
Me, please.
What? What are you
so cranky about?
Have fun with
your next opponent.
Why, I think I will, a lot
more than I did with you.
Gosh. She's
really very rude, isn't she?
My heart breaks for you.
Oh, really?
Being married to a toddler.
I don't want to be racist,
but, I mean, is there some sort of
custom at this time of the night
in her country, where...
- I mean, what's she doing?
- Where what?
I don't know. I don't know
if she's up stealing things
or attacking people, I mean...
I want to go dancing.
When?
Right now.
- You're joking.
- No, I'm not.
It's New Year's Eve.
Well, I'm not going dancing.
There's a party at the Devonshire
Hall to celebrate the New Year
and I want to go.
We need to go dancing.
So what are you going
to do about it?
I'm going to stay right here
and I'm going to work.
On the hour,
ladies and gentlemen!
Are you ready to welcome in our
lovely, glorious, Happy New Year?
Are you ready?
Here we go!
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
How does it feel?
Well, I think
it feels a little big.
Shall we just take it in on the waist?
We can take it in a little on the waist.
- Yes.
- Yes, okay. Just take it out.
How's that feeling?
I think that's better.
Would you excuse me for a
minute, please, Mrs. Vaughan?
Where has
Henrietta Harding been?
- She's been to another house.
- Which one?
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Because I didn't want to.
Is there something I'm unaware of?
Because as far as I can remember,
all I have done is
to dress her beautifully.
I don't think that matters
to some people.
I think they want what
is fashionable and chic.
Chic? Oh, don't you start using
that filthy little word. "Chic"?
Whoever invented that ought to
be spanked in public. I don't...
I don't even know what that word means.
What is that word? Fucking "chic"?
They should be hung, drawn
and quartered! Fucking "chic"!
It shouldn't concern you.
It does concern me.
It concerns me very much, Cyril,
because it's hurt my feelings.
It's hurt my feelings.
So, what's all
this moaning about?
I am not moaning.
I do not like
to be turned away from.
Nobody does.
But I don't want to hear it
because it hurts my ears.
I've made a terrible mistake in
my life, Cyril. I've made a...
I've made a terrible mistake.
I need you to help me.
What do you want me to do?
I can't work.
I can't concentrate,
I have no confidence.
She does not fit in this house.
We built this house,
the two of us.
Now, she's turning the whole
bloody place upside down.
She's turning me inside out.
She's turning you and me
against each other.
Her arrival has cast
a very long shadow, Cyril.
Mrs. Vaughan is satisfied
with the dress.
No one gives a tinker's fucking curse
about Mrs. Vaughan's satisfaction!
Thank you, Alma.
Not at all.
What a model of
politeness you two are.
There is an air of quiet
death in this house
and I do not like
the way it smells.
Would you like a glass of wine?
No, thank you.
Can I make you a martini?
Nothing for me, thanks.
Water?
I want you flat on your back.
Helpless.
Tender.
Open.
With only me to help.
And then I want you
strong again.
You're not going to die.
You might wish you were going to
die, but you're not going to.
You need
to settle down a little.
Kiss me, my girl,
before I'm sick.
I think, perhaps,
you should telephone
that boy doctor
of yours, just in case.
You don't trust me?
No, I do trust you.
It's just...
If you wish.
But I will make you well again.
I will.
I love you.
I love you, too.
And I think, perhaps, you should leave the room.
- Close the door behind you.
- Yes.
I'll be right outside.
If he didn't wake up from this,
if he wasn't here tomorrow,
no matter.
For I know he'd be waiting
for me in the afterlife.
Or some safe, celestial place
in this life and the next
and the next one after.
And for whatever there is on the
road that follows from here,
it would only
require my patience
to get to him again.
You see, to be in love with him
makes life no great mystery.
Say, "Ah."
Ahh.
Very good.
You can put your robe back on.
Sometimes I jump ahead
in our life together.
And I see a time near the end.
I can predict the future
and everything has settled.
And all our lovers
and children and friends
come back and are welcome.
And we have large gatherings
where everyone is laughing
and playing games.
I am older
and I see things differently,
and I finally understand you.
And I take care of your dresses.
Keeping them from dust
and ghosts and time.
Yes, but right now, we're here.
Yes, of course we are.
And I'm getting hungry.