- You're looking good, Dutch.
- It's been a long time, General.
Come on inside.
Eighteen hours ago,
we lost a chopper...
carrying a cabinet minister and his aide
from this charming little country.
We've got a transponder
fixed on their position...
...about here.
This cabinet minister does he always
travel on the wrong side of the border?
Apparently they strayed off course.
And we're fairly certain
they're in guerrilla hands.
So why don't you use the regular army?
What do you need us for?
Because some damn fool
accused you of being the best.
[Chuckles]
Dillon!
You son of a bitch!
What's the matter? The C.I.A. got you
pushing too many pencils?
Huh?
Had enough?
Make it easy on yourself, Dutch.
- [Laughs] Okay, okay, okay!
- You never did know when to quit, huh?
- Damn good to see you, Dutch.
- What is this fucking tie business?
Forget about my tie. I heard about
that job you pulled off in Berlin.
- Very nice, Dutch.
- Good old days.
Like the good old days.
Then how come you passed on Libya, huh?
- That wasn't my style.
- You got no style. You know that.
Come on.
Why did you pass?
We're a rescue team, not assassins.
Now, what do we got to do?
That cabinet minister is very important to
our operations in this part of the world.
The general's saying a couple of our
friends are about to get squeezed.
We can't let that happen.
We need the best.
- That's why you're here.
- Go on.
A simple setup.
One-day operation.
We pick up their trail
at the chopper, run 'em down...
grab those hostages and bounce back across the
border before anybody knows we were there.
- What do you mean, “we”?
- I'm going in with you, Dutch.
General, my team always works alone.
You know that.
I'm afraid we all have
our orders, Major.
Once you reach your objective...
Dillon will evaluate the situation
and take charge.
♪ [Man Singing on Radio]
[Speaking indistinct]
Roger. Over.
Yeah, okay.
[Chuckles]
- [Man On Radio] Delta 7-0.
- [Man] Roger.
[Man On Radio]
Two, Leader.
Rendezvous points and radio freqs
are indicated and fixed.
AWACS contact
on four-hour intervals.
- Who's our backup?
- No such thing, old buddy.
This is a one-way ticket. Once we cross
that border, we 're on our own.
[Chuckles]
This is getting better by the minute.
[Man on Radio, Indistinct]
- Roger 2-2. Roger.
- [Man On Radio, Indistinct]
[Man on Radio]
Tango, Charlie, Delta 7-0.
Two, Leader.
Hey, Billy.
Billy!
The other day, I went up
to my girlfriend. I said...
“You know, I'd like a little pussy.”
She said, “Me too.
Mine's as big as a house!”
You see, she wanted
a littler one, 'cause hers was-
As big as a house.
Get that stinking shit
out of my face.
A bunch of slack-jawed
faggots around here!
This stuff will make you a goddamn
sexual tyrannosaurus,just like me.
Yeah. Strap this
on your sore ass, Blain.
[Blain Laughing]
That was in '72. North of Hue.
Me and Dutch both got one.
That's a real nasty habit
you got there.
- [Beeping]
- [Man On Radio, indistinct]
Right.
[Beeping Continues]
♪ [Stops]
[Man on Radio, Indistinct]
[Man on Radio]
You got it, Leader.
[Beeping Continues]
Never knew how much
I missed this, Dutch.
- You never were that smart.
- [Buzzes]
Hawkins, you're up.
[Man On Radio]
Lines away.
[Animals Chittering]
[Chittering Continues]
The pilots have each
got one round in the head.
Whoever hit it
stripped the shit out of it.
- Took him out with a heat-seeker.
- There's something else, Major.
- Hmm?
- This is no ordinary army taxi.
It looks more like
a surveillance bird to me.
Pick up the trail yet?
Billy's on it.
Heat-seeker, Dillon.
That's pretty sophisticated for a bunch
of half-assed mountain boys.
Major!
I guess they're getting
better equipped every day.
There were 12 guerrillas.
They took the two men from the
helicopter, but there's something else.
What do you mean?
Six men wearing
U.S.-issued army boots.
They came in from the north,
and then they followed the guerrillas.
Mean anything to you?
Probably just another rebel patrol.
They operate in here all the time.
- Get ahead and see what you can find.
- Yes, sir.
[Birds Squawking]
What's he got?
Same business. Guerrillas hauling
two guys from the chopper...
followed by men
with American equipment.
Do you remember Afghanistan?
I'm trying to forget it.
Come on. Let's go.
[Wings Flapping]
[Flapping Continues]
[Predator Growling]
- [Gasps]
- [Birds Screeching]
[Shouts]
[Sighs]
Holy mother of God.
- [Grunts]
- [Squawking]
Jim Hopper.
Mac, cut 'em down.
I knew these men.
Green Berets out of Fort Bragg.
What the hell were they doing here?
I don't know, Dutch.
This is inhuman.
Nobody told me there was
an operation in this area.
- They shouldn't have been here.
- But somebody sent them.
The guerrillas skinned them?
Why did they skin them?
Ain't no way for no soldier to die.
- What happened here, Billy?
- Strange, Major.
There was a firefight.
They were shooting
in all directions.
I can't believe that Jim Hopper
walked into an ambush.
I don't believe he did.
I can't find a single track.
Just doesn't make sense.
What about the rest
of Hopper's men?
There's no sign, sir.
They never left here.
Hell, it's like
they just disappeared.
Stick with the guerrilla trail.
Let's get the hostages.
We move, five-meter spread.
No sound.
It's time to let
Old Painless out the bag.
Payback time.
[Heart Beating]
[Heartbeat Continues]
[Birds Screeching]
You're ghostin' us, motherfucker.
I don't care who you are
back in the world.
You give our position
one more time...
I'll bleed you real quiet
and leave you here.
Got that?
[Generator Whirring]
[Speaks Spanish]
[Speaking Spanish]
[Chattering]
[Man Groans]
- [Speaks Russian]
- Fuck you.
[Groans]
[Chattering Continues]
He killed one of the hostages.
We move.
Mac, Blain- the nest.
Billy, Poncho- the guard.
Hawkins, Dillon- backup.
As soon as they're set,
I hit the fuel dump.
[Exhales]
[Muffled Shout]
One down.
[Whistling Softly]
[Groans]
[Chattering Continues]
[Beeps]
What the hell's he doing?
What the fuck?
[Shouting]
[Screaming]
- Showtime, kid.
- [Man Shouting In Russian]
[Men Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
[Mac] Targets at the
center of the palapa!
[Screaming]
[Man Shouting, Screaming]
Dutch, on your nine!
[Helicopter Engine Revving]
[Speaking Russian]
[Man Screaming]
[Shouting]
[Grunts]
Get that mother-
[Screaming]
Go!
[Shouting Continues]
[Grunts]
Stick around.
Hostages are inside!
Knock, knock.
[Whistles]
I got 'em!
Hawkins, call in position
and situation.
Get Connor for the hook!
You got it, Major.
[Cocks]
Oh, shit.
- Mac, any sign of the other hostage?
- [Mac] Yo!
Found the other guy.
He's dead too.
And the kid from the chopper.
But if they're Central American,
I'm a goddamn Chinaman.
From the looks of it,
our cabinet minister was C.l.A.
Another thing, Major.
We were lucky.
Other guys we waxed-
Russian military advisers.
Something pretty big
was gonna happen here.
Good work, Mac.
Clear the area. No traces.
- Get the men ready to move.
- All right.
Son of a bitch is dug in
like an Alabama tick.
You're hit.
You're bleeding, man.
I ain't got time to bleed.
Oh, okay.
You got time to duck?
This is goddamn beautiful.
Goddamn jackpot.
This is more than
we ever thought we'd get.
- [Papers Rustling]
- Man, we got those bastards.
We got 'em.
I think this is
what you're looking for.
You set us up!
It's all bullshit, all of it- the
cabinet minister, the whole business.
- You got us in here to do your dirty work.
- We stopped a major invasion.
In three days, they'd have been
across the border with this stuff!
- Why us?
- Because nobody else could've pulled it off.
You're pissed about the cover story.
I knew I couldn't get you in here without it.
So what story did
you hand Hopper?
Look, we've been looking
for this place for months.
My men were in that chopper
when it got hit!
Hopper's orders were to go in
and get my men, and he disappeared!
He didn't disappear.
He was skinned alive!
My orders were to get somebody in
who could crack these bastards!
So you cooked up a story and dropped
the six of us in a meat grinder.
[Scoffs]
What happened to you, Dillon?
You used to be somebody
I could trust.
I woke up.
Why don't you?
You're an asset,
an expendable asset...
and I used you to
get the job done.
Got it?
My men are not expendable.
And I don't do this kind of work.
[Hawkins] Major! Major,
We stepped into some bullshit here!
- [Groans]
- [Dillon Speaking Spanish]
Air surveillance says we got guerrillas
all over the place.
Can't be more than one, two miles away.
This place is going down.
- How much time?
- Half an hour, maybe less.
- Tell Mac we move in five.
- Yes, sir.
She goes with us. She's too valuable.
She's got another whole network.
She'll give away our position
any chance she gets. No deal.
You're still under orders.
You want to make that call, or should I?
She's your baggage.
You fall behind, and you're on your own.
[Heart Beating]
[Man Speaking, Warped]
This place is too hot for a pickup.
They won't touch us
till we get over the border.
Hey, Billy, give me
a way out of this hole.
The aerial says we are cut off.
The only way out of here is that valley
that leads to the east.
I wouldn't waste that
on a broke-dick dog.
Not much choice.
Poncho, take lead.
Double-time it.
[Cocks Weapon]
- [Heart Beating]
- [Warped Voices]
[Warped Shouting]
[Shouting In Spanish]
- [Mac] Dillon! Dillon!
- Come on .
Over here.
- [Heartbeat Continues]
- [Growling]
- Turn around.
- Why?
Thanks.
Anytime.
Billy! Billy!
The other day,
I was going down on my girlfriend...
and I said to her,
“Geez, you got a big pussy.
Geez, you got a big pussy.”
She said, “Why did you
say that twice?”
I said, "I didn't."
See, it was 'cause-
'cause of the echo.
[Mutters, Laughs]
[Laughing, Warped Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
[Predator Growling]
[Growling Continues]
[Warped]
Over here. Over here. Over here.
- Turn around. Turn around
- [Laughing]
Turn around
Turn around over here.
[Laughing]
Anytime.
[Growling]
[Animal Squealing]
- [Insects Buzzing]
- Goddamn!
Buddy, buddy buddy, buddy'
I've seen some bad-ass bush before,
man, but nothing like this.
I hear you.
This shit's something.
Makes Cambodia look like Kansas.
Hey, qué pasa, amigo.
A little taste of home.
[Animal Growling, Distant]
You lose it here,
you're in a world of hurt.
Come on, sweetheart.
Stop sandbaggin' it. Now, get up.
Come on. Get up.
Would you get up?
[Shouts In Spanish]
- [Weapon Cocks]
- [Speaking Spanish]
[Chuckling] Maybe you'd better
put her on a leash, agent man.
Try it again, please.
[Spanish]
What's got Billy so spooked?
Can't say, Major.
Been acting squirrelly all morning.
That damn nose of his, it's weird.
What is it?
Billy-
What the hell is wrong with you?
There's something in those trees.
[Mutters]
[Warped]
Do you see anything...
up there?
Nothing.
What do you think?
I guess it's nothing, Major.
- [Weapons Cocking]
- [Predator Panting]
[Whistles]
[Pan ting Continues]
[Shouting, Warped Shouting]
Please.
Please!
[Predator Growling]
[Screams]
[Grunting]
[Leaves Rustling]
[Birds Shrieking]
Billy, break left.
- Mac, right.
- What the-
- This isn't her blood
- What the hell did you do to him?
Major, you'd better
take a look at this.
Did you find Hawkins?
I- I can't tell.
- What in God's name?
- [Insects Buzzing]
I think it's Hawkins.
Where the hell is his body?
There's no sign of it.
Ask her what happened.
[Spanish]
[Continues In Spanish]
[(Chattering Continues In Spanish]
She says the jungle,
it just came alive...
- and took him.
- Bullshit!
That's not what she said!
What she said
doesn't make any sense.
- Those sappers have been following us-
- They've been in front of us!
- [Both Shouting At Once]
- Hold it. Hold it!
Why didn't they take
his radio or his weapon?
Why didn't she escape?
- Hopper.
- What?
They did the same thing
to Jim Hopper.
I want Hawkins's body found.
Sweep pattern.
Double back.
Fifty meters. Let's go.
[Liquid Dripping]
[Rustling]
Come on in, you fuckers.
Come on in.
Old Painless is waiting.
[Chuckles, Grunts]
[Grunts]
Sergeant!
[Shouting]
- Motherfucker!
- [Gunfire Continues]
- [Screaming]
- [Gun Clicking]
Fucker!
[Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
- [Gunfire Stops]
- [Whirring]
- [Clicks]
- [Whirring Continues]
[Whirring Stops]
- What happened?
- I saw it.
- You saw what?
- I saw it!
Blain.
No powder burns, no shrapnel.
The wound's all fused, cauterized.
What the hell could have
done this to a man?
Mac. Mac, look at me!
Who did this?
I don't know, goddamn it.
I saw s-something.
Not a thing.
Not a fucking trace.
No blood no bodies.
We hit nothing.
Dillon, better get on the radio.
Mac.
- Sergeant!
- Yes, sir.
I want a defensive position
above that ridge...
mined with everything we've got.
Put him in his poncho.
Take him with us.
I got him.
Vamonos
[Animal Chittering]
[Mac] Major; I set up ﬂares,
ﬂags and claymores.
Nothing's coming near this place
without tripping on something.
[Dutch]
Thank you, Sergeant.
Mac...
he was a good soldier.
He was, urn...
my friend.
Good-bye, bro.
[Low Growling]
[Beeping]
[Hissing]
[Screeching]
[Dillon] Blazer 1, I repeat:
extraction necessary.
Say again, Blazer 1. Say again.
- [Radio Static]
- [Blazer 1] Request for extraction denied.
The area is still compromised. Proceed
to sector 3,000 for prisoner extraction.
- Priority, out. Next contact: 0930.
- [Radio Static]
Roger, Blazer 1. 1030 hours.
Damn bastards.
They say we're still in too far...
and they can't risk
comin' in after us.
We're assets, Dillon.
Expendable assets.
It comes with the job.
I can accept it.
Bullshit.
You're just like the rest of us.
Shitload of good a chopper's
gonna do us in here anyhow.
Sergeant? Sergeant! Sergeant!
Who hit us today?
I don't know. I only saw
one of them camouﬂaged.
He was there.
- Those eyes disappeared.
- What was that?
Those eyes, they-
they disappeared.
I know one thing, Major.
I drew down and fired straight at it.
Capped off 200 rounds
in the mini-gun, full pack.
Nothin'. Nothin' on this Earth
could've lived...
not at that range.
Mac, you take first watch,
then you get some rest.
Ask her-
Ask her what she saw.
Ask her
what happened to Hawkins.
Go ahead. Ask her.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Responds In Spanish]
She says the same fuckin' thing.
The jungle came alive and took him.
Billy, you know somethin'.
- What is it?
- I'm scared, Poncho.
Bullshit.
You ain't afraid of no man.
There's something out there
waiting for us...
and it ain't no man.
We're all gonna die.
The man's losin' it.
He's losin' his cool.
There is nothin' but a couple of guys runnin '
around out there, and we've gotta take 'em down.
You still don't understand,
Dillon, do you?
Whatever it is out there,
it killed Hopper...
and now it wants us.
[Animals Hooting]
Here we are again, bro.
just you and me.
Same kind of moon.
Same kind of jungle.
Real number 10 night.
Remember?
Whole platoon, 32 men, chopped into meat,
and we walk out, just you and me.
Nobody else. Right on top of 'em.
Not a scratch.
Not a fuckin' scratch.
You know, whoever got you,
he'll come back again...
and when he does,
I'm gonna cut your name right into him.
I'm gonna cut your name into him.
[Twig Snaps]
- [Dillon] What the hell is it?
- Mac!
[Screeching]
- [Dillon] This Way!
- Where the hell are you? Where are you?
Mac! Mac!
- [Creature, Mac Grunting]
- Mac!
[Creature Growling]
- Mac! Where are you?
- Don't fuck with me!
- Mac!
- [Creature Screeching]
- Mac, where are you?
- Jesus.
- Got you, motherfucker.
Killed you, you fuck.
[Poncho] Jesus.
You killed a pig.
[Billy] What the-
- Do you think you could've
found something bigger?
- Yeah. Fuck you, Poncho. Fuck you.
- [Dillon Laughing]
- Where's the girl?
- Aw, shit.
Why the hell wasn't
anybody watching her?
- [Gasping]
- Why didn't she try to get away?
[Dutch] Look at her.
She's scared out of her mind
Major, you'd better
take a look at this.
[Billy] Blain's body.
It's gone.
It came in through the trip wires.
Took it right out
from under our noses.
[Birds Screeching]
That boar had to
set off a trip flare, Major...
because there ain't no other tracks.
How could anyone get through this,
carry out Blain without us knowing it?
Why didn't he try and kill one of us?
He came in to get the body.
He's killing us one at a time.
[Billy]
Like a hunter.
He's using the trees.
- Yesterday. What did you see?
- You're wasting your time.
No more games.
I don't know what it was. it-
- Go on.
- It changed colors, like the chameleon.
It uses the jungle.
You saying that Blain and Hawkins
were killed by a fuckin' lizard?
That's a bullshit psych job. There's two
or three men out there at the most.
Fuckin' lizard!
- What's your name?
- Anna.
Anna, this thing
is hunting us, all of us.
You know that.
What the hell
do you think you're doin'?
We're gonna need everyone.
I'm takin' her back. We're
out of here in five minutes.
You're not going yet.
Look. The rendezvous
is 10 to 12 miles away.
- You think the chopper's gonna wait?
- Dillon, we make a stand now...
or there will be nobody left
to go to the chopper.
There is something else.
When the big man was killed,
you must've wounded it.
Its blood was on the leaves.
If it bleeds, we can kill it.
[Grunting]
Look out.
You really think this Boy Scout
bullshit's gonna work?
It can see our trip wires.
Maybe it can't see this.
Instead of complaining,
maybe you should help.
[Chuckles]
What makes you think
he's gonna come in through here?
There are trip wires on every tree
for 50 yards. This is the only way in.
When I was little, we found a man.
He looked like- like, butchered.
The old women in the village
crossed themselves...
and whispered crazy things,
said strange things.
[Speaking Spanish]
Only in the hottest years
this happens.
And this year, it grows hot.
We begin finding our men.
We found them sometimes
without their skin...
and sometimes
much, much worse.
[Spanish]
Means the demon
who makes trophies of man.
[Wings Fluttering]
[Bird Screeches]
So what are you gonna try next?
Cheese?
Hey, Dutch! Dutch!
- [Predator Screeching]
- Shit!
[Screeching Continues]
[Explosions]
- [Gunfire]
- [All Yelling]
[Grunts]
[Growling]
[Electrical Arcing]
[Gunfire]
Got you, you mother!
I got you!
- I'm comin'!
- Mac. Mac!
- Get Ramirez and get to the chopper.
- Right.
- Hold it, Dutch. I'm goin' after Mac.
- That's not your style, Dillon.
I guess I picked up some bad habits from
you. Now, get your people out of here.
You can't win this, Dillon.
Maybe I can get even.
Dillon.
just hold onto that damn chopper.
[Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
- He's busted up pretty bad, Major.
- I can make it. I can make it.
- Get the radio. Forget the rest.
- Right.
- [Poncho Yelps]
- Come on, Poncho. Come on, Poncho.
- [Yelps]
- [Dutch] Come on.
[Speaking Song Lyrics]
[Continues]
[Stops]
[Mac Whispering]
Turn around
[Mac]
Over here.
Mac?
Shh.
[Whispering]
Out there. Past them trees.
You see it?
I see you.
I see it.
Yeah.
You know, we can
get this thing, Mac.
You work your way
down there toward him.
I'm gonna loop around, get in back
of him, flush him toward you.
When I flush that son of a bitch,
you nail him.
I got a score to settle.
We both got scores to settle.
[Growling]
[Grunts]
- Vamos!
- [Poncho Grunts]
Vamos! Come on!
Quickly! Hurry up.
- [Poncho Groans]
- [Dutch] Don't. Leave it.
It didn't kill you because you
weren't armed. No sport.
[Whispering]
Mac.
- [Mac's Voice] Anytime.
- [Predator Growls]
[Screams]
[Metal Clanking]
- [Gunshot]
- [Screams]
- [Gunshots, Distant]
- [Screaming Continues]
[Groaning]
Let's go.
Billy!
Billy, let's go!
- [Gasping]
- [Groaning]
[Spanish]
Give me the weapon!
- [Grunting]
- [Anna Continues In Spanish]
- [All Gasping]
- [Billy Screams]
[Dutch Gasps]
[Panting]
[Whimpering]
- No!
- Run!
Run!
[Screams]
- Go! Get to the chopper!
- [Panting]
[Screams]
Oh, shit!
[Electrical Arcing]
[Squeaking]
[Low Growl]
[Exhales]
He couldn't see me.
[Grunts]
[Groans]
[Predator Growling]
[Screeching]
[Match Strikes]
[Guttural Yell]
[Yell Echoes]
[Low Growl]
[Panting]
[Twigs Cracking]
[Growling]
[Screeches]
[Grunting]
[Panting]
[Predator Screeches]
Bleed bastard
[Screeching]
[Yelling]
[Gagging]
[Hissing]
[Low Growl]
You're one ugly motherfucker.
[Screeches]
Bad idea.
- [Blow Lands]
- [Predator Shrieks]
[Dutch Panting]
- [Dutch Coughs]
- [Predator Yells]
[Dutch Grunts]
Come on. Come on.
Do it. Do it!
[Low Growl]
Come on. Come on.
Kill me. I'm here. Kill me!
I I'm here. Kill me!
Come on! Kill me! I'm here!
Come on! Do it now!
Kill me!
[Sighs]
[Wood Creaking]
[Predator Growling]
[Growling Continues]
[Gurgling]
[Low Growl]
[Coughing]
What the hell are you?
[Guttural Voice]
What the hell...
are you?
[Growls]
[Whirring, Beeping]
[Device Beeping Warning Tone]
[Predator Growls]
[Laughing Maniacally]
[Continues Laughing]
Holy shit.
- Check the battery.
- [Man] Okay.
- Did you get it?
- [Man] Got it!
What the-
[General]
My God.
[Chopper Approaching]