...unprecedented violence,
and with the strike
entering its fourth month,
the government insisted
that it will push ahead
with plans to close 20 pits with
the loss of over 20,000 jobs,
an action that Mr. Scargill says
will destroy entire communities.
You can look back in 10
years and you can say:
"In 1984, I was proud and privileged
to be a party to the
greatest struggle on Earth."
I left my number.
Just in case.
Everything's at stake for me.
I'm 27 years old, right?
See you on the march then?
I'm fighting for their jobs, not me own.
We've used the savings up.
We have no money left.
All we've got is pride and self-respect,
and we'll carry on keeping that.
The prime minister today
defended her position.
I can't change my style.
It has to be a style of firm leadership.
One isn't here to be a softie.
You're here to be a good, firm leader.
- Here, Mark, do you wanna play ball?
- Tomorrow, buddy.
- Here you go, Mark.
- Great, thanks.
I've spoken to the council
about your deviant parties.
There's no need to do that.
Knock on the door, we'd let you in.
They're sending a policeman.
Oh, I do hope so.
Mark!
Thanks.
Then the riot squad,
the helmeted policemen
with their plastic shields
were deployed after smoke
bombs were thrown.
- The violence continued.
- Thanks, Dad.
The pickets nearly broke
through the barricade.
The train now approaching
is the 9:23 to London Victoria.
Is that copper really straight?
Two, four, six, eight.
Hey, grab a hold of this,
will you, mate?
- Oh, no, sorry. I...
- Five minutes till me friends get here.
- Come on.
- Just that I don't want to be too visible.
- Is it your first Pride?
- Yeah, first anything.
Yeah, well, this is the best way.
You need to throw yourself in.
The thing is,
is I'm actually from Bromley.
Well, don't worry about that.
We're a broad church.
No, it's the train. It's further
out than people think and I...
Oi! I been dragging this
thing since Marble Arch.
What, are they buckets?
Surprised you have to ask that,
coming from Accrington.
- Does anything get rid of love bites?
- No, where's Mark now?
- Listen up.
- Where have you been?
Everyone, take a bucket
and start rattling.
- This is for the miners.
- Miners?
We agreed on a banner, Mark.
It's a show of solidarity.
Who hates the miners? Thatcher.
Who else? The police, the public and
the tabloid press. Sound familiar?
- Surely, Mark...
- But the only problem we've got,
is Mary Whitehouse,
and that can be a matter of time.
- Mark...
- I know, it's not been planned.
It's not been thought through,
but it's a really good idea, isn't it?
Isn't it?
- What am I supposed to do with this?
- Give it to the lesbians.
Oh, for God's sake. Right, looks like
you're off the hook, mate. Good lad.
Whatever Mark says, we do it.
Don't ask me why.
- Disgusting.
- Yes.
We're collecting for the
miners and their families!
Collecting for the miners
and their families, guys!
Gays and lesbians support
the miners and their families!
I was wondering, do you need a hand?
Well, well, if it isn't Bromley.
I mean, my last train's
actually not for ages.
- Gays and lesbians support miners!
- Support the miners!
Guys, support the miners!
Gays and lesbians support miners!
Collecting for miners!
Support the miners. Come on.
Support the miners! Support the miners!
It's just a couple of
the lads from college.
And one of them lives in Chislehurst,
so he can't be too late, either.
I've got my key.
Just mind yourself on that last train.
There's weirdoes and all sorts on there.
Thanks, Mum.
Hey, Bromley.
Over here.
I'm hiding from that girl.
- Why?
- Broke my heart at a Smiths concert.
I've never met a lesbian before.
Really? I've never met anyone
who irons their jeans.
- I live at home.
- No shit.
Is that where you got
that lovely brooch?
That's embarrassing.
It's today.
What are you, 10?
- I'm 20.
- I wouldn't go spreading that around.
You're illegal, darling.
Sixteen for the breeders,
21 for the gays.
Did you learn nothing on that march?
You're still a minor.
- Jesus.
- Victory to the minors.
- Don't make a mess, okay?
- They've counted it.
Well, come on,
you've collected as much as anyone.
Stephanie, were you with
Jeff in The Bell last night?
For fuck's sake, it's a bruise, okay?
My neck is bruised.
No red wine on the floor, please.
Ashtrays!
It was a pretty good march today.
Not much in the way
of beatings or abuse.
Hardly any petrol bombs or swastikas.
Is it me or are the police getting soft?
It's funny, they've stopped hanging
around outside our clubs lately.
What's that about?
Do you think they finally got
sick of all that Donna Summer?
Yeah, headline.
My guess is they went somewhere else.
To pick on someone else.
My guess is that while we're
enjoying a temporary reprieve,
they're here.
Giving these poor sods
the shit we usually get.
Now, these mining communities
are being bullied just like we are.
Right? Bullied by the police,
bullied by the tabloids,
bullied by the government.
- Do any of them need a hug?
- No.
What they need is cash.
And they need it urgently.
Because the miners have
always come to our aid.
- Are you kidding me? Are you...?
- Why don't we talk about today?
Today, with only a couple of buckets,
we raised nearly 200 quid.
Right? Think what we could achieve
if we really started trying.
- I'm from Durham.
- You know what we're talking about.
I know those bastards kicked the
shit out of me every morning
on my way to school.
And every night on my way home.
We are proposing to meet
at least once a week
and just to do as many
collections as we can.
Oh, and we've got a name.
LGSM.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
- It's not very catchy.
- It's a support group, not a band.
Right. Come on, let's have a show
of hands, shall we? Who's in?
Guys?
Come on, guys, please.
- Oh, come on, guys.
- Is that it?
We've actually been looking for
things to do together as a couple.
Perfect. Youse can feed the
miners and your relationship.
- How many is that?
- That's six.
It's better than five.
- Not as good as seven.
- Jonathan.
Oh, God, here come the gay libbers.
Brilliant party, Geth.
I'm sure you could use the backroom here
- if you're looking for a base, that is.
- We are.
We are. That's amazing.
Gethin, thank you.
And what about me and Jonathan?
Or is it exclusively for the under 25s?
- No.
- Of course not. Everyone's welcome.
Touch me, baby, tainted love
You sure Jonathan's interested?
He's at a bit of a loose end.
He just needs something
to occupy him. A project.
What about Bromley over there?
I... I've just started catering college.
Good. Congratulations all of you.
You're the founder members
of Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
Terrific. Let's bring
down the government.
- Support for the miners.
- Give generously.
Put your hand in your
pockets for the miners.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
National Union of Mineworkers.
Oh, hello, I represent a group
called Lesbians and Gays
Support the Miners and...
Hello?
Hello...
And there's the desired consistency.
It's glossy and wobbly.
Glossy and wobbly.
Jonathan?
Why don't you go out with them today?
Because I've got better things to do
than run around with a bunch of kids.
What happened to gay lib, Jonathan?
I don't know. What did happen to it?
Is that Gethin's boyfriend?
Jonathan. He stabbed Susannah
York with an ice pick.
He's an actor.
- Support the miners!
- Lesbians and Gays
Support the Miners, sir.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
We've raised some money and we're
looking for a mining community...
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
Somebody will call you back.
Sure, but you've said
that before and we...
They'll call back.
They will.
Mark, face it.
- They're on strike. They're busy.
- They don't wanna take our money
- because we're poufs.
- And a dyke.
- They'd rather starve.
- Hand the money over anonymously.
- We don't have to say we're gay.
- No.
At least, we'd be helping.
This is a gay and lesbian group,
and we are unapologetic about that.
- Why are you wasting time with this?
- Mark!
They will call. Nothing to do
with the fact that we're poufs.
- And a dyke.
- They will call us. End of meeting.
They're never gonna call us back.
Someone needs to go with him.
First rule of the group.
- I'll go.
- Thank you, Steph.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners!
Pervert.
First rule of the group, comrade.
Nobody collects alone.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners!
- Lesbians and Gays Support...
- Gethin!
- You're supposed to be a bookshop.
- We don't have maps, Mark.
People ask for the
poems of Walt Whitman.
I hope there's a good reason
why I've been abandoned.
Let me get this right.
So we are gonna pick a mining town
at random, and just ring.
Is that the plan, is it, Mark?
The town hall, the council.
- It's as easy as that.
- Why not?
We bypass the union altogether.
- I think it's inspired.
- So do I.
- See, even Bromley agrees.
- Right, here we go.
Aha! So, what do we want?
- Somewhere north, industrial.
- Humberside, is that a place?
Oh, Jesus Christ, give it to me.
If it's miners you're looking for,
- there, Wales.
- Of course.
- That's a big fucking coalfield.
- That's the Brecon Beacons.
That's the coalfield there, and that is.
- And what are we supposed to do?
- Do you know people, Gethin?
No, I haven't been back there
in 16 years.
Why not?
Well, let's just say there isn't
always a welcome in the hillsides.
Shall I get the phone book?
Well, what's the worst that can happen?
Oh, hello, I represent a bunch
of screaming homosexuals.
May I inquire about your communal baths?
- What's that got to do with a strike?
- Oh, nothing. I'd just like to inquire.
Please, can I have some...?
All right, thank you.
All right! Hey!
If we're gonna do this,
we need to take it seriously.
Have a look.
Right.
O, one, nine...
What's the Welsh for lesbian?
Hello?
Yes.
I see.
- Yeah!
- Yes!
Solidarity forever
Didn't occur to you
to get a description?
She were off the phone fast.
Maybe we should try and
look more obviously gay.
Achievable goals, please, Jeff.
- Shut up. That's him.
- Are you sure?
- God, he's coming.
- How did you know it were him?
It's the same as in a nightclub.
It's all in the eyes.
I'm Dai Donavan. From the Dulais Valley.
- Right.
- You must be Mark.
- Yes. Hello.
- Hi. Mike.
- How you doing?
- Steph.
- Joe.
- Jeff.
Dai. So...
LGSM, what does that stand for, then?
You get a garbled
message over the phone.
I thought the L was for London.
London something.
I never dreamed for a
moment it was L for...
Hi.
This money you've raised,
it's all from gays and lesbians?
Mostly. Yeah.
Right.
- There we are.
- This is just the beginning.
- Oh.
- We've got big plans.
Well, I'm not going to pretend I'm
not surprised. You can see that.
Truth told, you're the first
gays I've ever met in my life.
As far as you're aware.
That's true.
And you're the first
miner I've ever met.
- Yeah.
- Me too.
Now, I... I want you to
do something for me.
I want you to go back to your community
and convey my thanks, my personal thanks
and the thanks of all
the people of Dulais.
Yeah, of course we will.
- Won't we?
- Yeah.
- Absolutely.
Won't we, Mark?
Who fancies a pint?
You can have five minutes.
- Are you sure?
- Dead sure.
Yeah, but for Dai...
- Oh, I'm all right, lad.
- Trust me, Dai,
if you can handle this,
it's gonna make a huge difference.
What's he gonna do,
take his clothes off?
I'm going to say thank you.
Well, don't blame me if you get bottled.
Right! Shut up, you fuckers.
Thank you. Thank you. Right, listen.
Some of you know me.
- My name is Mark Ashton.
- Commie!
I'm gonna invite somebody
onto the stage now
who wants to talk to you,
and I want you to listen to him.
He comes from the Dulais Valley
in South Wales, and he...
Well, he's a striking miner,
and he has something
he wants to say to you.
I've had a...
I've had a lot of new
experiences during this strike.
Speaking in public.
Standing on a picket line.
And now I'm in a gay bar.
Well, if you don't like it,
you can go home.
As a matter of fact, I do like it.
Beer's a bit expensive, mind.
But, really,
there's only one difference between this
and a bar in South Wales.
The women.
They're a lot more feminine in here.
What I'd really like to say
to you tonight is thank you.
If you're one of the people that's
put money in these buckets,
if you've supported LGSM,
then thank you,
because what you've given
us is more than money.
It's friendship.
When you're in a battle
against an enemy so much bigger,
so much stronger than you,
well, to find out you had a
friend you never knew existed,
well, that's the best
feeling in the world.
So thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. My God.
I haven't even finished this one.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
Support the miners.
So you're the only girl?
That's right. I'm the L in LGSM.
- Good speech.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
I've worked a few tough
crowds myself over the years.
- In politics?
- In panto.
- Oh, all right.
- Okay, LGSM over here, please.
- Something we could use.
- What?
An official photographer.
Jesus, Mark. We don't even
have an official typewriter.
- Nice and close.
- I could do it.
I've got a camera.
It's a really good one.
I'd be happy to do it.
- Bromley, if you're sure.
- Of course he's sure.
Never let it be said that LGSM
discouraged youth enterprise.
Right. What are you gonna say? "Cheese"?
Victory to the miners.
Victory to the miners!
Martin, come on.
Tell them you've run a
whole canteen before.
- You're not just packing food parcels.
- Go.
And don't look so bloody worried.
It's not the first day of school.
Right.
What do they need to come here for?
We sent them a thank-you note.
Every other group has been invited.
Every other group was approved
by the whole committee.
- Oh, I see.
- Dai had to make a snap decision.
Oh, this is all my fault.
He was in London. Would you have
told them to keep their money?
I'll tell you what I would've done.
I would've come back.
All right, I run a civil meeting here.
If you want to scream and shout,
get on the pickets.
I don't have a problem
with what they are.
- None of us do.
- It's the men.
Well, you bring a load of gays
into a working men's club,
you get trouble. I'm sorry.
No other group has raised as much.
- I'm not disputing that.
- Or been so consistent.
Why don't you just invite them?
Sorry, but everyone's saying
they don't have a problem.
Good. They've raised the
most money, so invite them.
And who the bloody hell are you?
- You did what?
- I know.
But Hefina, she's like the head honcho,
absolutely terrifying,
well, she obviously can't
stand this Maureen.
Kids, mind the fish fingers.
What's the matter?
You told me not to sell myself short.
I'm not talking about that.
Gays and lesbians.
- We are trying to fit in here, Sian.
- What?
Volunteer, I said. Run the canteen.
They didn't want me on the canteen.
Wanted me on the committee.
All right, so keep your head down.
Do the paperwork.
Don't start stirring it all up,
inviting a load of gays and lesbians.
Oh, it's like that, is it?
I had you down as many things,
but prejudiced was never one of them.
- I'm not prejudiced.
- No?
I'm a realist. I know what
small towns are like, Sian,
and I know exactly how those
lads are going to react.
- You think so?
- I know so.
I'm standing on a bloody picket
with them day after day.
It was a majority decision.
The committee decided.
I hope you and your bloody committee
can guarantee their safety, Sian. I do.
I really do.
All aboard the deviants bus.
No pushing, no community singing,
and absolutely no
back-chatting the driver.
- Right, where are we going?
- Wales.
Fuck me.
Someone better roll
me a little spliffette.
What I'd like to know is,
what Bromley told his mum and dad.
- Yeah.
- I just... Oh, it's no big deal.
Come on.
I said that I was doing
so well at college,
they were sending me
on a residential course.
Doing what?
Choux pastry.
Bromley! Bromley!
Bromley! Bromley! Bromley!
Bit late in the day for that, isn't it?
That's the fourth one I've done.
Fast as I put them up,
they pull them down.
I'm running out of staples.
Every woman is a lesbian at heart
You can't possibly say that
every woman is a lesbian.
- Why not?
- Because they're not.
Esther Rantzen isn't a lesbian.
My mum is not a lesbian.
How do you know?
How do I know my mum's not a lesbian?
What he's trying to say is,
you can't make
grand, sweeping generalizations.
It's not acceptable.
Every woman is a lesbian at heart
Including Reggie's mum
Look at the map. We should have
turned left at that village.
How can that be a village?
It doesn't have vowels.
- Hang on a minute.
- Yes?
I think so.
Are we here?
We're here.
Oh, my God.
Come on, let's go.
Right, then.
- I guess we just...
- I'm starting to freak out slightly.
Dai, your gays have arrived.
- Good to see you again.
- Good to see you.
Hi there. Welcome.
Welcome. Come on in, everybody.
Great to see you again.
Hello. Come on in.
Welcome, everybody.
- This is my wife, Margaret.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- This is Gail.
- And Sian, who wrote to you.
- Sian.
This is Hefina, who chairs
the welfare committee.
This is Gwen.
- And this is Cliff, our club secretary.
- How you doing?
I'm going to officiate you.
Oh, good.
Hold that, and name here, please.
And in the corresponding box,
the group or organization you represent.
In this case...
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
Yep. Quite. Absolutely.
Thank you. Thank you
very much for having us.
Now, I'm hoping you can clear
something up for me about lesbians.
- Not now, Gwen.
- Something I was told in the market,
and to be honest with you,
it did surprise me...
- Let them get settled in first, shall we?
- Oh.
Now, who's making the speech?
A speech?
No big deal. One of you has to go up
on stage and say a few words.
Just so we know who you are, like.
I'll tell the band to shut up,
and we'll push you on.
And welcome, all of you.
To be honest,
I never thought you'd come.
Anybody else feel like
appointing themselves leader?
Didn't think so. Ahem.
A million miles from home
But I'm walkin'
Walkin'
For you
Walkin' for you
Now then, ladies and gentlemen,
we're joined once again by
one of our support groups,
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
Will you, welcome their
spokesman onto the stage?
Thank you.
Thank you, Dai. Thank you,
Falling Leaves.
Actually, Dai Donovan made
a speech at our local pub,
and he's a pretty tough act to follow,
so maybe now is the moment for
my musical tribute to Judy Garland.
Look, we raised this money
because we wanna help you.
And that's it.
And we'll keep on trying to help
you for as long as you want us to
because we've been through
some of the same things
you've been through.
Listen, if one in five people is gay,
then one in five miners
must be too, right?
So that's at least a fifth of
you who's pleased to see us.
Thank you.
Thank you for inviting us here.
Thanks.
One, two, three, four...
Them falling leaves
They say that summer's done
The wind and rains
They say so too
But ain't no winter skies
Will ever shadow the sun
While I'm with you...
- Night, everybody.
- Good night, Dai.
There we are.
All settled in.
It's teething problems, love.
Everything will be all right
once they start to mix.
I'm not talking about running away.
I'm talking about making
a dignified exit.
Tomorrow before dawn.
We can't waltz into a town
like this, expect them not to...
- Slit our throats?
- Just be cautious.
I don't know about anybody else, but I don't
have to travel to get my head kicked in.
- I can very easily get that at home.
- Anyone who wants to go should go.
- I came to help.
- They don't want your help.
Well, they can tell me that to my face.
Until that time, I'm a member of LGSM.
I'm gonna do what I set out to do.
No hiding, no running away,
no apologies.
Me too.
- Yeah.
- And me.
And me.
This is a Welsh castle, mind.
None of your Norman rubbish.
According to legend,
the maiden Sabrina came here, see,
and became the goddess
of the River Severn.
- How'd she manage that then, Cliff?
- By drowning.
Sabrina fair
Listen where thou art sitting
Under the glassie cool, translucent wave
And so on.
I grew up in Northern Ireland.
I know all about what happens when
people don't talk to each other.
That's why I've never understood
what's the point of
supporting gay rights
but nobody else's rights, you know?
Or workers' rights,
but not women's rights.
It's, I don't know, illogical.
There's a lodge banner
down in the welfare,
over 100 years old.
We bring it out for special
occasions, you know?
I'll show it to you one day.
It's a symbol, like this, right?
Two hands.
That's what the labor movement means.
Should mean.
You support me, I support you,
whoever you are, wherever you come from,
shoulder to shoulder, hand to hand.
Dai!
There they go.
They're bringing the men
from London, from Bristol, all over.
They're pulling the lads
in for anything now.
They can't do that.
There's two from my street in
custody right now. Lee and Carl.
Where's your humanity?
We're citizens of this country, mind.
Citizens.
No, I mean, they can't do that.
It's totally illegal.
A police officer has the
right to stop you if...
That's the important word here.
If he has reasonable grounds to believe
a crime is gonna be committed.
Are you absolutely sure about this?
Police harassment, dear,
I could set it to music.
And if he does?
Then he must formally charge you
within 24 hours of that arrest.
But reasonable grounds
means concrete evidence
that can stand up in court.
It doesn't mean he doesn't
like the look of you.
That's the same whether you're
standing on a picket line
or trolling down Clapham
High Street in full drag.
Hefina, tell Martin to mind the kids.
- Where you going?
- The police station.
She's finding her feet.
Right, gentlemen, listen to me.
A police officer only has the right
to detain a group of people...
You need evidence to
stand up in a court of law.
They need evidence. Detain them
for longer than 24 hours...
There's no proof. No proof.
And I will not be leaving
this desk until you do.
We've got all day, so chop-chop.
Nobody said anything
about hiding who we are.
Yes, they did. You.
I just think if everybody
takes it easy on the...
Flamboyance.
We're more likely to fit in.
I'm sorry, just to be clear,
when you say "flamboyance,"
you mean "gay."
And when you say "everyone,"
you mean me.
- Jonathan.
- Good.
It's just I haven't spoken
1950s in quite a while.
Over here, please.
We're packing parcels.
- You'll stay for a pint?
- No, you're all right, Cliff.
Welfare's had a change of
atmosphere, if you know what I mean.
I don't know what you mean, Lee, no.
He means these faggots.
If it wasn't for those people,
you would still be in the nick.
- What?
- He's right.
They make me sick. That's all I know.
That's enough.
Physically sick!
- Gays?
- From London.
They were the ones, got you out.
I thought Sian got us out.
They told her.
They told her what to say.
- Carl.
- It's you lot, is it?
- The gays?
- What's going on?
No, it's all right. It's all right.
We're LGSM. Lesbians and Gays
Support the Miners, yes.
My name's Mark Ashton.
You'll have a pint, will you, Mark?
What I was told about
lesbians really did shock me.
It can't be true, can it?
You're all vegetarians?
Actually, Zoe and I are both vegans.
So you live together like,
you know, husband and wife,
- but what I want to know is...
- I know what you're gonna say.
Which one does the housework?
Oh, okay, well, that's...
That's not what I thought
you was gonna say.
- Are you joking?
- Certainly not.
It's embarrassing enough they spent
one night on Dai's floor, Maureen.
From here on in, the hosting
committee's gonna start hosting.
I'm sorry, not me.
I'm concerned about AIDS.
What?
It's not a trivial matter, Sian.
They've issued leaflets.
I don't mind taking more, Hefina.
Not the lesbians so much,
because of their cuisine,
but I'll take an extra gay.
I'll tell you something right now,
Maureen Barry.
If you get AIDS, so help me God,
I'll nurse you myself.
Though how you're gonna get AIDS
from a couple of sleeping bags
in your extension, I don't know.
Listen, it's fine.
No. I can take another one,
and so can Cliff.
Think it's gonna be that easy, do you?
You just bulldoze the whole village
into thinking the same thing as you.
I don't need to bulldoze anyone.
It's you who's got the problem.
They're all in there getting
along perfectly well.
Oh, really?
What the hell do you think you're doing?
- Just talking to Kev about something.
- Talk to Kev any day of the week.
Get over there and find a
gay or a lesbian right now.
Look, Hefina, I've shaken their hands,
I've bought them a pint. See?
I don't wanna labor the point, do I?
I might, you know, give them
the wrong impression.
- Right.
- Oh, right.
Because you're so bloody irresistible,
is that it, Carl Evans?
Listen to me, I've seen you dancing
round my backyard with no clothes on
since you were this high,
and I can tell you right now,
these gays have thrown better away.
Now move yourself, and you.
This is a first, this.
Men on the dance floor.
You can't be serious.
Welsh men don't dance, do they, Sian?
Never. Can't move their hips.
Well, why don't we show
them what they're missing.
Oh, my God, he's amazing.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, look at that.
God, I miss disco.
Everyone back to mine for a nightcap.
What? Go to bed, Cliff.
I promise I'll do it, man.
For God's sakes.
He always gets like this.
What did I bloody say to you?
Showing us up in front of our guest?
Don't worry. You're gonna love it.
Cheers, mate.
- Oi. What was that about?
- He's gonna give him dance lessons.
You joking? He was all
prancing about like that.
Listen, if you're gonna spend the
rest of your life standing at the bar
wishing you could speak to
Debbie Thomas, that's fine by me.
I'm gonna be a woman magnet.
Where the bloody hell did you get that?
I don't know why you're so het up.
They're going in the morning.
Well, this strike matters
to you two, does it?
Of course it does.
What do you think people will
say when they hear about this?
We're being backed up by perverts.
You want people taking the piss, do you?
Scabs, coppers,
calling us all sorts of names?
No.
Well, I know one thing.
Your father would never
have stood for it.
That went well, considering.
"Considering"?
Sometimes people can surprise you,
that's all I'm saying.
I never had a problem with it, Sian.
Well, I'm glad to hear it,
because this is Joe
and he's gonna be sleeping in our house.
How do?
Nice to meet you.
No need to do the full
Barry White, Martin.
He knows you're heterosexual.
This is fine.
- We should take him to the door.
- No, just here, please.
Just drop me here.
- Come on.
- What about that?
- All right. Oh, leave him alone.
- Hang on a minute.
- What is it?
- Gotta keep up the fiction.
See you.
Was it fun?
It was the best experience
of my entire life.
Making pastry?
You wanna start something,
you start it with me!
Lesbians and gays support the miners.
- Oh, thank you.
- Thank you.
Keep it moving, girls. Just put it in.
Victory to the miners!
Lesbians and gays support the miners.
Any donations, sir?
Don't worry about me freezing
to death in Brixton, will you?
Aren't you going to ring your mom?
What for? A long-distance queer bashing?
- Hi.
- Here you are, love.
Why don't I pretend to be your girlfriend?
That way, you get an alibi
and I get to watch The Sound of Music.
- Come to ours, Steph.
- Can I?
Yeah. Orphans of the storm.
No queen's speech, no carols.
Oh, sounds like heaven.
Support the miners.
Very happy Christmas to you too.
There is now a danger that has
become a threat to us all.
It is a deadly disease and
there is no known cure.
The virus can be passed
during sexual intercourse
with an infected person.
AIDS. Anally injected death sentence.
Will you switch that off, please, Tony?
But it's spreading.
- Thank you.
- So protect yourself.
Hello?
Can I speak to Jonathan?
No, he's being creative in the kitchen,
- I'm afraid.
- Take a message.
I just wanted to thank him
for his beautiful card.
Homemade too.
My husband was particularly
impressed with it.
I'll tell him.
Is that a Welsh accent I can hear?
Maybe. The remnants.
I haven't been home
in a long time, so...
We're looking forward to seeing
them all back here soon.
And wish Jonathan a happy Christmas
from all of us in Dulais, will you?
Of course. Of course I will.
Nadolig Llawen to you, my love.
The One O'Clock News from the BBC.
The Coal Board called a press conference
in near despair today after the
collapse of last night's talks
and the strike entered its 42nd week.
The union responded
with a renewed attack
on the government's cuts to benefits
for the families of those on strike.
They're calling it an
attempt by Mrs. Thatcher
to starve the miners back to work.
Severe weather in England
and Wales is set to continue...
Bloody hell, it's bricked up.
Oh, Jesus.
Let's get the stuff unloaded
and share it out as
fast as possible, yeah?
What the bloody hell am I doing?
Right, come on, then. You heard him.
There's noises in the village.
Small voices.
Nothing we can't handle, but...
They wanna go back?
They've been told they'll save
the pits that go back first.
They won't,
but desperate people,
they'll believe anything.
Tell him about the bus.
Our bus has broken down.
And our gas has been cut off,
so we're having baths next door.
We're playing for a tin of beef now.
Remember, all your proceeds
to the strike fund, ladies and gents.
So please dig deep.
There's a pair for you. Happy Christmas.
There you go.
Not even Kim Wilde's got them in orange.
- This is Gethin.
- Hello.
- He's a little nervous.
- Jonathan.
There's no need to be nervous, boy.
- With a good Welsh name like that?
- Where you from, then?
Rhyl, originally.
No. No way.
Listen here, see.
We don't mind the gays and
the lesbians, that's fine.
But don't you dare be bringing
people from North Wales down here.
Stupid bugger.
Come on.
That bus is a lifeline.
It takes the men to the picket.
It takes the food parcels to the
remotest villages. Without it...
All the fours, 44.
We need to start thinking
in larger chunks of money.
Without it they're gonna fail.
Simple as that.
But when are you gonna address
my question about a women's group?
Blind 70.
Stella, this is important.
I know, but this group has
absolutely no democratic process.
What do you need a group for?
- Lady and me, 23.
- To address the women's issues.
Singly and in a safe environment.
What is unsafe about this environment?
Kelly's eye, number one.
I'm a woman, Mike.
Okay? I'm also a lesbian
- and a feminist.
- Listen, love.
I don't care if you're Arthur Scargill.
Don't talk during the bingo.
Tickety-boo,
62.
Thirty six.
For God's sake, leave him alone.
He's not a Girl's World.
But we love him, Mom.
Okay, design speed.
It's called the Great Atlantic Fault.
And it starts here in Spain,
and then it goes under
the Bay of Biscay,
and then it comes up in South Wales.
And then it goes under the Atlantic
for miles and miles and miles,
and it comes up again in Pennsylvania.
My father used to talk about it.
- Yeah.
- And mine.
- The dark artery.
- That's it. Yeah, that's it.
And you could take a miner
from Wales or Spain,
or America, and you could
show them that seam,
and they would recognize it.
There's no other coal like it.
It's perfect.
Pure.
Yeah.
I lost my younger brother to that pit.
Thirty-six years old.
But without it,
these villages are nothing.
They're finished.
That's what I'd say,
if I ever came face to face
with Margaret fucking Thatcher.
That's what I'd tell her.
The pit and the people
are one and the same.
Yeah.
Well...
Welcome home, son.
Thank you.
Listen to me, everyone!
- I just wanna say something. I...
- Get your feet off those seats.
We've let you down.
No, we have. We haven't
collected enough,
we haven't raised enough awareness.
We know that.
Now, it's not enough to
always be defending.
Sometimes you have to
attack to push forward,
and that's exactly what we're gonna do.
When we get back to London,
and you have my word on this,
we are gonna...
We're gonna do something so spectacular.
And it will be so incredible,
so effective, that the
National Coal Board...
I promise you this.
...will come crawling on
their hands and knees,
in full drag,
to beg you for forgiveness.
Now, victory!
Victory to the miners!
Well done!
Victory to the miners.
As we come marching, marching
In the beauty of the day
A million darkened kitchens
A thousand mill lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance
That a sudden sun discloses
For the people hear us singin'
Bread and roses, bread and roses
As we go marching, marching
We battle too for men
For they are women's children
And we mother them again
Our lives shall not be sweated
From birth until life closes
Hearts starve as well as bodies
Give us bread, but give us roses
As we go marching, marching
Unnumbered women dead
Go crying through our singing
Their ancient cry for bread
Small art and love and beauty
Their drudging spirits knew
Yes, it is bread we fight for
But we cry for roses too
Go back to where you came from!
No! What...?
- We've come to take back our welfare.
- What are you talking about?
- From all your bloody queers.
- What the hell's going on?
There's normal people who
wanna drink in here as well.
You listen to me, those people
in there are our guests.
Yeah? Well, they wanna watch themselves!
Leave it, Martin. Come on,
for God's sake, man. Come on, leave it.
Come on, Martin.
You so much as lay one finger
on anyone inside that hall,
and so help me God, I'll break
your bloody arms and legs for you.
Come on, come back in. Come on.
Bent bastards!
There you go. I know it's freezing,
but at least the beers will be cold.
Anyone want a beer? Anyone?
- Yeah, over here.
- I've got one. Thanks, mate.
Here you go, Alan.
Say not the struggle naught availeth
The labor and the wounds are vain
The enemy faints not, nor faileth
And as things have been they remain
If hopes were dupes...
Oh, that's more like it.
I'm Gary.
Hi.
I want to learn to dance.
- We need to make something happen.
- Yeah, well, we do now, yeah.
Something big, an event,
something bigger than
we've ever tried before.
- Come inside. It's warmer in there.
- It's morale.
That's the thing.
It's just as important as money.
We need to keep them up, Mike.
The minute they start to
feel like a lost cause...
I know, I know.
And there's nothing worse
than a lost cause.
I'm in Wales,
and I don't have to pretend
to be something that I'm not.
I'm home.
And I'm gay.
- I'm Welsh.
- That's right.
Get him another beer
before he starts singing.
What I don't understand is why
you never came back before.
My mother.
- She couldn't accept me.
- Not then, perhaps.
She's religious.
She hasn't said one
word to me in 16 years.
And what about you?
What words have you said to her?
You got a sweetheart, have you, love?
I'm a gobby Northern lesbian, Gwen.
I tend to scare them off.
Look.
That's my William.
Forty-four years I had him with me.
And I wish you as many
with someone one day.
And as happy.
Jesus, I'm pissed.
Alan, no!
Give us a hand, will you, Steph?
He's thrown up again.
Margaret, I am so sorry.
Alan Pritchard, so help me.
"For many years now,
we have been force-fed an agenda
that has represented homosexuals
first as victims, now as heroes."
Margaret Donovan could be reported.
All those people in her house.
"The homosexuals have been told
that it is us, the normal population,
and not them, that is out of step.
Any society that accepts
that sick deception
is swirling headlong into a
cesspool of its own making."
Well, they wanna see
what's going on up here.
They'd have a field day.
Why don't you come over to Dai's?
Just for a minute.
I think if you met one or two of them...
Have you seen this, Cliff?
About the gays?
I don't believe what
they say about us, Lee.
Why listen to what they say about them?
Get inside, you, and shut up.
You're a respected woman, Maureen.
People follow you.
You could set an example.
You're the backbone of that committee.
You work hard.
You've been both mother
and father to those boys.
Sitting on your own
in the dark, Maureen?
You wanna take that rod
out of your ass for a minute.
Good luck.
Morning.
Thanks.
Hello.
I'm in a phone box,
so I'll have to be quick.
I got a story for your news desk.
Hello, Mum.
See you.
Hello, sailors.
Morning, ladies.
Come on, Maries.
- What are they on about?
- With your bum chum.
What's going on?
Wait till you see this.
Jesus.
"Perverts support the pits.
A gaggle of gays and
lesbians has come out
in favor of the miners' strike.
Our editor says, 'We knew
the miners were desperate,
but now we have the final
and compelling evidence
that they are finished."'
"Does anyone else hear the bottom
of the barrel being scraped?
From where I'm sitting,
the noise is pretty deafening."
Unbelievable.
Who did this?
Have to go to a vote,
but I'm warning you,
we can do without trouble.
This isn't trouble, it's mischief.
Jesus, man, we've had worse
than this before now.
Every day they're out collecting for us.
It's the men, Dai.
They've already got their wives
supporting them, and now this, gays.
The whole country laughing at us.
It's about dignity.
It'll have to go to a vote.
Right. They're calling
an emergency meeting.
A vote.
Dai is speaking up for us, of course,
but it's done a lot of damage.
Yeah, but we're not gonna let
a little thing like this break.
- Oh, down.
- Get down.
- Stay down!
Jesus Christ!
Gethin, please!
Bastard!
I don't care about what they do,
but it's a distraction.
It's distracting people from the strike.
And then there's the children.
I mean, what example is it for kiddies
to have gays and
lesbians roaming around?
It's unnatural.
There used to be a tradition in
Wales of honoring your guests.
Do you remember that, ladies?
Respect, generosity?
- Hefina...
- There's one thing unnatural
about this whole bloody business.
Betraying the community.
And when I find out who sold
that story, believe me,
they'll know what it feels
like to be ashamed.
What the hell are we doing?
Let's just get this finished, Mark.
No, no. What the hell are we doing?
They'd never have known
if it wasn't for this article.
- So?
- So they'd never have found us.
What are you saying? Send them the bill?
Do you know how many
people read this paper?
This our chance to do
something spectacular.
We could never drum up this kind
of publicity in a million years.
Mark, don't you just think we
ought to hold back and regroup?
There isn't time to regroup.
This is a news item now, today.
- We have to take advantage.
- They called us perverts.
Bromley, it's time for an
important part of your education.
Hands up, in this room, if you've
ever been called a name like that.
Now, there is a long and honorable
tradition in the gay community,
and it has stood us in good
stead for a very long time.
When somebody calls you a name...
Am I right, Jonathan?
- Dead right.
- You take it and you own it.
- I love you.
- You owe me.
It's a fundraising concert,
and we're looking for bands to...
No. No. No, I am in no way
suggesting that Sting
or indeed any other member
of The Police is a pervert.
Cool. Cheers.
Oh, I can probably get you some more.
Next week, if you want.
He'll call.
Okay.
There are no gay artists
on this label. I'm sorry.
They don't have to be gay.
That's the point.
This is a coming together
of all different people...
Reception.
It arrived about 10 minutes ago, Barry.
Yeah, well, you could
come down and get it.
What the bloody hell do
you think you're doing?
That's the number for Gay Switchboard.
You never know.
One of them might need it one day.
We'll be back in time for the vote.
- Right-o.
- Any problems, we can be reached
- at the bookshop.
- You're gonna miss this train.
Rowena Roberts has had a baby.
She needs an extra box.
I can't hear you.
- Rowena Roberts had a baby...
- Strange.
I can't... I can't hear you.
She needs an extra box.
And the difference is,
this is open to everyone, okay?
Gay, straight, it doesn't matter.
We want people to come together
to show their support.
And why should gay people
like me support the miners?
Because miners dig for coal,
which produces power,
which allows gay people like you
to dance to Bananarama
until 3:00 in the morning.
Next question?
Are you all right?
Yes, you, the cute one.
I've never met a pop star.
I have. Max Boyce.
He was playing Swansea Grand
the year our Jane was born.
What's funny about that?
You need to push the T-shirts and
the badges as hard as you can.
This is a fundraiser.
Make sure people are buying stuff.
- Is he in charge?
- He's the official photographer.
We don't want it to be all churchy.
Do you know what I mean?
It's a christening.
Yeah, but the readings don't all have
to come from the Bible, do they?
You can have all sorts
of things nowadays.
It's more open.
Meeting's tomorrow afternoon,
3:00 sharp.
We'll make it, long as we leave early.
- And the vote?
- At the end.
Single question: can we
continue taking your support
in the light of recent events?
- Recent events.
- Won't have anything to worry about.
I'm telling you, when they see
what you make out of this...
- If we make anything out of it.
- You joking? You're already famous.
Give it here.
"Bronski Beat are to headline
a benefit for the miners
at the Electric Ballroom.
Pits and Perverts is being organized
by the London Lesbians and Gay Men
- Support the Miners group."
- Got the name wrong.
"The event is open to everyone,
gay or straight,
and will be a real festive occasion
through which we can express our
solidarity with the mining community."
Don't dawdle, love. Get indoors.
Support the miners.
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen.
To the gays,
to the straights,
and to the as yet undecided.
- Welcome to the Electric Ballroom,
- It's amazing.
for this,
the first ever Pits and
Perverts Benefit Ball.
Tell me why
Contempt in your eyes
As I turn to kiss his lips
Broken, I lie
All my feelings denied
Blood on your fist
Can you tell me why?
This is the first gay club
we've ever been to.
Yeah? As a matter of fact,
we're not gay, either.
We're miners.
- That's perfect.
- Hide me.
Hey. Why?
If you see Steph,
perhaps you'd give her this?
They want me to join their breakaway
group, Lesbians Against Pit Closures.
Strictly women only.
Don't think I could
trust myself, do you?
Are you gonna take my picture, then?
Tell me why
Can you tell me why?
Well, it's incredible to see such
a mix of people here tonight.
Gay and straight.
Can you see what we've done here?
By coming together, all of us,
by pledging our solidarity,
our friendship, we've made history.
Back in our...
Back in our miners' lodge in Wales,
we have a banner.
And it's old. It's very old,
maybe a hundred years.
And it's this,
two hands together,
joined like this.
Well, I tell you now,
you've worn our badge,
"Coal not dole,"
and when the time comes,
you have my word on this,
we will wear yours.
Shoulder-to-shoulder, hand-to-hand.
Come on. We're off out for the night.
Now, I hope you ladies
aren't gonna let me down.
What? We want to see
everything, don't we?
- What, everything?
- Even the rubber scene.
Sorry, ladies, this is a men-only venue.
Oh, don't be daft, love.
We've come all the way from Powys.
Evening.
Hello.
That's my youngest, yeah.
How'd you get into that leotard, then?
Talcum powder.
What?
- Talcum powder.
- Oh.
Lily of the valley, I use.
Mark?
Oh, my God. Mark Ashton.
Tim?
- I know. I know.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, this is insane.
I'm bumping into everybody tonight.
How are you?
Still changing the world?
- Bit by bit.
- Tim, come on.
I haven't been home in four days.
Haven't you?
I'm on a farewell tour.
Where are you going?
You are a beautiful man, Mark.
I miss you.
Please take care of yourself, okay?
Please.
- Come on.
- Please take care.
Come on then, girls.
That's enough. Back to ours.
Bedtime.
- Come on.
- I'm sorry.
Don't worry, you're lighter
than your husband.
Do you know what I was when I met Alan?
Drunk?
Sixteen.
Think that's ridiculous?
I was pretty then.
You're pretty now.
All goes south, doesn't it?
Love, looks, everything.
That's cheery.
Sod it.
I always thought sex was
for the men, really.
Anyway, we just put
up with it, don't we?
- Keep them quiet.
- Okay.
I will listen to a certain amount
of drunken bollocks, Gail,
but sex is not just for the men.
It's for the women too, believe me.
Oh, yeah.
No carpets.
This is Laura Ashley.
I've seen it before.
Where?
- Cardiff.
- What I want to know
is what's this?
Hefina, put that back immediately.
That's nothing. Here,
look what else I've found.
You never went under his bed!
When was the last time
you saw anything like that?
When? When?
Don't those women ever sleep?
Oh, Jesus, God.
That takes me back.
No, look. Wait, look. Look...
Put it down.
Mum.
So, what were their names again, boys?
Mine was Jess.
- And mine was Carol.
- Hey.
Straight people asked
if they could join.
- You're joking.
- We should set up another group.
Straights Supporting
Gays Supporting Miners.
- This is right...
- That's it, yeah...
Excuse me.
That's it, we're off.
- What about Bromley?
- It's too late.
- You've got a meeting to get to.
- The vote, remember?
Okay.
- Surely you've got his number, Steph.
- Nobody's got his number.
- He still lives at home.
- Mark's right. If we're gonna get...
- He's blown it. Come on, let's go.
- Oh, what a shame.
He was sucking face when
the lights came up.
I wouldn't waste any time
feeling sorry for him.
Can I please have an aspirin?
What the hell is this?
Plans change, Cliff. It's not my fault.
No answer.
- They must be on their way.
- Okay.
I can't speak in front of
all these people, Cliff.
I can't.
I know you think you
know what you want, Joe,
but you're so young.
That's what the law's for,
to protect you.
I didn't know who I was at your age.
It's such a terrible life, Joe.
It's lonely.
Is that what you want?
No family?
Hiding from people at work?
From everyone?
Keeping secrets?
Come here.
So now Cliff will speak
on behalf of the LGSM.
Floor's yours, Cliff.
Well, what I want to say abo...
About the gays and lesbians...
Why don't you do us a poem, Cliff?
Poem! Poem! Poem!
I want to propose that
this meeting is unlawful.
I want to propose that this meeting
was brought forward unlawfully
and that most of the people here
aren't even from this village!
All right. Let's bring
it forward to the vote.
There we go.
Two hours to spare.
Hefina Heddon,
you drive like a bloody lunatic.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
- Gwen, look after the gays.
- Right-o!
- Three o'clock.
- You can't dictate
when the committee sits.
You told us 3:00.
- Had to change it. If you weren't in...
- A bloody disgusting way to behave.
It's invalid.
This whole decision is invalid.
- We can fight it.
- We got one fight.
The fucking strike!
Or have you forgotten that?
Dancing around in London?
The trouble with those people
- is they jump on the bandwagon.
- What?
It's well-known. They pretend
they're backing you,
but what they're really doing
is pushing their own agenda.
Gay rights.
- What?
- We've seen articles, Hefina.
Christ Jesus, help me.
You better shut her mouth or
I'm gonna do it permanently.
No, come on then!
That's enough!
- An official letter will be sent.
- I can't...
I can't listen to this.
To thank them, most sincerely,
but the vote was we won't be
accepting their support anymore.
They're causing us embarrassment,
Dai. That's the thing.
And we're not strong enough, not now.
We're struggling to survive as it is.
Oh, that reminds me.
Courtesy of those people
and their agenda.
Jesus Christ.
I don't suppose you opened
your mouth, did you?
Didn't want to rock
the boat, is that it?
There's bloody thousands here.
You think you've known
someone your whole life.
Turns out they're a complete stranger.
- I'd say the same about you, Cliff.
- I'll tell you something.
If you think this is what my brother
would've wanted, you're wrong.
We came to help you win, and if
we're not helping, we have to go.
Hey, this was all you.
- No.
- It was.
All right, take my advice.
Don't give it all to the fight.
Save some for home.
There's more to life, you know?
You girls have opened my eyes.
I'm going to extend my
repertoire, you'll see.
The vegan Delia Smith.
- Bye.
Take care now.
It's a bloody travesty, man.
I don't accept it.
- Gethin.
- I don't!
They can't stop me from
collecting money, now, can they?
- Don't be crazy, Gethin.
- Geth.
Somebody better tell
Lesbians Against Pit Closures.
- What now?
- What do you mean?
- What we doing? Where we going?
- It's over.
Were you not paying attention?
We lost. And I don't know
about you, but I'm pissing off.
- Where?
- Anywhere. I'm out of here.
What about the rest of us?
Think it might be possible just for once
you could make your own decision?
- You what?
- Do you think that just for once
you could stop following me
around like a fucking spaniel
and let me have a life of my own?
Yeah.
- Yeah. I think I could manage that.
- Good.
Piss off, all of you. Leave me alone.
Lesbians and Gays Support the Miners.
Never mind the miners.
There's gay people dying every day.
That's what you should
be thinking about.
Not the bloody miners.
Asshole.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, I only wanna talk to you.
Tell you what we'll do,
let's come over here.
This is the key you swapped it to.
Oh, well, we'll leave
that there, but I'll...
Is Joe there, please?
No, I'm afraid he's out.
Can you tell him that his
friend Gethin's in hospital?
It's very important. He's...
He's in St. Thomas' Hospital.
He's been beaten up.
Yes, of course I'll tell him.
And will you tell him that Steph
called round, to see how he was?
Yeah.
Who was that?
Tina. She wants a lift in the morning.
You're back at the job center
tomorrow, don't forget.
I should've...
I should've said more.
I could have. I could've spoken better.
If you're gonna cut, cut it straight.
Into triangles.
I'm gay.
I know.
I've known for a little
while now, Cliff.
Since the gays arrived?
Well, I can't speak for
the rest of the village,
but speaking for myself,
since about 1968.
Well...
Yeah.
What's that?
It's a new van.
About time too.
What the hell's this?
New van, courtesy of our gay
friends down in London.
- I'm not getting in that.
- Then you'll have to stay here.
In you get, lads. Quick now.
You a lesbian, are you, love?
That's right. We're just off to
Swansea now for a massive lez-off.
Britain's longest-running
national strike is over.
Amongst scenes of bitterness and anger,
NUM delegates voted narrowly
for an organized return
to work on Tuesday.
Tomorrow, most of Britain's coal
miners will return to work.
They say they'll march
back heads held high.
It's almost a year to the very
day since they walked out
and embarked on a course
of action which...
Joe!
Have you seen the news?
Thank God for that!
The cost, financial and social...
Joe?
Good lads, good lads.
Bloody hell.
- Mark, where are you going?
- I'm leaving.
I was trying to make myself
feel better, and I failed.
I've been virtually under house arrest.
Stuck with my parents.
I haven't seen anyone.
Tried ringing Steph, but she...
- Why don't you leave?
- I did last night.
- I didn't even tell them I was going.
- That's not leaving, it's running.
- What are you gonna do now?
- Stay here.
And do what?
And get a job down in the pit?
That's all they need,
a trained pastry chef with a camera.
When are you gonna get some guts, huh?
You're a member of LGSM,
so stop sneaking out
of your mommy's house
and stand up for yourself.
Have some pride.
Because life is short, okay?
It's short.
Okay?
- What should I tell the others?
- Nothing.
I wasn't here.
You're a mad bugger.
I'm taking you home after that.
In the van. No arguments.
Will you give this to Jeff, please, Joe?
Of course I will.
Come on.
What about Gethin? Is he okay?
Gethin?
The last I heard,
he was back on the ward.
I don't like Meltis Fruits.
Well, then maybe you won't
go through them quite so fast.
Oh, help me out with these,
will you, Bromley?
Stay in bed.
Keep an eye on Jonathan
for me, will you?
He needs to take care of himself.
It's you we're taking care of.
If you could just make sure
he's got some groceries in.
- Gethin.
- He's HIV positive, Sian.
He not supposed to smoke,
and he needs to eat properly.
Please, for me.
Gethin?
Hello.
This is my mum.
- Hi.
- Come in.
Back then, when they knew
even less about this thing,
they gave out numbers
with each diagnosis.
One, two, three, and so on.
Of course, when they got
into the high thousands, it...
I'm number two.
Nobody knows what's keeping me alive.
I think it's the grass.
What are you gonna do now?
Make you some soup.
Drive back to Wales.
No, I mean, with your life.
I'm a wife and mother, love.
My life goes back to normal now.
Well, it shouldn't.
You have a first-class mind.
You should do something. Go to college.
Don't waste it, Sian.
There are young people
dying every day now.
Good people.
Clever, promising.
Don't you dare waste it.
Shit.
I'm sorry.
What the hell is this?
And where have you been?
You must be Joe's mom. I'm Sian.
Will you please remove
your van from my property?
I hope you appreciate him.
Because there's a whole village back
in Wales who thinks he's a hero.
- Joe.
- Mum, he's done this on purpose.
It's all right. I'm leaving.
I hope one day we can
be friends again, Mum.
Oi, you got something
to say to your sister?
I've got something to say to you,
Jason. You're a dick!
And, Tina, that tight perm
doesn't suit you. It never has.
I'm sorry.
Joe?
Joe.
You all right?
Cheers.
While you've been away,
I've been changing my act.
You watch.
Demure and accommodating. That's me.
The lesbian Lady Di.
I think I'd find that a
tremendous disappointment.
I'm glad you came back, Bromley.
It wasn't the same without you.
Thanks.
I'm glad I came back too.
If we were normal,
this is when we'd kiss.
- That's the rest of it.
- Thanks.
"Screw you, Thatcher" or "fuck you"?
I can see the appeal of both.
Jonathan, "screw" or "fuck"?
"Screw." More visceral.
Attention, attention:
We have reason to believe that
there are known homosexualists
and a confirmed lesbo
inside these premises,
and that they are armed with
sewing machines and glitter.
Aha.
Now that you have made
yourselves known to me,
I have a question for the
notorious Accrington sodomite,
- known as Mike Jackson.
- Will you please put that down?
We have good relationship
with our neighbors.
Mike!
Mike.
I behaved like a prick before.
Do you forgive me?
Just... Just get up here and
sew something, will you?
There you go, Bromley.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Right. Now get to work.
All right, just for future reference,
- my name is Joe.
- You tell him, Bromley.
Bromley! Bromley! Bromley!
- Bromley.
- Bromley! Bromley! Bromley!
Haven't you heard about
the miners, dearie?
They lost.
- Have you heard? No politics.
- What?
- Mark's with the steward.
- No politics?
- No slogans.
- We're a Mardi Gras, apparently.
- A general feeling.
- Amongst who?
Amongst the committee that people
have become tired of politics,
and that this year the
tone should be celebratory
- with affirmative slogans.
- Horseshit.
If you insist with your banner, you march
at the back with the fringe groups.
No, mate, we're LGSM.
We fought alongside the miners.
Congratulations,
but it's time for a party.
- What? I'm not gonna go at the back.
- Bollocks!
Complete and utter bollocks!
- What's LGSM's position?
- We're going to march.
Yes, but with banners or without?
- With.
- With. This is a demonstration.
- We've decided to lead the groups.
- Why would you?
- I'm not getting rid of the banner.
- No.
- Listen.
- There's got to be some compromise.
- Why?
- That's the way you get things done.
- No, it fucking isn't. Listen.
- Why does everything get
so aggressive with you lot?
Listen to me! Listen to me!
Whether we march with
banners or without,
the important thing is that
we march together, all of us.
That's what this has been
about since the beginning,
and that is absolutely
how it is going to end.
Together, us united.
Bloody hell.
Yeah!
Hey!
I can't believe you're here.
Where are my lesbians?
- Hey.
- GWEN:
- Hey. Guys, I'm here.
- Jeff!
These are all cucumber, no butter,
Stork SB every one.
- I can't believe youse came.
- Miners, see? We love a good march.
- Where do you want us?
- You lot!
- I'll tell them.
- There's too many of you.
- What?
- You'll have to go to the front.
- You'll have to lead.
- We're not losing our banners.
What do you mean?
What's he mean too many?
What's he on about?
I think he means them.
Caerphilly.
West Glamorgan.
East Glamorgan.
- Abercrave Lodge.
- Yes.
Abernant Lodge.
Bargoed Surface Lodge.
Fernhill Lodge. Mardy Lodge.
Blaengwrach Lodge. Cambrian Lodge.
Fernieside Plant. Mountain Ash Lodge.
Dulais Valley Lodge, Onllwyn.
Haverfordwest Lodge.
South Wales NUM headquarters.
The gays and lesbians have
been absolutely magnificent.
- No other word for it.
- You must've found it weird,
a load of gays and lesbians
descending on you like that.
Why on earth would we
have found that weird?
This way, guys! We're at the front!
Come on, guys,
we're at the front! This way!
Not worried about being
too visible this time?
Shut up and march.