[insects chirping]
[bird calling]
[man speaking indistinctly]
[speaking native language]
[donkey snorts]
[bird warbling]
[animal calls echoing]
[insect chirping]
[man screaming]
[birds screeching]
[screaming continues]
[birds calling]
The Hovitos are near.
The poison is still fresh,
three days.
They're following us.
If they knew
we were here,
they would've
killed us already.
[animals screech and croak]
[cocking]
[whip whooshes and cracks]
[gun fires]
[panting]
This is it.
This is
where Forrestal cashed in.
A friend of yours?
A competitor.
He was good.
He was very, very good.
Señor... nobody's
come out of there alive.
Please...
[water dripping]
[quietly]:
Señor.
[whimpers]
[whimpering]
[gasps]
Stop.
Stay out of the light.
[snapping]
[screaming]
[whimpering]
Forrestal.
[creaking]
[gasping]
[panicked breaths]
Let us hurry.
There is nothing to fear here.
That's what scares me.
[stone scrapes]
[whoosh and twang]
Stay here.
If you insist, señor.
[sharp breath]
[anxious gasp]
[laughs]
[stone scraping]
[low rumbling]
[arrows whooshing]
[creaking]
Give me the whip.
Throw me the idol.
[deep rumbling]
No time to argue.
Throw me the idol,
I throw you the whip.
Give me the whip!
Adios, señor.
[grunts]
[rumbling]
[grunts and gasps)
[snap]
[sharp thud]
[gasps]
Adios, Satipo.
[heavy thud]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[branches snap]
[birds chittering]
Dr. Jones.
Again we see there is nothing
you can possess
which I cannot take away.
And you thought
I had given up.
[bows creak]
You chose the wrong friends.
This time,
it will cost you.
Too bad the Hovitos...
don't know you the
way I do, Belloq.
Yes, too bad.
You could warn them,
if only you spoke Hovitos.
[shouts in Hovitos]
[Hovitos chant softly]
[breathy whistling]
[shouting in Hovitos]
[laughing]
[maniacal laughter echoing]
[grunts]
[Hovitos shouting]
Jock! Start the engines!
Get it up!
Jock, the engines!
Start the engines, Jock!
[Hovitos shouting]
[darts and arrows whistling]
There's a big snake
in the plane, Jock!
Oh, that's just
my pet snake Reggie!
I hate snakes, Jock!
I hate 'em!
Come on!
Show a little backbone, will ya?
[engine thrumming]
JONES:
"Neo," meaning "new"
and "lithic"... I-T-H...
[students chuckling]
...I-C, meaning "stone."
All right,
let's get back to this site:
Turkdean Barrow, near Hazelton.
Contains a central pas-passage
and three chambers, or cysts...
...don't confuse that
with robbing,
in which case we mean...
[door clicking open]
...the removal of the contents
of the barrow.
This site also demonstrates...
...one of the great dangers
of archaeology--
not to life and limb, although
that does sometimes take place--
no, I'm talking about folklore.
In this case,
local tradition held
that there was golden coffin
buried at the site,
and this accounts for the holes
dug all over the barrow
and the generally poor condition
of the find.
However, chamber three
was undisturbed,
and the undisturbed chamber
and the grave goods
that were found in another, uh--
in the area, give us a r--
Uh...
...reason to da--
to, uh, to-to date this,
uh, find as we have.
Um...
[bell rings]
Any questions, then?
No? Okay, that's it
for the day, then.
Um, don't forget--
Michaelson, chapters four
and five for next time.
And I will be in my office
on Thursday, but not Wednesday.
[students chatting
indistinctly]
I had it, Marcus.
I had it in my hand.
What happened?
Guess.
[chuckles]
Belloq?
You want to
hear about it?
Not at all.
I'm sure everything you do
for the museum
conforms to
the International Treaty
for the Protection
of Antiquities.
It's beautiful, Marcus.
I can get it.
I got it all figured out.
There's only one place
he can sell it: Marrakech.
I need $2,000. Look--
Listen to me, old boy.
I brought some people
to see you.
Look.
I got these pieces.
They're good
pieces, Marcus.
Look.
Indiana...
Yes, the museum will buy them,
as usual, no questions asked.
Yes, they are nice.
They're worth at least
the price of a
ticket to Marrakech.
But the people
I brought are important,
and they're waiting.
What people?
Army Intelligence.
They knew you were coming
before I did.
Seem to know everything.
They wouldn't tell me
what they want.
Well, what do I want
to see them for?
What am I, in trouble?
MUSGROVE:
Yes, Dr. Jones,
we've heard a great deal
about you.
Have you?
MUSGROVE:
Uh, professor of archaeology,
expert on the occult,
and, uh,
how does one say it?
Obtainer
of rare antiquities.
That's one way of saying it.
Why don't you sit down?
You'll be more comfortable.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Yes, you're a man
of many talents.
Now, you studied
under Professor Ravenwood
at the University of Chicago.
Yes, I did.
You have no idea of his
present whereabouts?
Uh... well, just rumors,
really.
Somewhere in Asia,
I think.
I haven't really spoken
to him for ten years.
We were friends, but, uh...
had a bit of a falling out,
I'm afraid.
MUSGROVE:
Mmm.
Dr. Jones, now,
you must understand
that this is all strictly
confidential, eh?
I understand.
Uh...
[clears throat]
Yesterday afternoon,
our European sections
intercepted a...
a German communiqué
that was sent from
Cairo to Berlin.
Now, to Cairo...
See, over the last two years,
the Nazis have had teams
of archaeologists
running around the world
looking for all kinds
of religious artifacts.
Hitler's a nut on the subject.
He's crazy.
He's obsessed with the occult.
And, right now, apparently,
there's some kind
of German archaeological dig
going on in the desert
outside of Cairo.
Now, we've got some
information here,
but we can't make anything
out of it, and maybe you can.
"Tanis development
proceeding.
[mouthing] "Acquire headpiece,
Staff of Ra.
Abner Ravenwood, U.S."
The Nazis
have discovered Tanis.
MUSGROVE: Just what does that
mean to you, uh, Tanis?
Well, it--
The city of Tanis
is one of the possible
resting places
of the Lost Ark.
The Lost Ark?
Yeah, the Ark of the Covenant.
The chest the Hebrews used
to carry around
the Ten Commandments.
What do you mean,
"commandments"?
You talking about
the Ten Commandments?
Yes, the actual
Ten Commandments.
The original stone tablets
that Moses brought down
out of Mount Horeb and smashed,
if you believe
in that sort of thing.
Any of you guys
ever go to Sunday school?
Well, I...
INDIANA:
Oh, look.
The Hebrews took
the broken pieces
and put them in the Ark.
When they settled
in Canaan,
they put the Ark
in a place called
the Temple of Solomon.
In Jerusalem.
Where it stayed
for many years.
Until, all of a sudden,
whoosh, it's gone.
Where?
Well, nobody knows
where or when.
However,
an Egyptian pharaoh...
Shishak.
Yes.
...invaded the city of Jerusalem
right about 980 BC,
and he may have taken the Ark
back to the city of Tanis
and hidden it
in a secret chamber
called the Well of Souls.
Secret chamber?
BRODY:
However, about a year
after the pharaoh
would return to Egypt,
the city of Tanis was
consumed by the desert
in a sandstorm which
lasted a whole year.
Wiped clean by
the wrath of God.
Uh-huh.
Obviously, we've come
to the right men.
Now you seem to know, uh,
all about this Tanis, then.
No, no, not really.
Ravenwood is the real expert.
Abner did the first serious work
on Tanis.
Collected some of its relics.
It was his obsession, really.
But he never found the city.
Frankly, we're somewhat
suspicious of Mr. Ravenwood.
An American being mentioned
so prominently
in a secret
Nazi cable.
Oh, rubbish.
Ravenwood's no Nazi.
Well, what do the Nazis
want him for, then?
Well, obviously, the Nazis
are looking
for the headpiece
to the Staff of Ra
and they think
Abner's got it.
What exactly is a headpiece
to the Staff of Ra?
Well, the staff
is just a stick--
I don't know,
about this big,
nobody really knows
for sure how high--
and it's... it's, uh...
it's capped
with an elaborate
headpiece...
in the shape of the sun,
with a crystal in the center.
And what you did was
you take the staff
to a special room in Tanis--
a map room
with a miniature
of the city
all laid out on the floor--
and if you put the staff
in a certain place,
at a certain time of day,
the sun shone through here
and made a beam that came down
on the floor here...
and gave you the exact location
of the Well of the Souls.
Where the Ark of the
Covenant was kept, right?
Which is exactly what the Nazis
are looking for.
What does this Ark
look like?
Uh...
There's a picture of it
right here.
That's it.
EATON:
Good God.
Yes, that's just what
the Hebrews thought.
Uh...
now, what's that supposed to be
coming out of there?
INDIANA:
Lightning...
fire...
power of God
or something.
MUSGROVE: I'm beginning
to understand
Hitler's interest
in this.
BRODY:
Oh, yes.
The Bible speaks of the
Ark leveling mountains,
and laying waste
to entire regions.
An army which carries
the Ark before it...
is invincible.
You did it, didn't you?
They want you
to go for it.
Oh, Marcus!
They want you to get ahold of
the Ark before the Nazis do
and they're prepared
to pay handsomely for it.
And the museum?
The museum gets the Ark
when we're finished?
Oh, yes.
Oh...
The Ark of
the Covenant.
Nothing else has come close.
That thing represents
everything
we got into archaeology
for in the first place.
Mmm!
You know, five years ago,
I would've gone after it myself.
I'm really rather envious.
I've got to locate Abner.
I think I know
where to start.
Suppose she'll
still be with him?
Possibly, but...
Marion's the least
of your worries right now,
believe me, Indy.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean that
for nearly 3,000 years,
man has been searching
for the Lost Ark.
Not something to be taken
lightly.
No one knows its secrets.
It's like nothing you've ever
gone after before.
[chuckles]
Oh, Marcus.
What are you trying to do,
scare me?
You sound like my mother.
We've known each other
for a long time.
I don't believe in magic,
a lot of superstitious
hocus-pocus.
I'm going after a find
of incredible
historical significance.
You're talking about
the bogeyman.
Besides, you know
what a cautious fellow I am.
[engine starting]
Nice to see you again,
Dr. Jones.
Thank you.
[engines revving]
[clamoring]
Shh... shh...
[crowd quiets]
[cheering]
MAN:
Shh...
[crowd groaning]
[clamoring]
[shouting in foreign language]
[crowd quiets]
[awed gasps and murmuring]
[cheering and applause]
MAN: Give him space!
Give him space!
Go on, Regan!
[crowd clamoring]
MAN:
Shh! Shh!
Shh! Shh! Shh!
[cheering]
[body thuds]
[clamoring]
[shouting in foreign language]
[speaking native language]
[wind whistling]
INDIANA:
Hello, Marion.
[door closing]
[glass shatters]
[sighs]
[chuckles]
Indiana Jones.
[heavy sigh]
Always knew, someday,
you'd come walking back
through my door.
I never doubted that.
Something made it inevitable.
So, what are you doing here
in Nepal?
I need one of the pieces
your father collected.
I learned to hate you
in the last ten years.
I never meant to hurt you.
I was a child.
I was in love.
It was wrong
and you knew it!
You knew what you were doing.
Now I do!
This is my place.
Get out!
[speaking
foreign language]
[man replies
in native language]
I did what I did.
You don't have to be happy
about it,
but maybe we could help
each other out now.
[door closing]
I need one of the pieces
your father collected.
Bronze piece, about this size,
with a hole in it, off-center,
with a crystal.
You know the one I mean?
Yeah.
I know it.
Where's Abner?
Abner's dead.
Marion, I'm sorry.
Do you know what you
did to me, to my life?
I can only say
I'm sorry so many times.
Well, say it again,
anyway.
Sorry.
Yeah, everybody's sorry.
Abner was sorry for dragging
me all over this earth
looking for his
little bits of junk.
I'm sorry to still be
stuck in this dive.
Everybody's sorry
for something.
It's a worthless bronze
medallion, Marion.
You going to give it
to me?
Maybe.
I don't know
where it is.
Well, maybe
you could find it.
3,000 bucks.
Well, that will
get me back,
but not in style.
I can get you another two
when we get to the States.
It's important, Marion.
Trust me.
You know the piece I mean?
Do you know where it is?
[chuckles]
Come back tomorrow.
Why?
Because I said so,
that's why.
Ha!
See you tomorrow,
Indiana Jones.
[wind whistling powerfully]
[door shuts]
[wind blowing outside]
[chain rattling]
[wind whistles]
[quiet laugh]
[hinges creaking]
[German accent]:
Good evening, Fraulein.
MARION:
The bar's closed.
We... We are... [laughs]
not thirsty.
What do you want?
The same thing your friend
Dr. Jones wanted.
Surely he told you
there would be
other interested
parties.
Must've slipped his mind.
[snickering]:
The man is... nefarious.
I hope, for your sake,
he has not yet acquired it.
Why, are you willing
to offer more?
Oh, almost certainly.
Do you still have it?
[coughing]
No.
But I know where it is.
Hey, how about a drink
for you and your men?
Your fire is dying here.
Why don't you tell me
where the piece is right now?
Listen, Herr Mac...
I don't know what kind of people
you're used to dealing with,
but nobody tells me
what to do in my place.
Fraulein Ravenwood,
let me show you
what I am used to.
[barks command in German]
Take your hands off me!
[grunting, glass shattering]
Take your lousy hands off!
[grunting]
[anxious gasping]
Wait a minute.
Wait, I... I can
be reasonable.
That time is passed.
You don't need that.
[whimpering]
Wait...
I'll tell you everything.
Yes, I know you will.
[sizzling]
[whip cracking]
Let her go.
[gun cocks]
[gunfire]
[yelling]
[screaming]
[gasps]
[speaks German]
[grunts]
[groans]
Whiskey.
[choking]
Shoot them.
Shoot them both.
[sizzling]
[screaming]
[whimpering]
[gasps]
[gunshot]
[laughs]
My medallion!
[wind blowing]
Well, Jones, at least
you haven't forgotten
how to show a lady
a good time!
Boy, you're something!
Yeah, I'll tell you what.
Until I get back my $5,000,
you're going to get more
than you bargained for.
I'm your goddamn partner!
[children laughing
in distance]
Cairo, city of the living.
A paradise on earth.
[laughing]
Silence!
Why do you forget yourselves?
What is this?
Where did this animal come from?
[monkey chittering]
Oh... oh, no.
[all laughing]
Cute.
What an adorable
creature.
[laughing]
Then it shall be welcome
in our house.
Oh, well, no, you don't have to
keep it here just because of me.
[children laughing]
[chuckling]
I knew the Germans
would hire you, Sallah.
You're the best digger
in Egypt.
My services are entirely
inconsequential to them.
They've hired or shanghaied
every digger in Cairo.
The excavation
is enormous.
They hire only strong backs
and they pay pennies for them.
It's as if the pharaohs
had returned.
When did they find the map room?
Three days ago.
They have not one brain
among them.
Except one.
He is very clever.
He's a French archaeologist.
What's his name?
They call him "Bellosh."
[laughing]
Belloq. Belloq.
The Germans have
a great advantage over us.
They are near to discovering
the Well of Souls.
Well, they're not
going to find it without this.
Who can tell us
about these markings?
Perhaps a man I
know can help us.
Indy...
[sighs]
there is something
that troubles me.
What is it?
The Ark.
If it is there, at Tanis,
then it is something that man
was not meant to disturb.
Death has always surrounded it.
It is not of this earth.
Do we need
the monkey, huh?
I'm surprised at you, Jones--
talking that way about our baby.
He's got your looks, too.
And your brains.
[laughing]:
Oops!
I noticed that.
She's a smart
little thing-- smart.
[laughs and screams]
Hey!
Hey, where you going?
She'll be all right.
Have a date.
Come on. Come on.
Okay...
Marion.
What's this?
It's a date.
You eat 'em.
[sniffling and grunting]
[chittering]
Sieg heil!
Ja.
[screeches]
Heil Hitler.
Sieg heil!
[speaking German]
MARION: How come you haven't found
some nice girl to settle down with,
raise eight or nine kids,
like your friend Sallah?
INDIANA:
Who says I haven't?
[laughs]
[spits]
I do.
Dad had you figured
a long time ago.
He said you were a bum.
Oh, he's being generous.
The most gifted bum
he ever trained.
You know, he loved
you like a son.
Took a hell of a lot
for you to alienate him.
Not much, just you.
[cloth ripping]
Marion, get out of here!
Duck!
[horse neighs]
[laughing]
Right.
[clanging]
[chittering]
[screeching]
[speaking German]
Shh! Shh!
Marion!
[chuckling]
[cheering]
MARION:
Help! Over here, Indy!
Get out of the way!
Move! Move it!
MARION:
Help me!
You can't do this to me!
I'm an American!
Indy!
Indiana Jones!
Help me, Jones!
[crowd clamoring]
MARION:
Jones!
Marion!
Indy!
[speaking Arabic]
[coins clattering]
[barks command in German]
[gunfire]
[engine revving]
[grunts]
Marion...
[monkey chittering]
[screeching]
MAN:
Dr. Jones.
[speaking German]
[monkey chittering]
You looking for me?
[laughing]
Belloq.
Good afternoon, Dr. Jones.
I ought to kill
you right now.
Not a very private place
for a murder.
Well, these Arabs don't care
if we kill each other.
They're not going
to interfere in our business.
It was not I who brought
the girl into this business.
Please, sit down
before you fall down.
We can at least behave
like civilized people.
[monkey chittering]
I see your taste in friends
remains consistent.
How odd that it should end
this way for us,
after so many
stimulating encounters.
I almost regret it.
Where shall I find
a new adversary
so close to my own level?
Try the local sewer.
[quiet laugh]
You and I are
very much alike.
Archaeology is
our religion,
yet we have both fallen
from the purer faith.
Our methods have not differed
as much as you pretend.
I am a shadowy
reflection of you.
It would take only a nudge
to make you like me,
to push you out
of the light.
Now you're getting nasty.
You know it's true.
How nice.
Look at this.
It's worthless.
Ten dollars from a
vendor in the street.
But I take it,
I bury it in the sand
for a thousand years,
it becomes priceless...
like the Ark.
Men will kill for it.
Men like you and me.
What about your boss,
der Fuehrer?
I thought he was waiting
to take possession.
All in good time.
When I am finished
with it.
Jones, do you realize
what the Ark is?
It's a transmitter.
It's a radio for
speaking to God.
And it's within my reach.
You want to talk to God?
Let's go see Him together.
I've got nothing better to do.
BOY:
Uncle Indy, come back home now!
[children clamoring]
Uncle Indy!
[crowd laughing]
Next time, Indiana Jones,
it'll take more than children
to save you.
[children clamoring]
GIRL:
Uncle Indy!
[crowd laughing]
I thought I would
find you there.
Better than the United
States Marines, eh?
[monkey chittering]
[all laughing]
Marion's dead.
Yes, I know.
GIRL:
And me! And me!
I'm sorry.
Life goes on, Indy.
There is the proof.
[chitters]
Uh-oh.
I have much
to tell you.
First we will
take them home,
and then I will take you
to the old man.
[engine starts]
[men singing prayers
in distance]
[crickets chirping]
[wind chimes tinkling gently]
[hinges creaking]
[top unscrews, pops]
INDIANA: I can't figure out
how Belloq did it.
Where'd he get a copy
of the headpiece?
There are no pictures,
no duplicates of it anywhere.
I tell you only what I saw
with my own eyes:
A headpiece like that one,
except round the edges,
which were rougher.
In the center, the Frenchman
had embedded a crystal,
and... and surrounding
the crystal, on one side,
there were raised markings,
just like that one.
They made their calculations
in the map room?
This morning.
Belloq and the boss
German, Dietrich.
When they came out
of the map room,
they gave us a new spot
in which to dig,
out away from the camp.
The Well of the Souls, huh?
Come, come, look.
Look here... look.
Sit down.
Come, sit down.
What is it?
This is a warning
not to disturb
the Ark of the Covenant.
What about the height
of the staff, though?
Did Belloq get it
off of here?
Yes.
It is here.
This were the old way,
this mean six kadam high.
About 72 inches.
Wait!
"And take back one kadam
to honor the Hebrew God
whose Ark this is."
[wind chimes tinkling]
[wind blows eerily]
[wind subsides]
You said their headpiece
only had markings on one side.
Are you absolutely sure?
Belloq's staff is too long.
BOTH: They're digging
in the wrong place.
[lilting laughter]
♪ I am the monarch
of the sea ♪
♪ I am the ruler of the--
[gasps]
Bad dates.
I told you
not to be premature
in your communiqué
to Berlin.
Archaeology is not
an exact science.
It does not deal
in time schedules.
The fuehrer is not
a patient man.
He demands constant reports,
and he expects progress.
You led me to believe...
Nothing!
I made no promises.
I only said
it looked very favorable.
Besides, with the information
in our possession,
my calculations were correct.
INDIANA: Boy, they're not
kidding, are they?
What time does the sun
hit the map room?
SALLAH: At about 9:00
in the morning.
Not much time, then.
Where are they digging
for the Well of the Souls?
On that ridge... but the
map room's over there.
Let's go, come on.
[workers chanting cadence
in distance]
[staff clanks]
[suspenseful, mysterious theme
playing]
[yelling in German]
[suspenseful, mysterious theme
playing]
[blowing]
[music crescendos]
[mysterious theme building]
[staff clanks]
[otherworldly chorus joins in]
[low rumbling]
[whooshing]
♪
Sallah.
Sallah!
They're here.
[yelling in German]
Please, my friend,
what is the matter?
I fetch the water.
I shall get it for you.
If you want water,
I will get you water.
No problem, no problem.
[muffled cry]
I thought you were dead.
You must have
switched baskets.
[laughing]
Are you hurt?
No. You have to get me
out of here, quick.
They're gonna be back
at any minute.
Cut me loose.
Quick.
They keep asking about you.
What you know.
What's wrong?
Cut me loose.
I know where the
Ark is, Marion.
The Ark's here?
I'm coming with you, Jones.
Get me out of here!
Cut me loose!
You can't leave me here!
If I take you
out of here now,
they'll start combing
the place for us.
Jones, you've got to get me
out of here!
Come on, Jones, are you crazy?!
Marion, I hate to do this,
but if you don't sit
still and keep quiet,
this whole thing is
going to be shot.
[gasping]
I'll be back to get you.
Jones, what's the matter?
[quiet laugh]
That's it.
BELLOQ:
Who knows?
Perhaps the Ark
is still waiting
in some antechamber
for us to discover.
Perhaps there's some vital
bit of evidence which eludes us.
Perhaps...
Perhaps the girl
can help us.
My feeling exactly.
She was in possession
of the original
piece for years.
She may know much,
if properly motivated.
I tell you,
the girl knows nothing.
[chuckles]
I'm surprised
to find you squeamish.
That is not
your reputation.
But it needn't
concern you.
I have the perfect man
for this kind of work.
Heil Hitler.
[suspenseful, mysterious
theme playing]
[music building]
[whistles]
[music crescendos]
[workers singing
in native language]
[rumbling, wind blowing]
[lightning crackling]
[thunder rolling]
SALLAH:
Indy! Here!
We've hit stone!
Clear it off.
Come on, find the edges.
[Sallah speaking Arabic]
[lightning crackling]
[workers murmuring]
SALLAH:
Good, good, good.
You see, Indy?
You see?
Okay, bring the pry bars in.
As a team, boys!
As a team!
[commanding in Arabic]
Push!
[workers groaning]
INDIANA:
Get 'em in there.
Get 'em under.
Good, good, that's it.
Watch your toes.
[hissing]
[rumbling]
[men grunting]
SALLAH:
Carefully, carefully!
[workers groan with effort]
[rumbling]
[thunder cracks]
[screams]
Sorry, Indy.
Indy...
why does the floor move?
[low rumbling]
Give me your torch.
[hissing]
[thunder rumbling]
Snakes.
Why did it have to be snakes?
[thunder cracks]
Asps.
Very dangerous.
You go first.
[thunder rumbling]
[muffled shouting]
[grunts]
If you're trying
to escape on foot,
the desert is three weeks
in every direction,
so please, eat something.
I must apologize
for their treatment of you.
Yeah. Whose idea was it?
No food, no water.
What kind of people are
these friends of yours?
At this particular time
and place, to do my work,
they are necessary evils.
They're not my friends.
However, with the
right connections,
even in this part
of the world,
we are not entirely
uncivilized.
[huffs]
It's beautiful.
I would very much like
to see you in it.
[laughs]
I'll bet you would.
All right.
What do you got to
drink around here?
We don't have much time.
Soon they will come
to harm you,
and I will not be able
to stop them,
unless you are able
to give me something
to placate them.
Some, uh, piece
of information...
which I can use
to protect you from them.
I've already told you
everything I know.
I have no loyalty
to Jones.
He's brought me
nothing but trouble.
Marion, you are beautiful.
I don't think we
need a chaperone.
[workers muttering]
[thunder rumbling]
SALLAH:
Steadily.
Steadily. Whoa!
Down...
Down-- Whoa.
Carefully, carefully!
You all right, Indy?
[hissing]
SALLAH: Now gently, boys.
Gently, gently!
[hissing]
[loud hiss]
[men scream]
Whoa...
[loud hissing]
[hissing]
[quiet whimper]
I told you it will be all right.
[laughs]
[hissing]
[moans]
Huh...
[snarling hiss]
Sallah, get down here!
[hissing]
You pour.
[thunder rumbles in distance]
[satisfied sigh]
[coughing]
[flame whooshes]
[thunder rumbles]
[suspenseful, mysterious
theme begins]
[thunder rumbling]
[Sallah grunting]
[both groaning with effort]
[grunting]
[heavy thud]
Oh, that's good.
[laughing]
[laughing drunkenly]
Whoops.
[laughing]
What is this stuff, Rene?
I grew up with this.
[laughing]
It's my family label.
Well... I have to be
going now, Rene.
[laughing]
I like you, Rene, very much.
Perhaps we'll
meet someday
under better
circumstances.
We meet again, Fraulein.
You Americans,
you're all the same.
Always overdressing for
the wrong occasions.
[gasps]
[sighs]
Now...
what shall we talk about?
[thunder rumbling]
[quiet creaking]
[low rumbling]
[harsh hissing]
INDIANA:
All right... take it up!
Easy!
[pulley squeaking]
DIETRICH: You're as stubborn
as that girl.
TOHT: You like her too
much, I think.
BELLOQ: Your methods of archaeology
are too primitive for me.
You would use a bulldozer
to find a... China cup.
Shliemann!
Wake your men!
Indy, the torches
are burning out.
Go on, get
out of here.
Hyah!
[yelling in German]
Sallah!
BELLOQ:
Hello!
Why, Dr. Jones,
whatever are you doing
in such a nasty place?
Why don't you come on down here!
I'll show you!
Thank you, my friend,
but I think we are all
very comfortable up here.
That's right, isn't it?
[officers chuckling]
Yes, we are very comfortable
up here.
So, once again, Jones,
what was briefly yours
is now mine.
What a fitting end
to your life's pursuits.
You're about to become
a permanent addition
to this archaeological find.
Who knows?
In a thousand years,
even you may be worth something.
[forced laugh]
Son of a bitch.
SHLIEMANN: I'm afraid we must be
going now, Dr. Jones.
Our prize is awaited
in Berlin.
But I do not wish
to leave you
down in that awful
place all alone.
MARION:
Slimy pig, you let me go!
Stop it!
[screams]
Marion!
Hang on.
[grunting]
Don't...
Indy!
Don't fall!
Marion, I got you!
I got you! I got you!
[screams]
[grunts]
You traitor!
You get your hands off of me!
[hissing]
[gasps and whimpers]
[yelling]
[screaming]
Snakes!
Oh, sh... oh, at your feet!
[screaming]
BELLOQ:
The girl was mine!
She's of no
use to us.
Only our mission for
the fuehrer matters.
I wonder sometimes,
Monsieur,
if you have that
clearly in mind.
It was not to be, chérie.
You bastards!
I'll get you for this!
Indiana Jones...
adieu.
[Toht laughing]
[stone lid rumbling]
No!
[thud echoing]
[hissing]
Take this.
Wave it at anything
that slithers.
MARION:
Thank you.
Oh, my God, this whole
place is slithering.
Indy!
Ow! Jesus!
[hissing]
Where did you get this?
From him?
I was trying to escape.
No thanks to you.
How hard were you trying?
Well, where the
hell were you?
Watch it, watch it.
What are you doing?!
For the fire!
How the hell are we going
to get out of here?
I'm working on it!
Well, whatever you're
doing, do it faster.
[slithering]
Ah...
Where are you going?
Through that wall.
Just get ready to run,
whatever happens to me.
What do you mean
by that?
[hissing]
Indy!
Damn it! Don't you leave me
down here by myself!
[rattling]
[reptilian screech]
[screaming]
[gasps]
[hissing]
[gasping]
[Marion gasping]
Indy!
Here we go!
Get ready!
Indy, the torch is going out!
[coughing]
[panting]
[groans]
Indy?
[screaming]
[eerie moaning]
[gasping]
[blood-curdling scream]
Marion!
Look. Look.
[panting]
[grunting]
[heavy thud]
[engines revving]
[man shouting in German]
They're going to fly it
out of here.
When that Ark gets loaded,
we're already going
to be on the plane.
Ah, monsieur, let us toast
our success in the desert.
To the Ark.
When we are very far
from here.
That will do.
[speaking German]
[officer shouting in German]
[chuckles]
[laughs]
Hey, you now--
come here!
Come here!
[speaking German]
[shouting in German]
[groans loudly]
[groans]
[Marion grunts]
Indy!
[all exclaiming]
Stay with the Ark!
Look out!
Oh, my God.
Marion.
MARION:
In here! Up here!
Indy, come on!
Hold on!
MARION: Move up!
It's gonna blow up!
It's stuck! Indy!
[mechanic grunting]
I can't push it off!
[speaks German]
[screams]
It's stuck!
Turn it! Turn it!
Turn it there!
Never mind!
Get back! Get back!
Get the Ark away from
this place immediately.
Have it put
on the truck.
We'll fly it out
of Cairo.
And Gobler, I want
plenty of protection.
[Gobler speaks German]
Jones.
[workers clamoring]
[man whistles]
Holy smoke, my friends,
I... I'm so pleased
you're not dead!
[explosion booms in distance]
Indy, Indy,
we have no time.
If you still want the Ark,
it is being loaded
onto a truck for Cairo.
Truck?
What truck?
[workers clamoring angrily]
[gunfire]
Let's go!
Get back to Cairo.
Get us some transport
to England--
boat, plane, anything.
Meet me at Omar's.
Be ready for me.
I'm going after that truck.
How?
I don't know.
I'm making this up
as I go.
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
[horse whinnies]
Hyah! Hyah!
[workers cheering]
[rousing adventure theme
playing]
[whinnying]
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
[speaks German]
[soldiers screaming]
[whinnies]
[yells]
[screams]
[yelling in German]
[worker screaming]
[chuckles]
[engine revving]
[villagers yelling]
[burst of gunfire]
[speaking German]
[thud, tires skidding]
[yelling in German]
[gunfire]
[screams]
[speaking German]
[shouting in German]
Ew!
[screams]
[yelling]
[speaks German]
[metallic screeching]
[yelling in German]
He's there!
[yells]
[groans]
BELLOQ:
Idiot! Idiot!
[chickens clucking]
[clamoring]
[dog barking]
[melon splats, dog yelps]
[cheering]
[singing in native language]
Everything at last
has been arranged.
The Ark?
Is on board.
Nothing is lacking,
now that you're here.
Or what is left of you.
INDIANA:
You trust these guys?
Yes.
Mr. Katanga.
Mr. Katanga,
these are my friends.
They are my family.
I will hear of it
if they are not treated well.
My cabin is theirs.
Mr. Jones...
I've heard a lot
about you, sir.
Your appearance is exactly
the way I imagined.
[both laughing]
Good-bye.
[groaning]
Look out
for each other.
I am already
missing you.
You're my good friend.
Sallah.
That is for Fayah...
that is for
your children...
and this is for you.
[ship's horn blaring]
Thank you.
♪ A British tar
is a soaring soul ♪
♪ As free as
a mountain bird ♪
♪ His energetic fist
should be ready to... ♪
[laughter]
♪ ...a dictator...
[whistling happily]
Where did you go?
I'm cleaning up.
[groans]
Where'd you get that?
From him.
Who him?
Katanga.
I got a feeling
I'm not the first woman
ever to travel
with these pirates.
It's lovely.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Really?
[loud thud]
[Indiana screams]
What'd you say?
[groans]
Wait... I don't need
any help.
You know you do.
You're not the man
I knew ten years ago.
It's not the years, honey,
it's the mileage.
You are...
Please, I don't
need a nurse.
I just want to sleep.
Don't be such a baby.
Marion, leave me alone.
What is this here?
Go away.
Yes, it hurts.
Ow!
Well, goddamn it, Indy,
where doesn't it hurt?
Here.
This isn't too bad.
[snoring]
Jones...
Jones?!
We never seem to get
a break, do we?
[rats squeaking]
[deep, eerie pulsing hum]
[squeaking]
What is it?
Engines have stopped.
I'm going
to go check.
[door opens and shuts]
What's happening?
We have most
important friends.
Holy shit.
[man speaking German
over bullhorn]
I sent my man for you.
You and the girl
must disappear.
We have a place
in the hold.
Come on, go, go, go.
Come on, go,
my friend, go.
[bell ringing]
[speaking German]
MAN:
Where is Dr. Jones?
MARION:
What's the big idea?
Let go!
Don't you touch me.
[Marion yells]
[speaking German]
[laughing]
What about Jones?
There's no trace
yet, sir.
KATANGA:
Jones is dead.
I killed him.
He was of no use to us.
This girl, however, has certain
value where we're headed.
She'll bring
a very good price.
Mmm?
Herr Colonel, that
cargo you've taken--
if it's your goal,
go in peace with it,
but leave us the girl.
It would reduce our loss
on this trip.
Savage!
You are not in the position
to ask for anything.
We will take
what we wish.
And then decide
whether or not
to blow your ship
from the water.
The girl goes with me.
She'll be part
of my compensation.
I'm sure your fuehrer
would approve.
If she fails
to please me,
you may do with her
as you wish.
I will waste no more
time with her now.
Excuse me.
I can't find Mr. Jones,
Captain.
I've looked everywhere.
He's got to be
here somewhere.
Look again.
I found him.
Where?
There.
[crew cheering in distance]
[rousing adventure theme
playing]
[speaking German]
[alarm blaring]
[conversing in German]
[yelling in German]
[man speaking German
over loudspeaker]
[blows landing]
[speaking German]
[grunting]
The altar has been
prepared in accordance
with your radio
instructions, sir.
Good.
Take the Ark there
immediately.
Monsieur...
I am uncomfortable
with the thought
of this... Jewish ritual.
Are you sure
it's necessary?
Let me ask you this:
Would you be more comfortable
opening the Ark in Berlin,
for your fuehrer?
Finding out, only then,
if the sacred pieces
of the Covenant are inside?
Knowing, only then,
whether you have
accomplished your mission,
and obtained
the one true Ark?
Hello!
Jones.
Jones!
I'm going to blow up
the Ark, Rene.
Your persistence
surprises even me.
You're going to give
mercenaries a bad name.
Dr. Jones...
surely you don't think you can
escape from this island.
That depends on how reasonable
we're all willing to be.
All I want
is the girl.
If we refuse?
Then your fuehrer
has no prize.
Okay, stand back.
All of you, stand back.
Stand back.
Okay, Jones.
You win!
Blow it up.
[yelling in German]
Yes, blow it up!
Blow it back to God.
All your life
has been spent
in pursuit of
archaeological relics.
Inside the Ark
are treasures
beyond your wildest
aspirations.
You want to see it open
as well as I.
Indiana...
we are simply passing
through history.
This...
This is history.
Do as you will.
[thunder rumbling]
[speaking Hebrew]
[laughing]
[laughing continues]
[mysterious screeching]
[pulsating tone rumbling]
[eerie hissing]
Marion, don't look at it.
Shut your eyes, Marion.
Don't look at it,
no matter what happens.
Ah...
[ethereal howling]
It's beautiful!
[growling]
[screaming]
Indy?
Don't look, Marion!
Keep your eyes shut!
[screaming]
[rumbling and whooshing]
[thunderclap]
Marion.
You've done
your country
a great service,
and we thank you
and we trust you found
the settlement satisfactory.
Oh, the money's fine.
The situation's
totally unacceptable.
Well, gentlemen,
I guess that just about
wraps it up.
Where is the Ark?
I thought
we'd settled that.
The Ark is somewhere
very safe.
From whom?
The Ark is a source
of unspeakable power
and it has to
be researched.
And it will be,
I assure you, Dr. Brody,
Dr. Jones.
We have top men
working on it right now.
Who?
Top men.
Hey, what happened?
You don't look
very happy.
Fools. Bureaucratic fools.
What'd they say?
They don't know
what they've got there.
Well, I know what
I've got here.
Come on.
I'll buy you a drink.
You know...
a drink?