https://t.me/RickyChannel
Last night,
I dreamt I went to Manderley again.
It seemed to me I stood by the iron gate
leading to the drive,
and for a while, I could not enter,
for the way was barred to me.
Then, like all dreamers,
I was possessed of a sudden
with supernatural powers
and passed like a spirit
through the barrier before me.
The drive wound away in front of me,
twisting and turning
as it had always done.
But as I advanced,
I was aware
that a change had come upon it.
Nature had come into her own again,
and little by little
had encroached upon the drive
with long, tenacious fingers.
On and on wound the poor thread
that had once been our drive,
and finally, there was Manderley.
Manderley, secretive and silent.
Time could not mar
the perfect symmetry of those walls.
Moonlight can play odd tricks
upon the fancy,
and suddenly it seemed to me
that light came from the windows.
And then a cloud came upon the moon
and hovered an instant
like a dark hand before a face.
The illusion went with it.
I looked upon a desolate shell
with no whisper of the past
about its staring walls.
We can never go back to Manderley again.
That much is certain.
But sometimes in my dreams,
I do go back
to the strange days of my life
which began for me
in the South of France.
No! Stop!
What the devil are you shouting about?
Who are you? What are you staring at?
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to stare,
but I... I only thought...
Oh, you did, did you?
Well, what are you doing here?
I was only walking.
Well, get on with your walking.
Don't hang about here screaming.
I'll never come to Monte Carlo
out of season again.
Not a single well-known personality
in the hotel.
Stone cold. Waiter!
Garcon! Call him.
Tell him to get me some...
Why, it's Max de Winter.
How do you do?
I'm Edythe Van Hopper.
It's so nice to run into you here,
just when I was beginning to despair of
finding any old friends here in Monte.
But do sit down and have some coffee.
Mr. De Winter is having
some coffee with me.
Go and ask that stupid waiter
for another cup.
I'm afraid I must contradict you.
You shall both have coffee with me.
Garcon. Coffee, please.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
You know,
I recognized you as soon as you came in,
though I haven't seen you since that
night at the casino at Palm Beach.
Perhaps you don't remember
an old woman like me.
Are you playing the tables much
here at Monte?
No. I'm afraid that sort of thing
ceased to amuse me years ago.
I can well understand that.
As for me, if I had
a home like Manderley,
I should certainly never come to Monte.
I hear it's one of the biggest places
in that part of the country,
and you just can't beat it for beauty.
What do you think of Monte Carlo?
Or don't you think of it at all?
Well, I think it's rather artificial.
She's spoiled, Mr. De Winter,
that's her trouble.
Most girls will give their eyes
for a chance to see Monte.
Wouldn't that rather defeat the purpose?
Now that we've found each other again,
I hope I shall see something of you.
You must come and have a drink
in my suite.
I hope they've given you a good room.
The place is empty, so if you're
uncomfortable, mind you make a fuss.
Your valet has unpacked for you,
I suppose?
I'm afraid I don't possess one.
Perhaps you would like to do it for me?
Well, I... I hardly think...
Perhaps you could make yourself
useful to Mr. De Winter
if he wants anything done.
You're a capable child in many ways.
That's a charming suggestion,
but I'm afraid I cling to the old motto,
"He travels fastest who travels alone. "
Perhaps you've not heard it. Good night.
What do you make of that?
Do you suppose that sudden departure
was intended to be funny?
Come, don't sit there gawking,
let's go upstairs.
- Have you got the key?
- Yes, Mrs. Van Hopper.
I remember, when I was younger,
there was a well-known writer
who used to dart down the back way
whenever he saw me coming.
I suppose he was in love with me
and wasn't quite sure of himself.
Well, c'est la vie.
By the way, my dear,
don't think that I mean to be unkind,
but you were just a teeny-weeny bit
forward with Mr. De Winter.
Your effort to enter the conversation
quite embarrassed me,
and I'm sure it did him.
Men loathe that sort of thing.
Oh, come, don't sulk. After all,
I am responsible for your behavior here.
Perhaps he didn't notice it.
Poor thing, I suppose he just
can't get over his wife's death.
They say he simply adored her.
Oh... How awkward of me.
What a stupid thing to do.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Please don't bother.
It doesn't really matter.
No, leave that, leave that.
Go and lay another place at my table.
- Mademoiselle will have lunch with me.
- Oh, but I couldn't possibly.
- Why not?
- Oh, well, please don't be polite. I...
It's very kind of you but I'll be
all right if they just change the cloth.
I wasn't being polite.
I should have asked you
to have lunch with me
even if you hadn't upset the vase
so clumsily.
Come along.
We needn't talk to each other
if we don't feel like it.
Well, thank you very much.
Oh, I... I'll just have
some scrambled eggs.
Oui, mademoiselle.
- What's happened to your friend?
- She's ill in bed with a cold.
I'm sorry I was so
rude to you yesterday.
The only excuse I can offer is that I've
become boorish through living alone.
You weren't really.
You simply wanted to be alone and...
Tell me, is Mrs. Van Hopper
a friend of yours or just a relation?
No, she's my employer.
I'm what is known as "a paid companion. "
I didn't know companionship
could be bought.
I looked at the word "companion"
in the dictionary once.
It said, "a friend of the bosom. "
I don't envy you the privilege.
Well, she's very kind, really,
and I have to earn my living.
Haven't you any family?
No. My mother died years and years ago,
and there was only my father,
and he died last summer.
And then I took this job.
How rotten for you.
Yes, it was rather, because, you see,
we got on so well together.
You and your father?
Yes. He was a lovely person,
very unusual.
- What was he?
- A painter.
Ah! Was he a good one?
Well, I thought so,
but people didn't understand him.
Yes, that's often the trouble.
He painted trees.
At least, it was one tree.
You mean, he painted the same tree
over and over again?
Yes. You see, he had a theory that
if you should find one perfect thing
or place or person,
you should stick to it.
Do you think that's really silly?
Not at all.
I'm a firm believer in that myself.
And what did you find to do with
yourself while he was painting his tree?
Well, I sat with him and I sketched a
little. I don't do it very well, though.
Were you going sketching
this afternoon?
Yes.
- Where?
- Well, I haven't made up my mind.
I'll drive you somewhere in the car.
Oh, no, please, I didn't mean...
Oh, nonsense. Finish up that mess,
and we'll get along.
Thank you. It's very kind of you,
but I'm not very hungry.
Come on. Eat it up like a good girl.
You've taken long enough
for that sketch.
I shall expect a really fine
work of art.
Oh, no, don't look at it.
It's not nearly good enough.
Well, it can't be as bad as all that.
Now don't rub it all out.
Let me see it first.
Well, it's the perspective.
I never can get it right.
Let me see it, let me see it. Oh, dear.
Tell me, is it the perspective
that gives my nose that curious
twist in the middle?
Well, you're not a very easy subject
to sketch. Your...
Your expression keeps changing
all the time.
Does it?
Well, I'd... I'd concentrate on the view
instead, if I were you.
Much more worthwhile.
It rather reminds me of our coastline
at home. Do you know Cornwall at all?
Yes, I went there once with my father
on holiday. I was in a shop once,
and I saw a postcard with a beautiful
house on it, right by the sea.
I asked whose house it was, and
the old lady said, "That's Manderley. "
I felt ashamed for not knowing.
Manderley is beautiful.
But to me,
it's just the place where I was born,
and have lived in all my life.
But now, I don't suppose
I shall ever see it again.
We're lucky not to be home
during the bad weather, aren't we?
I can't ever remember enjoying
swimming in England till June, can you?
The water's so warm here
that I could stay in all day.
There's a dangerous undertow and
there was a man drowned here last year.
I never have any fear of drowning.
Have you?
Come, I'll take you home.
Oh, yes, I know Mr. De Winter well.
I knew his wife, too.
Before she married, she was the
beautiful Rebecca Hildreth, you know.
She was drowned, poor dear,
while she was sailing near Manderley.
He never talks about it, of course,
but he's a broken man.
I suppose I'd better have it.
Wretched stuff!
Give me a chocolate, quick!
Oh, there you are. It's about time.
Hurry up. I want to play some rummy.
She was the beautiful
Rebecca Hildreth, you know.
They say he simply adored her.
She was the beautiful Rebecca
Hildreth, you know.
I suppose he just can't
get over his wife's death.
She was the beautiful Rebecca
Hildreth, you know.
But he's a broken man.
Bonjour.
- Well, where are you going?
- I thought I'd take a tennis lesson.
I see.
I suppose you've had a look at the pro,
and he's desperately handsome,
and you've conceived
a schoolgirl crush on him.
All right. Go ahead.
Make the most of it.
Off duty?
Well, yes. Mrs. Van Hopper's
cold's turned into flu,
so she's got a trained nurse.
I'm sorry for the nurse.
You keen on tennis?
- Well, not particularly.
- That's good. We'll go for a drive.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Van Hopper.
How are you feeling?
You got on rather well
with him, didn't you?
That pro must have been teaching you
other things than tennis.
Hurry up, I want you to make some calls.
I wonder
if Mr. De Winter is still in the hotel.
May I go now?
For the number of lessons you've had,
you ought to be ready for Wimbledon.
But this will be your last,
so make the most of it.
The trouble is, with me laid up like
this, you haven't had enough to do.
I'm getting rid of that nurse today. And
from now on, you'll stick to your job.
Yes, Mrs. Van Hopper.
- Nurse?
- Yes, Mrs. Hopper?
Are you absolutely sure you left
those messages for Mr. De Winter?
- Why, yes, madame.
- I simply can't believe it.
He would most certainly
have called me back.
Oh, well. Poor boy, I simply hate
to see him so alone.
You know, I... I wish there could be
an invention
that bottled up the memory,
like perfume, and it never faded,
never got stale.
Then whenever I wanted to,
I could uncork the bottle
and live the memory all over again.
And what particular moment in your
young life would you want to keep?
All of them. All these last few days.
I feel as though I'd... I'd collected
a whole shelf full of bottles.
Sometimes, you know,
those little bottles contain demons
that have a way of popping out at you,
just as you're trying
most desperately to forget.
Stop biting your nails.
I wish I were a woman of 36, dressed
in black satin with a string of pearls.
You wouldn't be here
with me if you were.
Would you please tell me, Mr. De Winter,
why you asked me to come out with you?
It's obvious you want to be kind, but
why do you choose me for your charity?
I asked you to come out with me
because I wanted your company.
You've blotted out
the past for me more than
all the bright lights
of Monte Carlo.
But if you think I just asked you
out of kindness or charity,
you can leave the car now
and find your own way home.
Go on. Open the door and get out.
- Better blow your nose.
- Thank you.
Please don't call me Mr. De Winter.
I have a very impressive array
of first names.
George Fortescue Maximilian.
You needn't bother with them all
at once. My family call me Maxim.
And another thing,
please promise me
never to wear black satin or pearls,
or to be 36 years old.
Yes, Maxim.
For the love of Pete! Come here!
What do you think?
My daughter's engaged to be married.
Oh, really? How nice!
We must leave for New York at once.
Get reservations on the Aquitania,
and we'll take the 12:30 train
for Cherbourg.
Hurry up and get me the maid
to help with the packing.
We've no time to waste.
Go on and don't dawdle.
Mr. De Winter, please.
He's gone out riding?
He won't be back till noon?
Give me the porter, please.
I'll go and see
if there's anything left in my room.
Has Mr. De Winter come in yet?
Oh, he has?
Would you connect me, please?
I was looking for my book.
I suppose I've packed it.
Well, come on,
the car's waiting at the door.
I'd like to leave a forwarding address,
if they happen to find that book.
- Would you ring Mr. De Winter, please?
- Yes, madame.
- There isn't any answer.
- Thank you.
- Tell her to hurry up!
- Yes, madame.
I was looking for Mr. De Winter.
Mr. De Winter just ordered breakfast
in his room, mademoiselle.
Come in.
Hello. What are you doing here?
Anything the matter?
I've come to say goodbye.
We're going away.
What on Earth are you talking about?
It's true. We're going now,
and I was afraid
I wouldn't see you again.
- Where's she taking you to?
- New York. I don't want to go.
I shall hate it.
I shall be miserable.
I'll dress in here.
I shan't be long.
Which would you prefer,
New York or Manderley?
Oh, please don't joke about it.
Mrs. Van Hopper's waiting.
I'd better say goodbye now.
I'll repeat what I said.
Either you go to America
with Mrs. Van Hopper,
or you come home to Manderley with me.
You mean you want a secretary
or something?
I'm asking you to marry me,
you little fool.
Come in.
Is that my food? I'm famished.
I didn't have any breakfast.
My suggestion didn't seem
to go at all well. Sorry.
Oh, but you don't understand.
It's the...
- I'm not the sort of person men marry.
- What on Earth do you mean?
I don't belong in your sort of world,
for one thing.
Well, what is my sort of world?
Well, Manderley. You know what I mean.
Well, I'm the best judge of whether
you belong there or not.
Of course, if you don't love me,
that's a different thing.
Fine blow to my conceit, that's all.
I do love you.
I love you most dreadfully.
I've been crying all morning because
I thought I'd never see you again.
Bless you for that.
I'll remind you of this one day
and you won't believe me.
It's a pity you have to grow up.
Well, now that's settled.
You may pour me out some coffee.
Two lumps of sugar and some milk,
please. Same with my tea, don't forget.
Who is going to break the news to
Mrs. Van Hopper? Shall you or should I?
You tell her. She'll be so angry.
What's the number of her room?
She's not there.
She's downstairs in the car.
Hello. Give me the desk, please.
Hello. You'll find Mrs. Van Hopper
waiting outside in her car.
Would you ask her,
with my compliments,
if she'd very kindly come up
and see me in my room?
Yes, in my room.
Mr. De Winter says
please for you to come up to his room.
Mr. De Winter?
Why, certainly.
This isn't at all
your idea of a proposal, is it?
It should be in a conservatory,
you in a white frock,
with a red rose in your hand,
and a violin playing in the distance,
and I should be making violent love
to you behind a palm tree.
Poor darling. Never mind.
I don't mind.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
You won't have to say a word.
I'm so glad you called me,
Mr. De Winter.
I was making a hasty departure.
It was so rude of me
not to let you know.
But a cable came this morning
announcing that my daughter
is engaged to be married.
That's rather a coincidence,
Mrs. Van Hopper.
I asked you up here in order
to tell you of my engagement.
You don't mean it.
How perfectly wonderful.
How romantic. Who is the lucky lady?
I apologize for depriving you
of your companion in this abrupt way.
I do hope it won't inconvenience you
too greatly.
When did all this happen?
Just now, Mrs. Van Hopper.
Just a few minutes ago.
I simply can't believe it.
And I suppose I ought to scold you
for not having breathed a word
of all of this to me.
What am I thinking of?
I should give you both
my congratulations and my blessings.
I'm very happy for you both.
- When and where is the wedding to be?
- Here, as soon as possible.
A whirlwind romance. Splendid! I can
easily postpone my sailing for a week.
This poor child has no mother,
so I shall take responsibility
for all the arrangements.
Trousseau, reception and everything,
and I'll give the bride away.
But our luggage.
Go down and tell the porter
to take everything out of the car.
Just a minute. We're most
grateful, Mrs. Van Hopper,
but I think we'd both prefer to
have it all as quiet as possible.
And I couldn't possibly allow you
to change your sailing plans.
- Oh, but...
- No, no, no.
Dear, I'll go down and see that
your luggage is brought back.
Thank you, Maxim.
So this is what's been happening
during my illness.
Tennis lessons, my foot.
I suppose I've to hand it to you
for a fast worker.
How did you manage it?
Still waters certainly run deep.
Tell me, have you been doing
anything you shouldn't?
- I don't know what you mean.
- Well, never mind.
I always did say that Englishmen
have strange tastes.
You certainly have your work cut out
as mistress of Manderley.
To be perfectly frank with you,
my dear, I can't see you doing it.
You haven't the experience,
you haven't the faintest idea
what it means to be a great lady.
Of course you know why
he's marrying you, don't you?
You haven't flattered yourself
that he's in love with you?
Fact is, that empty house got on
his nerves to such an extent,
he nearly went off his head.
He just couldn't go on living alone.
You'd better leave, Mrs. Van Hopper.
You'll miss your train.
Mrs. De Winter.
Goodbye, my dear, and good luck!
Monsieur!
What is he saying?
He says I've forgotten
the proof that we're married.
Good heavens.
Somebody else had the same idea.
- Isn't she sweet?
- Yes.
You'd have liked a bridal veil,
wouldn't you?
Or at least...
Oh, Maxim, how lovely.
How perfectly lovely.
Perfectly lovely.
Welcome home, Mr. De Winter.
Thank you, Smith.
- Cold, darling?
- Yes, just a little bit.
There's no need to be frightened,
you know.
Just be yourself,
and they'll all adore you.
You don't have to worry
about the house at all.
Mrs. Danvers is the housekeeper.
Just leave it to her.
Hello. It's starting to rain.
We'd better hurry up.
Here. Have this. Put it over your head.
Thank you.
That's it. That's Manderley.
- Here we are. Frith, everybody well?
- Yes, thank you, sir.
Glad to see you home, sir.
- This is Mrs. De Winter, Frith.
- How do you do?
I didn't expect the whole staff
to be in attendance.
Mrs. Danvers' orders, sir.
Oh. Sorry about this.
It won't take long.
This is Mrs. Danvers.
How do you do?
I have everything in readiness for you.
That's very good of you. I...
I didn't expect anything.
- I think we'd like some tea, Frith.
- Ready in the library, sir.
Come along, darling.
Oh, Maxim, come in.
Oh.
- Good evening, Mrs. Danvers.
- Good evening, madam.
- I hope Alice was satisfactory, madam.
- Oh, yes, thank you, perfectly.
She's the parlor maid.
She'll have to look after you
until your own maid arrives.
Oh, but I haven't a maid.
I'm sure Alice will do very nicely.
I'm afraid that would not do
for very long, madam.
It's usual for ladies in your position
to have a personal maid.
I hope you approve the new decoration
of these rooms, madam?
Oh, I didn't know it had been changed.
I hope you haven't been
to too much trouble.
I only followed out
Mr. De Winter's instructions.
Well, what did it look like before?
It had an old paper
and different hangings.
It was never used much
except for occasional visitors.
Oh. Then it wasn't
Mr. De Winter's room originally?
No, madam.
He's never used the east wing before.
Of course, there's no view
of the sea from here.
The only good view of the sea
is from the west wing.
The room's very charming,
and I'm sure I'll be comfortable.
If there's anything you want done,
madam, you have only to tell me.
I suppose you've been at Manderley
for many years, longer than anyone else.
Not so long as Frith.
He was here when the old gentleman
was living,
when Mr. De Winter was a boy.
Oh, I see.
And you didn't come till after that?
I came here when the first
Mrs. De Winter was a bride.
Mrs. Danvers,
I do hope we'll be friends.
You must be patient with me.
This sort of life is new to me
and I do want to make a success of it,
and make Mr. De Winter happy,
so I know I can leave
all the household arrangements to you.
Very well. I hope I shall do everything
to your satisfaction, madam.
I've managed the house
since Mrs. De Winter's death
and Mr. De Winter has never complained.
I think I'll go downstairs now.
That room in the west wing I was telling
you about is there, through that door.
It's not used now.
It's the most beautiful room
in the house,
the only one that looks down
across the lawns to the sea.
It was Mrs. De Winter's room.
- Good morning.
- You're Mrs. De Winter, aren't you?
- Yes.
My name's Crawley.
I manage the estate for Maxim.
Awfully glad to meet you.
A fearful lot of stuff piled up
while Maxim was away.
Yes, I'm sure there must have been.
I do wish I could help with some of it.
No, no! Frank never allows anybody
to help him.
He's like an old mother hen
with his bills and rents and taxes.
Come on, Frank,
we must go over these estimates.
I'll get my papers.
You'll find quantities
of breakfast over there.
But you must eat it all,
or Cook will be mortally offended.
I'll do my best, Maxim.
I have to go over the place
with Frank,
just to make sure that he
hasn't lost any of it.
You'll be all right, won't you?
Getting acquainted with your new home?
Have a look at The Times.
There's a thrilling article
on what's the matter
with English cricket.
Oh, yes...
My sister, Beatrice,
and her husband, Giles Lacy,
have invited themselves over for lunch.
- Today?
- Yes.
I suppose the old girl
can't wait to look you over.
You'll find her very direct.
If she doesn't like you, she'll
probably tell you so to your face.
Don't worry, darling, I'll be back
in time to protect you from her.
- Goodbye, darling.
- Goodbye, Maxim.
- Goodbye.
- Good morning, madam.
- Good morning, Frith.
Isn't there anything
I could get for you, madam?
No, thank you, Frith.
I'm really not very hungry.
Thank you.
- The paper, madam.
- Oh, yes. Thank you, Frith.
I slipped.
Thank you, Frith.
- It's big, isn't it?
- Yes, madam, Manderley is a big place.
This was the banquet hall
in the old days.
It's still used on great occasions,
such as a big dinner or a ball.
And the public is admitted here,
you know, once a week.
That's nice.
I beg pardon, madam.
I'm afraid the fire is not usually lit
in the library until the afternoon.
But you'll find one in the morning room.
Of course, if you wish
this fire lit now, madam...
No, Frith, I wouldn't dream of it.
Mrs. De Winter...
I mean, the late Mrs. De Winter
always did her correspondence
and telephoning in the morning room,
after breakfast.
Thank you, Frith.
Is anything wrong, madam?
Oh, no. Which way is the morning room?
Oh, it's that door there, on the left.
Oh, yes, thank you.
Mrs. De Winter?
Oh, I'm afraid you've made a mistake.
Mrs. De Winter's been dead
for over a year.
Oh, I mean...
Oh.
That was the house telephone, madam.
Probably the head gardener
wishing instructions.
Did you want to see me, Mrs. Danvers?
Mr. De Winter informed me that
his sister, Mrs. Lacy, and Major Lacy
are expected for luncheon.
I'd like to know
if you approve of the menu.
Oh, well, I'm sure it's very suitable,
very nice indeed.
You will notice, madam, that I've
left a blank space for the sauce.
Mrs. De Winter was most particular
about sauces.
Let's have whatever you think
that Mrs. De Winter would have ordered.
Thank you, madam.
When you've finished your letters,
Robert will take them to the post.
My... My letters?
Oh, yes, of course.
Thank you, Mrs. Danvers.
How are you, Frith?
- Good morning, Mrs. Lacy.
Where's Mr. De Winter?
I believe he went down
to the farm with Mr. Crawley.
How tiresome of him not to
be here when we arrive, and how typical.
I must say old Danvers
keeps the house looking lovely.
She's certainly learned that trick
of arranging flowers from Rebecca.
I wonder how she likes it now,
being ordered about
by an ex-chorus girl.
Now, where on Earth
did you get the idea
she's an ex-chorus girl?
He picked her up in the South of France,
didn't he?
What if he did?
Well, I mean to say, there you are.
How do you do? I'm Maxim's wife.
How do you do?
Well, I must say you're quite different
from what I expected.
Don't be so silly.
She's exactly what I told you she'd be.
Well, how do you like Manderley?
It's very beautiful, isn't it?
And how do you get along
with Mrs. Danvers?
Well, I...
I've never met anyone
quite like her before.
You mean, she scares you.
She's not exactly an oil painting,
is she?
Giles, you're very much in the way here.
Go somewhere else.
Well, I'll try and find Maxim, shall I?
Giles.
I didn't mean to say anything
against Mrs. Danvers.
Oh, there's no need for you
to be frightened of her,
but I shouldn't have any more
to do with her than you can help.
- Shall we sit down?
- Yes. Yes, please.
You see, she's bound to be
insanely jealous at first
and she must resent you bitterly.
But why should she?
Don't you know?
I should have thought
Maxim would have told you.
She simply adored Rebecca.
- How are you, Robert?
- Quite well, thank you, madam.
- Still having trouble with your teeth?
- Unfortunately, yes, madam.
You must have them out, all of them.
- Wretched nuisances, teeth.
- Thank you, madam.
What a plateful.
Do you hunt?
No, I don't.
I'm afraid I don't even ride.
You have to ride down here, we all do.
Which do you ride,
sidesaddle or astride?
Well, of course, I forgot.
You don't, do you?
You must.
Nothing else to do around here.
Maxim, when are you going to have
parties here again, like the old days?
I haven't thought about it.
- But everyone's dying to see you and...
- Yes, I bet they are.
Why don't you have
the masquerade ball again this summer?
My dear, are you fond of dancing?
I love it, but I'm not very good at it.
Do you rumba?
- Never tried.
- You must teach me.
Actually, I'm trying to find out
exactly what your wife does do.
She sketches a little.
Sketches.
Not this modern stuff, I hope, you know,
portrait of a lampshade upside down
to represent a soul in torment.
Don't sail, do you?
No, I don't.
Thank goodness for that.
Huh?
You're very much in love with Maxim,
aren't you?
Yes, I can see you are.
Don't mind my saying so, but why
don't you do something about your hair?
Why don't you have it cut
or sweep it back behind your ears?
Oh, no, that's worse.
What does Maxim say about it?
Does he like it like that?
Well, he never mentions it.
Oh, well, don't go by me.
I can see by the way you dress
you don't care a hoot how you look.
But I wonder Maxim hasn't been at you.
He's so particular about clothes.
I don't think he ever notices
what I wear.
Oh. He must have changed a lot, then.
You mustn't worry
about old Maxim and his moods.
One never knows what goes on
in that quiet mind of his.
Often, he gets into a terrible rage,
and when he does...
I don't suppose he'll
lose his temper with you.
You seem such a placid little thing.
Come on, old girl. We've got to go
on the first tee at 3:00.
All right, I'm coming.
Well, goodbye, Maxim, old boy.
Goodbye, Giles.
Thanks for coming, old boy.
Goodbye, my dear. Forgive me for asking
you so many rude questions.
We both really hope
you'll be very happy.
Thank you, Beatrice,
thank you very much.
And I must congratulate you
upon the way Maxim looks.
We were very worried about him
this time last year.
But then, of course,
you know the whole story.
Goodbye, Beatrice.
- Goodbye, old boy.
- Goodbye.
Well, thank heavens they've gone.
Now we can have a walk about the place.
Looks as though we might have a shower.
But you won't mind that, will you?
No, but wait a minute.
I'll go upstairs and get a coat.
There's a heap of mackintoshes
in the flower room. Robert?
Run and get a coat from the flower room
for Mrs. De Winter, will you?
What do you think of Beatrice?
Oh, I liked her very much,
but she kept saying
that I was quite different
from what she expected.
What the devil did she expect?
Oh, someone smarter
and more sophisticated, I'm afraid.
Do you like my hair?
Your hair? Yes, of course I do.
What's the matter with it?
Oh, I don't know. I just wondered.
How funny you are.
Thank you.
- Do I have to put it on?
- Yes, certainly, certainly, certainly.
You can't be too careful with children.
Come on, Jasper.
Come and take some of that fat off.
Jasper! Here. Not that way! Come here!
Where does that lead to?
Oh, it leads to a little cove
where we used to keep a boat.
Oh, let's go down there.
Well, no. It's a perfectly dull,
uninteresting stretch of sand,
- just like any other.
- Oh, please.
Well, all right. We'll walk down
and take a look if you really want to.
That's Jasper.
There must be something wrong.
- Perhaps he's hurt himself.
- No, he's all right, leave him alone.
Don't you think I'd better go and see?
Don't bother about him, I tell you,
he can't come to any harm.
He'll find his own way back!
Jasper! Jasper?
Oh, there you are.
What do you want in there, Jasper?
Come on. Come on home. Let's go home.
Jasper...
Oh.
I didn't know that there was anybody...
I know that dog.
He comes from the house.
He ain't yours.
No. He's Mr. De Winter's dog.
Have you anything I could tie him with?
Come on, Jasper.
You won't tell anyone
you saw me in there, will you?
Don't you belong on the estate?
I weren't doing nothing.
I was just putting me shells away.
She's gone in the sea, ain't she?
She'll never come back no more.
No. She'll never come back.
Come on, Jasper.
Maxim! What's the matter?
Maxim!
I'm sorry I was such a time,
but I had to find a rope for Jasper.
Hurry up, Jasper, for heaven's sake.
Please wait for me. Maxim, what is it?
You look so angry.
You knew I didn't want you to go there,
but you deliberately went.
Why not? There was only a cottage
down there and a strange man who...
- You didn't go in the cottage, did you?
- Yes, the door was...
- Don't go there again, do you hear?
- Well, why not?
Because I hate the place.
And if you had my memories,
you wouldn't go there or talk about it
or even think about it.
What's the matter?
Oh, I'm sorry, please.
We should have stayed away.
We should never have come back
to Manderley.
Oh, what a fool I was.
I've made you unhappy.
Somehow, I've hurt you.
Oh, I can't bear to see you like this
because I love you so much.
Do you?
I've made you cry.
Forgive me.
I sometimes seem to fly off the handle
for no reason at all.
Don't I?
Come, we'll go home and have some tea
and forget all about it.
Yes, let's forget all about it.
Here, let me have Jasper.
- Hello. Come in.
- Oh, please don't get up, Mr. Crawley.
I was just wondering
if you meant what you said the other day
- about showing me the run of things.
- Of course I did.
What are you doing now?
Notifying all the tenants
that in celebration of Maxim's return
with his bride,
this week's rent will be free.
Oh, is that Maxim's idea?
Oh, yes, all the servants get
an extra week's wages, too.
Oh, he didn't tell me.
Can't I help you?
I could at least lick the stamps.
Well, that's terribly nice of you.
Won't you sit down?
Yes, thank you.
I was down at the cottage on the beach
the other day.
There was a man there,
a queer sort of person.
Jasper kept barking at him.
Oh, yes, it must have been Ben.
Excuse me. He's quite harmless.
We give him odd jobs now and then.
That cottage bay
seemed to be going to rack and ruin.
Why isn't something done about it?
I think if Maxim wanted anything
done about it, he'd tell me.
Are those all Rebecca's things
down there?
Yes.
Yes, they are.
What did she use the cottage for?
The boat used to be moored near there.
What boat? What happened to it?
Was that the boat she was sailing in
when she was drowned?
Yes. It capsized and sank.
She was washed overboard.
Wasn't she afraid to go out
like that alone?
She wasn't afraid of anything.
Where did they find her?
Near Edgecombe,
about 40 miles up channel
about two months afterwards.
Maxim went up to identify her.
It was horrible for him.
Yes, it must have been.
Mr. Crawley, please don't think me
morbidly curious. It isn't that. It's...
It's just that I feel
at such a disadvantage.
All the time, whenever I meet anyone,
Maxim's sister or even the servants,
I know they're all thinking
the same thing,
that they're all comparing me with her,
with Rebecca.
You mustn't think that.
I can't tell you how glad I am
that you married Maxim.
It's going to make
all the difference to his life.
From my point of view,
it's very refreshing
to find someone like yourself,
who's not entirely in tune,
shall we say, with Manderley.
That's very sweet of you.
I daresay I've been stupid,
but every day I realize
the things she had that I lack.
Beauty and wit and intelligence,
and all the things
that are so important in a woman.
You have qualities
that are just as important,
more important, if I may say so.
Kindliness and sincerity,
and if you'll forgive me, modesty,
mean more to a husband than all
the wit and beauty in the world.
We, none of us want to live in the past,
Maxim least of all.
It's up to you, you know,
to lead us away from it.
Right.
I promise you I won't
bring this up again,
but before we end this conversation,
would you answer
just one more question?
If it's something I'm able to answer,
I'll do my best.
Tell me, what was Rebecca really like?
I suppose...
I suppose she was the most
beautiful creature I ever saw.
Good evening, Maxim.
Hello. The films of the honeymoon
have arrived at last.
Do we have time, do you think,
before dinner?
What on Earth have you done to yourself?
Oh, nothing. I just ordered a new dress
from London.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, no, no. Only, do you think
that sort of thing's right for you?
- It doesn't seem your type at all.
- I thought you'd like it.
And what have you done to your hair?
Oh, I see.
Dear, oh, dear. I'm sorry.
You look lovely, lovely.
It's very nice, for a change.
- Shall we see these pictures?
- Yes. I'd love to see them.
Look now, look at that.
Wasn't it wonderful, darling?
https://t.me/RickyChannel
Can't we go back there someday?
Yes, of course. Of course.
Look at you.
Won't our grandchildren be delighted
when they see how lovely you were?
Oh, look at you.
Oh, I like that.
Look at that.
Yes, very nice.
- Remember that?
Yes.
I wish our honeymoon could have
lasted forever, Maxim.
Dash it, look.
Hang it.
I've threaded it up wrong as usual
or something.
Yes, Frith. What is it?
Excuse me, sir.
May I have a word with you?
Yes. Come in.
It's about Robert, sir.
There's been a slight unpleasantness
between him and Mrs. Danvers.
Oh, dear.
- Robert is very upset.
- This is trouble.
What is it?
It appears that Mrs. Danvers has accused
Robert of stealing a valuable ornament
from the morning room.
Robert denies the accusation
most emphatically, sir.
- What was the thing, anyway?
- China cupid, sir.
Oh, dear.
That's one of our treasures, isn't it?
Well, tell Mrs. Danvers
to get to the bottom of it somehow.
- Tell her I'm sure it wasn't Robert.
- Very good, sir.
Why do they come to me with these
things? That's your job, sweetheart.
Maxim, I wanted to tell you,
but I forgot.
The fact is, I broke the china cupid.
You broke it?
Now, why on Earth didn't you say
something about it when Frith was here?
I don't know. I didn't like to.
I was afraid he'd think me a fool.
He'll think you much more
of a fool now.
You'll have to explain to him
and Mrs. Danvers.
Oh, no, Maxim.
You do it. I'll go upstairs.
Don't be such a little idiot, darling.
Anybody would think
you were afraid of them.
It's all a mistake, Mrs. Danvers.
Apparently, Mrs. De Winter
broke the cupid herself
and forgot to say anything about it.
I'm so sorry. I never thought
that I'd get Robert into trouble.
Is it possible to repair
the ornament, madam?
No, I'm afraid it isn't.
It smashed into pieces.
What did you do with the pieces?
Well, I put them at the back of one
of the drawers in the writing desk.
Well, it looks as though
Mrs. De Winter was afraid
you were going to put her in prison,
doesn't it, Mrs. Danvers?
Well, never mind.
Do what you can to find the pieces.
See if they can be mended, and
above all, tell Robert to dry his tears.
I shall apologize to Robert, of course.
Perhaps if such a thing happens again,
Mrs. De Winter will tell me personally.
Yes, yes, all right.
Thank you, Mrs. Danvers.
Well, I suppose that clip
will hold all right. I don't know.
I'm awfully sorry,
darling. It was very careless of me.
- Mrs. Danvers must be furious with me.
- Hang Mrs. Danvers.
Why on Earth
should you be frightened of her?
You behave more like an upstairs maid
or something,
- not the mistress of the house at all.
- Yes, I know I do.
But I feel so uncomfortable.
I try my best every day, but it's very
difficult with people looking me
up and down as if I were a prize cow.
What does it matter if they do?
You must remember
that life at Manderley is the only thing
that interests anybody down here.
What a slap in the eye
I must have been to them, then.
I suppose that's why you married me,
because you knew I was dull and gauche
and inexperienced,
and there'd never be
any gossip about me.
Gossip? What do you mean?
I don't know.
I just said it for something to say.
Don't look at me like that. Maxim.
What's the matter? What have I said?
Wasn't a very attractive thing
to say, was it?
No. It was rude, hateful.
I wonder if I did a very selfish thing
in marrying you.
How do you mean?
I'm not much of a companion
to you, am I?
You don't get much fun, do you?
You ought to have married a boy,
someone of your own age.
Maxim, why do you say this?
Of course we're companions.
Are we? I don't know.
- I'm very difficult to live with.
- No, you're not difficult.
You're easy, very easy.
Our marriage is a success,
isn't it, a great success?
We're happy, aren't we? Terribly happy?
If you don't think we are happy,
it would be much better
if you didn't pretend.
I'll go away.
Why don't you answer me?
How can I answer you
when I don't know the answer myself?
If you say we're happy,
let's leave it at that.
Happiness is something
I know nothing about.
Oh, look. There's the one
when I left the camera
running on the tripod, remember?
Pardon me, madam.
Is there anything I can do for you?
I'm all right, Hilda.
Thank you very much.
I'll bring the sandwiches
immediately, madam.
- Hilda.
- Yes, madam?
The west wing.
Nobody ever uses it anymore, do they?
No, madam.
Not since the death of Mrs. De Winter.
Come along, Mr. Jack,
or someone may see you.
Well, Danny, old harpy,
it's been good to see you again.
I've been simply breathless
to pick up all the news.
I really don't think it's
wise for you to come here, Mr. Jack.
Jasper, come here.
Oh, nonsense, nonsense.
It's just like coming back home.
Quiet, Mr. Jack.
Yes. We must be careful
not to shock Cinderella, mustn't we?
She's in the morning room.
If you leave through the garden door,
she won't see you.
I must say,
I feel a little like the poor relation,
sneaking around through back doors.
Well, toodle-oo, Danny.
Goodbye, Mr. Jack,
and please be careful.
Jasper, be quiet.
Looking for me?
- I didn't make you jump, did I?
- No.
Of course not.
I didn't quite know who it was.
Yes. You're pleased to see me,
aren't you, old boy?
I'm glad there's someone in the family
to welcome me back to Manderley.
And how is dear old Max?
Very well, thank you.
I hear he went up to London,
left his little bride all alone.
It's too bad.
Isn't he rather afraid that somebody
might come down and carry you off?
Danny, all your precautions
were in vain.
The mistress of the house
was hiding behind the door.
Oh. What about presenting me
to the bride?
This is Mr. Favell, madam.
How do you do?
- Won't you have some tea or something?
- Now, isn't that a charming invitation?
I've been asked to tea, Danny,
and I've a good mind to accept.
Oh, well, perhaps you're right. Pity,
just when we were getting on so nicely.
We mustn't lead the young bride astray,
must we, Jasper?
Goodbye. It's been fun meeting you.
Oh, and by the way, it would be
very decent of you if you didn't mention
this little visit
to your revered husband.
He doesn't exactly approve of me.
- Very well.
- That's very sporting of you.
I wish I had a young bride of
three months waiting for me at home.
I'm just a lonely old bachelor.
Fare thee well.
Oh, and I know what was wrong
with that introduction.
Danny didn't tell you, did she?
I am Rebecca's favorite cousin.
Toodle-oo!
Do you wish anything, madam?
I didn't expect to see you,
Mrs. Danvers.
I noticed that a window wasn't closed
and I came up to see
- if I could fasten it.
- Why did you say that?
I closed it before I left the room.
You opened it yourself, didn't you?
You've always wanted to see this room,
haven't you, madam?
Why did you never ask me
to show it to you?
I was ready to show it to you every day.
It's a lovely room, isn't it?
Loveliest room you've ever seen.
Everything is kept
just as Mrs. De Winter liked it.
Nothing has been altered
since that last night.
Come. I'll show you her dressing room.
This is where I keep all her clothes.
You would like to see them,
wouldn't you?
Feel this.
It was a Christmas present
from Mr. De Winter.
He was always giving her expensive
gifts, the whole year round.
I keep her underwear on this side.
They were made specially for her by
the nuns in the Convent of St. Claire.
I always used to wait up for her,
no matter how late.
Sometimes she and Mr. De Winter
didn't come home until dawn.
While she was undressing, she'd tell me
about the party she'd been to.
She knew everyone that mattered.
Everyone loved her.
When she finished her bath,
she'd go into the bedroom
and go over to the dressing table.
Oh, you've moved her brush, haven't you?
There. That's better.
Just as she always laid it down.
"Come on, Danny. Hair drill, "
she would say.
And I'd stand behind her like this
and brush away for 20 minutes at a time.
And then she would say,
"Good night, Danny, "
and step into her bed.
I embroidered this case for her myself,
and I keep it here always.
Did you ever see anything so delicate?
Look. You can see my hand through it.
You wouldn't think she'd been gone
so long, would you?
Sometimes when I walk along
the corridor,
I fancy I hear her just behind me.
That quick light step.
I couldn't mistake it anywhere.
Not only in this room,
it's in all the rooms in the house.
I can almost hear it now.
Do you think the dead come back
and watch the living?
No, I don't believe it.
Sometimes I wonder if she doesn't
come back here to Manderley,
and watch you
and Mr. De Winter together.
You look tired.
Why don't you stay here
a while and rest?
And listen to the sea.
So soothing.
Listen to it.
Listen.
Listen to the sea.
Tell Mrs. Danvers
I wish to see her immediately.
You sent for me, madam?
Yes, Mrs. Danvers.
I want you to get rid
of all these things.
- These are Mrs. De Winter's things.
- I am Mrs. De Winter now.
Very well. I'll give the instructions.
Just a moment, please.
Mrs. Danvers, I intend to say nothing
to Mr. De Winter
about Mr. Favell's visit.
In fact, I prefer to forget
everything that happened this afternoon.
Maxim, Maxim, you've been gone all day.
You're choking me.
Well, well, well, what have
you been doing with yourself?
- I've been thinking.
- What did you want to do that for?
Come in here and I'll tell you.
Darling, could we have a costume ball
just as you used to?
Now what put that into your mind?
Has Beatrice been at you?
No, no, but I feel
that we ought to do something
to make people feel that Manderley
is just the same as it always was.
Oh, please, darling, could we?
You don't know what it would mean,
you know.
You'd have to be hostess
to hundreds of people, all the county.
And a lot of young people
would come up from London,
- and turn the house into a nightclub.
- Oh, yes. But I want to. Please.
I've never been to a large party,
but I could learn what to do.
And I promise you,
you wouldn't be ashamed of me.
All right, if you think you'd enjoy it.
You'd better get Mrs. Danvers
to help you out, won't you?
No, no. I don't need Mrs. Danvers
to help me. I can do it myself.
All right, my sweet.
Thank you, darling. Thank you.
- What'll you go as?
- I never dress up.
That's the one privilege I claim
as the host.
What will you be? Alice in Wonderland,
with that ribbon around your hair?
No, I won't tell you.
I'll design a costume all by myself
and give you the surprise of your life.
Come in.
Robert found these sketches
in the library, madam.
- Did you intend throwing them away?
- Yes, Mrs. Danvers, I did.
They were just some ideas I was
sketching for my costume for the ball.
Hasn't Mr. De Winter suggested anything?
No, I want to surprise him. I don't want
him to know anything about it.
I merely thought
that you might find a costume
among the family portraits
that would suit you.
Oh, you mean those at the top
of the stairs? I'll go and look at them.
This one, for instance.
Might have been designed for you.
I'm sure you could have it copied.
I've heard Mr. De Winter say that this
is his favorite of all the paintings.
It's Lady Caroline de Winter,
one of his ancestors.
Oh, well, that's a splendid idea,
Mrs. Danvers. I'm very grateful.
- Everything under control, Frith?
- Yes, sir, thank you.
Excuse me, sir, are you supposed to be
a schoolmaster?
Oh, no. This is just
my old cap and gown.
It certainly makes a very nice costume,
sir. And economical, too.
Yes. That was the idea.
Good evening, Robert.
Not very good weather for the ball.
- No, sir.
- Very misty on the way and very chilly.
Oh, this wig's so tight
they ought to send an aspirin with it.
Hello. What's the idea? Adam and Eve?
Oh, Maxim, don't be disgusting.
- Strongman. Where's my weight thing?
- What thing?
You haven't left it in the car,
have you?
There it is.
- You were the first one down?
- Yes.
Where's the child?
Well, she's keeping her costume
a terrific secret.
Wouldn't even let me into her room.
Oh, lovely.
I'll go up and give her a hand.
- I could do with a drink.
- Won't you catch a cold in that thing?
Don't be silly. Pure wool, old boy.
- Pardon me, sir. You forgot this.
- Thank you.
Here I am, dear, it's Bea.
I've come to give you a hand.
Oh, please don't
come in, Beatrice.
I don't want anyone to see my costume.
Oh. Oh, you won't be long, will you?
Because the first people
will be arriving any moment.
Now, you're sure
that's where that should be?
Yes, madam, it's just right.
- Isn't it exciting?
- Indeed it is, madam.
I've always heard of the Manderley ball,
and now I'm really going to see one.
I'm sure there will be no one there
to touch you, madam.
Do you really think so?
Now, where's my fan?
Here.
- You're sure I look all right?
- You look ever so beautiful.
Well, here goes.
Good evening, Mr. De Winter.
What the devil do you think
you're doing?
Rebecca.
But it's the picture.
The one in the gallery.
- What is it? What have I done?
- Go and take it off.
It doesn't matter what you put on.
Anything will do.
What are you standing there for?
Didn't you hear what I said?
Sir George and Lady Moore.
Dudley Tennant.
Admiral and Lady Burbank.
I watched you go down,
just as I watched her a year ago.
Even in the same dress,
you couldn't compare.
You knew it.
You knew that she wore it, and yet
you deliberately suggested I wear it.
Why do you hate me? What have I done
to you that you should ever hate me so?
You tried to take her place,
you let him marry you.
I've seen his face, his eyes.
They're the same as those first weeks
after she died.
I used to listen to him walking
up and down, up and down,
all night long, night after night,
thinking of her, suffering torture
because he'd lost her.
I don't want to know.
I don't want to know!
You thought you could be Mrs. De Winter,
live in her house, walk in her steps,
take the things that were hers.
But she's too strong for you.
You can't fight her. No one ever
got the better of her. Never. Never.
She was beaten in the end,
but it wasn't a man, it wasn't a woman.
It was the sea.
Oh, stop it. Stop it. Oh, stop it.
You're overwrought, madam.
I've opened a window for you.
A little air will do you good.
Why don't you go?
Why don't you leave Manderley?
He doesn't need you.
He's got his memories.
He doesn't love you.
He wants to be alone again with her.
You've nothing to stay for.
You've nothing to live for, really,
have you?
Look down there. It's easy, isn't it?
Why don't you? Why don't you?
Go on.
Don't be afraid.
Shipwreck.
Ship on the rocks!
- A ship aground, sending up rockets!
- Shipwreck!
Come on, everybody,
down to the bay.
Notify the coast guard.
She's aground.
Maxim! Maxim!
Ship ashore.
Come on! Come on, everybody.
Come on! Come on!
- Maxim! Maxim!
Oh!
Ben, have you seen
Mr. De Winter anywhere?
She won't come back, will she?
You said so.
Who, Ben? What do you mean?
The other one.
- Frank, have you seen Maxim anywhere?
- Not since about half an hour ago.
I thought he'd gone up to the house.
No, he hasn't been in the house at all,
and I'm afraid something
might have happened to him.
Frank, what's the matter?
Is anything wrong?
- There is something wrong.
- Well...
The diver who went down to inspect
the bottom of the ship
came across the hull of another boat.
A little sailboat.
- Frank, is it...
- Yes.
It's Rebecca's.
How did they recognize it?
He's a local man. Knew it instantly.
It'll be so hard on poor Maxim.
Yes. It's going to bring it all
back again, and worse than before.
Why did they have to find it?
Why couldn't they have left it
there in peace
at the bottom of the sea?
Well, I'd better get along and arrange
some breakfast for the men.
All right, Frank.
I'll go and look for Maxim.
- Hello.
- Maxim.
You haven't had any sleep.
- Have you forgiven me?
- Forgiven you?
What have I got to forgive you for?
For last night.
My stupidity about the costume.
Oh, that.
I'd forgotten.
I was angry with you, wasn't I?
Hmm.
Maxim, can't we start all over again?
I don't ask that you should love me.
I won't ask impossible things.
I'll be your friend, your companion.
I'll be happy with that.
You love me very much, don't you?
But it's too late, my darling.
We've lost our little chance
of happiness.
- No, Maxim, no.
- Yes.
It's all over now.
The thing's happened.
The thing I have dreaded day after day.
- Night after night.
- Maxim, what are you trying to tell me?
Rebecca has won.
Her shadow has been between us all
the time, keeping us from one another.
She knew that this would happen.
What are you saying?
They sent a diver down.
- He found another boat.
- Yes, I know. Frank told me.
Rebecca's boat. Oh, it's
terrible for you. I'm so sorry.
The diver made another discovery.
Broke one of the ports
and looked into the cabin.
There was a body in there.
She wasn't alone.
There was someone sailing with her,
and you have to find out who it was,
that's it, isn't it, Maxim?
You don't understand.
There was no one with her.
It's Rebecca's body lying there
on the cabin floor.
Oh, no.
The woman that was washed up
at Edgecombe,
the woman that is now buried
in the family crypt,
that was not Rebecca.
That was the body
of some unknown woman,
unclaimed, belonging nowhere.
I identified it.
But I knew it wasn't Rebecca.
It was all a lie.
I knew where Rebecca's body was,
lying on that cabin floor
on the bottom of the sea.
How did you know, Maxim?
Because I put it there.
Will you look into my eyes
and tell me that you love me now?
You see? I was right.
It's too late.
No, it's not too late.
You're not to say that.
I love you more than anything
in the world.
- Oh, please, Maxim, kiss me, please.
- No.
It's no use. It's too late.
Oh, we can't lose each other now.
We must be together always.
No secrets, no shadows.
We may only have a few days,
a few hours.
Maxim, why didn't you tell me before?
I nearly did sometimes,
but you never seemed close enough.
How could we be close when I knew
you were always thinking of Rebecca?
How could I even ask you to love me,
when I knew you loved Rebecca still?
What are you talking about?
What do you mean?
Whenever you touched me, I knew
you were comparing me with Rebecca.
Whenever you looked at me or spoke
to me or walked with me in the garden,
I knew you were thinking, "This I did
with Rebecca, and this, and this. "
Oh, it's true, isn't it?
You thought I loved Rebecca?
You thought that?
I hated her.
Oh, I was carried away by her,
enchanted by her as everyone was.
And when I was married, I was told
I was the luckiest man in the world.
She was so lovely, so accomplished,
so amusing.
"She's got the three things that really
matter in a wife, " everyone said.
"Breeding, brains and beauty. "
And I believed them. Completely.
But I never had
a moment's happiness with her.
She was incapable of love
or tenderness
or decency.
You didn't love her.
Do you remember that cliff
where you first saw me in Monte Carlo?
Well, I went there with Rebecca
on our honeymoon.
That's where I found out about her,
four days after we were married.
She stood there laughing,
her black hair blowing in the wind
and told me all about herself.
Everything.
Things I'll never tell a living soul.
I wanted to kill her.
It would have been so easy.
You remember the precipice?
I frightened you, didn't I?
You thought I was mad.
Perhaps I was. Perhaps I am mad.
It wouldn't make for sanity, would it?
Living with the devil?
"I'll make a bargain with you, "
she said.
"You'd look rather foolish
trying to divorce me now
after four days of marriage,
so I'll play the part
of a devoted wife,
mistress of your precious Manderley.
I'll make it the most famous showplace
in England, if you like,
and people will visit us and envy us,
and say we're the luckiest,
happiest couple in the country.
What a grand joke it'll be.
What a triumph. "
I should never have accepted
her dirty bargain, but I did.
I was younger then, and tremendously
conscious of the family honor.
Family honor.
She knew that I'd sacrifice everything
rather than stand up in a divorce court
and give her away, admit that
our marriage was a rotten fraud.
You despise me, don't you?
As I despise myself.
You can't understand
what my feelings were,
can you?
Of course I can, darling.
Of course I can.
Well, I kept the bargain
and so did she, apparently.
Oh, she played the game brilliantly,
but after a while,
she began to grow careless.
She took a flat in London,
and she'd stay away for days at a time.
Then she started
to bring her friends down here.
I warned her,
but she shrugged her shoulders.
"What's it got to do with you?"
She said.
She even started on Frank.
Poor, faithful Frank.
Then there was a cousin of hers,
a man named Favell.
Yes. I know him.
He came the day you went to London.
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't like to.
I thought it would
remind you of Rebecca.
Remind me?
As if I needed reminding.
Favell used to visit her here
in this cottage.
I found out about it, and I warned her
that if he came here again,
I'd shoot them both.
One night, when I found she had
come back quietly from London,
I thought that Favell was with her,
and I knew then
that I couldn't stand
this life of filth and deceit
any longer.
I decided to come down here
and have it out with both of them.
But she was alone.
She was expecting Favell,
but he hadn't come.
She was lying on the divan, a large
tray of cigarette stubs beside her.
She looked ill, queer.
Suddenly, she got up,
started to walk toward me.
"When I have a child, " she said,
"neither you nor anyone else
could ever prove it wasn't yours.
You would like to have an heir,
wouldn't you, Max,
for your precious Manderley?"
Then she started to laugh.
"How funny.
How supremely, wonderfully funny.
I'll be the perfect mother,
just as I've been the perfect wife.
No one will ever know.
It ought to give you
the thrill of your life, Max,
to watch my son grow bigger day by day
and to know that when you die,
Manderley will be his. "
She was face to face with me.
One hand in her pocket,
the other holding a cigarette.
She was smiling.
"Well, Max?
What are you going to do about it?
Aren't you going to kill me?"
I suppose I went mad for a moment.
I must have struck her.
She stood staring at me.
She looked almost triumphant.
Then she started toward me again.
Smiling.
Suddenly, she stumbled and fell.
When I looked down,
ages afterwards, it seemed,
she was lying on the floor.
She had struck her head
on a heavy piece of ship's tackle.
I remember wondering
why she was still smiling.
Then I realized she was dead.
But you didn't kill her.
It was an accident.
Who would believe me?
I lost my head.
I just knew I had to do something.
Anything.
I carried her out to the boat.
It was very dark. There was no moon.
I put her in the cabin.
When the boat seemed a safe distance
from the shore, I took a spike,
and drove it again and again
through the planking of the hull.
I had opened up the seacocks
and the water began to come in fast.
I climbed over into the dinghy
and pulled away.
I saw the boat heel over
and sink.
I pulled back into the cove.
It started raining.
- Maxim, does anyone else know of this?
- No. No one except you and me.
We must explain it.
It's got to be the body of someone
you've never seen before.
No, they're bound to know her.
Her rings, bracelets she always wore.
They'll identify her body,
then they'll remember the other woman.
The other woman buried in the crypt.
If they find out it was Rebecca,
you must simply say you made a mistake
about the other body.
That the day you went to Edgecombe,
you were ill,
you didn't know what you were doing.
Rebecca's dead. That's what
we've got to remember. Rebecca's dead.
She can't speak. She can't bear witness.
She can't harm you anymore.
We're the only two people in the world
that know, Maxim, you and I.
I'd told you once that I'd done
a selfish thing in marrying you.
You can understand now what I meant.
I've loved you, my darling.
I shall always love you,
but I've known all along
that Rebecca would win in the end.
No, no. She hasn't won.
No matter what happens now,
she hasn't won.
Hello?
Hello, Frank.
Hello, Frank. Yes.
Who? Colonel Julyan?
Yes. Tell him I'll meet him there
as soon as I possibly can.
What?
Well...
Say we could talk about that
when we're sure about the matter.
What's happened?
Colonel Julyan called.
He's the chief constable of the county.
He's been asked by the police
to go to the mortuary.
He wanted to know if I could possibly
have made a mistake
about that other body.
Well, Colonel Julyan, apparently I did
make a mistake about that other body.
The mistake was natural
under the circumstances.
- Besides, you weren't well at the time.
- That's nonsense. I was perfectly well.
Don't let it worry you, Maxim. Nobody
can blame you for making a mistake.
The pity is, you've got to go through
the same thing all over again.
What do you mean?
There'll have to be another inquest,
of course. Same formality and red tape.
Wish you could be spared the publicity
of it, but I'm afraid that's impossible.
Oh, yes, publicity.
I suppose Mrs. De Winter went below
for something and a squall hit the boat
with nobody at the helm.
I imagine that's about the solution now,
don't you think so, Crawley?
Oh, yes. Probably the door jammed,
and she couldn't get on deck again.
Yeah.
Tabb, the boat builder, will undoubtedly
come to some such conclusion.
Why, what would he know about it?
Well, he's examining the boat now.
Purely as a matter of routine, you know.
I'll be at the inquest tomorrow, Maxim,
quite unofficially, you know.
We must get together for a game
of golf when it's all over, eh?
Bye-bye.
I have the evening papers, madam.
Would you care to see them?
Oh, no thank you, Frith,
and I prefer that Mr. De Winter
weren't troubled with them, either.
I understand, madam. Permit me to say
that we're all most distressed outside.
Thank you, Frith.
I'm afraid the news has been
a great shock to Mrs. Danvers.
Yes, I rather expected it would be.
It seems there's to be
a coroner's inquest, madam?
Yes, Frith. It's purely a formality.
Of course, madam. I...
I wanted to say that if any of us
might be required to give evidence,
I should be only too pleased to do
anything that might help the family.
Oh, thank you, Frith, why, I...
I'm sure Mr. De Winter
will be very happy to hear it.
But I don't think
anything will be necessary.
Maxim.
Hello, darling.
Oh, Maxim, I'm worried about
what you'll do at the inquest tomorrow.
What do you mean?
You won't lose your temper, will you?
Promise me
that they won't make you angry.
All right, darling. I promise.
No matter what he asks you,
you won't lose your head?
Don't worry, dear.
They can't do anything at once,
can they?
No.
Then we've a little time left
to be together.
Yes.
- I want to go to the inquest with you.
- I'd rather you didn't, darling.
But I can't wait here alone.
I promise you,
I won't be any trouble to you.
And I must be near you
so that no matter what happens,
we won't be separated for a moment.
All right, dear.
I don't mind this whole thing
except for you.
I can't forget what it's done to you.
I've been thinking of nothing else
since it happened.
It's gone forever,
that funny, young, lost look I loved.
It won't ever come back.
I killed that
when I told you about Rebecca.
It's gone.
In a few hours,
you've grown so much older.
Oh, Maxim, Maxim.
Black Jack Brady was his name.
The most important arrest I ever made.
It must have been
about two years ago now.
Of course, there was no doubt about it.
He was hung a month after I caught him.
Hello. Wait a minute.
They've got old Balmy Ben up now.
You remember
the late Mrs. De Winter, don't you?
- She's gone.
- Yes, we know that.
- She went in the sea. The sea got her.
- That's right. That's right.
Now we want you to tell us
whether you were on the shore
- that last night she went sailing.
- Eh?
Were you on the shore that last night
she went out, when she didn't come back?
I didn't see nothing.
I don't want to go to the asylum.
Them cruel folks there.
Now, nobody's going to send you
to the asylum.
All we want you to do
is tell us what you saw.
I didn't see nothing.
Come, come.
Did you see Mrs. De Winter
get into her boat that last night?
I don't know nothing.
I don't want to go to the asylum.
Very well. You may go.
- Eh?
- You may go now.
- Mr. Tabb, step forward, please.
- Yes?
The evidence you give
will be the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
I do, so help me God.
The late Mrs. De Winter
used to send her boat
- to your shipyard for reconditioning.
- That's right, sir.
Can you remember any occasion
when she had any sort of accident
with the boat?
No, sir. I often said
Mrs. De Winter was a born sailor.
Now, when Mrs. De Winter
went below, as is supposed,
and a sudden gust of wind came down,
that would be enough to capsize
the boat, wouldn't it?
Excuse me, sir. But there's
a little more to it than that.
- What do you mean, Mr. Tabb?
- I mean, sir, the seacocks.
What are the seacocks?
Sea...
The seacocks are the valves
to drain out the boat.
They're always kept tight closed
when you're afloat.
Yes?
Well, yesterday, when I examined
that boat, I found they'd been opened.
What could be the reason for that?
Just this, that's what flooded the boat
and sunk her.
Are you implying
that boat never capsized at all?
I know it's a terrible thing to say,
sir, but in my opinion,
she was scuttled.
- And there's them holes.
- What holes?
- In her planking.
- What are you talking about?
Of course, that boat's been underwater
for over a year,
and the tide's been knocking her
against the ridge.
But it seemed to me them holes looked
as if she'd made them from the inside.
Then you believe
she must have done it deliberately.
Couldn't have been no accident,
not with her knowledge of boats.
You knew the former Mrs. De Winter
very well, I believe?
Oh, yes.
Would you have believed her
capable of suicide?
No. Frankly, I would not.
But you never can tell.
You may stand down, Mr. Tabb.
Mr. De Winter, please.
Sorry to drag you back
for further questioning, Mr. De Winter.
But you've heard
the statement of Mr. Tabb.
I wonder if you can help us in any way.
I'm afraid not.
Can you think of any reason
why there should be holes
in the planking
of the late Mrs. De Winter's boat?
Well, of course
I can't think of any reason.
Has anyone ever discussed
these holes with you before?
Well, since the boat has been
at the bottom of the ocean,
I scarcely think that likely.
Mr. De Winter, I want you
to believe we all feel very deeply
for you in this matter.
But you must remember
that I don't conduct this inquiry
for my own amusement.
- That's rather obvious, isn't it?
- I hope that it is.
Well, since she went sailing alone,
are we to believe
that she drove those holes herself?
You may believe what you like.
Can you enlighten us as to
why Mrs. De Winter should have wanted
to end her own life?
I know of no reason whatever.
Mr. De Winter,
however painful it may be,
I have to ask you
a very personal question.
Were relations between you and the late
Mrs. De Winter perfectly happy?
I won't stand this any longer!
You might as well know now...
We'll adjourn till after lunch.
Mr. De Winter, I presume
you'll be available for us then?
I told you,
you should have had some breakfast.
You're hungry.
That's what's the matter with you.
Mr. Frith thought you might
like to have some lunch from the house,
and sent me with it.
No, that's fine.
Pull around the corner.
Very good, sir.
Awfully foolish of me,
fainting like that.
Nonsense. If you hadn't fainted like
that, I'd have really lost my temper.
Darling, please be careful.
Darling, wait here a few moments.
I'll see if I can find old Frank.
Of course, darling.
Don't worry about me. I'll be all right.
Sure?
Here, try a spot of this. Do you good.
Thank you.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, of course.
- I won't be long.
- Right you are.
Hello.
And how does the bride
find herself today?
I say, marriage with Max
is not exactly a bed of roses, is it?
I think you'd better go
before Maxim gets back.
Oh, jealous, is he?
Well, I can't say I blame him.
But you don't think I'm
the big bad wolf, do you?
I'm not, you know. I'm a perfectly
ordinary, harmless bloke.
And I think you're behaving splendidly
over all this. Perfectly splendidly.
You know, you've grown up a bit
since I last saw you. It's no wonder...
What do you want, Favell?
Oh, hello, Max. Things are going
pretty well for you, aren't they?
Better than you ever expected.
I was rather worried about you at first.
That's why I came down to the inquest.
Well, I'm touched by your solicitude.
But if you don't mind,
we'd rather like to have our lunch.
Lunch? I say, what a jolly idea.
Rather like a picnic, isn't it?
I'm so sorry.
Do you mind if I put this there?
You know, Max, old boy, I really think
I ought to talk things over with you.
Talk what things over?
Well, those holes in the planking,
for one thing.
Those holes
that were drilled from the inside.
- Oh, Mullen?
- Yes, sir?
Would you, like a good fellow,
have my car filled with petrol?
- It's almost empty.
- Very good, sir.
- And, Mullen, close the door, will you?
- Yes, sir.
Does this bother you?
You know, old boy, I have a strong
feeling that before the day's out,
somebody's going to make use
of that rather expressive,
though somewhat old-fashioned term,
"foul play. "
Am I boring you with all this?
No?
Good. Well, you see, Max, I find
myself in a rather awkward position.
You've only got to read this note
to understand. It's from Rebecca.
And, what's more, she had the foresight
to put a date on it.
She wrote me the day she died.
Incidentally, I was at a party
on that night
so I didn't get it until the next day.
And what makes you think
that note would interest me?
Oh, I'm not gonna bother you
with the contents now.
But I can assure you
that it is not the note of a woman
who intends to drown herself
that same night.
By the way, what do you do
with old bones? Bury them?
However, for the time being...
You know, Max, I'm getting fed up
with my job as a motorcar salesman.
I don't know if you've
ever experienced the feeling
of driving an expensive motorcar
which isn't your own?
But it can be very, very exasperating.
You know what I mean.
You want to own the car yourself.
I often wonder what it would be like
to retire to the country.
Have a nice little place
with a few acres of shooting.
I've never figured out
what it would cost a year,
but I'd like to talk about it with you.
I'd like to have your advice on how
to live comfortably without hard work.
Hello, Favell.
You looking for me, Maxim?
Yes.
Mr. Favell and I have a little
business transaction on hand.
I think we had better conduct it
over at the inn.
They may have a private room there.
Well, see you later.
Find Colonel Julyan.
Tell him I want to see him immediately.
Come on, Favell. Let's go.
- Have you a private room, please?
- Of course, sir. Through there, sir.
Hope this will do, Mr. De Winter.
Splendid. Splendid.
Exactly like the Ritz.
Any orders, gents?
Yes. You might bring me
a large brandy and soda.
How about you, Max? Have one on me.
I feel I can afford to play host.
Thanks. I don't mind if I do.
Make it two, will you,
like a good fellow?
- Very good, sir.
Where's Mr. De Winter?
Through the other door, sir.
Colonel Julyan, this is Mr. Favell.
Oh, I know Colonel Julyan.
We're old friends, aren't we?
Since you're old friends,
I assume you also know
he's head of the police here.
He might be interested to hear your
proposition. Tell him all about it.
I don't know what you mean. I merely
said I hoped to give up selling cars
and retire into the country.
Actually, he offered to withhold a vital
piece of evidence from the inquest
if I made it worth his while.
I only want to see justice done,
Colonel.
Now, that boat builder's evidence
suggested certain possible theories
concerning Rebecca's death.
One of them, of course, is suicide.
Now I have a little note here
which I consider
puts that possibility
quite out of court.
Read it, Colonel.
"Jack, darling,
I've just seen the doctor and I'm going
down to Manderley right away.
I shall be at the cottage
all this evening
and shall leave
the door open for you.
I have something terribly
important to tell you.
Rebecca. "
Now, does that look
like the note of a woman
who had made up her mind
to kill herself?
And apart from that,
do you mean to tell me
that if you wanted to commit suicide,
you would go to all the trouble
of putting out to sea in a boat,
and then take a hammer and chisel
and laboriously knock holes
through the bottom of it?
Come, Colonel. As an officer of the law,
don't you feel there are some
slight grounds for suspicion?
- Of murder?
- What else?
You've known Max a long time. So
you know he's the old-fashioned type,
who'd die to defend his honor,
or who'd kill for it.
It's blackmail, pure and simple.
Blackmail is not so pure, nor so simple.
It can bring a lot of trouble
to a great many people.
And the blackmailer sometimes
finds himself in jail at the end of it.
Oh, I see. You're going to hold
de Winter's hand through all this.
Just because
he's the big noise around here
and he's actually permitted you
to dine with him.
Be careful, Favell.
You've brought an accusation of murder.
- Have you any witnesses?
- I do have a witness.
It's that fellow, Ben.
If that stupid coroner hadn't been
as much of a snob as you are,
he'd have seen
that half-wit was hiding something.
And why should Ben do that?
Because we caught him once,
Rebecca and I,
peering at us through
the cottage window.
Rebecca threatened him with the asylum.
That's why he was afraid to speak.
But he was always hanging about.
He must have seen this whole thing.
It's ridiculous,
even listening to all this.
You're like a little trade union,
all of you, aren't you?
And if my guess is right, Crawley,
there's a bit of malice in your soul
toward me, isn't there?
Crawley didn't have
much success with Rebecca,
but he ought to have
more luck this time.
And the bride will be grateful
for your fraternal arm, Crawley,
in a week or so.
Every time she faints, in fact.
- De Winter!
- Maxim, please!
That temper of yours
will do you in yet, Max.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
- Now is there anything else?
- Yes.
You might bring
Mr. De Winter a sedative.
- No, no. Nothing at all. Just leave us.
- Very good.
Now, Favell,
let's get this business over.
https://t.me/RickyChannel
As you seem to have worked out
the whole thing so carefully,
perhaps you can provide us
also with a motive.
I knew you were going
to bring that up, Colonel.
I've read enough detective stories to
know that there must always be a motive.
And if you'll all excuse me,
I might supply that, too.
I wish you'd go home. You ought
not to be here through all this.
Please let me stay, Maxim.
Surely, Colonel Julyan, you're
not going to allow this fellow to...
My opinion of Favell
is no higher than yours, Crawley.
But in my official capacity,
I have no alternative
but to pursue his accusations.
I entirely agree with you, Colonel.
In matters as serious as this,
we must make sure of every point
and explore every avenue.
And in fact, if I may coin a phrase,
leave no stone unturned.
Here she is, the missing link, the
witness who will help supply the motive.
Colonel Julyan, Mrs. Danvers.
I believe you know everyone else.
Won't you sit down?
No offense, Colonel,
but I think I'll put this to Danny.
She'll understand it more easily.
Danny, who was Rebecca's doctor?
Mrs. De Winter always had Dr. McClean
from the village.
Now, you heard.
I said Rebecca's doctor in London.
I don't know anything about that.
Oh, don't give me that, Danny.
You knew everything about Rebecca.
You knew she was in love with me,
didn't you?
Surely you haven't forgotten
the good times she and I used to have
down at the cottage on the beach.
She had a right to amuse herself,
didn't she?
Love was a game to her. Only a game.
It made her laugh, I tell you.
She used to sit and rock with laughter
at the lot of you.
Can you think of why Mrs. De Winter
should have taken her own life?
No, no. I refuse to believe it.
I knew everything about her
and I won't believe it.
There. You see? It's impossible.
She knows that as well as I do.
Now, listen to me, Danny.
We know that Rebecca went
to a doctor in London
on the last day of her life. Who was it?
I don't know.
I understand, Danny.
You think we're asking you
to reveal secrets of Rebecca's life.
You're trying to defend her.
But that's what I'm doing.
I'm trying to clear her name
of the suspicion of suicide.
Mrs. Danvers, it has been suggested
that Mrs. De Winter
was deliberately murdered.
There you have it in a nutshell, Danny.
But there's one more thing you'll want
to know, the name of the murderer.
It's a lovely name
that rolls off the tongue so easily.
George Fortescue Maximilian de Winter.
There was a doctor.
Mrs. De Winter sometimes
went to him privately.
She used to go to him
even before she was married.
We don't want reminiscences, Danny.
What was his name?
Dr. Baker.
165 Goldhawk Road, Shepherd's Bush.
There you are, Colonel.
There's where you'll find your motive.
Go and question Dr. Baker.
He'll tell you why Rebecca went to him.
To confirm the fact
that she was going to have a child.
A sweet, curly-headed little child.
It isn't true. It isn't true.
She would have told me.
She told Max about it.
Max knew he wasn't the father.
So, like the gentleman of the old school
that he is, he killed her.
I'm afraid we shall
have to question this Dr. Baker.
Hear, hear. But for safety's sake,
I think I'd like to go along, too.
Yes. Unfortunately, I suppose
you have the right to ask that.
I'll see the coroner
and have the inquest postponed
pending further evidence.
I say, aren't you rather afraid that
the prisoner, shall we say, might bolt?
You have my word for it
that he will not do that.
Toodle-oo, Max. Come along, Danny.
Let's leave the unhappy couple to spend
their last moments together alone.
Are you sure you don't want me
to go with you, Max?
No, darling.
It'll be very tiring for you.
I'll be back the very first
thing in the morning.
- And I won't even stop to sleep.
- I'll be waiting for you.
- Ready, Maxim?
- Yes.
You two go on ahead.
I'll follow with Favell.
Dr. Baker, you may have seen
Mr. De Winter's name
in the papers recently.
Yes. Yes. In connection
with the body that was found in a boat.
My wife was reading all about it.
A very sad case. My condolences.
This is going to take hours.
Let me...
Don't bother, Favell.
I think I can tell Dr. Baker.
We're trying to discover certain facts
concerning the late Mrs. De Winter's
activities on the day of her death.
October the 12th, last year.
I want you to tell me if you can,
if anyone of that name
paid you a visit on that date?
I'm awfully sorry.
I'm afraid I can't help you.
I should have remembered
the name de Winter.
I've never attended
a Mrs. De Winter in my life.
How can you possibly tell
all your patients' names?
I can look it up in my engagement diary
if you like.
- Did you say the 12th of October?
Yes.
Here we are.
No. No de Winter.
Are you sure?
Well, here are all the appointments
for that day.
Ross, Campbell, Steadall,
Perrino, Danvers...
- Danny? What the devil?
- Would you read that name again?
Did you say Danvers?
Yes. I have a Mrs. Danvers for 3:00.
What did she look like?
Can you remember?
Yes, I remember her quite well.
She was a very beautiful woman.
- Tall, dark, exquisitely dressed.
Rebecca.
The lady must have used
an assumed name.
Is that so?
This is a surprise.
I've known her a long time.
What was the matter with her?
Well, there are certain ethics.
Could you supply a reason, Dr. Baker,
for Mrs. De Winter's suicide?
For her murder, you mean?
She was going to have a kid, wasn't she?
Come on. Out with it!
Tell me, what else would a woman of
her class be doing in a dump like this?
I take it the official nature of this
visit makes it necessary for me to...
I assure you we'd not be troubling you
if it were not necessary.
You want to know
if I can suggest any motive
as to why Mrs. De Winter
should have taken her life?
Yes, I think I can.
The woman who called herself
Mrs. Danvers was very seriously ill.
She was not going to have a child?
That was what she thought.
My diagnosis was different.
I sent her to a well-known specialist
for an examination and x-rays.
And on this date,
she returned to me for his report.
I remember her standing here
holding out her hand for the photograph.
"I want to know the truth, " she said.
"I don't want soft words
and a bedside manner.
If I'm for it,
you can tell me right away. "
I knew she was not the type
to accept a lie.
She'd asked for the truth,
so I let her have it.
She thanked me.
I never saw her again, so I assumed...
- What was wrong with her?
- Cancer.
Yes, the growth was deep-rooted.
An operation would have been
no earthly use at all.
In a short time,
she would have been under morphia.
There was nothing that could be done
for her, except wait.
Did she say anything
when you told her?
She smiled
in a queer sort of way.
Your wife was a wonderful woman,
Mr. De Winter.
And, oh, yes, I remember
she said something
that struck me
as being very peculiar at the time.
When I told her it was
a matter of months, she said,
"Oh, no, Doctor, not that long. "
You've been very kind.
You've told us all we wanted to know.
We shall need
an official verification.
- Verification?
- Yes.
- To confirm the verdict of suicide.
I understand.
Can I offer you gentlemen
a glass of sherry?
No, that's very kind.
I think we ought to be going.
Thank heaven we know the truth.
Dreadful thing. Dreadful.
Young and lovely woman like that.
No wonder...
I never had the remotest idea.
Neither did Danny, I'm sure.
I wish I had a drink.
Will we be needed at the inquest
any further, Colonel Julyan?
No, no. I can see to it
that Maxim's not troubled any further.
- Thank you, sir.
- You ready to start, Colonel?
No, thank you.
I'm staying in town tonight.
And let me tell you, Favell,
blackmail is not much of a profession.
And we know how to deal with it
in our part of the world,
strange as it may seem to you.
I'm sure I don't know
what you're talking about.
But if you ever need a new car, Colonel,
just let me know.
It's impossible to thank you for
your kindness to us through all this.
You know what I feel
without my saying it.
Not at all.
Put the whole thing behind you.
But let your wife know.
She'll be getting worried.
Yes, of course.
I'll phone her at once
and we'll get straight down
to Manderley.
Goodbye, Crawley.
Maxim's got a great friend.
- Frank.
- Yes, Maxim?
- There's something you don't know.
- Oh, no, there isn't.
I didn't kill her, Frank.
But I know now that when
she told me about the child,
she wanted me to kill her.
She lied on purpose.
She foresaw the whole thing.
That's why she stood there laughing
when she...
Don't think about it anymore.
Thank you, Frank.
Hello, Danny.
I just wanted to tell you the news.
Rebecca held out on both of us.
She had cancer.
Yes, suicide.
Now Max and that
dear little bride of his
will be able to stay on at Manderley
and live happily ever after.
Bye-bye, Danny.
- This your car, sir?
- Yes.
Will you be going soon?
This isn't a parking place, you know.
Oh, isn't it? Well, people are entitled
to leave cars outside if they want to.
It's a pity some of you fellows
haven't anything better to do.
When you phoned,
did she say she'd wait up?
I asked her to go to bed,
but she wouldn't hear of it.
I wish I could get some more speed
out of this thing.
Is something worrying you, Maxim?
I can't get over the feeling
something's wrong.
https://t.me/RickyChannel
- Frank.
- What's the matter? Why did we stop?
What's the time?
Well, this clock's wrong.
It must be 3:00 or 4:00. Why?
That can't be
the dawn breaking over there.
It's in the winter that you see
the northern lights, isn't it?
That's not the northern lights.
That's Manderley.
Frith! Frith!
Mrs. De Winter. Where is she?
- I thought I saw her, sir.
- Where?
Maxim!
Thank heavens you've come back to me!
- Are you all right, darling?
- Oh, yes, I am.
Are you all right?
Mrs. Danvers, she's gone mad.
She said she'd rather destroy Manderley
than see us happy here.
Look! The west wing!