Open it.
Don't.
We've got to see if
there's anything...
I know.
But not just yet.
Let's stay this way
for a minute.
Phillip, we don't have
too much time.
It's the darkness
that's got you down.
Nobody ever feels
really safe in the dark.
Nobody who was ever
a child, that is.
I'll open these,
all right?
There, that's much better.
What a lovely evening.
Pity we couldn't
have done it with
the curtains open
in the bright sunlight.
Well... Can't have
everything, can we?
We did do it in daytime.
All right now, Phillip?
Yes.
Good. You better
put those away.
Put them in
my checkbook drawer,
behind that metal box.
Now... This is
a museum piece now.
We really should
preserve it for posterity,
except it's such good
crystal, and I'd hate
to break up the set.
Out of this,
David Kentley had
his last drink.
It should have been
ginger ale or even beer.
I've always thought
it was out of character
for David to drink anything
as corrupt as whiskey.
Out of character for
him to be murdered, too.
Yes, wasn't it?
But good Americans usually
die young on
the battlefield,
don't they?
Well, the Davids
of this world
merely occupy space,
which is why he was
the perfect victim
for the perfect murder.
Course, he was
a Harvard undergraduate.
That might
make it justifiable homicide.
He's dead
and we've killed him.
But he's still here.
In less than eight hours,
he'll be resting
gently but firmly at
the bottom of a lake.
Meanwhile, he's here.
What are you doing?
It's not locked.
All the better.
It's much more dangerous.
Anyway,
the lock's too old,
it won't work.
I wish it would.
I wish we had him
out of here.
I wish it were
somebody else.
It's a trifle late for that,
don't you think?
Whom would you have
preferred? Kenneth?
Oh, I don't know. I suppose
anyone was as good
or as bad as any other.
You, perhaps.
You frighten me.
You always have,
from that very first
day in prep school.
Part of your charm,
I suppose.
I'm only kidding, Brandon.
I obviously can't
take it as well as you,
so I'm turning on you
a little.
That's rather foolish,
isn't it?
Yes, very.
May I have a drink now?
By all means.
This is an occasion.
It calls for champagne.
Champagne?
I put some in the icebox.
When did you put
it there, Brandon?
Just before David arrived.
You were certain
it would come off,
weren't you?
Of course.
You know I'd never
do anything unless
I did it perfectly.
I've always wished for
more artistic talent.
Well, murder
can be an art, too.
The power to kill
can be just as satisfying
as the power to create.
Phillip, do you realize
we've actually done it,
exactly as we planned?
And not a single
infinitesimal thing
has gone wrong.
It was perfect.
Yes.
An immaculate murder.
We've killed for
the sake of danger and
for the sake of killing.
We're alive, truly
and wonderfully alive.
Even champagne
isn't equal to us,
or the occasion.
I'll take it, though.
You're not really
frightened anymore,
are you, Phillip?
You can't have fear,
you know?
Neither of us can.
That's the difference
between us and
the ordinary men, Phillip.
They talk about
committing the perfect crime,
but nobody does it.
Nobody commits
a murder just for the...
Here.
...experiment
of committing it.
Nobody except us.
You're not frightened
anymore, are you,
Phillip?
No.
Not even of me?
That's good.
You just astound me,
as always.
That's even better.
To David, of course.
Brandon, how did you feel?
When?
During it.
I don't know, really.
I don't remember feeling
very much of anything.
Until his body went limp,
and I knew it was over.
And then?
Then I felt
tremendously exhilarated.
How did you feel?
I...
Brandon, you don't
think the party's
a mistake, do you?
No, the party's
the inspired finishing
touch to our work.
It's more,
it's the signature
of the artist.
Not having it
would be like...
Painting a picture
and not hanging it?
I don't think that's a very
good choice of words.
It may turn out to be
a little too choice,
thanks to the party.
Oh, rot. This party
will be the most
exciting ever given.
With these people?
They're a dull crew,
all right.
The Kentleys
couldn't be duller
if they tried,
but we did have
to have them.
After all, they are
David's mother and father.
That doesn't make them
any easier to talk to.
Don't worry.
Janet'll be buttering
them up, poor girl.
She's banked everything
on hooking David.
Somehow, I don't think
she's going to succeed.
Do you?
No, somehow, I don't.
Well, she can switch back
to Kenneth tonight.
You must admit,
it was most
considerate of me,
in view of
recent events, to...
Phillip.
What?
Take the other one.
What for?
Never mind. Come with me.
What's this all about?
You'll see. It's brilliant!
What the devil
are you doing?
Making our work of art
a masterpiece.
Brandon, you're
going too far.
Why? What do you mean?
I just thought
it'd be nice to
have supper in here.
On this.
Isn't it a good idea?
Well, at least this way,
no one will try to open it.
I don't think you
appreciate me, Phillip.
I'm beginning to, Brandon.
Well, come on,
we don't have
too much time.
Mrs. Wilson will
be coming back soon.
Did you forget
to borrow her key?
I might've known
better than to...
I didn't forget.
I have her key.
I told her I lost mine.
Oh, good.
How are you going to
explain this to her?
I'm not.
We've got to
have some excuse.
We don't want to leave
our guest of honor
alone during supper.
Brandon, we've got
to have an excuse
for the others.
All right, all right.
Let me think.
Really, you get
much too upset
much too easily, Phillip.
We have
a very simple excuse
right here.
What are you
worrying about, Phillip?
After all, old Mr. Kentley's
coming mainly to
look at these books.
Now what could be
better than to have them
laid out neatly on
the dining room table
where the poor, old man
can easily get at them?
Considerate, aren't we?
Most...
Hello? Oh. Of course.
You start on the books...
Who is it?
Mrs. Wilson.
Brandon.
Brandon!
What the devil?
Don't you have any
more sense than to...
What is it?
Well, go on, yank it out.
I can't.
If Mrs. Wilson were here,
she'd yank it out for you.
A stupid display like that
in front of somebody else
will be just as
good as a confession.
Now, take these
and get a hold of yourself.
If you'd let me keep
the light on before
as I'd wanted,
I would have seen it.
All right! You're perfect.
We have to be, Phillip.
We agreed there was
only one crime either
of us could commit.
The crime of
making a mistake.
Being weak is a mistake.
Because it's being human?
Because it's being ordinary.
I won't let
either of us stoop...
You owe me $2.40 for taxis,
including the tip.
If it weren't for
the traffic, I'd have
been here a half hour ago.
Oh, it's just as well.
We didn't expect
you back until now.
Well,
I went to five stores for
the special pâté we like.
But the prices!
I couldn't see any reason
for throwing away
our good money.
So I went downtown
to that little delicatessen
where Mr. Cadell goes.
But I tell you, the next
time we give a party,
I'm only going...
Good evening, Mrs. Wilson.
What, may I ask,
is happening to my table?
We're just moving
the things in here.
Well...
I personally thought
my table was quite lovely.
Oh, it was quite lovely.
But you see,
Mr. Kentley's coming
to look at these old books
I had in the chest.
And I'm sure
you wouldn't want
the poor, old man
to have to get
down on his knees
to see them.
Well, I think
it looks
downright peculiar.
Peculiar?
Very. Particularly
those candlesticks.
They don't
belong there at all.
On the contrary,
I think they suggest
a ceremonial altar,
which you can heap
with the foods for
our sacrificial feast.
Heap is right.
Certainly isn't
enough room
for me to set
things out properly.
Is there, Mr. Phillip?
Oh, you can make it do.
You two will be the death of me.
What's to be done
with the books?
We'll lay them out on
the dining room table.
A crazy idea,
if you ask me.
Well, I have too much
to do to discuss this
thoroughly, dear.
However, I still
think it's peculiar.
What on Earth's the matter?
I was sure she'd notice.
Notice what?
The rope, of course.
Brandon, we've
got to hide it.
Why?
Yes, why?
It's only
a piece of rope, Phillip.
An ordinary household
article. Why hide it?
It belongs in
the kitchen drawer.
Uh, Mrs. Wilson?
Yes?
There's champagne
in the icebox.
Oh, we're not giving
them champagne?
We are.
Oh, well, it's going to
be that kind of party.
I'd better doll up a little.
We only serve champagne
at Mr. Cadell's
on very high occasions.
Matter of fact,
he and I once had
a glass together
on my birthday.
Tonight, Mrs. Wilson,
you'll have an opportunity
to renew that romance.
May I?
Mr. Cadell's coming.
Oh, my. Oh, Mr. Cadell's
terribly nice.
Rupert's coming?
Yes, I thought I told you.
Oh, I must say
I did enjoy working
for Mr. Cadell.
No, you didn't.
Such a gentleman!
Of course some people say
he's a little peculiar,
but I always...
Well, you might
let me finish.
I thought
you liked Rupert.
I do.
Well, then.
Brandon, of all
the people on this Earth,
Rupert Cadell is
the one man most
likely to suspect.
He's the one man
who might appreciate this
from our angle,
the artistic one.
That's what's exciting.
I'm glad it excites you.
It frightens me.
I know...
I suggest you keep
your voice down.
It would have been too
easy with the others,
Phillip, and too dull.
As for Rupert,
I once thought of
inviting him to join us.
Why didn't you?
The more the merrier.
Because he hasn't the nerve.
Oh, intellectually,
he could've come along.
He's brilliant.
But he's
a little too fastidious.
He could've invented
and he could've admired,
but he never
could have acted.
That's where
we're superior, Phillip.
We have courage,
Rupert doesn't.
Mr. Cadell got
a bad leg in the war
for his courage.
And you've got your sleeve
in the celery, Mr. Phillip.
Oh, they're here.
Are we ready?
As ready as we'll ever be.
Now mind you.
Don't you be so busy
at that piano
that you don't eat anything,
getting too thin.
And don't you
let them gobble up
all that pâté
before you have any.
Let's hope it's a success.
Oh, mind my tray.
Take it in the kitchen,
Mrs. Wilson.
I'll answer the door.
There wouldn't be
this last minute
hustle-bustle
if you'd kept my table
and let those old books...
Now the fun begins.
Hello, come in.
How are you, Brandon?
Fine. Just put
your hat there.
Thank you.
It's been quite a while,
hasn't it?
Yes, that's why I sounded
so stupid on the phone.
Surprised, I guess.
Hello, Kenneth.
Good to see you.
You, too.
Been up to much lately?
Nothing to speak of.
You?
Oh, just trying to
get ready for exams.
I always have
to start cramming
before everybody else.
Am I the first?
You are.
Why is it I'm always
too early at parties?
Probably because
you're always on time.
Uh, Mrs. Wilson, champagne.
Oh...
It isn't someone's
birthday, is it?
Don't look so worried,
Kenneth.
It's really
almost the opposite.
The opposite?
Phillip's bidding
the world a temporary
farewell tonight.
I'm driving him
up to Connecticut
after the party.
Oh. Where are you going?
Just to
Brandon's mother's place
for a few weeks.
I'm to be locked up.
What?
To make sure
he practices
six hours a day.
I've finally
wangled a debut for him.
Town Hall, at that.
That's wonderful.
I hope you knock 'em dead.
Thank you.
Mmm! Most decorative.
Think so?
Hey.
What is it?
I feel pretty honored.
Oh? Why?
Looks like a pretty
small farewell party.
Oh, well, we're really
killing two birds
with one stone.
The party's also
for Mr. Kentley.
David's father?
Yes.
Oh...
Is David going
to be here?
Of course.
Who else is coming?
Oh, no one you don't
know, if that's
what's bothering you.
The Kentleys,
Janet Walker...
Janet?
Yes. I thought you'd
be glad to see her.
Won't you be?
Brandon, Janet and I
are all washed up.
Didn't you know?
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't.
Well, you knew, Phillip.
Oh, I heard vague rumors,
but I never pay attention
to that sort of thing.
I wish you had.
Why?
Well, Janet and David are...
Hello, Mrs. Wilson.
May I?
Help yourself.
And cheer up.
I have the oddest
feeling, anyway,
that your chances
with the young lady
are much better
than you think.
What do you mean?
Janet!
Hello, ducks. Angel!
Be careful of my hair,
it took hours.
You smell dreamy.
What is it?
That swill you gave me
last Christmas.
I always knew
I had good taste.
You do. You look lovely.
I won't by the time
it's all paid for.
Was that funny?
I never know when
I'm being funny.
Whenever I try to be,
I lay the bomb of all time.
Phillip, sweet.
Hello.
What's this rumor I hear
about you and Town Hall?
I bet you're going to
play a foul trick on
all of us and become...
...horribly famous.
I believe you've met.
Hello, Ken.
Hello, Jan.
Well, that was fascinating,
wasn't it?
I seem to have run down.
What would you say
to some champagne?
"Hello, champagne."
You see what I mean
about trying to be funny?
How've you been, Ken?
Fine, thanks.
How's the new job?
What are you doing?
Writing that
same dreary column
on how to keep
the body beautiful.
For whom this time?
Oh, an untidy little
magazine known as Allure.
Thanks, chum.
Oh, isn't that painting new?
Yes, it is.
Do you like it?
Well, what is it?
A new, young,
American primitive.
I have a new, young,
American sister.
She's only three
and her stuff is
really primitive.
You dirty dog.
Why?
Didn't I notice
another new one in
the foyer when I came in?
I don't think so. Which?
Anyone else coming
besides Mr. Kentley?
Yes, another old friend of yours.
This.
Even older.
Who?
I could really
strangle you, Brandon.
What have I done now?
At times, your sense
of humor is a little
too malicious, chum.
What are you
chattering about?
Why did you invite Kenneth?
Why not?
You know perfectly well
why not.
We called it quits
ages ago
and I'm practically
engaged to his best friend.
David?
Yes, David.
Which makes everything
just ginger-peachy.
I'm terribly sorry,
but it is
a little difficult
trying to keep up
with your romances.
After me came Kenneth,
now it's David.
Why the switch from Kenneth
to David, anyway?
Obviously,
I think he's nicer.
Well, he's certainly richer.
That's a new low,
even for you, chum.
Gave me a "D" in conduct.
How's your drink doing?
All right.
How many years has
it been since I said,
"Oh, it tickles"?
And don't you tell me.
I hear Rupert's coming.
Well, he was invited,
but you never
know with Rupert.
I hope he does come.
How is he?
Who is he?
Rupert Cadell,
he was our housemaster
at prep school.
Housemaster for you
three little dears?
Four little dears.
He tried valiantly
to teach David, too.
Rupert's a publisher
now, isn't he?
Successful?
Maybe he can
give me a job.
Rupert only publishes
books he likes,
usually philosophy.
Oh. Small print,
big words, no sales.
Right.
Rupert's extremely radical.
Do you know that he selects
his books on the assumption
that people not only can read,
but actually can think?
Curious fellow,
but I like him.
You always did.
Golly, those bull sessions
you and Rupert used
to have at school.
Brandon would sit
up till all hours
at the master's feet.
Brandon at someone's feet!
Who is this Rupert?
He used to tell you
the weirdest things,
didn't he?
Really?
What sort of things?
I suppose Kenneth means
Rupert's impatience
with social conventions.
For example, he thinks
murder is a crime
for most men, but...
A privilege
for the few.
Yes.
A privilege for what few?
It's all right, Mrs. Wilson.
I'll answer the door.
Oh, Mr. Kentley.
So glad you could come.
Thank you, Brandon.
Mrs. Kentley isn't well,
so I took the liberty
of bringing my sister-in-law,
Mrs. Atwater.
She's been staying with us.
Oh, delighted to
have you, Mrs. Atwater.
Delighted to come,
dear boy.
I've been in
New York two weeks.
Alice has been ill
almost the whole time,
and Henry is forever
cataloging his library.
Oh, no, Anita.
Occasionally, I even
read one of my books.
But I'm on a visit, Henry.
This is just my second party.
I suppose
it's only fair...
Let me take your things.
Thank you.
I'm sorry to hear
Mrs. Kentley's so ill.
Oh, it's just a cold.
Oh, colds can be
very dangerous
this time of the year.
I hope Mrs. Kentley's
staying in bed with
lots of fruit juice.
She is, thank you.
Well, that'll do the trick.
Colds dangerous,
in this heat? I don't
understand that at all.
Exactly two years
ago this summer,
I had one myself.
I was down for three weeks.
The doctors were
just about ready...
Excuse me.
This way, Mrs. Atwater.
...particularly at parties.
Particularly at this party.
This is all
way over my head.
David!
Oh, no.
You've made a mistake.
This is Kenneth Lawrence.
I'm so sorry.
That's all right, Anita. Kenneth is often
mistaken for David,
even by people
who aren't nearsighted.
We haven't had
much opportunity
to observe the resemblance
lately, my boy.
Haven't been studying,
have you?
I've been
trying to, sir.
Oh, dear.
The resemblance
is only physical.
I believe you both
know Ms. Walker.
Janet, my dear.
I finished working
out your horoscope
just before we came.
Oh, tell.
The stars are very kind.
They indicate
a marriage very soon
to a tall,
fair-haired young man
with a very lovely father.
Oh, come, Anita,
I told you that
a week ago.
Oh, well,
I suppose you did.
But the stars confirm it.
Wonderful.
Uh, Mrs. Atwater,
may I present
Mr. Phillip Morgan?
How do you do?
Oh, you've hurt your hand.
Oh, it's nothing,
just a little cut.
What happened?
Nothing. The glass was
cracked and it broke,
that's all.
May I get you some
champagne, Mrs. Atwater?
Oh, I should adore some.
Daddy used to have a glass
every morning at 11:00.
But, of course,
Henry doesn't like it.
Mr. Kentley,
may I get you some?
Well, I'd prefer
a little scotch
with a lot of water
if you don't mind.
Is David here?
I expected him
to come with you.
He called and said
that he'd meet us here.
Where did he call from?
Oh, our maid spoke to him.
He was at the club,
studying for
his examinations.
Tennis.
The trouble with David is
he doesn't have to study.
He's too bright.
Well, David does all right,
very much so.
Thank you.
How's Mrs. Kentley?
As usual,
it's a cold this time.
I hope David arrives soon.
She wants him to call her.
David's her only child,
Mr. Kentley.
He's my only child, too,
but I'm willing
to let him grow up.
Why don't I call
and tell her
he's been detained?
No, you mustn't
pamper her, Janet.
David might even
have stopped off
to see her.
Mr. Kentley?
May I use the phone?
Of course.
It's in the bedroom.
How cozy.
Aren't you ready
for another?
I will be.
I am, thank you.
What a charming young man.
I wish David
saw more of him.
Yes.
I'll go and call.
Kenneth, there's too
much air in your glass.
Oh, mine's fine, thanks.
Would you mind
taking this in to Janet?
Sure. Why?
No particular reason.
It's hers.
I thought you'd like
to take it in to her.
She's in the bedroom,
telephoning.
Then you'd like
David to walk in.
No, no, that'd be
too much of a shock.
When were you born?
July 14.
Can you really tell
my future from that?
Of course, I'm only
an amateur astrologer.
I'm sure you're very good.
I do my best.
I suppose you want to
know if your concert
will be a success?
Yes, I do.
Let me see now.
You were born on
the 14th of July.
You're Cancer, the crab.
You're a moon child.
You're very much
influenced by the moon.
May I see your hands?
You don't remember
the hour of your birth,
by any chance?
No.
Good fingers.
Strong. Artistic.
What about the concert?
These hands will
bring you great fame.
Extremely.
Well, I consider myself a very
fortunate man today.
I'm on hand for
the grand opening.
Of what?
Of your collection,
so to speak.
Oh, yes, of course.
Are you going to play?
How lovely.
Your wife
sends her love.
David wasn't there?
No. He'll probably
be here in
a minute, though.
Your touch has
improved, Phillip.
Rupert!
I was beginning to think
you weren't going to show.
You know me
better than that.
Mrs. Atwater, may I present
Mr. Rupert Cadell?
Delighted.
Thank you.
Mr. Kentley.
How do you do,
Mr. Kentley?
Rupert Cadell,
the housemaster
at Somerville?
I used to be.
Then you must have
taught my son, David.
You flatter me.
How do you do?
Hello, chum.
Ms. Walker.
How did you know?
Brandon spoke of you.
Did he do me justice?
Do you deserve
justice? Well!
Well, little
Kenneth Lawrence.
How you've grown.
Hello.
Now come, Kenneth.
School's out.
You can say it.
Rupert,
you're the same as ever.
It's awfully good
to see you again.
Why?
Well...
Don't mind me.
Very pleased to
see you again.
And that bears
a curious resemblance
to champagne.
It is.
It's very good
champagne, too.
What's the occasion?
I told you on the phone.
It began as a little
party for Mr. Kentley,
so he could look over
those first editions.
Then it turned out
Phillip and I were
going to the country...
Yes, you told me that,
too, Brandon.
Did I?
Yeah.
Well, I thought
I'd make it sort of
a farewell for Phillip.
Therefore, champagne?
Yes.
I see.
Well, it's true.
You always did stutter
when you were excited.
Well, I guess
I'm always excited
when I give a party.
-Really?
-Mr. Cadell!
Oh, Mrs. Wilson.
Well, what have we here?
I got that
special pâté you like.
I don't like it anymore.
Oh, no!
No, no, no,
I'm just teasing.
Just teasing.
Oh, you're awful.
Thank you. Thank you.
You'd better get
along with the carving.
The rest of
the things'll be here
in two shakes.
Oh, Mr. Brandon!
I found it.
I haven't the least notion
what it was she lost.
Wonderful Mrs. Wilson.
I may marry her.
It looks heavenly.
I hope David gets here soon.
Yes, where is David?
I haven't
the faintest idea.
But he's so late,
Mr. Kentley's
getting annoyed.
And you?
Me? I'm hungry.
Brandon, exactly
what is this?
A cassone
I got in Italy.
No, I mean why are
we eating off it?
Oh, I've turned
the dining room
into a library.
Trust you to find
a new use for a chest.
One was always turning up
in the bedtime stories
he told in prep school.
The Mistletoe Bough,
that was always your
favorite tale, wasn't it?
What was that one about?
I don't remember
exactly how it started.
It was about
a lovely young girl...
She was a bride-to-be.
And on her wedding day,
she playfully hid
herself in a chest.
Yes, that's right.
Unfortunately,
it had a spring lock.
Fifty years later,
they found her skeleton.
I don't think
I'll get that playful.
Would you all
please help yourselves?
Talking of skeletons,
have you seen that
new thing at the Strand?
Yes, I adored it.
Did you? Good.
I didn't like
the new girl much.
Definitely Scorpio.
No, I didn't
like her either,
but her clothes
were fabulous.
Simply divine!
Absolute heaven!
I must see it.
Of course, the man
I have a passion for
is James Mason.
Is he good?
Absolutely terrific!
So attractively sinister!
Taurus, the bull, you know?
Very obstinate.
Really?
But I have
a confession to make.
Do you know
I think I like Mason
as much as Errol Flynn?
I'll take Cary Grant,
myself.
Oh, so will I!
Capricorn, the goat.
He leaps divine!
So much... Mmm!
Yes.
Absolutely.
Oh, he was thrilling
in that new thing
with Bergman.
What was it called now?
"The Something
of the Something."
No, that's the other one.
This was just plain
"Something."
It was sort of...
You know?
It's right on
the tip of my tongue.
Mine, too.
It was just plain
"Something." I'm sure.
I adored it.
And Bergman!
She's the Virgo type!
Like all these...
You know?
Oh, I think
she's lovely.
I once went to the movies.
I saw Mary Pickford.
I was mad about her!
Didn't you love her?
The Virgo type, rather,
like all of these...
Well, what did you
see her in?
I don't quite recall.
"The Something Something."
Or was it just
plain "Something"?
Really something
rather like that.
I don't believe
you ever went.
Really?
If I were you, I'd go easy on
the pâté, dear.
Calories.
Come on, Kenneth,
don't be polite.
Phillip,
would you mind
helping Mrs. Atwater?
I'd be glad to.
You sit down,
Mrs. Atwater.
I'll bring it to you.
Thank you so much,
dear boy.
I really must
apologize for David.
I can't think
what's keeping him.
He's only in town
for the weekend,
Mr. Kentley,
and David is a very
popular young man.
Here, let me help.
White or dark?
A little of both on this
for Mrs. Atwater.
What about you?
I don't eat it.
How queer. I never
heard of anyone who
didn't eat chicken.
Did you, Brandon?
Oh, you probably did.
Why don't you eat it,
Phillip?
I just don't.
Well, now,
there must be a reason.
Freud says there's a reason
for everything. Even me.
There's no reason, Janet.
As I remember,
Phillip, you have
a very funny reason.
Doesn't he, Brandon?
Yes.
I knew there had to be one.
Now, what is it? Tell.
Oh, it's nothing too much.
Well, I think
it's quite fascinating.
Come on,
Brandon, please.
Well, it happened
about three years ago
in Connecticut.
Mother has a place there,
you know?
We were going to
have chicken, so we
walked over to the farm.
It was a lovely Sunday
morning in late spring.
Across the valley,
the church bells
were ringing.
And in the yard,
Phillip was doing likewise
to the necks of two
or three chickens.
Oh, dear!
It was a task
he usually performed
very competently.
But on this
particular morning,
his touch was, perhaps,
a trifle too delicate,
because one of the subjects
for our dinner table
suddenly rebelled.
Like Lazarus, he rose...
That's a lie!
Phillip!
There isn't a word
of truth in the whole story.
I never strangled
a chicken in my life!
Now, look here, Phillip...
I never strangled a chicken,
and you know it.
Forgive me, but
it just seemed very funny,
you two being so intense
about an old, dead chicken.
Sorry. We were
ridiculous and very rude.
I apologize for both
of us and the story.
Well.
Is it all over?
I'm afraid so, Rupert.
Oh, what a pity.
In another moment,
you might have been
strangling each other
instead of a chicken.
Mr. Cadell, really!
No. But a man's
honor was at stake.
And personally,
I think a chicken is
as good a reason for murder
as a blonde, a mattress
full of dollar bills,
or any of the customary,
unimaginative reasons.
Now, you don't
really approve of murder,
Rupert, if I may?
You may, and I do.
Think of the problems
it would solve.
Unemployment, poverty,
standing in line
for theater tickets.
I must say, I've had
a perfectly dreadful time
getting tickets
for that new musical,
what's it called?
You know.
"The Something,"
with what's her name?
Mmm-hmm.
My dear Mrs. Atwater,
careful application
of the trigger finger
and a pair of seats
in the first row is
yours for the shooting.
And have you
had any difficulty
getting into our
velvet rope restaurants?
Frightful!
A very simple matter.
A flick of the knife,
madam, and if you'll
kindly step this way.
No, step over
the head waiter's body.
Thank you,
and here's your table.
Rupert, you're the end.
There's a hotel clerk I could cheerfully
flick a knife at.
Oh, no, sorry.
Knives may not be
used on hotel employees.
They are in
the "death by slow
torture" category.
Ohh!
Along with bird lovers,
small children,
and tap dancers.
Landlords, of course,
are another matter.
You seeking an apartment?
Call on our Ms. Sash Weight
of the blunt
instrument department.
What a divine idea!
If it suits your purpose,
merely...
But then we'd all be
murdering each other.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
After all, murder is,
or should be, an art,
not one of the seven
lively, perhaps,
but an art nevertheless.
As such, the privilege
of committing it
should be reserved
for those few
who are really
superior individuals.
And the victims,
inferior beings
whose lives are
unimportant anyway.
Obviously. Now mind you, I don't
hold with the extremists
who feel that there
should be open season
for murder all year round.
No, personally,
I would prefer to have
"Cut a Throat Week."
Oh!
Or "Strangulation Day."
Probably a symptom of
approaching senility,
but I must confess
that I really
don't appreciate
this morbid humor.
Well, the humor
was unintentional.
You're not serious
about these theories?
Of course, he is.
Oh, you're both
pulling my leg.
No. Why do you
think that?
Well, Brandon,
the notion that
murder is an art
which a few superior beings
should be allowed
to practice...
In season!
Now I know
you're not serious.
But I am.
I'm a very serious fellow.
Then may I ask,
who is to decide
the human being is inferior,
and therefore
a suitable victim for murder?
The few who are privileged
to commit murder.
And just who might they be?
Oh, myself, Phillip,
possibly Rupert.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Kenneth, you're out.
Gentlemen, I'm serious.
So are we, Mr. Kentley.
The few are those men
of such intellectual
and cultural superiority
that they're above
the traditional
moral concepts.
Good and evil,
right and wrong,
were invented for
the ordinary, average man,
the inferior man,
because he needs them.
Then obviously you
agree with Nietzsche
and his theory
of the superman.
Yes, I do.
So did Hitler.
Hitler was
a paranoiac savage.
His supermen,
all fascist supermen,
were brainless murderers.
I'd hang any who were left.
But then, you see,
I'd hang them first
for being stupid.
I'd hang all incompetents
and fools anyway.
There are far too
many in the world.
Then perhaps you
should hang me, Brandon,
for I'm convinced I'm
so stupid, I don't know
whether you're
all serious or not.
But in any case,
I'd rather not hear any more
of your, forgive me,
contempt for humanity,
and for the standards
of a world that
I believe is civilized.
Civilized?
Yes.
Perhaps what is
called "civilization"
is hypocrisy.
Perhaps.
Well, I'm sure Rupert,
fortunately...
Now, gentlemen. Really...
...has the intelligence
and imagination...
Please, Brandon,
I think we've had
just about enough!
Phillip, where did you
put those books you
set out for Mr. Kentley?
I'd very much like
to see them myself,
if I may.
Of course.
They're in the dining room.
Mr. Kentley,
wouldn't you like
to see the books now?
I apologize, sir,
again.
I'm afraid I let
myself get carried away.
Oh, that's quite
all right, my boy.
I think
it's a good collection.
The first editions,
I mean.
Yes, I'd like to
see them. May I use
the telephone first?
I'd like to talk to
my wife. She may have
some word of David.
Of course.
It's this way.
Dear, dear.
I'm afraid Henry...
Uh...
Brandon?
Yes.
You were really
pushing your point
rather hard.
You aren't planning
to do away with a few
inferiors, by any chance?
I'm a creature of whim.
Who knows?
I see.
I think he's definitely Scorpio.
I know exactly what you mean.
Uh, Mrs. Atwater,
wouldn't you like
to see the books?
Oh, I'd love it.
Do you know,
when I was a girl,
I used to read quite a bit.
Oh, we all do
strange things
in our childhood.
Kenneth, why don't
you switch on the radio
or play some records?
A little atmospheric music
goes a long way.
He is such a sly,
little devil, isn't he?
Bringing us
back together again
with sweet music.
Don't let it get you.
He's always doing
something like this.
I'm going in the other room.
To see the books?
No, to let Brandon see me.
Do you care what he thinks?
I know what he thinks!
He thinks I threw you over
because David has
a bigger bank account.
Then why do you go?
Because...
Because I'm embarrassed
at being here with you.
Oh, Janet.
Never thought I
could be, did you?
Honestly? No.
Well, I am,
and I don't like it
one bit.
I should think
you'd have the decency
to be embarrassed yourself.
Why?
Well, you threw me over,
chum, remember?
My, wouldn't friend Brandon
love to know that?
What's the matter?
Nothing. I'm just thinking.
What about?
Female vanity.
Well, I'm also
embarrassed because...
Go on.
Well, you and David
used to be
such good friends,
and you're not now,
and it's my fault.
I'm such an idiot girl.
No, you're not.
Then I'm certainly giving
a good imitation of one.
Why must I try and
be so smart with
everyone but David?
Don't you kid
with David, too?
I relax with David,
thanks to you.
To me?
Yes.
That grim Sunday at Harvard,
when you called it quits,
David took me for a walk.
My chin was about
an inch from the ground.
I just couldn't
be the gay girl.
I just relaxed and
let everything pour out.
The real, real me stuff.
Did you hear that phrase?
I hear myself saying
things like that and...
Oh, where's David?
You know,
I'm not very smart.
Why?
I never realized you were...
Brandon and
his atmospheric music.
You are in love
with David, aren't you?
Yes.
I don't get it.
Get what?
Brandon made a crack
when I got here.
He sort of implied
I'd have a better chance
with you again
because David would
be out of the running.
Wait. You mean,
before I got here,
Brandon knew
we had broken...
He even knew
about you and David.
What?
Kenneth, he pretended
to be completely ignorant
when I told him.
He said...
What's going on here, anyway?
I don't know,
but I'm going to find
out once and for all!
Brandon?
Yes?
May I see you for a moment?
Certainly.
Why can't he keep
his hands off people?
Well?
Just exactly what
are you up to, chum?
I'm up to getting
you coffee if you like.
Let's dispense
with the charm.
I'd like to know
why you had the gall
to tell Kenneth
he wouldn't have to
worry very much longer
about David and me?
I don't think
that's precisely
what I said, Kenneth.
It's what you implied,
and I want to know why.
Some women are
quite charming when
they're angry, Janet.
Unfortunately,
you're not.
Cut that out, Brandon.
Well, chivalry
rears its ugly head!
I don't believe
David's coming!
Wait and see.
I don't have to.
He's never this late.
He's never late at all.
And if something had come up,
he'd have phoned.
I think you
deliberately arranged it
so that he wouldn't come.
How clever of me!
I might have known
you couldn't just give
a party for Mr. Kentley.
No, you'd have to
add something that appealed
to your warped
sense of humor.
Well, I hope
you've enjoyed yourself,
Brandon. I haven't!
He's really impossible.
You shouldn't
let him upset you so much.
Something gone wrong,
Brandon?
No.
Janet just has
a talent for being
bothersome at times.
However,
I suppose I'd better...
What did you mean,
"Something gone wrong"?
You always plan
your parties so well,
it's odd to have
anything go wrong.
She seems to be
missing David.
As a matter of fact,
I'm beginning to
miss him myself.
Aren't we all?
Two desserts, Mr. Cadell?
One for you
and one for me, my love.
Oh, Mr. C.
Well, the others
don't seem to be in
the mood for ice cream.
No, though they could all do
with a little cooling off.
My, it's a peculiar party,
not that that surprises me.
Why not?
I could have predicted it
this morning.
Both of them must have
got up out of the wrong
side of the bed.
They've been in
a state all day!
Oh, Mr. Brandon says
he's always in a state
when he gives a party.
It's the first time
I've seen it.
Usually, he lets me
prepare everything
in my own way,
but, look at this,
the chicken's
hardly been touched!
Well, what was
so different today?
What wasn't!
Mr. Brandon was
in the maddest rush
for me to clean up
and get the table set.
And, oh,
it looked so lovely!
But then when I
was whisking out
to do the shopping,
he suddenly told me to take
the whole afternoon for it.
The whole afternoon,
after that mad rush
in the morning.
Did he say why?
No, just a whim,
I suppose.
But when I came back,
he and Mr. Phillip
were going at it
hammer and tongs.
Oh. What about?
Well, now, Mr. Cadell,
even if I did know,
do you think I'd tell?
Well, I hope so.
Not me.
Really?
I'm like the grave.
I see.
Look at this mess!
Just makes double the work.
After I have
this cleaned off,
I just have to
clear all those books
off the dining room table,
bring them in here,
and put them
back in the chest,
which is where they
were in the first place.
Why did you serve
from here, anyway?
It wasn't my idea.
I had everything laid out
in the dining room
and it was just beautiful.
Of course on this thing,
there isn't half of the room.
Is she still harping
on her table
and how awkward it is
to serve from this?
It's really much more
convenient, you know?
Because this way,
people don't have
to go all the way
into the dining room
to get their food
and come all the way
back here to eat it.
Hmm. Seems to me
they've gone all the way
in there now
for their dessert
and coffee.
Mrs. Wilson,
please serve the guests.
Don't lecture them.
We did get up on the wrong side of
the bed, didn't we?
I'm in quite
an embarrassing position.
How do you mean?
Well, I seem to
be the only one
having a good time.
You and Mrs. Atwater.
What's going on, Phillip?
Would you mind
turning that off?
Sorry.
I don't like to play
with light in my eyes.
You know, Phillip,
I get quite intrigued
when people don't
answer questions.
And quite curious.
Did you ask me a question?
Yes, Phillip,
I asked you a question.
Well, what was it?
I asked you,
"What is going on here?"
A party.
Yes, but
a rather peculiar party.
What's it all about,
Phillip?
What's what all about?
Stop playing crime
and punishment, Rupert.
If you want to know
something, come out
with it! Otherwise...
No. Temper, temper.
Don't stop.
I'd like a drink.
Wait, I'll get it for you.
Keep playing.
What would you like, scotch?
No, brandy.
You're very fond
of that little tune,
aren't you?
You know, Phillip,
I wish I could
come straight out with
what I want to know.
Unfortunately,
I don't know anything.
I merely suspect.
I said that...
I heard you.
This all right?
Thank you.
That's fine.
Do you use this?
Sometimes.
I thought only
beginners did.
I must say...
All right, Rupert,
I'll ask you.
What do you suspect?
Oh, I've forgotten.
Where's David, Phillip?
I don't know.
Why?
Brandon knows.
Does he?
Doesn't he?
Not that I know of.
Oh, come now.
I don't.
Why don't you ask Brandon?
I have.
But he's too busy
maneuvering the other
two points of the triangle.
What for, Phillip?
Just what is
Brandon trying to do
with Janet and Kenneth?
What's the matter?
What are you laughing at?
Nothing.
What is it?
What, am I so far
off the track?
There's nothing
going on at all, Rupert.
You're...
...more than usually
allergic to the truth
tonight, Phillip.
That's the second time
you haven't told it.
Thanks.
When was the first?
When you said you never
strangled a chicken.
You're confused.
Brandon dreamt that up
for the sake of
a very unfunny joke.
No, he didn't.
No, he didn't, Phillip.
And if you'll think
back very carefully,
you'll realize
that I know he didn't.
About a year ago,
I was up at the farm.
Do you remember?
One morning I saw you
display your handiwork.
You're quite a good
chicken-strangler,
as I recall.
Well, I just meant that
Brandon's story wasn't true.
I didn't mean
I hadn't killed any chickens.
That's what you said.
Well, I didn't think
it was a suitable topic
of conversation
while we were eating!
You could have said that.
All right, I didn't!
We're not eating
now, Phillip. What'd
you lie to me for?
Because I don't
like to talk about...
About what?
Strangling...
I can't play with that thing!
I want you to
have them very much.
It's extremely
generous of you, Brandon.
Please, I know you appreciate first editions
far more than I, Mr. Kentley.
It's really very nice of you, Brandon.
What's wrong?
You and Phillip must come to
dinner very soon...
What's wrong now,
Phillip?
Don't you want Mr. Kentley
to have the books?
No. I mean,
I don't care if he
has them, I just...
What? What?
I just think it's
a clumsy way of tying
them up that's all.
David never had any trouble
taking care of himself.
I know, but I cannot understand this.
Whenever he's
been detained before,
he's telephoned.
Isn't that so, Janet?
Oh, yes. He's always been after me
to be more punctual.
As well he might.
You wouldn't
know me these days.
I'm a new woman.
Punctual as a clock.
That's very unfeminine, my dear.
Perhaps, but I prefer manners
to femininity.
Oh, Henry, you sound
just like Daddy.
I remember once
when David was very small...
Take it easy, Phillip.
Rupert's on to something.
He isn't. Now, let up.
I've got to have a drink,
Brandon.
You've had enough.
You're not...
Take your hand off my arm!
Don't you ever again
tell me what to do
and what not to do.
I don't like it, Brandon,
and I'm not going to take it.
All right,
keep your voice down!
I hope I didn't
upset Phillip.
Uh, no, he's more
likely mixing his drinks.
You seem rather
upset yourself.
Do I?
Yes, there's something
upsetting both of you
a great deal,
something that...
Excuse me, sir.
There's a lady phoning
for either Mr. Kentley
or Mrs. Atwater.
Oh, it must be Alice.
I'll talk to her, Henry.
All right.
Down the hall to
your left, dear.
Thank you.
The first bedroom.
Mr. Kentley, do you suppose David
could possibly be home?
I don't know, Janet.
I hope so.
I hate to throw a damper,
but if David was home,
I should think
he'd be calling
instead of Mrs. Kentley.
Wouldn't you say so,
Brandon?
I wouldn't know.
The David I remember was very polite
as well as very punctual.
He hasn't changed.
Of course. If he's not at home,
where could he be?
Don't ask me.
I don't know.
He might be any number of places,
such as the club,
or the Bradleys
are giving a party,
or maybe he went
down to Janet's.
Why?
Perhaps he decided
to pick her up after all.
I phoned my place after I spoke
with Mrs. Kentley.
He wasn't there?
No. I left a message
just in case, but...
We might have a better chance at
finding out where he is now
if we knew where
he was this afternoon.
What do you think, Brandon?
I haven't the least idea where
he was this afternoon.
But don't you think it would help
if we found out where he was?
I suppose so.
I know he went to the club
this afternoon to play tennis,
-and I know that he got there.
-Why?
Because someone phoned from there
with a message that
David would meet us here.
Well, do you know
who gave the message?
No.
Well, then, obviously, David
ran into someone
at the club
who changed his plans.
You weren't there
this afternoon,
by any chance,
were you, Kenneth?
No. I wish I had been.
I don't suppose
you or Brandon were, Phillip?
-No.
-Hardly. We had our hands full
getting ready for the party.
Oh, there was a lot
to be done this afternoon.
Well, you know.
Yes, I see. You didn't speak to David
at all today, then?
No. Why do you ask?
I just thought that perhaps
he might have called
to say he'd be late
or something.
He didn't. Neither Phillip nor I
have talked to David
since the day we
invited him to the party.
That's odd.
What do you mean?
I thought I heard David on the phone
to Phillip yesterday morning.
Really?
Yes, you did.
I'd forgotten.
Oh? What were you talking to him about?
Did he call about the party?
Yes, he wanted to make sure about the time,
that was all.
Here, I'll help
you with that.
Oh, thank you,
Mr. Cadell.
Very good.
That's all right,
Mrs. Wilson.
You can put the books back
when you come in to
clean in the morning.
Well, I didn't have
any idea of coming in
in the morning.
I'm afraid you have to.
Just let the books
go for now.
Well, all right.
Henry, Alice hasn't
had a word from David.
She's frantic.
I better talk to her.
She hung up.
She began to cry
so badly.
Oh, Henry, I'm worried.
What did she say?
She's been calling
every place he might be.
Not once, but several times.
And now, Henry,
she thinks he may
have had an accident.
She wants you to
call the police.
The police?
Oh, no, Anita, I don't think
that's necessary.
David's no longer a child.
I'm quite sure
he's all right. I...
Brandon, I think
I'd better go home.
My wife needs me.
This isn't like
David. He...
Of course.
I understand.
May I go with you,
Mr. Kentley?
Thank you, Janet.
I'll get your things.
Thank you.
Oh, Mr. Kentley,
your books.
Oh. Yes.
I can't tell you
how sorry I am.
Would you call me
as soon as you
hear from David?
Be glad to.
I'm sure the dear boy will
turn up somehow.
Janet.
Yes?
This is hardly the time,
but I'm very glad
we had that talk.
So am I.
And David will be, too.
Good.
Well...
Kenneth, why don't
you come along with us?
Oh, I don't...
Please.
Thanks.
This yours, Janet?
Yes, I'll just carry it.
Oh... Thanks.
I'll get my hat.
Going with Janet?
Yes, we're all
going together.
Well, what did
I predict?
Good night,
Mr. Kentley.
I hope Mrs. Kentley's
feeling better very soon.
Thank you.
Uh... You will call me the moment
you hear from David?
I will.
Say good night
to Phillip for me.
I'll get your hat, Mr. Cadell.
Mrs. Atwater,
thank you so much for coming.
Thank you for letting me come. I'm
so sorry we have to leave.
Good-bye.
-Good night.
-Good-bye.
That's not yours.
I'm very sorry
we had to spoil it.
You couldn't possibly spoil it,
Mr. Kentley.
Well, I meant by leaving so early.
Good night. Be careful
of those stairs, Anita.
Here we are.
I'm all right.
Thank you, Mrs. Wilson.
Good night,
Mr. Cadell.
You going, too?
Yes. Yes, I must.
Good night.
Can I help you with those books,
Mr. Kentley?
Thank you.
Thank you for
a lovely evening.
Good night, good night.
It's been charming.
Oh, Phillip, this party
really deserves to
go down in history.
Well, come on, it's over,
and it couldn't have
gone more beautifully.
Yes, it could.
Without Rupert.
Oh, but he was brilliant.
He helped me
say all the things
I've wanted to say
to those idiots.
He gave the party
the very touch I predicted.
The touch of what?
Prying? Snooping?
Or just plain pumping?
Do you know how busy
he was questioning me?
About what?
Oh, what difference?
You were busy in there
arranging that other
little touch of yours.
What touch?
Tying up the books
that way.
Oh, I thought
that was wonderful.
Didn't you like it?
No, Brandon, I didn't
like it one bit.
You'll ruin everything
with your neat
little touches.
Be quiet.
Mrs. Wilson's still here.
Determined to get drunk,
aren't you?
I am drunk.
And just as childish
as you were before
when you called me a liar.
You had no business
telling that story.
Why did you lie, anyway?
I had to.
Have you ever bothered,
for just one minute,
to understand how
someone else might feel?
I'm not sentimental
if that's what you mean.
No, that's not what I mean,
but it doesn't matter.
Nothing matters,
except that Mr. Brandon
liked the party.
Mr. Brandon gave the party.
Mr. Brandon had
a delightful evening.
Well, I had
a rotten evening.
Keep drinking and you'll
have a worse morning.
At least if
I have a hangover,
it'll be all mine.
You know, Phillip,
I've been thinking.
We deserve a real holiday
after it's all over.
Where would you like to go?
Of course, I think
we should come back here
for a few days, first.
Otherwise, it might
look a little like...
I've been praying
I'd wake up and find
we hadn't done it yet.
But why?
I'm scared to death,
Brandon. I think we're
going to get caught.
Oh, there's not a chance.
There was, I suppose,
but not anymore.
Why, we're...
Uh... Is that you,
Mrs. Wilson?
Yes. I'll need a key to get in
and clean up in the morning.
That is if you're
still driving up
to the farm tonight.
Oh, we're driving up,
all right.
Oh, well, that's good.
You don't look well,
either one of you. Thanks.
Of course, I could
do with a rest myself.
But I want both of you
to come back in tip-top,
A-one shape.
We will.
Well, I'm off.
Enjoy yourselves.
Don't forget to write.
And mind your P's and Q's.
Mmm-hmm.
Who are you calling?
Only the garage.
Hello?
This is Mr. Brandon Shaw.
Would you send
my car around, please?
Yes, right away. Thank you.
We'd better
draw the curtains.
Who's that?
Brandon, who's that?
Probably the garage man
with my car keys.
Answer it.
There hasn't been
time for him to get here.
Then maybe Mrs. Wilson
forgot something.
Answer it.
Brandon, couldn't we pretend
we're not home?
With all these lights on?
Answer it, Phillip.
Who is it?
Brandon. Brandon,
it's Rupert.
What?
He wants to come up.
He says he left
a cigarette case here.
He wants to come up.
Well, let him come.
But you know he's lying!
He's caught on!
He didn't leave...
Shut up and get
back to that phone.
I won't.
Get back to that phone.
Brandon, I can't.
You've got to.
No! He knows!
Shut up!
Rupert? Come on up.
No, of course not.
He's just a little tight.
No, but we'll find it
in no time.
Right.
Phillip.
Phillip, listen to me.
Rupert's on his way up now,
and you've got to
pull yourself together.
Phillip, did you hear me?
Come on,
have another drink
if you must,
but get hold of yourself
and keep your mouth shut.
It'll be over
in five minutes.
I don't know how much,
if anything, Rupert knows,
but I promise you,
he'll be out of
here in five minutes,
one way or the other.
Phillip,
for those five minutes,
you've got to pull
yourself together.
Brandon, Brandon...
Now look,
I'm not going to
get caught because of
you or anyone else.
No one is going to
get in my way now.
Brandon, it's not
loaded, is it?
Sorry to bother you, Brandon.
It's no bother
at all. Come in.
I knew you were
leaving tonight,
and I didn't want to
be left without my case.
Hello, Phillip.
Hello.
I didn't mean to
alarm you before.
You didn't alarm him.
I'm afraid Phillip's
a little antisocial tonight.
Oh? I thought perhaps...
Any idea where
you left the case?
No. No, none at all.
Completely unlike me
to forget it, isn't it?
I suppose a psychoanalyst
would say that I didn't
really forget it at all.
I unconsciously left it
because I wanted
to come back.
But why should I
want to come back?
Yes, why?
For the pleasure
of our company,
or another drink.
Well, that's a very
good idea. May I have
one for the road?
Of course. A short one?
No, I'd prefer a long one
if you don't mind.
Not at all.
Phillip, will you
fix Rupert a drink?
Now let me see.
The last I remember
having the case
was when I was there.
I was just going to
open the chest
for Mrs. Wilson
when you came over, Brandon.
And then what?
I think I...
Wonder where it could be.
Oh.
Well, here it is
right where I left it.
Gentlemen,
I beg your pardon.
I'm very sorry.
Well, may I have
that drink anyway?
Of course.
You really don't mind?
No. Why should we?
Well, you might be...
What?
Tired. You're sure
it's all right?
He said
you could have it.
Thank you.
Don't mind Phillip.
I'm afraid he's
had a few too many.
Well, why not? Why not?
After all, it was a party.
Well, it's very
pleasant to sit here
with a good drink
and good company.
I'm glad.
Please don't let me
be in the way.
Of what?
Well, I know you
have things to do.
What do you mean?
Oh, packing,
last-minute odds and ends.
You are driving up to
Connecticut tonight,
aren't you?
Yes, but
we're all packed.
Oh, I see.
All ready.
All except one guest,
who must be gotten rid of.
Well, I'll be off,
as soon as
I finish my drink.
There's no need
to hurry, Rupert.
Thank you. I would
like to stay a bit.
Perhaps even
see you off.
I always hate
to leave a party,
especially when
the evening has been
unusually stimulating,
or strange,
like this evening.
What do you mean
"strange"?
Did I say "strange,"
Brandon?
Well, you often
pick words for sound
rather than meaning.
I don't exactly
know what I meant,
unless I was
thinking about David.
What was strange
about David?
His not showing up.
You don't think
anything really did
happen to him, do you?
What could have?
He could have been
run over or held up.
In broad daylight?
That's right.
I'd forgotten.
Yes, it must have
been broad daylight
when it happened.
When what happened?
When whatever did
happen to David.
Nothing, probably.
Still, where is he?
What's your theory?
Mine?
I was considering
Janet's for the moment.
I didn't know she had one.
Yes, you do.
I couldn't help
overhearing Janet.
I gather she thinks
you kidnapped David,
or did something
to prevent him from coming.
I'm not interested
in Janet's prattle,
but you always
interest me, Rupert.
Do you think
I kidnapped David?
Well,
it's the sort of mischief
that would have
appealed to you in school
for the experience,
the excitement,
the danger.
But it would be
slightly more difficult
to pull off now,
though, don't you think?
You'd find a way.
How?
I mean, suppose you were I.
How would you get David
out of the way?
You're much better
at this sort of thing
than I am.
No, but what would
you do if you were I?
Well, if I wanted
to get rid of David,
I'd invite him for
a drink at the club
or some quiet bar,
or better still,
I'd invite him here.
Then no one would
see us together.
That's good.
And no witnesses.
Yes, that's right.
Then what?
Well...
Well, let me see.
At the appointed time,
David would arrive,
I'd walk slowly out of
the room into the hall,
and greet him.
Tell him how fine
he's looking and so forth,
and take his hat.
And I'd bring him in here,
make some small talk
to put him at his ease,
probably offer him a drink,
and then he'd sit down.
Yes?
I'd try to make it all very pleasant,
you understand?
Phillip would
probably play the piano.
Now, as I recall,
David was quite strong.
He'd have to be knocked out.
So I'd move quietly
around behind the chair
and hit him on
the head with something.
His body would fall
forward on the floor.
Then where would
you put him?
Well...
Uh...
Well, let me see.
Well, I think I'd
get Phillip to help me
carry him out of the room,
down the back stairs,
and the two of us
would put him into the car.
You'd be seen.
What?
Well, you said yourself
that if anything did happen,
it must have happened
in broad daylight.
Oh, that's right.
I'd forgotten.
That means I'd have to
find someplace to
hide the body until dark.
Yes, you would,
but where, Rupert?
Yes.
Yes, where?
Cat and mouse!
Phillip!
Which is the cat
and which is the mouse?
That's enough of that.
Mind your own business.
That's enough, Phillip!
I told you before,
mind your own business!
It really isn't
any of my business.
I'm not his keeper.
With him in
this condition, though,
there doesn't
seem to be much point
in your staying, Rupert.
That is,
unless you came back
to find something
besides your cigarette case.
You mean, for example,
to find if you
really got rid of David?
Yes, that's what I mean.
Oh, you're as
romantic as Janet.
I don't think for a moment
that you kidnapped David.
Oh, I will admit that Janet
put the notion in my head,
but I never would
have mentioned it
if it weren't that you
seem to be carrying fear
of discovery in your pocket.
What?
That's a gun, isn't it?
That teased my suspicions
more than anything else.
And to tell you the truth,
it really scares me
a little.
I'm terribly sorry, Rupert.
I don't blame you,
but, well, here.
You can relax.
I have to take it
up to the country.
There've been
several burglaries,
and Mother's a bit on edge.
Finished, Phillip?
All right.
Did you hear what Rupert said
about the gun?
He thought...
It's odd the way
one can pyramid
simple facts into
wild fantasies,
isn't it?
We all do it,
don't we, Phillip?
Yes.
Particularly after a few drinks.
How is yours, Rupert?
I think I'll be running along.
Phillip, you'll feel much better
once you get out
in the open air.
I don't think
there'll be much traffic,
and we ought to
make good time.
It's a lovely night. You'll be driving
up in good weather.
I almost wish
I were going with you.
It might be rather exciting.
Driving at night always is,
but driving with
you and Phillip now
might have an additional
element of suspense.
You were right, Phillip.
Those books
were tied clumsily.
He's got it.
He's got it!
Phillip!
He knows.
He knows. He knows.
All right, Phillip.
Easy. I'll take
care of it.
He knows!
No, you won't.
I'd just as soon kill
you as kill him. Sooner!
This is what you wanted,
isn't it?
Somebody else to know.
Somebody else to see
how brilliant you are,
just like at school.
I told you he'd
find out, but, oh, no! No,
you had to have him here.
And now we're done for!
Shut up! Shut up!
No! You made me do it,
and I hate you.
I hate both of us! I...
Stupid, babbling drunk.
I'm sorry, Rupert.
It's all right.
If you really
want to kill,
you don't miss,
not at that range.
Of course he didn't
want to kill you.
He didn't know
what he was doing,
any more than he knew
what he was saying.
I didn't want
anyone to know this,
but he's been becoming
an alcoholic, Rupert.
Brandon, will you
step over there, please?
Phillip's drunk, Rupert.
Surely you don't take
those nightmare ideas
of his seriously?
Brandon.
Brandon, I'm tired.
And in a way,
I'm frightened, too.
But I don't want
to fence anymore.
What are you going to do?
I don't want to,
but I'm gonna look
inside that chest.
Are you crazy?
I hope so.
With all my heart,
I hope I'm crazy.
Rupert, this has
nothing to do with you.
I've got to.
Don't! Rupert!
I've got to look
inside that chest.
All right!
Go ahead and look.
I hope you like
what you see.
Oh, no. No!
Rupert...
I couldn't
believe it was true.
Rupert, please.
Please what?
Listen to me.
Just listen. Let me explain.
Explain? Do you think
you can explain that?
Yes, to you I can.
Because you'll understand.
Understand?
Rupert. Rupert,
remember the discussion
we had before
with Mr. Kentley?
Yes.
Remember we said,
"The lives of inferior beings
are unimportant"?
Remember we said...
We've always said,
you and I,
that moral concepts
of good and evil
and right and wrong
don't hold for
the intellectually superior.
Remember, Rupert?
Yes, I remember.
Well, that's all
we've done. That's all
Phillip and I have done.
He and I have lived
what you and I have talked.
I knew you'd understand,
because you have to,
don't you see?
You have to.
Brandon.
Brandon,
till this very moment,
this world
and the people in it
have always been dark
and incomprehensible to me.
And I've tried to clear
my way with logic
and superior intellect.
And you've thrown
my own words right back
in my face, Brandon.
You were right to.
If nothing else,
a man should
stand by his words.
But you've given my words
a meaning that
I never dreamed of!
And you've tried to
twist them into a cold,
logical excuse for
your ugly murder!
Well, they never
were that, Brandon.
And you can't
make them that.
There must have been
something deep inside you
from the very start
that let you do this thing.
But there's always
been something
deep inside me
that would never
let me do it,
and would never let me
be a party to it now.
What do you mean?
I mean that tonight
you've made me ashamed
of every concept I ever had
of superior or
inferior beings.
But I thank you
for that shame,
because now I know
that we are each of us
a separate human being,
Brandon,
with the right to
live and work and
think as individuals,
but with an obligation
to the society we live in.
By what right do you dare say
that there's a superior few
to which you belong?
By what right
did you dare decide
that that boy in there
was inferior and therefore
could be killed?
Did you think
you were God, Brandon?
Is that what you thought
when you choked
the life out of him?
Is that what you thought
when you served food
from his grave?
I don't know
what you thought,
or what you are,
but I know
what you've done.
You've murdered!
You've strangled the life
out of a fellow human being
who could live and love
as you never could,
and never will again.
What are you doing?
It's not what I'm
going to do, Brandon.
It's what
society's going to do.
I don't know
what that will be,
but I can guess.
And I can help.
You're going to die,
Brandon, both of you!
You're going to die.
Was that a gun?
Yes, there were
three shots fired.
It must be
in the next street.
Did you see
the firing from the gun?
No, we thought
it came from the next street.
No, I saw them back there.
There were three!
Did you hear
that gun fired?
Yeah, they came
from up there.
There were shots
fired, weren't there?
I think we better have somebody
call the police.
Did any of you
hear any shots fired?
Yes.
Somebody better
call the fire department.
Can I use your phone?
Here comes
a squad car now.
They're coming.