Help! Someone help me!
Is someone there?
Hey!
Oh, shit, I'm probably dead.
You're not dead.
-Who's that?
Who's that?
There's no point in yelling,
I already tried that.
Turn on the lights!
I would if I could.
What the fuck is going on?
Where am I?
-I don't know yet.
-What is that smell?
Shh. Hang on a second.
I think I found something.
Holy shit.
Aaaargh! Help!
Help!
No-one can hear you.
What the fuck is this?
Calm down. Just calm down.
Are you hurt?
I don't know. Yeah!
-What's your name?
-My name is Very Fucking Confused.
What's your name?
What's going on here?
My name is Lawrence Gordon, I'm a doctor.
I just woke up here, just like you.
Aaaargh!
Recognize him?
No.
Do you have any idea how you got here?
-What's the last thing you remember?
-Nothing.
I went to bed in my shit-hole apartment,
and woke up in an actual shit-hole.
What about you, huh?
There's... There's not much to tell.
I was on my way home from work, and...
I don't remember anything else.
First dead body I've ever seen.
They look different in real life.
They don't move.
From the looks of these chains,
someone didn't want us
to go very far, either.
- Can you see any scars?
- What?
Ha? This is what they do man,
they kidnap you and drug you...
before you know what, you're lying in a
bathtub and your kidneys are on eBay.
No-one has taken your kidneys.
How can you tell from way over there?
Because, you'd either be in terrible
agony, or you'd be dead by now.
Trust me.
-What are you, a surgeon?
-Yeah.
So...
Are you gonna tell me
your name, or what?
Adam.
Well, Adam...
What we need to do...
is start thinking about why we're here.
Whoever brought us here
could have killed us by now.
But they didn't.
They must want something from us.
The question is, what?
-That clock.
-What about it?
-It's brand-new.
-So?
So... somebody obviously
wanted us to know the time.
Wait, I think I might be
able to reach the door.
What is that?
Excuse me.
It's a tape.
-Where did you find it?
-It was in my pocket.
It says, "Play me."
Come on. Come on.
Throw it over here.
Fuck.
No?
-Use your shirt.
-What?
Your shirt.
Come on.
-It won't work.
-Look around.
There must be something else you can use.
-There's nothing.
-Well, there must be something.
Come on. You can do it.
Come on. Come on.
Again.
Rise and shine, Adam.
You're probably wondering where you are.
I'll tell you where you might be.
You might be in the room that you die in.
Up until now, you've simply sat in the shadows,
watching others live out their lives.
But what do voyeurs see
when they look into the mirror?
Now, I see you as a strange mix
of someone angry yet apathetic.
But mostly just pathetic.
So, are you going to watch
yourself die today, Adam,
or do something about it?
I don't get it.
Throw me the player.
No. You throw me your tape.
Look, we're gonna have to work together,
if we want to get out of here. Now just...
- throw it to me.
- I'm not gonna risk breaking it.
You throw me your tape.
Dr. Gordon...
this is your wake-up call.
Every day of your working life,
you have given people the news
that they're gonna die soon.
Now you will be the cause of death.
Your aim in this game is to kill Adam.
You have until 6 on the clock to do it.
There's a man in the room with you.
When there's that much poison in your blood,
the only thing left to do is shoot yourself.
There are ways to win this,
hidden all around you.
Just remember,
X marks the spot for the treasure.
If you do not kill Adam by six,
then Alison and Diana will die,
Dr. Gordon.
And I'll leave you in
this room to rot.
Let the game begin.
Give me that.
Now.
Then Alison and Diana will die,
Dr. Gordon...
...and I'll leave you in
this room to rot.
-Any idea who that is?
-Let the game begin.
-He knows us.
-Wait a minute.
What do you think? Probably a joke, right?
Shh! Shh!
-Let the game begin.
-Listen. Listen.
Follow your heart.
What the hell does "follow your heart" mean?
There, right next to you, on the toilet.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, man!
-Anything?
-No solids.
Take off the lid.
Come on.
I really wish I had've checked in there first.
Huh! What is it?
Hey.
Mind passing me the other one?
Fuck! Fuck!
He doesn't want us to cut through our chains.
He wants us to cut through our feet.
I think I may know who's done this to us.
What did you say?
Well, it's not someone I know personally.
It's just someone I know of.
Jesus Christ! Tell me. Who is it?
Last I heard...
.. the police still hadn't caught him.
And the only reason I know that...
is because I was a suspect.
I'll start from the beginning.
This one's not fresh any more.
At least three weeks out.
Victim's a 46-year-old male.
Died of massive blood loss,
mostly through the femoral artery.
He started at the back of the cage and
tunneled his way through that razor wire so fast,
it's amazing he got as far as he did.
Cut himself so deep, we found
traces of stomach acid on the floor.
We also found this.
Hello, Paul. You are a perfectly
healthy, sane, middle-class male,
yet last month,
you ran a straight razor across your wrists.
Did you cut yourself because
you truly wanted to die, or...
..did you just want some attention?
Tonight, you'll show me.
The irony is that if you want to die,
you just have to stay where you are.
But if you want to live,
you'll have to cut yourself again.
Find a path through the razor wire to the door.
But hurry.
At three o'clock that door will lock.
And then this room becomes your tomb.
How much blood will you shed
to stay alive, Paul?
Door was on a timer.
It was unlocked until three o'clock.
Then it slammed shut. He was given two hours.
A jigsaw piece.
I think we're gonna be here for a while, Sing.
The newspapers started
calling him "the jigsaw killer".
Actually, technically speaking, he's...
...not really a murderer.
He never killed anyone.
He finds ways for his victims
to kill themselves.
Hello, Mark. If you're so sick,
then why do I have so many photos of you
up and about?
Let's put your so-called illness to the test.
Right now, there's a slow-acting
poison in your veins.
The antidote is inside the safe.
Help!
The combination to the safe...
...is written on the wall.
Hurry up and program it in.
But watch your step.
By the way, that's a flammable substance
smeared on your body.
So, I would be careful
with that candle, if I were you.
Or all the people you've burned with your act
just might have their revenge.
Aaaargh!
I found something else.
Well, two things, actually.
There was someone standing outside
here, watching through this peephole.
Looks like our friend Jigsaw likes to book himself
front-row seats to his own sick little games.
He was there at the last one as well.
Only, this time... he left us his penlight.
Hm...
Get a rush on the prints.
Copy that.
Okay...
This patient has an inoperable frontal lobe
tumor extending across the midline.
It started as colon cancer.
The patient has come in for a standard checkup,
by which we are able to monitor the rate
at which his condition is declining.
- The patient had...
- His name is John.
Dr. Gordon. He's a very interesting person.
Thank you for that information, Zep.
As you can see, our orderlies
form very special bonds with the patients.
- Continuing on, the patient had...
- Dr. Gordon...
Dr Lawrence Gordon,
please page the operator.
Obviously, someone doesn't want me to
tell you what the patient had! Excuse me.
Dr. Gordon.
I'm Detective Tapp, this is Detective Sing.
City homicide.
- Very impressive.
- Oh, thank you.
I do my best.
- Sorry to interrupt you while you're working.
- It's Fine.
Now, how can I help you gentlemen?
Are you able to tell us where you were between
the hours of 11 PM and 1 AM last night Doctor?
Why is it that you're interested?
We'd like to ask a few questions about it.
For your sake, I think it's best
if we do it down at the station.
Would you like to follow us there?
I'm afraid that's... that's
quiet out of the question.
I can't just leave, I have work to do.
Plus my wife has the car today.
Uh.. That's Okay. You can ride with us.
Doc?
I'm sorry.
You'll have to tell me again.
Wha... What is this all about?
Is this yours, Doctor?
So you have no idea how your penlight
showed up at the murder scene?
Of course not, Brett.
Well, I have to ask.
What were you doing last night?
I was seeing someone.
Who?
Look, if you can't be honest with me...
I was visiting someone, It wasn't a patient.
All right?
What am I gonna do?
Well, as your lawyer and your friend,
my advice to you is to bite the bullet
and give them your alibi now,
cause no one's gonna believe you later.
That was five months ago.
He tried to set me up for murder.
Okay.
We checked your alibi, It holds up.
Good. Can I go home now?
We have one of the victims
who managed to escape.
Want to know if you wouldn't mind sticking
around and listening to her testimony.
Maybe it'll trigger something.
-I'd like to help, really, but...
-Well, we'd appreciate it.
-She's the only one who made it.
-OK.
Amanda...
In your own time...
tell me the first thing you remember.
I woke up.
All I could taste was blood...
...and metal.
Hello, Amanda.
You don't know me, but I know you.
I want to play a game.
Here's what happens if you lose.
The device you're wearing
is hooked into your upper and lower jaws.
When the timer on the back goes off,
your mouth will be permanently ripped open.
Think of it like a reverse bear trap.
Here, I'll show you.
There's only one key to open the device.
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
Look around, Amanda.
Know that I'm not lying.
You'd better hurry up.
Live or die.
Make your choice.
No!
And then I saw the body.
There was a knife.
He'd been injected with an opiate overdose.
Couldn't move or feel much of anything.
You mean... he was alive?
Was.
What happened after you took it off?
Congratulations. You are still alive.
Most people are so ungrateful to be alive.
But not you. Not any more.
You are, in fact, a drug addict.
Isn't that right, Mandy?
Do you think that is why he picked you?
Are you grateful, Mandy?
He... He... helped me.
Are you sure it's him?
-Yeah, I'm sure.
-How do I know you're telling the truth?
You could be the one who put me in this room!
I'm in exactly the same situation you're in.
Wrong. Wrong! You've got one thing I don't.
Information. You know who did this.
Now, you either tell me what is really
going on, or I'll cut you with this!
You hear me, I'll cu...
-What?
-It's a two-way mirror.
I can see you.
So, that's what this is. Reality TV.
Don't look at me, I can't help you.
Can you hear me in there? Huh?
I'm having a blast.
This is the most fun I've had without lubricant.
Make sure you're getting everything.
That's not gonna do anything.
-You want to leave it running on us?
-You won't stop it.
That's why we can't cut through these chains
or why you won't break that glass.
Every possible angle
has been pre-thought out by him.
You make it sound like you admire this prick.
To overcome something, you have to
understand what a perfect engine it is.
That's how you fight disease.
The tape told us to find an X.
That X has to be somewhere in this room.
Help me find it.
How can you be the calm doctor when
your wife and kid are out there?
He has them too.
He could be doing anything to them now.
-Are you thinking about that?
-I am thinking about that.
I've been thinking about
the last thing I said to my daughter.
Diana, honey, are you OK?
Diana, honey, can you hear me?
-Mommy...
-What is it, sweet pea?
There's a man in my room.
Oh, honey, are you sure he's not
just hiding in your imagination?
He talked to me.
OK, I'll come and check your room.
I want Daddy. He'll get the scary man.
All right, if you want. Come on.
Larry, sorry to bother you,
but your daughter had a bad dream again.
Just a minute.
She wants you to check her room.
Mm-hm. Just got to finish this paragraph.
Come on, sweetie, I'll check with you.
Nope, I'm done.
See? There's no-one in your room.
There's no such thing as the Bad Man.
-Now can you go to sleep?
-I'm still scared.
You are? Give me your tootsie.
Oh, what a big tootsie.
Remember this one?
This little piggy went to market.
This little piggy stayed home.
This little piggy had roast beef.
This little piggy had none.
This little piggy ran...
Whee! All the way home!
I hate that thing.
Well, I have to go to work, sweetheart.
You know what Daddy's job is like.
Now, come on.
Let's see.
Try and get some sleep, now, OK?
You're not gonna leave us, are you, Daddy?
What?
What are you talking about?
You mean, leave you and Mommy?
No. No, sweetheart, I...
I would never do that.
-Who gave you that idea?
-No-one.
Well, it's not true. OK?
-OK.
-How much do I love you?
-Love you very much.
-That's right. That's right.
-Good night, sweetie.
-Good night, Daddy.
Tomorrow... I'll read you your favorite story.
OK.
I don't know
how much longer I can do this.
-What are you talking about?
-How can you pretend you're happy?
-I am happy.
-That is complete bullshit.
I'd rather you just tell me you hate me.
At least there would be some passion in it.
Would you like to see her?
-She's beautiful.
-Thank you.
You gonna have any more kids?
Ah, we've... talked about it, but er...
.. with our schedules,
it's difficult enough to concentrate on one.
So, where's the lucky wife?
There's another picture
behind the one you're looking at.
It's my favorite one because...
we're all in it together.
Someone, usually me, has to hold the camera,
which means I'm always missing
from the photos.
It's er... It's not here.
What?
This photo you're talking about's not here.
Really? Are you sure?
Yeah. Just...
Why, he... he must have taken it, I...
How can you pretend you're happy?
-I am happy.
-That is complete bullshit.
I'd rather you just tell me you hate me.
At least there would be some passion in it.
We'll talk about this later. OK?
Just leave.
Good night, little girl.
Diana?
Diana!
Mommy!
Shh.
Don't you dare!
Get away from her!
Mommy!
Mommy! Mommy!
Get your fucking hands off my daughter!
Get off of her!
Oh, you little man! I see you.
Does Dr. Gordon know
you're at home with his wife?
I know you know something.
What are you doing in there?
Waiting for the doctor?
I'm waiting for the doctor, too.
Huh!
I never should have let you go.
There was someone
standing outside here watching.
I want to play a game.
Jigsaw piece.
We're gonna be here for a while. Sing.
Hello, Amanda.
Dr. Gordon, are you able to tell us
where were you last night?
You have no idea how your penlight
showed up at the murder scene?
-We checked your alibi, it holds up.
-Isn't that right?
I never should have let you go.
Here we are.
That was er...
quite an amazing story that poor woman told.
Look, I'm...
I'm sorry I can't be of more help
to your investigation.
You know, we arrested a dentist last week.
He liked to play with kids a bit too much.
He lived two blocks from here.
The sewer lines run under this neighborhood,
too... Doctor.
Hello, Amanda.
You don't know me, but I know you.
I want to play a game.
Here's what happens if you lose.
There's a timer at the back
of the device you're wearing.
When the timer goes off...
-I'll catch you guys down there.
-... like a reverse bear trap.
I'll show you.
-Hey, Tapp.
-Hmm?
We're gonna go down to get a beer.
You want to come?
I don't think so. But thanks, anyway.
Well, you know, I always ask.
-There is one key to open the device.
-Have fun.
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
Hey, Tapp.
I don't mean for this to be disrespectful.
Maybe you should find yourself a girlfriend.
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
Look around...
Look around, Amanda. Know that I'm not lying.
You'd better hurry up.
Wait, wait, wait. Sing.
-Get back here.
-What?
What?
Remember 118th Street?
Er... K2K. That gang's territory
was only about four blocks.
Now, listen to this.
Check the records for all fire emergencies
in that area within the last two weeks.
Go -right now.
Mmm!
On Tuesday 17th, a fire alarm went off
in the rear wing of 213 Stygian Street.
It's an old listing.
Used to be a mannequin factory.
Think we have enough for a warrant, though?
Who said anything about a warrant?
Right now?
Why not?
Yeah, why not?
At least we'll have the cover of darkness.
Yeah, well, so will anybody else.
I got you.
What the hell is this?
Shit.
Oh, fuck!
Wait, Sing. Let's see what he's gonna do.
-Why? We fuckin' got him.
-We don't know what he looks like.
-Let's see what he's gonna do.
-No fucking way.
Fuck that, I'm gonna take him.
What the fuck? Shit!
Awake already, Jeff?
I need more-powerful tranquillizers next time.
Don't cry, I've given your life a purpose.
You're a test subject
for something greater than yourself.
Freeze!
-Hold it right there!
-Put your hands in the air!
Now you'll make a choice.
In 20 seconds, the life of this man will be ended.
-Get down here!
-Turn it off!
Sing, stop that thing, I'm taking him down.
Fine.
Move!
-How do you turn it off?
-Tell him, asshole!
One key will unlock it.
-Where is it?
-It's in the box.
-Box?
Fuck!
-Which key? Which key?
-Tell him which key it is!
-Time's running out.
-Shut up and get down here!
Now, asshole!
What's more important to you, Officer?
Arresting me or the life of a human being?
Get down on your knees, asshole!
Hands behind your head!
-Tapp!
-Sick bastard!
-Yes, I'm sick, Officer.
-Tapp, there's a hundred keys here!
Sick from the disease eating away at me inside.
Sick of people
who don't appreciate their blessings.
Sick of those who scoff at the suffering of others.
I'm sick of 'em all!
Tapp!
No! No! Tapp! Tapp!
Shit! You're OK. Let me see.
I'll be back, I'm gonna be back, OK? I'll be back.
Freeze, or I'll shoot!
I had you.
I had you on your knees.
But you're running. You're running.
You're running scared cos...
cos we had you.
We're gonna close this case.
Gonna close it. Right, Sing? Right?
We're gonna close it, Sing.
"X" marks the spot.
We need to search this room again.
What are you doing over there?
Excuse me.
Just because I'm stuck in this room with you
doesn't mean I have to report
to you every 10 seconds.
I really don't see the point
in us not helping one another.
What do you want me to do? I'm on a leash.
That's exactly why we need to talk and think.
-I am thinking!
-Then don't keep me in the dark
about what you're thinking!
Turn off the lights.
What?
Turn them off now, please.
-Why?
-Just turn them off for a second.
Jesus. Behind you.
How come we didn't see that before?
The lights in here hadn't charged it.
It's glow-in-the-dark paint or something.
-Open it!
-It's locked.
The key... the one from my envelope.
Where is it?
Where the fuck? Here.
A cellphone.
The most beautiful invention on this planet.
Make that second-most beautiful invention.
Give me that.
Are you joking? You're going to put something
you found in this room in your mouth?
Yes, I'm willing to risk it.
Give me that sweet cancer.
I don't care, I really don't.
Give me one of those.
The cigarettes
are harmless, I promise.
Smoking is only poisonous when it ends
in bloodshed. Think about this.
You don't need a gun to kill Adam.
May I please have a cigarette?
I'm trying the police.
Shit.
This was meant to receive calls, not make them.
Wait a minute.
This has happened before.
Last night, after I finished at the hospital...
...I was walking back to my car.
I thought I was alone, but...
...I'm sure someone else was there.
Great.
That... thing... was waiting for me.
How did you know to turn off the lights?
-Who cares? It worked.
-Yeah, but how did you know?
Instinct.
Instinct?
-Yeah.
-You know what?
You're a terrible liar.
You say that like you know me.
What else aren't you telling me?
Well, um, let's see...
On my sixth birthday, my best friend at the time,
Scott Tibbs,
stabbed me with a rusty nail -
I didn't tell you that.
My last girlfriend, a feminist vegan punk,
broke up with me because I was too angry.
-One of my toenails is slightly...
-Just stop it!
You knew to turn off these lights.
-Whatever.
-I'm dealing with a juvenile.
-You wanna know?
-Yeah!
Here it is.
Come.
Oh, God.
W-Where did you get this?
It was in your wallet.
Behind the photo of your daughter.
-Why didn't you show me this before?
-I couldn't.
I'm sorry.
What are you doing to them, you bastard?
OK. OK.
OK, I've got to think now.
Think about this -
you don't need a gun to kill Adam.
When there's that much poison in your blood,
the only thing left to do is shoot yourself.
What are you doing?
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
Shh. Adam, listen to me.
I want you to play along with me on this.
You got that?
So, you er... You still want that cigarette?
Um... yeah.
Sure.
There! I've done it!
I've killed him with the poison like you wanted!
Now where's my family?
Where are they?
Aaaargh!
-Aagh! Jesus Christ!
-What are you...?
I-I-I just got electrocuted!
What?
Jesus. That was our way out!
Did you hear what I said? Get this thing off me!
-Get it off!
-Stop acting!
You think I would make that up just to mess up
your stupid fucking charade?
All right, that's it.
Damn it!
I remember everything now.
I remember how I got here.
Oh...
Great.
Is someone there?
I can hear you.
Huh!
What the...?
What the Christ...?
Huh!
Who is that?
Who's in there?
Come out!
I'll kill you, you motherfucker!
Aagh!
Who is this?
Daddy?
Diana.
Daddy, is that you?
Yeah, baby, it's me, I'm here.
I-I'm scared, Daddy.
Don't worry, honey. Everything's gonna be OK.
-Where's Mommy?
-She's here with me.
Let me talk to her, sweetie.
OK? Put Mommy on.
The bad man from my room is here.
He has us tied up...
And he has a gun.
Wh-What man?
Please come home, Daddy.
Hello?
Diana?
Diana!
Larry.
Ali? Is that you?
Is Adam there?
Well, how do you know...
Ali...
What is going on?
Don't believe Adam's lies.
He knows you.
He knew all about you before today.
Hello? Ali?
Ali?
Hello!
Goddamn you!
If you so much as lay a finger on them,
I'll kill you.
You hear me, you son of a bitch? I'll kill you!
Damn!
Are they OK?
My wife, she er... She mentioned your name.
What did she say?
She told me...
not to believe you.
Believe me about what?
She told me you knew me.
Who are you?
You know who I am.
Stop the lies! You're a liar!
I need to know the truth!
I'm a liar?
What did you do last night, Lawrence?
Work at a hospital, saving sick children?
You told me
that after you left your house last night,
you went to work at a hospital.
-That's because it's the truth.
-No, it's not.
Your wife is right, Larry.
You don't recall getting your picture taken
in that parking lot?
I can prove that you didn't go anywhere near
a hospital last night.
It's not the first time I've done it either, Larry.
I've been taking pictures of you for days now.
-Why?
-You want to know what I do?
I get paid to take pictures of rich guys like you,
who go to seedy motels to fuck their secretaries.
Last night, I went to your house.
and watched you leave.
I followed you...
...all the way to that shit-bag hotel.
You've er... had these with you the whole time?
I found them in there with the hacksaws.
I don't know how they got there.
-Right! You're so full of it!
-Face it, Larry, we're both bullshitters!
But my camera isn't. It doesn't know how to lie.
It only shows you what's put right in front of it.
Just out of curiosity,
what did you do in that motel room?
You got out of there pretty fast.
Why did you um...
deem it necessary to page me
when you knew I was at home?
I didn't know if you were going to make it.
I gave you a precise time at which to page me.
You can't do that.
It's not like I know the rules for this sort of stuff.
-What's wrong, Dr. Gordon?
-Look, um...
It was wrong of me to make you come here.
-But I thought we've...
-No, no. Please.
I'm sorry.
You tell anyone you were here?
No.
Hello.
-It's for you.
-For me?
Hello.
I know what you're doing... Doctor.
I...
I have to go.
-What happened?
-I gotta go.
Who was it?
Who was what?
The person who paid you to follow me.
Who was it?
He calls himself Bob and he gives me
the money upfront. 200 bucks a night.
If I'd known I'd end up here,
I'd have asked for a lot more.
What does that mean?
Does that mean you saw what happened to me?
What I saw was you get into your car. That's it.
I didn't ask your name.
I didn't know who you were.
I don't know how I got here.
I don't know how you got here.
I took the shots and went straight home
to develop them.
Next thing I know, I'm chained to a pipe
in some prehistoric bathroom, staring at
the guy I've been taking shots of.
Clearly, whoever paid you to take pictures of me
is the one who put us here.
Maybe.
Of course it is! What did he look like?
-Just a guy.
-Was he tall? Skinny? Obese?
-I don't take notes.
-You must remember something about him.
-I can't.
-You don't remember a thing about the guy?
-I told you, I...
-For fuck's sake! I give up!
He's a tall black guy.
He's got a scar around his neck, OK?
Tapp.
-Detective Tapp.
-Whoa.
The guy who paid me to take these photos
was not a cop.
No, no. He was discharged from the police force.
He broke down after his partner was killed.
But that didn't stop him harassing me.
The guy became obsessed.
He's convinced I must have somehow
been involved with the murders.
He's crazy. And you helped him.
You took money from him to invade my privacy.
How could you do that?
-Call it my need to eat.
-Right.
Right. You know what, Adam,
you're not a victim of this game.
-You're part of it.
-Oh, really?
This cop thinks you're the one behind it all.
I told you, he's not a cop.
He's a bottom feeder, just like you!
What are you pissed off about?
The fact I took shots of you
or the fact that I took shots of you
while you cheated on your wife?
-I did not cheat on her!
-What do you care what I think anyway?
I don't give a crap if you covered yourself in
peanut butter and had a 15-hooker gangbang.
How did I get here? I had...
I had everything in order.
My whole life was in perfect order.
Sweetheart, are you OK?
Mommy just needs you to be
really, really, really, really strong right now.
I'm not gonna let anybody hurt you.
You got that?
OK. That's my good girl.
Hey, was there someone else
at your house last night.
besides your wife and daughter?
-No.
-Well, there's someone here.
I know him.
-Zep.
-Who?
His name is Zep. He's an orderly at my hospital.
Zep.
You perverted little psychopath.
I'm gonna take great pleasure
in seeing you pay for this,
you bastard fuck!
Look.
We're out of time.
Shh, sweetie... sweetie.
-Mommy, help me!
-Ssh...
Dr. Gordon's time is up.
Now I've got to do what I've got to do, and...
.. I'm afraid it has to be you
that tells him he failed.
Is that you, Zep, you bastard?
I know it's you, you son of a bitch!
La... Larry.
Ali?
You failed.
Hello?
-You!
-Wait.
Don't move! Stay on the ground.
Give me... Give me the phone.
Give it to me!
Larry?
Ali! Honey, are you all right?
No... No, we're not. Get down!
-Larry, where are you?
-I don't know.
I'm being held captive in a room somewhere.
Wh-What are you talking about?
-I'm so sorry, Ali.
-Honey, we need you here.
So sorry for everything. It's my fault.
Forgive me, I've always been happy with you.
Mommy!
Aagh!
Jesus!
Ali!
Mommy!
Ali! Ali!
Aargh! Aaargh!
Freeze!
Oh, no!
What the fuck?
-Yaaaa!
-Ya!
Argh! Urgh!
Mrs. Gordon?
Diana!
I'm gonna kill your husband now, Mrs. Gordon.
Lawrence!
Lawrence, get up!
Lawrence! Get up!
I need you!
Oh, thank God, I thought you were dead.
He... He... He electrocuted me.
I told you.
The same thing happened to me. See?
I wasn't lying. See?
Fuck this shit!
No!
Lawrence, calm down.
-There must be a way out of this.
-Shut up!
Just shut up! My family needs me!
No! God!
God! No!
Argh!
Lawrence! I have a family too.
I don't see them, that's my mistake.
It's a mistake I'd like to fix.
I'm gonna kill you, you sick asshole.
Lawrence!
Stop it.
Lawrence, just calm down.
There's a way out of here.
There's a way out!
Lawrence!
No! What are you... No!
Oh, my God! Lawrence!
What are you doing?
What... are you doing?
What are you... What are you...
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Lawrence, don't! No!
No, Lawrence, please!
I'm begging you!
Lawrence! It's not me who did this to you!
-You have to die.
-No! I want to live!
-I want to live!
-I'm sorry.
-My family...
-Argh!
There! I've done it!
Now show them to me!
Show them to me.
-Thank you very much, Officer.
-Larry?
Did you get through to him?
-There's still no answer.
-It's all right. I've called the police.
Everything is OK.
You bastard!
I'll fucking kill you! I'll fucking kill you!
You fucking bastard!
I'll fucking kill you!
I'll fucking kill you.
You're too late.
-Why?
-It's the rules.
Argh!
You're gonna be all right.
You're just wounded...
wounded in the shoulder.
I... have... to go.... and get help.
If.. If I don't g...g... get help....
I'm going to bleed to death.
Don't leave me!
No!
No! No!
No! Ow!
Don't... Don't worry.
I'll bring someone back.
I promise.
Lawrence! Lawrence!
We're gonna be okay?
I... I wouldn't lie to you.
Key.
Key! Key! Key!
Hello, Mr. Hindle.
Or as they called you around the hospital...
...Zep.
I want you to make a choice.
There's a slow-acting poison
coursing through your system
which only I have the antidote for.
Will you murder a mother and her child
to save yourself?
Dr. Gordon's time is up.
Mrs. Gordon!
Listen carefully, if you will. There are rules.
-Why?
-It's the rules.
The key to that chain is in the bathtub.
He's a very interesting person.
His name is John.
He has an inoperable frontal-lobe tumor.
-I'm sick from disease eating away at me inside.
-Sounds like our friend Jigsaw.
I'm sick of people who don't
appreciating their blessings.
Looks like our guy likes to book himself
front-row seats to his own sick little games.
Hello, Mark, Paul, Amanda,
Zep, Adam, Dr. Gordon.
I want to play a game.
Most people are so ungrateful to be alive.
But not you.
Not any more.
Aaargh! Aaargh!
- Game over.
- Aaargh!
Aaargh! Aaargh!
Don't! Don't!
Don't! Aaargh!
Aaargh! Aaargh!
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitles
Subtitles E
Subtitles En
Subtitles Enc
Subtitles Enco
Subtitles Encod
Subtitles Encode
Subtitles Encoded
Subtitles Encoded b
Subtitles Encoded by
Subtitles Encoded by :
M
Ma
Subtitles Encoded by :
Man
Mann
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu
Mannu S
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sa
Mannu Sad
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sada
Mannu Sadan
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
e
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@i
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il :
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : M
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Ma
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Man
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mann
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.S
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sa
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sad
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sada
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadan
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@g
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gm
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gma
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmai
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.c
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.co
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
M
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mb
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl.
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+9
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-9
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-92
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-925
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-9253
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-92531
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-925312
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-9253127
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-92531272
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-925312726
Subtitles Encoded by :
Mannu Sadana
eM@il : Mannu.Sadana@gmail.com
Mbl. #+91-9253127265