[Fidel Castro
Speaking Spanish]
[Cheering]
[Speaking Spanish]
Mira. Mira.
Mira. Mira. Mira.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Man]
Okay, so what do you call yourself?
- Como se llama?
Antonio Montana.
And you, what you call yourself?
- Where'd you learn to speak
the English, Tony?
- Uh, in a school.
And my father, he was, uh,
from the United States.
Just like you, ya know?
He was a Yankee. Uh, he used to
take me a lot to the movies.
l learn. l watch the guys
like Humphrey Bogart,
James Cagney.
They, they teach me to talk.
l like those guys.
l always know one day
l'm comin' here, United States.
- So where's your old man now?
- He dead. He die.
Sometime. Somewhere.
- Mother?
- She dead too.
- What kind of work
you do in Cuba, Tony?
- Ah, you know, things.
l was, uh--
This, that.
Construction business.
l work a lot with my hands.
l was in the army.
Any family in the States, Tony?
Any cousins, brother-in-law, anybody?
Nobody. Everybody's dead.
- [Man #2]
You ever been to jail, Tony?
- Me? Jail?
No way. No.
Been in a mental hospital?
Oh, yeah.
On the boat coming over.
What about homosexuality, Tony?
You like men, huh?
You like to dress up
like a woman?
What the fuck is wrong with this guy?
He kidding me or what?
Just answer the questions, Tony?
Okay. No. Okay?
Fuck no!
Arrested for vagrancy?
Marijuana?
- Never, man.
- Heroin?
- Cocaine?
- No.
Where'd you get the beauty scar,
tough guy? Eatin' pussy?
How am l gonna get
a scar like that eating pussy?
- This was when l was a kid, ya know?
- Mm-hmm.
You should see the other kid.
You can't recognize him.
And this?
Oh, that's nothing, man.
That's for my sweetheart.
Sweetheart, my ass! We've been
seein' more and more of these.
Some kind of code
these guys used in the can.
Pitchfork means an assassin
or somethin'.
You wanna tell us about it,
or do you wanna take a little trip
to the detention center?
Okay, you got me.
l was in the can one time.
For buying dollars. Big, big deal.
- That's pretty funny, Tony.
- Well, that's true.
lt was a Canadian tourist.
Hmm? What'd ya do? Mug him first?
Get him outta here!
- Come on!
- So l fuck up!
Let me talk to this guy. Please!
Let me talk to him a minute.
You a Communist?
Huh?
How'd you like it, man?
They tell you all the time what to do,
what to think, what to feel.
Do you wanna be like a sheep? Like all
those other people? Baah. Baah.
l don't have to listen
to this bullshit!
You wanna work eight,
ten fucking hours?
You own nothing, you got nothing!
Do you want a chivato on
every corner looking after you?
Watching everything you do?
Everything you say, man?
Do you know l eat octopus
three times a day?
l got fucking octopus
coming out of my fucking ears.
l got the fuckin' Russian shoes
my feet's comin' through.
How you like that?
What, you want me to stay there
and do nothing?
l'm no fuckin' criminal, man.
l'm no puta or thief.
l'm Tony Montana,
a political prisoner from Cuba.
- And l want
my fuckin' human rights, now!
- [Slams Desk]
Just like the President
Jimmy Carter says. Okay?
Carter should see this human right.
He's really good.
- What do you say, Harry?
- l don't believe a word of this shit!
They all sound the same to me.
That son of a bitch Castro
is shittin' all over us.
Send this bastard to Freedomtown.
Let them take a look at him.
- Get him outta here.
- You know somethin'?
You can send me anywhere. Here, there,
this, that; it don't matter.
- There's nothing you can do
to me that Castro has not done.
- Get him outta here!
- [Man Sighs] So?
- [Tony] So?
What'd you tell him?
l told him what you told me.
Told 'em we were-- l was in sanitation.
They didn't go for it.
- Sanitation?
- Yeah.
l told you to tell 'em
you was in a sanitarium,
not sanitation.
- Sanitarium. Yeah.
- You didn't tell me that.
No, l told you to say you had T.B.
and you was in a sanitarium.
You was cured.
- That l was cured?
When did you tell me that?
- Come on.
- You should have kept
your mouth shut anyway.
- Oh, okay.
They'd have thought you was
a horse and let you out.
/ Vamos a la bailar /
/ Esta noche /
/ Vamos acostar /
/ Hasta la mañana /
// [Woman Continues Singing
ln Spanish]
[Chattering ln Spanish]
¡Ay! Por favor, por favor.
Mucho cuidado.
// [Humming]
/ Que vamos a bailar //
Tony!
Montana!
Tony Montana!
Ven acá, man. Come here.
-  ¿Qué te pasa?
- Come here, man. l gotta talk to you.
Come on, man.
lt's important.
- So close, man.
- Come on.
- Come on, man. l gotta talk to you.
- Where are you going, man?
- Leave him alone.
- l got better things to do.
You're chicken, man.
You almost made it.
Are you ready
for some good news?
Sure. What you got, man?
We can be outta this place
in 30 days.
Not only that, but we got
a green card and a job in Miami.
Now are we made
or are we made, man?
What do we gotta do?
Go to Cuba and hit the beard or what?
- No, man, somebody else.
- You're kidding?
- No.
- You're not kidding?
Guy named Rebenga, man.
Emilio Rebenga.
Rebenga?
- Coño, man. l know that name.
- Yeah?
- He's political.
- Yeah.
Well, he's coming in here today, man.
Castro just sprung him.
This guy, man, was one of the top dogs
for Fidel in the early days.
But Castro felt like he couldn't
trust him anymore and threw him in jail.
But while he was on top,
he tortured a few guys to death.
And one of the guy's brother
is a rich guy in Miami now,
and he wants the favor repaid.
That's where we come in.
He's ugly, man.
[Laughs]
Yeah.
You tell your guys in Miami--
your friend--
it'd be a pleasure.
l kill a Communist for fun,
but for a green card,
l gonna carve him up real nice.
[People Shouting]
[Dogs Barking]
[Glass Shatters]
[Siren Wailing]
[Shouting Continues]
¡Libertad! ¡Libertad!
¡Libertad!
¡Rebenga!
¡Libertad! ¡Libertad!
[All Chanting]
¡Libertad!
¡Libertad! ¡Libertad!
[Chanting Continues]
- ¡Rebenga!
- [Groans]
From a friend you fucked!
[Chanting Continues]
[Shouting Continues]
[People Chattering]
That face.
That's nice.
- That doesn't look like me.
- Hey, that looks pretty, man.
Woo-hoo!
[Plates, Utensils Banging]
[Tony Mutters]
¡Coño! Fuck!
- ¿Qué pasó, man?
- ¿Qué pasa, man?
Your big shot friend better come up
with something soon.
l didn't come to the United States
to break my fuckin' back.
- Hey, he's coming, okay?
What do you want from me?
- ¡Coño! Fuckin' thing!
l told you--
- Qué le pasa a este hombre ahora?
What's wrong?
- Qué voy a hacer, compadre?
Jamón. Ponle jamón.
[Shouting ln Spanish, lndistinct]
¡Ay, Dios mío! ¡Mira eso!
Look at that one.
That one right there in the pink.
She's beautiful, man.
Look at those titties.
Look at that punk with her.
What's he got that l don't have?
Well, he's very handsome,
for one thing, you know?
[Chuckles]
l mean, look at the way he dresses, man.
Come on. That's style.
Flash, pizzazz. And a little
coke money doesn't hurt nobody.
¡Coño! Look at this.
Fuckin' onions.
They oughta be pickin' gold
from the street.
¡Ay, cabrón!
Hey, there's two guys
looking for you out there.
Uno grande y uno pequen'o.
That's him, man.
That's El Mono. l told you.
Don't stay too fuckin' long.
We've got a lot of work to do, so--
// [Salsa]
[Laughs]
- Qué se cuenta, señores?
Caballero.
- Qué se cuenta?
Waldo, good to see you, man.
This is my friend, Tony Montana,
l've been telling you about.
- Sí.
- Tony, that's Omar Suárez and
that's Waldo Rojas over there.
- - Qué tal?
- l got something for you.
Yeah? What do we gotta do?
Gotta unload a boat. Marijuana.
25 tons. You get 500 each.
- 500? Eh? That's great, eh?
- You gotta be kidding.
Five hundred?
Who do you think we are?
Baggage handlers?
The going rate on a boat
is a thousand a night. You know that.
First you gotta work
your way up to 500.
After what l did for you guys
in Freedomtown? What was that?
That Rebenga hit
was a game of dominoes?
- That was something else.
- Shut up! Take it easy.
What's with this dishwasher, chico?
[Laughing]
Don't he think we could've got
some other space cadet to hit
Rebenga cheaper? Fifty bucks.
Then why didn't you?
And don't be callin' me
no fuckin' dishwasher,
or l'll kick your monkey ass--
- Who the fuck are you?
- You can't do that, man!
- The Colombians!
- Ah, sí.
Okay, okay--
All right, big man!
You wanna make some big bucks?
Let's see how tough you are.
You know something about cocaine?
¡Digame!
What, you kidding me or what?
There's a bunch of Colombians
coming in Friday.
New guys. They say they got
two keys for us for openers.
Pure coke. Hotel in Miami Beach.
l want you to go over there.
And if it's what they say it is,
you pay 'em and bring it back.
You do that, you got five grand.
Go, pay 'em,
bring it back, yeah?
[Sniffing]
You know how to handle
a machine gun?
Yeah, man.
We were in the army.
- You gonna need a couple other guys.
- That's no problem.
Be at Hector's bodega at noon Friday.
You get the buy money then.
And, chico,
if anything happens
to that buy money-- ¡y pobreci--!
my boss is gonna stick
your heads up your asses faster
than a rabbit gets fucked!
l'm scared.
[Tires Screeching]
- Man, you're pushing your luck.
- Don't worry.
- That was dumb.
- Mi hijo, you worry too much.
You're gonna have a heart attack.
You act like that guy's
doing you a favor or somethin'.
- What's this with the Colombians?
- What does it matter?
What does it-- He says Colombians,
and you make these eyes--
l don't like fuckin' Colombians!
Okay?
Hey, hey, what you guys doing?
There's a lot of dishes to be washed.
Wash 'em yourself, man.
- l retire!
- What the fuck you gonna do then now?
- Don't come back here!
- l gotta look after my investment!
- Fuck you, guys!
- Close the shop!
// [Radio Playing Salsa]
[Manny] Mira eso, man.
Look at those tits, man.
She's begging for it.
What? Are you fuckin' crazy?
She's 103 years old.
Not that one, man!
That one!
- Which one?
- Come on. Move the fuckin' car.
- Okay. Okay.
- We're at a stop sign.
- ¡Coño! ¡Qué rica!
- Come on. We're just staying
loose up here, okay?
You gotta stay loose. You can't worry.
You're gonna have a heart attack.
- Just play it cool. Miami Beach.
- Miami Beach!
// [Radio Continues]
Okay, man. The money stays
in the trunk 'til l come out.
You got it?
Me, nobody else. Okay.
l not out in 15 minutes,
something's wrong.
Okay? Room nine.
You ready?
- Sure thing.
- Okay, let's go.
[Horn Honks]
[Man On TV Chattering]
¡Hola!
- Cómo va todo?
Entra. Entra.
- Qué te pasa, man?
[Siren Wailing On TV]
Okay. You mind
leaving the door open?
- So as my brother-in-law
sees everything is okay.
- Sure. No problem.
No problem.
Hello. This is Marta.
Marta, hello.
l am Hector.
And l am Tony.
Tony.
So, Omar says you're okay.
Yeah? Good.
Omar's okay.
Okay.
So, you got the money?
You got the stuff?
Sure l have the stuff, but l don't
have it right here with me now.
l got it close by.
No te apures.
Well, l don't have
the money either, man.
l have it close by too.
Where? ln the car?
- No, not in the car, man.
- No?
How 'bout you?
Where you have your stuff?
- Not far.
- [Horn Honks]
Okay. You want me to come in?
We start over again?
[Chuckling]
Where you from, Tony?
What the fuck difference does
it make where l'm from, man?
¡Coño! Cogelo.
Take it easy, man.
l, uh-- l just want to get to know
who l do business with.
You'll get to know me once
you start doing business with me
and stop fucking around, Hector.
- Okay?
- Mira, Antonio--
- [Tony] What's the story?
- Tony!
¡Quieto!
¡No te muevas, cabroncito!
En el baño.
¡Ahora!
You know, frog face,
you just fucked yourself.
- You steal from me, you're dead.
- Yeah?
Okay.
You want to give me the cash...
or do l kill
your brother first,
before l kill you?
Why don't you try sticking
your head up your ass?
See if it fits.
Yeah? Okay.
Sube el volumen.
[TV Volume Rises]
Yeah, it's very important.
- [Woman On TV]
l understand. lmportant.
- Thank you.
[Man]
You forecasted an earthquake in the
three-to-four-point range this morning.
We had an earthquake in the
- l'm impressed.
- Thank you, sir.
However, isn't it
rather slender evidence--
[TV Continues, lndistinct]
// [Radio]
/ Oh, shake it up tonight /
- / Shakin' up our lives /
- Beautiful skin. l like it.
- / Shake it up tonight /
- l like the way you--
/ Tell me that you love me
Tell me that you'll stay the night /
l don't what l'm supposed
to do today, but--
[Chain Saw Motor Revving]
Hey! Antonio!
¡Mira!
Watch what happens to your friend.
You don't want this to happen
to you, gimme the money.
[Muffled Screams]
// [Radio Continues]
Come on, come on.
¡Coño!
/ Got to have you every day //
[Chain Saw Revving]
Now the leg, huh?
Ya me voy.
Ya es hora, man.
Let's do it, man.
Come on.
Okay.
No te apures. Okay?
We are gonna be all right.
[TV Continues Blaring]
Okay, ''Caracicatriz.''
You can die too.
lt makes no difference to me.
Okay, Chi Chi.
Sobra allí.
Sí, man.
Last chance, pendejo!
Fuck you!
[Spits]
[TV Blaring]
[Chain Saw Revving]
¡Ahora tú!
¡Vete!
- [Groans]
- You okay?
Yeah, man.
lt went in and out.
- [People Screaming]
- Okay, take him out of here, quick!
Chi Chi! Chi Chi!
Get the yeyo.
Está bien.
Está bien, Tony.
[People Screaming]
[Groans]
¡Cabrón! ¡Oye!
- Your turn.
- l kill you!
- Die!
- [People Screaming]
[Siren Wailing]
[Engine Starts]
Hurry up! Get in! Come on.
Come on. Come on. Let's go!
Close that door!
[Tires Screeching]
Yeah.
Bunch of cowboys.
Somebody fucked up.
[Man] Yeah, well,
l'll check it out right away.
Yeah, you do that, Omar.
You do that.
- You still got the money?
- Yeah.
And l got the yeyo.
- You got the yeyo?
- Yeah, right.
- Bring it here.
- Fuck you.
l am takin' it to López myself.
Yeah. Not you, me.
Gracias.
This fuckin' guy.
Frank López.
Tony Montana.
- Hey, Tony Montana.
- Mr. López. lt's a real pleasure.
You can call me Frank.
Everybody calls me Frank.
My Little League team.
Even the fucking prosecutors
around town, they all call me Frank.
- Okay, Frank.
- How are you?
- Manny Ribera.
- [Mutters]
- He caught one on the job.
- Went right through.
We heard about that. Omar, he tells me
great things about you guys.
Yeah. Yeah, well,
Omar's okay.
Not to mention, of course,
the nice job you did for me.
- That Commie son of a bitch--
- Well, you don't have to mention that.
- That was fun.
- That was fun?
- Damn right.
- [Laughing] That was fun.
- [Chuckling]
- Sometime it fun.
Hey, what do you want to drink?
Scotch, gin, rum? What do you like?
- Gin is fine. Want some? Two gins.
- Gin, gin, gin.
Hey, l need a guy with steel
in his balls, Tony.
A guy like you. And l need him
around me all the time.
You, Tony and
your compadre here.
Here's the stuff.
Two keys.
lt cost my friend Angel his life.
Here's your money.
My gift to you.
l'm sorry about your friend, Tony.
lf people would do business
the right way, there'd be
no fuck-ups like this.
Don't think l don't appreciate
the gesture.
You're gonna find you stay loyal
in this business,
you're gonna move up.
You're gonna move up fast.
- ¡Salud!
- ¡Salud! ¡Salud!
Then you're gonna find out your biggest
problem is not bringing in the stuff,
but what to do with all
the fucking cash!
[Laughing]
l hope l have
that problem some day.
You're gonna have that problem,
don't worry. Sit over here.
[Laughing]
Where the hell's Elvira already?
lt's late.
Go find her, will you?
Jesus! Fucking broad.
She spends half her life dressing,
the other half, undressing.
- [All Laughing]
- Gotta get her in between.
- [Man] She's coming.
- Yeah.
You gotta jump on her
when she's not looking. [Chuckles]
- That's the best time.
- [Laughing]
What are you guys
doing tonight?
You wanna go to a nice restaurant
with me? You hungry?
Yeah. l could eat a horse.
- Okay, they're gonna cook you a horse.
- l'll eat it.
[Chuckling]
Well, tell me, where'd they get you?
Right there in the side?
lt's nothing. lt went right through me.
lt hit the wall.
l ran out of bullets
like an asshole,
and when l'm changing the clip,
the guy who l thought l killed
but was not dead, shot me.
The guy was behind me.
l killed him.
-How many bullets you catch?
-Bullets? One bullet, nine millimeter.
[Manny Continues Talking,
lndistinct]
[Frank]
Elvira, where the hell you been?
lt's 10:00. l'm starving.
You're always hungry.
You should try starving.
Where you going? Come on.
Come over here! l want you to meet
a friend of mine. Come on.
Tony Montana. Elvira.
- Hello.
- Manny Ribera. Elvira.
So, there are five of us.
Where are we having dinner?
l thought we'd go
to the Babylon Club.
- Again?
- Again.
You know, Frank, if anyone ever wanted
to assassinate you,
you wouldn't be
too hard to find.
Assassinate me?
Who the hell would want to kill me?
[Laughing]
l got nothing but friends!
You never know, do you? Maybe
the catcher on your Little League team.
The catcher? That son of a bitch,
he didn't get a base hit all season.
l should kill him!
[Laughing]
/ Rush, rush to the yeyo /
/ Buzz, buzz doing the yeyo /
- / Yo, yo no yeyo /
- / Loco /
/ Rush, rush to the yeyo /
/ Now l'll never
take a chance before /
/ And now he's in a hurry /
/ Better, better
make your mind up, boy /
/ Rush, rush to the yeyo /
/ Buzz, buzz, buzz doing the yeyo /
[Frank]
Hey! [Chuckles]
You know who that is?
Luis and Miguel Echeverría.
They got the biggest distribution setup
from here to Houston,
Tucson,
all down that way.
What do you think of that, huh?
Look.
You see that fat bastard?
That's Nacho Contreras.
El Gordo!
He's got more cash
than anybody in this place.
He's a real chazzer!
[Laughing]
You-- You know what
a chazzer is?
No, Frank, you tell me.
What is a chazzer?
lt's a Yiddish word
for ''pig.''
See, the guy, he wants more than what
he needs. He don't fly straight no more.
So, it comes down to one thing,
Tony boy,
and you never forget.
Lesson number one:
Don't underestimate...
the other guy's greed!
[Laughing]
Lesson number two:
Don't get high on your own supply.
That's right. Lesson number two:
'Course not everybody
follows the rules, huh?
[Chuckling]
Your champagne, Mr. López.
- That is '64?
- The best, Mr. López.
Okay. Omar, you pour it, and you bring
another bottle right away, will you?
- Merci, Mr. López.
- [Laughing]
$550 for this bottle, Tony.
What do you think of that?
- That's pretty good.
- For a bunch of fucking grapes.
[Laughing]
So, here's to old friends
and to new friends.
Ahhh. [Sniffles]
How you like it, Tony?
- Oh, that's good, Frank.
- That's good, huh?
- Like you say, man.
- [Laughing] That's good!
Hey, l'm gonna get you
new clothes too.
l'm gonna get you
$550 suits...
so you look real sharp.
'Cause l want you
to work for me.
l want you and your boys
to work with Omar here.
Huh? We are going--
We are going to do something--
something big next month.
We are running a string of mules
from Colombia.
You do good on that,
there'll be some other things.
- That sounds like fun to me, Frank.
- [Chuckling]
You want a cigar?
So, you wanna dance, Frank, or you
wanna sit here and have a heart attack?
[Continues Chuckling]
Who? Me dance? Hey, l think l want
to have a heart attack instead.
- [Men Laughing]
- Well, don't foam into the Donnie P.
How about you?
What? You want me to dance?
Yeah, sure, go on, Tony.
You dance.
- Go on. Have some fun.
- Okay.
[Chuckles]
What do you think of him?
- l think he's a fucking peasant!
- [Chuckles]
[Frank]
Yeah.
But you get a guy
like that on your side,
he breaks his back for you.
/ She's on fire /
[People Chattering, Laughing]
/ With the heat of the beat
driving me for a fool /
/ She's on fire /
/ And the name of the game
is to fuel her flame /
/ She's on fire /
/ Fire, fire, fire /
/ Fire //
- What's your name?
- What?
What's your name?
Elvira what?
- Hancock.
- What?
- Hancock!
- Hancock?
Sounds like a bird. Hancock.
Flyin' around.
Where you from?
- Baltimore.
- What?
- Baltimore!
- Baltimore?
- Where's that?
- Look, it doesn't
really matter, all right!
l'm just trying
to be friendly, you know?
l have enough friends. l don't
need another one. Especially
one who got off a banana boat.
Banana boat?
Hold it. You got the wrong guy.
l don't come off no banana boat.
Okay?
You're thinkin'
of someone else maybe.
Aren't you part
of the Cuban crime wave?
What you talking crazy for?
l'm a political refugee here.
- Okay? So take it easy.
Don't talk crazy.
- Sorry.
l didn't know you were so sensitive
about your diplomatic status.
Hey, coño.
What is your problem, baby?
You're good-looking. You got
a beautiful body, beautiful legs,
a beautiful face,
all these guys in love with you.
Only you got a look in your eye
like you haven't been fucked in a year!
Hey, José,
who, why, when and how l fuck
is none of your business, okay?
Now you're talking to me, baby.
That l like. Keep it coming.
Don't call me ''baby''!
l'm not your baby.
Not yet, but you gotta
give me some time.
[Scoffs]
Even if l were blind,
desperate, starved and begging for it
on a desert island,
you'd be the last thing
l'd ever fuck.
That chick he's with--
- Yeah?
- She like me.
Oh, she like you, huh?
How do you know?
l know.
The eyes, chico.
They never lie.
What, are you serious?
Serious?
What do you think?
- Man, that's the boss's lady, okay?
- The boss's lady.
- You're gonna get us killed.
- Fuck you, man. The boss's lady.
That guy's soft.
Look in his face.
The booze and the cuncha
tell him what to do.
Don't fuckin' go crazy on me, okay?
Just remember last year at this time
we were in a fucking cage, okay?
You remember.
l'd like to forget that.
l say be happy with what you got.
You be happy.
- Me, l want what's coming to me.
- What's coming to you?
The world, chico,
and everything in it.
Oh, man.
[People Chattering]
- [Man] Spike it!
- [Woman] l got it!
This is paradise.
This is paradise,
l'm telling you.
- This town like a great big pussy
just waitin' to get fucked.
- [Chuckles]
l'm tellin' you.
l shoulda come here ten years ago.
l'd have been a millionaire
by this time.
- [Slurping]
- By this time, l'd have had
my own boat, my own car,
- Mmm.
- my own golf course.
You know what l want?
l thought of this the other day.
A line of blue jeans, right?
With my name written
on the back of chicks' asses.
How that? Hmm?
That sound
completely crazy to me, man.
Look at that. Look, look.
You're missing the sights.
That's what you're doing.
We're missing the action here.
¡Oye!
[Speaking Spanish]
You wanna have some ice cream
with my friend and me?
Get lost, greaseball!
- Look at that.
- lce cream?
- That's right.
- You said ice cream?
- Girls like ice cream.
- Oh, come on, man.
That's not gonna work.
You can't do it that way.
l'm telling you.
You know how you pick up chicks
in this country?
- What the fuck was that,
what you just did?
- That's what you do.
That is disgusting.
- Watch.
- Eeew, look at that fucking thing.
Look like a lizard.
Like a bug coming out of your mouth.
[Chuckles]
That figures you wouldn't understand.
But the women in this country,
when you do that, they know.
- They know what?
- They understand.
They-- They go crazy.
lt'll take a lot of practice,
but you gotta learn, because women love
when you suck the pussy.
Look at that.
¡Ay, coño!
She lookin' at us.
[Manny]
Mira eso.
- Go ahead. You think
you can do it with her?
- l think l can.
- You wanna try it with her?
- Why not?
- You gonna watch me?
- l'm lookin' at you. Go ahead.
- You're not gonna do it.
- Watch this.
- Come on. l'm with you, man.
- Okay.
l'm gonna get her.
Go ahead, Romeo!
Do your thing.
- Just be quiet. Just hang back.
- Romeo!
You're looking very pretty
today. Yes, you. l've been
watching you from over there.
You wanna see something funny? Hey,
take a look over there. See that man?
Watch that guy.
l gotta sit down here.
l gotta watch my friend. He gonna
stick his tongue out to that girl.
- Look at that. ¡Ay, coño!
- You're sick!
You see what happened to him? Hey!
- You know, if l wasn't
a nice guy, l'd crack you.
- She's too big for you.
- Causing trouble like that. Come on.
- Bitch!
- What l try to tell you?
- Lesbian!
What l try to tell you? This country,
you gotta make the money first.
Then when you get the money,
you get the power.
Then when you get the power,
then you get the woman.
That's why you gotta
make your own moves.
That's the one l rented.
No, no, no. They-- They--
That's her, man. There she is.
- Oh, oh, oh.
- 'Bout time.
Frank got held up at the golf course.
He told me to pick you up.
Uh, he said he'd meet us
at the track later.
He said to bet on lce Cream
in the first, by the way.
ln that thing?
You must be kidding.
What you talkin' about?
That's a Cadillac.
- l wouldn't be
caught dead in that thing.
- Aw, come on.
Hey, you know, l mean,
it's got a few years.
- [Chuckles]
- But it's a cream puff.
lt looks like
somebody's nightmare.
So, you like this better?
Yeah.
- lt like one of them tigers
from lndia, huh?
- Tigers, no?
Crazy guy.
You know what he's been doin'?
Dragging me to the zoo
to look at tigers.
He says he's gonna buy one now.
You do that, and you're not
gonna have any friends left.
- Not that you have any now--
- You're gonna like that tiger, man.
You gonna drive around with a tiger
in your passenger seat?
Maybe. Some lady tiger.
- How much?
- 43,000, fully equipped.
- That all?
- Machine gun turrets are extra.
He's a funny guy.
Come here, Manny.
Bullet-proof this, okay?
And this here and here.
- [Manny] Okay.
- And the windows.
Okay.
- And get me one of them phones,
you know, with a scrambler.
- And a scrambler.
And a radio with scanners, to pick out
flying saucers, stuff like that.
- Don't forget the fog lights.
- Oh!
ln case l get caught in the swamp.
That's a good idea.
[Horn Blaring]
Get out of the way, lady!
l'm tryin' to drive here!
l thought you were
taking me to Frank.
We got an hour.
You hungry?
No, but l'm bored.
Well, that figures.
- Hey, check it out, Manny, okay?
And pay the guy.
- Yeah.
And, uh, you take a taxi.
Meet me at the track, okay?
- Good doin' business with you.
- Mr. Montana.
Oh, God!
l wouldn't buy the car
if you didn't like it.
Plannin' on driving the girls crazy,
aren't you, Tony?
Oh, yeah.
You know who?
And what would Frank say?
l like Frank, you know?
Only l like you better.
[Snorting]
- You got some for me?
- Sure.
- [Tapping]
- Okay.
[Snorting]
- [Mutters]
- Okay.
Don't get confused, Tony.
l don't fuck around with the help.
Okay.
You wanna play that way with me,
l play with you.
Shit.
- Would you kiss me if l wear the hat?
- No!
Playtime is over, okay?
[Laughing]
Okay.
[Knocking]
Mamá.
Antonio.
Long time.
No postcards from jail?
¡Coño! Gina.
[Gasps]
Tony?
- Oh, man, look at you. [Chuckles]
- [Laughs]
Hey, you're beautiful.
- l didn't--
- Mamá, look at those eyes, huh?
- Look at that. She looks like me.
- [Chuckles]
You know the last time l saw you,
you was like that.
You looked like a little boy.
But now look at you.
Uh, l got something for you.
[Exhales Deeply]
For you.
This no big deal.
Oh, Tony!
[Crying]
- [Laughs]
- Oooh, Tony!
l never thought
l'd see you again, you know?
You think they're gonna keep
a guy like me down?
Well, no.
[Laughs] No.
[Sighs]
You look so good.
Look. You open that up.
Open it.
- For me?
- l think so.
lt's nothing much,
you know. Nothing.
- [Sighs]
- See?
Do you see what's written
on the back?
On the back?
[Sighs]
- ''Always.''
- ''Always.'' lt's beautiful, Tony!
So Mamá is still working
in the factory,
and l'm working part-time
in a beauty parlor.
l'm doing hair, Tony.
Do you remember Hiram González?
His father owned that barbershop.
lt's his place.
Plus l go to junior college.
Miami Dade.
And in two more years,
l get my cosmetology license.
- And then l'll be making enough money--
- Surprise!
All that's over...
starting today.
- Why?
- My kid sister don't have to work
in no beauty parlor,
and Mamá, she don't have to sew
in no factory.
Your son made it, Mamá.
He's a success.
That's why l didn't
come around before.
l want you to see
what a good boy l been.
Here's a thousand dollars.
For you, Mamá.
[Clears Throat]
- Who did you kill for this, Antonio?
- Mamá.
l didn't kill nobody, Mamá.
- No?
- No.
What are you doing now?
Banks, or is it still bodegas,
you and the others?
No! Things are different now.
l'm working
with an anti-Castro group.
l'm an organizer now, and l get
a lot of political contributions.
Sure you do.
A gun sticking
in somebody's face is how.
You know, all we hear about
in the papers...
is animals like you
and the killings.
lt's Cubans like you who are giving
a bad name to our people.
People who come here, work hard
and make a good name for themselves.
- People who send
their children to school--
- Mamá! What are you saying?
- That's your son!
- [Shouts] Son?
- l wish l had one. He's a bum.
- No. No.
He was a bum then,
and he's a bum now.
Who do you think
you are, hmm?
We haven't heard a word
from you in five years.
Cinco años.
You suddenly show up here,
throw some money around...
and think you can get
my respect.
-You think you can buy me with jewelry?
-Come on, Mamá.
You think you can come into my house
with your hotshot clothes...
and your jail manners
and make fun of us?
- Mamá, you don't know
what you're talking about.
- That's not the way l am!
That is not the way
l raised Gina to be!
You are not going
to destroy her.
l don't need your money.
Gracias.
l work for my living.
l don't want you
in this house anymore!
l don't want you around Gina.
So, come on. Get out!
Okay.
- No. Mamá--
- And take this lousy money with you.
- lt stinks.
- Tony--
Why do you have to spoil it
for everybody, huh?
l'm sorry, Tony.
Okay, Mamá.
Oh, no, no.
Tony, wait a minute!
- Don't go, please!
- Gina, stay here!
- [Gina] No, no, no, Mamá--
- [Mamá] He's no good. Gina!
- Tony, wait, please!
- Gina!
l'm sorry. l don't know, Mamá--
Ever since Papá left she's--
Forget Papá.
We never had one.
l know you did
some bad things back then.
ln the army, l know
you got into some trouble.
The Communists, they're always trying
to tell you what to do.
- Mamá doesn't understand that.
- l know.
l just-- l don't know. l just want you
to know, you know, l don't care.
lt doesn't matter to me how long
you've been away, five or ten years.
You're my blood, always.
l know. l know.
- Come on. Come on.
l want you to take this.
- l gotta go back in.
- No, Tony. Please. Tony.
- You need this. Come on.
- What am l gonna tell her?
- Take that. You don't
tell her anything.
Don't tell her l give it to you,
but give her some from time to time.
And listen, you go out yourself,
you know?
Go ahead, go out, do some things.
Have some fun.
You gotta get some fun
out of life.
You gonna beat yourself to death at 19?
Pussycat like you?
- Come here.
- Mmm.
- l'll talk to you again, all right?
- Okay.
- Put that money away.
Don't let her see it.
- l'll talk to her.
- Okay. l'll talk to you.
- [Train Whistle Blowing]
Okay.
Okay, let's go.
She's beautiful.
- How come you--
- Hey!
Stay away from her, man.
You hear?
- She not for you.
- Okay.
So this and my other factory,
l can guarantee production...
of 200 kilos refined
every month of the year.
The problem is
l have no steady market.
Basically, what l'm looking for
is somebody in the States...
who can share the risk with me,
somebody who can guarantee
to buy from me, say, 150 kilos a month.
Oh! That's a big commitment,
Mr. Sosa.
Something like that, uh--
lt's too bad Frank's not here.
You should talk to him.
- lt would've been nice
if he could have come.
- He would like to come,
but with his trial coming up, it's hard
for him to get out of the country.
- So he sent you instead?
- Yeah, something like that.
We'll talk at my house,
shall we?
You got good stuff here.
Class 'A' shit.
So this López guarantees to buy from me
150 kilos every month of the year.
He picks it up here.
l can sell it to him for as little as,
uh... 7,000 a key.
You cannot do better than that.
Yeah, but then we gotta
take the risk of moving it.
Also, we'll be cutting out the
Colombians. You know what that means?
That means we have
to go to war with them.
We cut out the Colombians,
we take risks on both sides.
Why don't we split the risk?
You guarantee your delivery,
say, as far as Panama.
We take it from there.
Panama is risky.
lt costs me more.
Panama l can sell for...
13.5 a key.
13.5?
What, are you nuts?
13.5? We still gotta take
that shit to Florida, man.
Do you know what that's like
these days? You got the fucking navy.
You got frogmen. You got EC-2s
with the satellite-tracking shit.
You got the fucking
Bell 209 assault choppers up the ass.
We're losing one
out of every nine loads.
That's no duck walk anymore, man,
let me tell you.
Forget about 13.5.
- [Phone Ringing]
- Well,
what do you suggest
that is reasonable?
[Ringing Continues]
Excuse me one moment.
Hey, Montana, what the fuck's
the matter with you?
- You negotiating for Frank López, huh?
- Don't worry about it.
- Take it easy.
- l'm not worried about it.
You should worry about it. lf he wants
to make a deal, it's up to him, not you.
- We're gonna do
this one deal. That's it.
- Fuck you. How's that?
- Fuck you.
[Omar] You need to open your eyes
and keep your mouth shut.
- That's it. Let it go at that.
- Don't worry about it.
Your head is in the wrong place.
You got to watch out for yourself.
Why don't you talk to him
about it? You think he
wants to give you the money?
- Shut the fuck up.
- l'm doing the talking here, not you.
You're here to watch my back.
Watch my back.
Better than your front, let me tell you.
That's easier to watch.
[Omar]
Close your mouth.
l can't wait to see what Frank's
gonna react to this one.
Just shut up.
l'm doing the talking here.
- Now where were we?
- Panama.
You're looking
for a partner, right?
Something like that.
Look, Mr. Sosa,
we're getting ahead of ourselves here.
l am down on Frank's authority
to buy 200 keys, that's it.
That's my limit.
l got no right--
- Nobody got no right
to negotiate for Frank--
- Let the man finish, okay?
Let him propose a proposition;
then we can talk more.
You got no authority here.
l started you in this fucking business,
so shut the fuck up.
- Frank is gonna love it.
Don't worry about it.
- That's up to Frank, not you!
l'm sorry about this, Mr. Sosa.
No, it is all right.
You're right.
Maybe you should talk to Frank.
Well, good.
l don't think it's something
l wanna do on an overseas phone.
But as soon as l get back to Miami,
l will talk to Frank personally.
Good.
My associates here
can escort you to my chopper.
My chopper can take you
to Santa Cruz.
l have a jet there,
can have you in Miami in five hours.
You should be back here tomorrow
in time for lunch.
Good. Good. Good.
Hasta mañana.
Good talking to you.
Why don't you leave
your friend here?
While you are gone, maybe he can
tell me how to run my business.
- l think Frank would like to see him--
- No, that's okay.
You tell Frank l keeping
this guy on ice for him.
- [Chuckling]
l guess so.
[Sosa]
Let's finish our lunch.
l have to hand it
to you, Mr. Sosa.
You got everything
a man could want.
l like you, Tony.
There is no lying in you.
Unfortunately, l do not feel the same
about the rest of your organization.
[Helicopter Whirring Overhead]
What do you mean
by that, Mr. Sosa?
l'm talking about Omar Suárez.
- This garbage was recognized
by my associate at lunch...
- [Helicopter Whirring]
from several years ago
in New York.
He was an informer
for the police.
[Omar Screaming]
[Sosa] He put Vito Duval
and the Ramos brothers, Nello and Gino,
away for life.
So how do l know you're not
a chivato too, Tony?
Hey, Sosa.
Let's get this straight now.
l never fucked anybody over in my life
didn't have it comin' to him.
You got that?
All l have in this life
is my balls and my word,
and l don't break 'em for no one,
you understand?
That piece of shit up there,
l never like him, l never trusted him.
For all l know, he had me set up and had
my friend, Ángel Fernández, killed.
But that's history.
l'm here, he's not.
You wanna go on with me, say it.
You don't, then you make a move.
l think you speak
from the heart, Montana.
But l say to myself,
this López, your boss,
he had chivatos like that
working for him.
His judgment stinks.
So l think to myself, how many
other mistakes has this López guy made?
How can l trust his organization?
You tell me, Tony.
Frank is smart, you know?
You can't blame him
for that animal.
lt's a crazy business we're in,
you know?
That could happen to anyone,
even you.
Why don't l go back
and talk to Frank...
and work it out?
l fix things between us.
You got my word on it.
l think you and me,
we can work this thing out,
we do business together
a long time.
Just remember--
l'll only tell you one time--
don't fuck me, Tony.
Don't you ever try to fuck me.
You what?
You made a deal
for a fucking $18 million...
without even checking with me?
Are you crazy, Montana?
Are you crazy?
- Coño, Frank. Take it easy.
- ¡Coño, my ass!
At 10.5 a key, it's puro.
You can't lose money.
No way.
We make 75 million
on this deal, Frank.
Seventy-five million.
That is serious money.
What the fuck is Sosa
going to do when l don't come up
with the first five million?
What is he gonna do?
ls he gonna send me a bill?
He's gonna send
a fucking hit squad up here!
Relax! Take it easy.
l'm in tight with Sosa.
You short a couple of mil,
l go on the street for you.
l make a couple of moves,
a mil here, a mil there,
you got it.
Okay?
Oh, you've been making moves
on your own, huh?
l got ears, you know?
l hear things.
Yeah?
What do you hear about Echevierra
and the Díaz brothers?
What about Gaspar Gómez?
What is he gonna do when you
start moving 2,000 keys--
Fuck Gaspar Gómez and fuck
the fucking Díaz brothers!
Fuck 'em all!
l bury those cockroaches!
What they ever do for us?
Look, Frank, the time has come.
We gotta expand.
The whole operation.
Distribution.
New York, Chicago, L.A.
We gotta set our own mark
and enforce it.
We gotta think big now.
Think big.
Like your friend Sosa.
Let me tell you something about
that greaseball cocksucker.
He is a snake,
that's what he is.
You turn your back on him,
he'll stick it in.
You don't trust a guy like that.
You want me to believe...
Omar was a stoolie
because Sosa said so?
You bought that line.
Maybe l made a mistake
sending you down there.
Maybe you and Sosa
know something l don't know.
Like what?
[Chuckling]
You tell me like what?
You calling me a liar, Frank?
That what you calling me?
Let's just say l want things
to stay the way they are for now.
You stall your deal with Sosa.
Stall him?
Okay, boss.
Come on.
l am the boss.
- Sure, you're the boss.
- Hey, Tony.
Remember l told you
when you started...
the guys who last
in this business...
are the guys who fly straight--
low-key, quiet.
And the guys who want it all--
chicas, champagne, flash--
they don't last.
You finished?
Can l go now?
[Birds Calling]
Hi there.
Tony.
You just missed Frank.
Oh, yeah?
Too bad.
Only l didn't come to see Frank.
This is not the time
or the place, Tony.
- Next time, make an appointment first.
- That's okay.
l got something important
l want to talk to you about.
Okay?
So why don't we have
a couple of drinks,
act normal...
and just take it easy, huh?
Come on. l like Scotch.
- Sure. Why not?
- Okay. l won't bite you.
We're all normal here.
[lce Cubes Clinking]
l heard you and Frank
aren't working together anymore.
That's right.
l think it's easier, don't you?
Makes things easier.
Well, uh--
Thank you.
Here's to the land of opportunity.
For you, maybe.
- You like kids?
- Kids?
Kids. You know, kid.
Little kids.
[Sighs] Sure. Why not?
As long as there's a nurse.
Good, 'cause l like kids too.
l like 'em. Boys, girls.
Don't matter to me.
[Sighs]
Look, Frank's gonna be back any minute.
Come here.
Come on. Come on.
Sit here.
l want to talk to you. Sit down.
l'm not gonna bite you.
Okay, here's the story.
l come from the gutter.
l know that.
l got no education,
but that's okay.
l know the street, and l'm making
all the right connections.
With the right woman,
there's no stopping me.
l could go right to the top.
Anyway, what l got
to tell you is this:
l like you.
l like you the first time
l laid eyes on you.
l say, ''She's a tiger.
[Chuckles]
She belong to me.''
Anyway...
l want you to marry me.
l want you to be
the mother of my children.
Me? Marry you?
That's right.
[Sighs]
What about Frank, Tony?
What are you gonna do about Frank?
Frank is not gonna last, okay?
He's finished.
Just think about it, okay?
l want you
to really think about it.
Okay? l go now.
Take care.
- // [Technopop Playing]
- All your enemies are gone.
Mr. Montana.
- How are you?
- Hello, boss.
What the fuck she doin' here?
Come on, man. Come on, come on.
She's just dancing.
Come on.
Take it easy.
- Right? l mean, it's just a disco.
- Who that guy she with?
He's some guy who works for Lugo.
He's nobody.
- He's harmless.
- Works for Lugo?
Yeah. He's--
Forget him.
[Mutters]
Hello, Tony.
Well, you remember me.
Bernstein.
Mel Bernstein, right?
Chief detective, narcotics.
That's right, yeah.
l think we should talk.
Talk? What are we
going to talk about?
l ain't killed nobody.
Not lately.
No, not lately. What about
ancient history, like Emilio Rebenga?
Or a bunch of whacked-out lndians
at the Sun Ray Motel?
Mel, who's ever giving you
your information is taking you
for a long ride.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Tony, baby,
we gonna talk,
or am l gonna bust
your wise-ass spic balls here and now?
[Woman Singing]
/ Turn out the night /
/ l can be strong //
Keep your eye on her.
- l'll do that.
- Okay.
- My office.
- Good.
The word on the street
is you're bringing in a lot of yeyo.
That means you're not
a small-time punk anymore.
You're public property now.
Supreme Court says
your privacy can be invaded.
Okay. How much?
How much?
Well, there's an answer to that too.
Here's how much.
Can you see it?
- Big number.
- Yeah!
That's on a monthly basis,
same thing every month.
You know how this works?
No. You tell me.
We tell you
who's moving against you,
and we shake down
who you want shaken down.
Let's say that you got
a real problem making a collection.
Hmm? And then
we step in for you.
Got eight killers with badges working
for me. When they hit, it hurts.
Same thing works the other way.
You feed me a bust now and then--
some cowboy setting himself up
in business.
Small-fry, you know?
[Sighs]
We like snacks.
How do l know you're the last cop
l'm gonna have to grease?
What about Fort Lauderdale?
Metro? D.E.A.?
How do l know what rock
they're gonna crawl out from under?
Well, it's not my business, Tony,
you know? We don't cross no lines.
[Chuckles] Listen, you think
l want this conversation...
going any farther
than this table?
My guys got families.
They're legitimate cops.
l don't wanna see them embarrassed.
lf they're embarrassed,
they're gonna suffer.
lf they suffer,
they're gonna make you suffer.
- Comprende?
You understand what
l'm talking about? Huh?
[Crowd Chattering]
/ She's on fire, fire, fire /
Thank you for the drink.
Oh, by the way,
l got a vacation coming up.
l'm gonna take the wife
to London, England.
We've never been there.
So, throw in a couple
of round-trip tickets,
first class, okay?
You oughta smile more, Tony.
You gotta enjoy yourself.
Every day above ground
is a good day.
Hello.
Yeah.
Now that's the idea.
Okay, Mel.
You think about what l said?
About the kids? Hmm?
- You know, you are really nuts.
You know that, Tony?
- l'm nuts about you.
Hey, Tony, why don't you
find your own girl?
- My own girl?
- Yeah.
- That's what l'm doing.
- Go do it somewhere else. Get lost.
Maybe l don't hear
so good sometime.
- You're not going to be hearing
anything if you go on.
- You gonna do something?
You're fucking right
l'm going to do something!
l'm giving you orders. Blow!
Orders?
You giving me orders?
Amigo, the only thing
in this world...
that gives orders is balls.
You got that?
[Tony]
Balls.
Let's go.
/ She's on fire //
Elvira.
When you gonna learn? Huh?
Looking good, honey.
Keep up the bad work.
- That cocksucker.
- What happened?
- He put that prick Bernstein on me.
- Who? López did?
- How do you know?
- Who else knew about Rebenga? Omar?
- He's fertilizer.
- [Laughing]
He's letting me know
he's got weight on me.
l'll tell you what, man.
[Continues, Muffled]
Wait. Where you going, man?
Walking back--
/ l'm coming on strong
like a burning flame /
- / Hey, hey, hey /
- No, no, no.
[lndistinct Chatter]
- / Gonna take it easy
Don't you get me uptight /
- [lndistinct Chatter]
/ l'm wound up like a spring
and l'm ready to fight /
/ l'm hot tonight /
- [Laughing]
- Welcome to my private room.
- Your private room.
- This is my private room, huh?
l got a beautiful, nice, white lounge--
barcalounge chair for you.
/ Hey, hey, hey //
- [Sighing]
- [Sniffs]
Oh, Gina, you taste
so muy bueno. Muy--
[Screams]
Tony!
- What are you doing? [Shrieking]
- Shut up!
- What the hell, man?
We wasn't doing nothing!
- Fernando, wait!
- [Shouting]
- Get out!
- What--
- [Gasps] Damn you!
- Get out!
- What, you think he's cute?
- What?
l saw him putting his hand all over
your ass. My kid sister in the toilet.
- lt's none of your business.
- None of my business?
The fuck it ain't!
[Gina]
You can't tell me what to do!
l'm telling you what to do!
Listen to me. Come here.
- [Panting] Mm-hmm.
- l catch you here again--
l catch you here again, l'm gonna
wipe you all over the fucking place.
Oh, yeah? Go ahead!
Do it now. l wanna see it.
- l wanna see it now, big shot.
- Don't push me, baby.
- l wanna see it now!
- Don't fucking push me!
Get the fuck outta here!
- Go outside--
- Got some nerve!
You got some nerve, Tony!
- You think you can come in here
and tell me what to do?
- Get out.
You can't tell me what to do.
l am not a baby anymore.
l'll do what l wanna do,
see whoever l wanna see.
And if l wanna fuck 'em,
then l'll fuck 'em! [Gasps, Moans]
- Fucking, man! Come on, man.
- [Sobbing]
- Come on.
- [Sobbing] No.
- [Gina] No.
- What the fuck you want?
You want something? Huh?
No. Don't touch me.
- Don't touch me.
- Gina, have a seat.
- No. No.
- We'll get outta here.
- Not there. l don't wanna go out there.
- Come on.
- Another great night
here at the Babylon, right?
- [Rim Shot]
- Okay. All right!
- [Audience Cheering]
- Do another gram,
you'll all be babbling on.
- [Audience Laughing]
ls that coke in your bra,
or are you just glad to see me?
A little bit of hope,
l'm sure, yes.
l was a little depressed
when l got up this morning.
- l had a dry dream, but--
- [Audience Laughing]
l'm better now.
[Continues, lndistinct]
[Slide Whistle]
l do Laurel & Hardy
in Spanish too.
- ¿Qué pasó, amigo?
Mmm, mmm, mmm!
That's the height of culture,
l can assure you.
But my favorite Cuban of all time
has to be Ricky Ricardo.
Mr. Babaloo himself.
He had the same problem for ten years.
[lmitating Ricky Ricardo]
Lucy, don't come down to the club.
Fred and Ethel--
[Continues, lndistinct]
- [M.C. Continues, lndistinct]
- [Laughter Continues]
He's your brother. He loves you.
That's why he did it.
All right?
He cares about you.
- To him, you're still
his little sister--
- Right!
That's the problem.
He still treats me like l'm a baby.
l'm 20 years old now.
- l'm not anybody's baby.
- Oh, you're so grown up.
Come on, Gina.
Put yourself in his place, okay?
Right now, you happen to be
the best thing in his life.
The only thing
that's any good, that's pure.
So, of course he doesn't want
you mixing with those people,
growing up to be like him.
He has this father thing for you.
He feels like he has to protect you.
Protect me against what?
Against guys like that asshole
that you were dancing with tonight.
Hey, l like Fernando.
He's a fun guy and he's nice.
And he knows how to treat
a woman. All right?
He knows how to treat
a woman? By taking you
to the toilet to make out?
You've been a great audience. Calm down.
l got a special treat for you.
Here's a guy l found strolling in the
jungle. He's from Caracas, Venezuela.
He's unlike anything
you'll ever see in your life.
Give a warm Babylon welcome
to the one and only Octavio!
[Audience Applauding, Cheering]
[Recording of Frank Sinatra]
/ Strangers in the night /
/ Exchanging glances /
/ Wondering in the night /
/ What were the chances /
/ We'd be sharing love before-- //
Look around.
Go out with, with somebody...
who's got something on the ball,
who's going somewhere in life.
Like who?
Like, for instance, someone who's got
a real job, like a banker.
- Or, or a doctor, a lawyer--
- What about you?
- What are you talking about?
- Why don't you take me out?
- What, are you crazy?
- l see the way you look at me, Manolo.
- What, do you think l'm blind? l see.
- Come on.
- What?
- Look, Gina,
Tony and l are like brothers,
all right?
- And you're his kid sister,
and that's where it ends.
- So what?
- That's where it stays.
- What, are you afraid of Tony? Huh?
- You afraid of Tony's kid sister?
- l'm not afraid of anybody!
That's not the point here!
/ l said dance, dance, dance /
/ Move to the music /
/ Let your heart go free /
/ Dance, dance, dance
You can't refuse it /
/ Dance, dance, dance with me /
/ Come on
Dance, dance, dance /
/ Move to the music //
[People Screaming]
[Screaming, Shouting]
[Tires Squealing]
- [Phone Ringing]
- [Manny] Oh, fuck.
- [Miriam Laughing]
- lt's not for me. Don't look at me.
- [Miriam] How do you know?
- 'Cause l'm not here.
Oh, really?
Then where are you? [Laughing]
- [Ringing Continues]
- Shit, you're weird. [Laughing]
- l'm weird?
- Hello?
- [Tony] Hello, Miriam?
- Hey, Tony!
- Put Manny on, okay?
- Okay. Just a second.
lt's Tony. Mmm!
Mamá? What are you doing,
checking up on me?
Get your clothes on and meet me
in front of López Motors in 45 minutes.
- What are you talking about?
What happened?
- Nothing we can't face.
All right. l'll--
l'll be there.
- You're still on the phone. Let's go.
- Take it easy, okay?
- l'm leaving now. Fuck.
- [Receiver Clicks]
- Uh, Nick?
- Yeah, Tony.
This is what
l want you to do for me:
You call López.
- Call him at his office
at 3:00 sharp, okay?
- Okay.
And you tell him--
you tell him,
''We fucked up, he got away.''
- Okay. Yeah.
- You got it?
What are you going to say?
We fucked up.
He got away.
- What time?
- 3:00, sharp.
[Frank] Yeah? So when are we gonna
make some money on this thing?
Six months to start
don't mean shit, Larry.
Hey, l'm not a Rockefeller,
you know? Not yet anyway.
[Laughing]
So you owe me a quarter.
Listen, go down
to the ball game tonight?
l couldn't make it.
l got things-- l'll tell you about 'em.
You're kidding?
What was the score?
Three to two?
[Laughing]
Hey, Mel, guess what?
My Little League team,
the Little Lopezers,
they won the division tonight.
- That's great. That's great.
- [Laughing]
What'd you do,
fix the umpire, Frank?
Jesus... Christ.
Tony, what happened to you?
They wanted to spoil
my $800 suit.
Who the fuck did this, huh?
Hitters. l don't know.
Somebody must've brought 'em in.
l've never seen 'em before.
Hello, Mel.
Got an answer to this too?
- There always is, Tony.
- l'll bet it was the Díaz brothers.
They got a beef going back
to the Sun Ray thing.
Maybe you're right, you know?
Maybe you're right.
Anyway, l-l'm glad
you made it, Tony.
We'll return the favor
for you, in spades.
No, l take care of this myself.
What is the gun for, Tony?
What, this?
lt's nothing.
l, uh--
How do you say?
Paranoid.
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
- You gonna answer, Frank?
- [Ringing Continues]
lt must be Elvira. She... got mad
after we left the club.
- You know?
- [Ringing Continues]
l tell her
you're not here, okay?
No, it's all right.
- l'll talk to her.
- [Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
Hello.
lt's all right. l'm gonna be home
in an hour. Don't worry.
Hey, Frank,
you're a piece of shit.
- What are you talking about?
- You know what l'm talking about,
you fucking cockroach.
What are you talking about?
Listen to me, huh?
You know what
a chazzer is, Frank?
That's a pig
that don't fly straight.
Neither do you, Frank.
Hey, Tony, why the fuck
would l hurt you?
l brought you in.
So we had a few differences, huh?
No big deal.
l gave you your start.
l was the one who believed in you.
l stayed loyal to you.
l made what l could on the side,
but l never turned you, Frank!
Never!
But you--
A man who ain't got his word
is a cockroach.
Mel, come on.
Do something, will you?
lt's your tree, Frank.
You're sitting in it.
Okay.
All right, Tony.
l was the one.
[Cocks Hammer]
Please, give me a second chance.
Huh, Tony?
Will you, will you
do that? Please?
l--
You give me a second chance,
l give you ten million dollars.
Okay?
Ten million dollars.
l got it in a vault
over there in Spain, Tony.
We go over there;
we get on a plane, and it's yours.
Okay? All of it.
Ten million dollars.
Okay, Tony? Huh?
Please, Tony?
[Sobbing]
Elvira? Elvira!
You want Elvira!
You can have her. l go away.
l'm gonna disappear.
You'll never see me again.
Please, Tony, l don't want to die.
l never did nothing
to nobody.
No, no, you never did
nothing to nobody.
- You had somebody else do it for you.
- Tony, l am begging you--
- Get up! Get up now!
- Jesus! No! God! [Sobbing]
[Sobbing Continues]
Look. Tony, no,
don't kill me, please.
- [Frank Moans]
- l won't kill you.
- Oh, Christ, thank you.
- Get off my foot.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Manolo, shoot that piece of shit!
No! No! No!
Oh!
[Sighs]
Every dog has his day, huh, Mel?
l told him...
it didn't make any sense, clipping you
when we had you working for us.
He wouldn't listen.
He got hot tonight,
about the broad, you know?
He fucked up.
You too, Mel.
You fucked up.
Don't go too far, Tony.
[Sighs]
l'm not, Mel. You are.
[Groaning, Gasps]
Fuck.
You can't shoot a cop!
Whoever says you was one?
Wait a minute!
You let me go.
l'll fix this up.
Sure, Mel.
Maybe you can hand yourself...
one of them first-class tickets
to the Resurrection.
Fuckin' punk!
Son of a bitch!
- So long, Mel. Have a good trip.
- Fuck you!
- Okay, come on.
- What about Ernie?
You want a job, Ernie?
- Sure, Tony.
- Okay, then you call me tomorrow.
Hey, man, you got a job!
[Chuckles]
Hey, Tony! Thanks.
[Chi Chi Chuckling]
Tony.
God, what's happened?
Where's Frank?
Where do you think?
Come on.
Get your stuff.
You're coming with me.
- / Push it to the limit /
- [Backup Singers] / The limit /
/ Walk along the razor's edge /
/ Don't look down
Just keep your head or you're finished /
- / Open up the limit /
- / The limit /
/ Past the point of no return /
/ Reach the top
but still you gotta learn /
/ How to keep it /
/ Hit the wheel
and double the stakes /
/ Throttle wide open
like a bat out of hell /
/ You crash the gate /
/ Crash the gate /
/ Goin' for the back of beyond /
/ Nothing's gonna stop you
There's nothing that strong /
/ So close now
You're nearly at the brink /
/ So push it
Oooh, yeah /
- / Welcome to the limit /
- / The limit /
/ Take it, baby
one step more /
/ The power game
Still playing /
/ So you better win it /
- / Push it to the limit /
- / The limit /
/ No one left to stand in your way /
/ You might get careless
but you'll never be safe /
/ While you're still living /
[Growling]
[Growls]
- / Welcome to the limit /
- / The limit /
/ Standing on the razor's edge /
/ Don't look down
Just keep your head /
/ Or you'll be finished /
/ Welcome to the limit /
/ Push it to the limit /
/ Ah, ah //
[Tony] So you come to me
with some kind of thing. Okay.
You propose it,
l talk to you.
[Clears Throat]
But we got a problem, you know?
l can't pay more.
l'm bringing in twice as much
as l ever did before.
We're doing ten million,
fifteen million a month. Come on.
That's serious money, you know?
- You bank boys gotta come down a bit.
- No way.
- That's crazy. We can't do that.
- Then that's too bad.
- What am l gonna do?
- Tony, sweetheart,
we're not a wholesale operation.
We're a legitimate bank.
The more cash you give me,
the harder it is for me to rinse.
That's a problem.
l didn't know.
The fact is l can't take any more
of your money...
unless l raise the rates on you.
- You gonna raise the r--
- l gotta do it.
- The l.R.S. is coming--
- Don't give me that shit!
Jerry, talk to me, man.
- l'm talking.
- l go low, you go high.
l know the game.
- This is business talk.
Don't talk to me like that.
- Let me explain something.
The l.R.S. is coming down heavy
on south Florida.
There was a Time magazine story
that didn't help.
There's a recession. l got stockholders
l gotta be responsible for.
- l gotta do it, Tony.
- Listen to this guy.
You're gonna learn from him.
l gotta go 10 percent on the first
12 million in denominations of 20.
l'll go eight percent
on your ten-dollar bills
and six points on your fives.
- That's it.
- We're going somewhere else, okay?
- There's no place else to go.
lt's not a conspiracy.
- Fuck you, man! Fuck you!
- l fly the cash myself to the Bahamas.
- Once maybe. Then what?
Huh? Then what? You gonna trust
some monkey in a Bahamian bank...
with 20 million
of your hard-earned dollars?
Come on, Tony.
Don't be a schmuck.
Who else can you trust? That's why
you pay us what you do. You trust us.
Huh?
Did you hear that guy? You gotta
listen to him. You'll learn something.
Stay with us. You're an old
and well-liked customer.
You're in good hands with us.
- And l gotta run.
- l'm safe but poor.
- How's married life treating you?
- Better than you are.
[Laughing] Say hello
to the princess for me, will you?
- She's beautiful.
- Okay.
- l'll see you. Take care.
- You too.
[Tony]
Come here.
That prick!
Fuckin' WASP whore.
Talkin' to me like l--
l some maricón come over on a boat.
l tell you what.
We don't need that
smilin' motherfucker.
We should talk to this Jewish guy,
Seidelbaum, okay?
He's got his own exchange.
He charges four percent at
the most. And he's connected.
Fuck 'em.
- Mob guys. Guineas.
- [Snorting]
l don't trust 'em.
Hey, Manny.
Did you sweep the house this month?
The cars?
Yeah. l told you about it.
The $5,000?
- Look at that.
- [Sniffs] What?
[Tony]
That cable truck there.
Since when does it take
three days to rig a cable?
What? You been watching it
for three days?
The fuckin' thing has been there
for three days? What am l
gonna do, not look at it?
- What, you think it's cops, right?
- l don't know.
Could be the Díaz brothers,
come to get me.
Maybe.
l'll check it out, okay?
You check it out. Then we're gonna blow
that fuckin' truck back to Colombia!
Come on, come on.
Monina.
We're not the only dopers living
on the block, okay? Remember that.
That fucking truck, that
could be anybody and anything.
lt could be a cable company--
You know something?
You got some fuckin' attitude.
For someone who's in charge
of my security--
Here. Here are the keys to
the front door. Go down there.
Give 'em the fuckin' keys!
- l'm just tryin' to say something.
- What?
- You're spending a lot of money
on this countersurveillance.
- l don't give a fuck.
lt's already twelve percent
of our adjusted gross.
Twelve percent is not peanuts.
l don't give a fuck! lt makes me sleep
good at night. That's what counts.
- Okay? You worry about it.
- l am worried about it.
l'm telling you.
We're getting sloppy.
Our thinking,
our fuckin' attitude, you know?
We're not fuckin' hungry anymore.
Miami's changing.
You can see it everywhere.
New construction.
New jobs.
Growth that's financed
by Florida Security Trust.
We've been putting your money
to work for 75 years building
a more prosperous Miami.
- Count on us being here tomorrow.
- [Tony] Oh, yeah?
That's because for 75 years
you been fuckin' everybody.
Somebody should do something
about these-- these whores.
l mean, chargin' me
ten points on my money.
They're gettin' away with it.
Fuck, there's no laws anymore.
- Forget it, man.
- l mean, anything goes.
They been around a thousand years.
They got all the angles figured out.
You know what capitalism is?
Gettin' fucked.
[Elvira]
True capitalist if ever l met one.
- [TV Shuts Off]
- Uh-oh. Did you hear that?
How would you know, bubblehead?
You ever do nothin' besides get
your hair fixed and powder your nose?
Look at it. You do too much
of that shit, you know?
Nothing exceeds like excess.
- You should know that, Tony.
- l should know what?
What should l know?
Why do you have to talk to me
like that all the time for?
- Like l gotta know something.
- Let me talk to you.
- Listen to me.
This Seidelbaum. Five to 7:00.
- What time is it?
- Okay.
- Okay?
- l met with this guy--
- The drug-related violence
that's plagued south Florida...
He's good for a laugh, this guy.
forces one to ask a question:
How, with a small law enforcement
budget, can you put a dent...
on an estimated
$100 billion-a-year business?
lt seems at times all you can do
is put your finger in the dike and pray.
Put your fingers in a dike?
The only place you can
get your fingers in some dyke.
Not by outlawing the substances,
but by legalizing and taxing them.
These voices say that will drive out
the organized crime element.
l am not one of those voices.
l know that.
But you know why, Vic?
'Cause you got your head
up your culo, that's why.
That fuckin' guy,
he never tells the truth.
...splendor of our city
at its best.
lt's those guys, man!
lt's the fuckin' bankers,
the politicians--
they're the ones
that wanna make coke illegal!
So they can make the fuckin' money,
and they get the fuckin' votes!
They fightin' the bad guys.
They're the bad guys!
They fuck anything and anyone--
Can't you stop saying ''fuck''
all the time?
Can't you stop talking about money?
lt's boring, Tony.
Where's this comin' from, man?
Boring? What's boring?
- You're boring.
- Oh.
Money, money, money, money, money.
That's all l ever hear in this house.
Manny, look at the pelican fly.
Come on, pelican!
- Here it is.
- Frank never talked about money.
Oh.
That's 'cause
he was so smart, you know?
[Tony Muttering]
Cuidado. Se te cae.
You know what
you're becoming, Tony?
You're an immigrant
spic millionaire...
who can't stop talking about
how much money he's got--
Who you callin' a spic,
you white piece of bread?
Get out of the way
of the television!
Why don't you dig a hole
in the garden and bury it?
l work hard for this!
l want you to know that.
lt's too bad.
Somebody should've given it to you.
You would've been a nicer person.
Oh. You know what
your problem is, pussycat?
What is my problem?
You got nothing to do
with your life.
Why don't you get a job
or something, you know?
Do something.
Be a nurse.
Work with blind kids, lepers.
Anything beats lying around all day
waitin' for me to fuck you!
Don't toot your horn, honey.
You're not that good.
Oh, no?
Frank was better, huh?
You're an asshole!
Where you going?
Come here!
Hey, Elvie!
l was kidding!
l was only kidding!
l guess sometimes married life is not
all it's cracked up to be, you know?
- Where you goin'?
- l got a date.
- You got a date?
- Yeah.
Come here.
- What?
- This Seidelbaum thing.
Yeah, it's all set up.
Yeah, well, you forget it.
Stay out of it. l take care of it.
''Stay out of it''?
lt's my deal. l set it up.
You're not a negotiator,
Manny, you know that.
You like the ladies more than you like
the money. That's your problem.
What the fuck are you talking about?
l'm your partner, okay?
You're not gonna trust me with that
kind of thing, who you gonna trust?
- Junior partner.
- Bullshit, man.
Hey, don't talk to me about trust.
l don't like it.
You should listen to your wife.
She's right. You are an asshole, man!
Come here. Gimme a kiss.
Come here.
Hey. Hey!
Fuck you, man!
Who put this thing together?
Me! That's who!
Who do l trust? Me!
Fuck him. Trust.
Por nada.
Asshole.
Fuck called me an asshole.
l need that shit.
l don't need him,
and l don't need her.
Fuck 'em.
l don't need nobody!
Back then l worked in pictures
down in Colombia.
l was in that movie Burn.
You ever see it?
Ah, you saw me, with Marlon Brando.
You know, we're good friends.
- l was his driver.
- No shit?
- Brando, huh?
- Yeah, they shot it there.
Cartagena. They shot it there.
- Yeah?
- Gillo Pontecorvo. He was
the director. ltalian guy.
- Tell me about him.
- Sure. l also worked--
l also know Paul Newman.
- l worked with him in Tucson.
- No kidding?
Hey, do you know Benny Álvarez?
They are in Tucson.
Benny Álvarez?
- Subtotal.
- No?
He's a nice guy.
$283,107.65.
You want a company check here?
[Clears Throat]
l got 284.6.
That's just not possible.
The machine don't make mistakes.
- Let's count it again.
- No, no. Come on.
Business is business. Come on.
You're talking $1,500 here.
Okay, you keep the change.
Okay. l don't give a shit.
- Well, l'll count it again for you.
- No, no, come on.
This check here,
where does this check go?
- Montana Realty Company.
- Montana what?
Montana Realty Company.
- That's 284.
- $284,600.
[Chi Chi] How come you
don't know Benny Álvarez?
- Me and Benny Álvarez
have lunch together.
- Yeah? He probably knows me.
You ask him.
[Men Yawning]
We're up to what?
Seven checks.
1,325,623.
- Two hundred thousand more,
and we ought to take a leak.
- Freeze!
Get 'em up! Get your hands
against the wall and turn around.
- You're not kidding.
- You're under arrest
for violation of the Rico Statute.
You have the right
to remain silent.
- Anything you say can
and will be taken against you.
- Fuck you!
- How do l know you guys are cops?
- What's that say, asshole?
Oh, that pretty good, man.
Where'd you get that?
¡Cabrón! You call yourself a Cuban?
You make a real Cuban throw up!
Call your dog off me, Seidelbaum.
- l wanna call my lawyer.
- Lotta good he's gonna do you.
You see that eye there
in the clock?
Say, hi, honey.
Ah, that's pretty cute. Look at that.
He jerk off in front of us, Seidelbaum?
l was supposed to meet
this chick at 3:00. You're
a fuckin' pain in the ass.
All right, Danny, kill it.
You understand the rights
l've given you?
l know all that bullshit, Seidelbaum!
Save your breath.
You got nothin' on me.
You know it! l know it!
l'm changin' dollar bills,
that's all.
You wanna waste my time?
Okay. l call my lawyer.
He's the best lawyer in Miami.
He's such a good lawyer,
that by tomorrow morning,
you gonna be working in Alaska.
So dress warm.
[Sheffield] Give me a check for
a hundred grand, plus 300 in cash,
and l guarantee you walk
on the conspiracy charge.
But they're gonna come back at us
on a tax evasion, and they'll get it.
So... what am l
lookin' at here?
Five years.
You'll be out in three.
Maybe less, if l can make a deal.
Three fuckin' years!
For what?
Washing money? The fuckin' country
was built on washed money.
- lt can't be that bad.
lt's not like Cuba.
- What the fuck you talking?
- The jails are like hotels.
- You kidding me or what?
- You fuckin' high or what?
- l'll delay the trial.
A year and a half, two years.
You won't even start--
Hey, fuck you, man!
l'm not going back in any cage, okay?
No way. l been there.
Okay, look.
[Clears Throat]
l give you $400,000 more.
Okay, now that's $800,000.
With that kind of money,
you can buy the Supreme Court.
Tony, the law has to prove
beyond a reasonable doubt.
l'm an expert
at raisin' that doubt.
But when you a got
a million-three undeclared dollars...
staring into a videotape camera,
honey, baby, it's hard to convince
a jury you found it in a taxicab.
[lce Cubes Rattle]
- [Sosa] Tony.
- Alex.
Tony, l'm so glad you could
come on such short notice.
l really appreciate it.
- lt's okay.
- How's Elvira?
- Ah, great. How's your wife?
- Three more months.
- Oh, yeah? Congratulations.
- How 'bout you?
When you gonna have another Tony
to take your place?
- l'm working on it.
- You have to work harder. Come.
l want you to meet
some of my friends.
This is Pedro Quinn,
chairman of the Andes Sugar Corporation.
- Pleasure meeting you, Mr. Montana.
- Nice to meet you.
General Edward Strasser, commander of
the First Army Corps. Tony Montana.
- Mucho gusto, amigo.
- Pleasure.
This is Ariel Bleyer with the Ministry
of the lnterior here. Tony Montana.
Bienvenido.
And here is our friend, Charles Goodson
from Washington. This is Tony Montana.
- How do you do?
- How do you do, Mr. Montana?
[Sosa]
Sit here, Tony.
Gentlemen.
l would like to discuss something
that is of interest to all of us here.
You have a problem, Tony.
We... have a problem.
l think together
we can solve all our problems.
We all know that you have
tax troubles in your country...
and that you may have
to do a little time.
But we have some friends
in Washington that assure us
these troubles can be taken care of.
You may have to pay
some back taxes, a big fine,
but, uh,
there will be no prison.
Okay.
So what's your problem, Alex?
l'll show you my problem.
[Reporter]
l've heard whispers about financial
support your government receives...
from the drug industry
in Bolivia.
Well, the irony of this is that
this money, which is in the billions,
is coming from your country.
You are the major purchaser
of our national product,
which is cocaine.
On one hand you're saying
the United States government...
is spending millions of dollars
to eliminate the flow of drugs
onto our streets.
At the same time, we are doing business
with the same government...
that is flooding
our streets with cocaine.
Sí. Let me show you
a few of the other characters...
that are involved
in this tragicomedy.
My organization just recently
traced a large purchase...
by this man.
This charming face here
belongs to General Cucombre.
He is the minister of the defense
of Bolivia, my country.
And General Cucombre just
a couple of months ago...
bought a $12 million villa
on Lake Lucerne in Switzerland.
Now, if Cucombre is supposed to be
the Bolivian defense minister,
what is he doing living in Switzerland,
guarding cash registers?
This man here,
Alejandro Sosa,
a very interesting character.
He's a wealthy landowner,
educated in England, very good family.
But this man is the business brain
and drug overlord...
of an empire that stretches
across the Andes.
He's not your ordinary drug dealer.
[Reporter]
Well, discussing it openly--
[Tape Stops]
He is scheduled
for 60 Minutes next.
He is going on French,
British, ltalian,
Japanese television.
People everywhere
are starting to listen to him.
lt's embarrassing, Tony.
- Yeah.
- That is our problem.
You remember Alberto, don't you?
How could l forget him?
Alberto is an expert
in the disposal business.
He's going to help us
fix our problem.
But he doesn't speak English.
He doesn't know his way
around the States too well.
He needs a little help.
ls that a problem, Tony?
No problem.
Good.
[People Chattering]
So what's the big mystery
with the Bolivian situation?
You gonna tell me
what happened with Sosa or what?
- A lotta bullshit, that what happened.
- [Laughs]
Politics.
Okay. l want you to stay
down here for a while.
Run things for me.
l gotta go to New York next week.
Okay?
[Clears Throat]
Fuck this, man.
l don't like it, man.
l don't like this at all.
You don't like it?
Okay.
You the one that got me into this mess
in the first place, you know that?
- Oh, yeah?
- With that fuckin' Seidelbaum,
that right?
With Seidelbaum? Man, what does
Seidelbaum have to do with Sosa?
How you connect those two?
- [Sniffing]
- Why don't you eat your food?
What's wrong with it?
- l'm not hungry.
- You're not hungry?
You even know about the trial?
- What did you order it for then?
- l lost my appetite.
Do you even know that Sheffield said
he can get you a postponement?
- [Manny] - Eh?
- [Sniffing]
ls this it? That's what
it's all about, Manny?
Eating, drinking,
fucking, sucking?
- Come on, man. [Snickers]
- Snorting?
Then what?
Tell me.
You're 50.
You got a bag for a belly.
You got tits; you need a bra.
They got hair on 'em.
You got a liver,
and they got spots on it,
and you're eatin'
this fuckin' shit,
and you're lookin' like
these rich fuckin' mummies in here.
Come on. lt's not so bad.
lt could be worse.
- ls this what it's all about?
- Forget it.
This what l work for?
Tell me.
¡Coño!
Look at that.
A junkie.
l got a fuckin' junkie for a wife.
She don't eat nothin'.
Sleeps all day...
with them black shades on.
- Wakes up with a Quaalude,
- Don't pick on her, man.
and who won't fuck me
'cause she's in a coma.
l can't even have
a kid with her, Manny.
Her womb is so polluted,
l can't even have
a fuckin' little baby with her!
- Don't start that.
- [Whispering] You son of a bitch!
- You fuck!
- You shouldn't talk like that.
How dare you talk to me like that!
What makes you
so much better than me?
- What do you do?
- Don't worry.
You deal drugs and you kill people.
Oh, that's wonderful, Tony.
Real contribution
to human history.
- Go ahead. Tell everybody.
- You want a kid?
- Tell the world.
- What kind of a father
do you think you'd make!
- [Shouting]
- Gonna drive him to school
in the mornings?
Are you even gonna be alive
by the time the kid goes to school?
- You don't even know
how to be a husband!
- Sit down before l--
Do we ever go anywhere without having
six thugs hanging around all the time?
- lt's okay.
- l have Nick the Pig as a friend.
- What kind of life is that?
- Come on.
Can't you see...
what we're becoming, Tony?
We're losers.
We're not winners;
we're losers.
Go home. You're stoned.
l'm not stoned; you're stoned.
- Hey, get her outta here.
- Come on.
No. No.
l'm not going home with you.
[Sighs]
l'm not going home with anybody.
l'm going home alone.
l'm leaving you.
[Patrons Whispering]
l don't need this shit anymore.
Okay, but l'll walk you out.
l'll take her home in a cab.
Let her go.
Let her go, man.
Another Quaalude,
she gonna love me again.
What you lookin' at?
You all a bunch
of fuckin' assholes.
You know why?
You don't have the guts
to be what you wanna be?
You need people like me.
You need people like me
so you can point your fuckin' fingers...
and say,
''That's the bad guy.''
So... what that make you?
Good?
You're not good.
You just know how to hide--
how to lie.
Me, l don't have that problem.
Me, l always tell the truth.
Even when l lie.
So say good night
to the bad guy!
Come on.
The last time you gonna see a bad guy
like this again, let me tell you.
Come on.
Make way for the bad guy.
There's a bad guy comin' through!
Better get outta his way!
[Tony]
Yeah, yeah.
No, no. You tell Sheffield
to keep his nose out of it.
There's gonna be no trial.
l got it all under control now.
Just tell him to stay out of it!
Okay, what about Elvira?
Did she call?
Okay.
Yeah, all right.
Tony, everything go okay?
Yeah, everything is roses.
[Tony Sighing]
Ernie, what time you got?
- Ten to.
- Where is this guy, man?
- l gotta call Manny again.
- Fuck you! You don't
tell me what to do here!
- He's coming out.
He's coming.
- l don't give a fuck.
- lt's him, man.
[Alberto Speaking Spanish]
l don't care
where you blow him up.
[Tony]
Tell me when, okay?
[Snorting]
You just tell me when.
That's all l care about.
l heard you the first time.
You don't have to keep telling me.
One time.
That's all you gotta tell me.
[Snorting]
This fuckin' guy,
l'm tellin' you.
[Snorting]
[Ernie]
Look. Here he comes.
Where's he goin'?
What's he doin' that way?
What the fuck he doin'?
What the fuck is that?
Hey, come here.
- You told me she took
the kids in the other car.
- She did, boss.
She did every fuckin' day.
l don't know what's goin' on.
Hey, no fuckin' way.
Hey, no fuckin' way. That's it!
This fuckin' guy.
Fuck you, you fuckin' vulture.
Two little kids in the car.
This is so fuckin' bad.
l see 'em, all right?
l see 'em!
Shut the fuck up, okay?
You don't have the guts to look 'em
in the eye when you kill 'em.
You gotta hide
with that fuckin' shit.
[Chi Chi] Tony, he's getting up.
Come on. Let's do it.
Make you feel good, huh?
Make you feel good to kill a mother
and her kids. Make you feel big.
Like you big man!
Well, fuck you!
What do you think l am?
You think l kill two kids and a woman?
Fuck that!
l don't need that shit in my life!
- You die, motherfucker!
- [Groans]
[Horns Honking]
What you think l am? What you think,
l a fuckin' worm, like you?
l told you, man!
l told you, don't fuck with me!
l told you,
no fuckin' kids!
No, but you wouldn't listen!
Well, you stupid fuck! Look at you now.
[Tony] Nick, Nick,
where the fuck you been?
On a delivery?
Where the hell is Manny?
l been callin' all over. Where is he?
Uh, l don't-- l don't know, Tony.
He's been gone the last couple of days.
- He didn't say nothin'.
- He gone? What? Where?
l left him in fuckin' charge, man!
Where the fuck is he?
You can't trust
nobody anymore!
l don't know, Tony.
He just took off.
- He didn't say nothing.
- He took off?
- Are you all right?
- No, l'm not all right! l'm pissed!
And when l get back there, l gonna kick
some ass all over the fuckin' place!
- When you comin' back?
- l'm comin' back tonight!
This fuckin' cocksucker!
Tony... your mama called.
Gina's gone.
- Gone? Where?
- She got to see you right away.
Okay, just tell her-- tell her
l call her tonight, okay?
Listen to me.
What about Elvie? She call?
- No.
- No?
Okay. Okay, listen to me.
lf she call, just tell her l love her.
Okay? Just tell her that.
- You hear from Manny?
- No. Your mama called again.
She gotta see you.
And Sosa has been ringing
every half hour. He sounds pissed.
Get him on the phone.
Elvie call?
No.
- You keep tryin' Manny.
l want that cocksucker here.
- Okay.
- l want him here now! Okay?
Come on. Go ahead.
Get him, get him! Let's go. Come on!
[Chi Chi] - Señor Sosa?
Ya él viene. Mira. Ahí está.
Aquí está el tipo ese.
[Ringing]
Yeah? Mamá.
Yeah, l know. l know.
Yeah, they told me.
Yeah, okay.
l'm coming over.
l'll be over to see you.
l'll be over, yeah.
- Oka-- Yeah, okay.
- Momento.
Put it on the speaker.
[Snorting]
[Sosa]
What happened, Tony?
- Alex, how you doing?
- What happened?
Oh, we had some problems,
you know?
Alex?
Tony, what happened?
- We had a little problem.
- l heard.
- How you hear that?
- Because our friend gave
a speech today at the U.N.
He was not supposed to give
that speech, Tony.
Well, your guy Alberto,
he's a piece of shit, ya know?
l told him to do something.
He didn't listen, so l had
to cancel his contract.
My partners and l
are pissed off, Tony.
That's okay.
No big deal.
There's other Albertos, you know?
We do it next month.
No, Tony, you can't do that.
They found what was
under the car, Tony.
Now our friend has got
security up the ass,
and the heat is gonna come down hard
on my partners and me.
There's not gonna be a next time,
you fuckin', dumb cocksucker!
- You blew it!
- Take it easy when you talk to me.
l told you a long time ago, you fuckin'
little monkey, not to fuck me!
Hey, who the fuck you think you're
talking to? You wanna fuck with--
Who the fuck you think l am,
your fuckin' bellboy?
[Muttering]
You wanna go to war?
We take you to war, okay?
- Tony. ¡Coño! ¡Cálmate!
- Alex, you there? Hey!
He's not there.
Cálmate, man.
She got a place of her own.
She don't tell me where.
One night l follow her
in a taxi, and she goes to this
fancy house in Coconut Grove.
- The Grove? Where'd she
get that kind of money?
- You!
You are giving her the money!
Don't you see what you do to her?
- l don't give her that kind of money.
- Yes, you did!
- One time, a thousand dollars
you gave her.
- Was a guy with her?
l don't know. l don't know.
There was this car
in the driveway.
l know if l go in there,
she'll kill me. She's like you.
Where's the place?
Where is it?
Four hundred something.
Cit-- Citrus Drive?
- Four hundred what?
- Four hundred nine, l think.
You gotta talk to her, Antonio.
She don't listen to me.
- Come on.
- She says to me, mira, ''Shut up.
Mind your own business.''
Exactly like you do to me.
Ever since you came back,
she's been getting this way.
- l gotta go.
- Why do you have to hurt
everything you touch?
- ¡Coño!
- Why do you have to destroy...
everything that comes your way?
¡Malagradecido!
¡Mal hijo!
- 409 Citrus Drive.
- Okay.
- Tony, l can't find Manny anywhere.
- Fuck!
- Okay.
- Hey, listen, boss. l'll try again.
[Snorting]
[Sobbing]
You stay here.
Keep trying Manny, okay?
[Door Buzzing]
Tony.
[Gunshot]
- [No Audible Dialogue]
- [Gunshot]
[Sobbing]
We got married just yesterday.
We were gonna surprise you.
[Ernie]
Jesus, Tony.
Tony, we gotta get outta here, man.
We gotta get outta here.
Go get Gina.
- No!
- Please.
No! No!
[Sobbing]
- [Shouting]
- No, Gina. Come on, Gina. No!
God! God!
[Sobbing Continues]
Tony, we can't stay here. We gotta go.
We gotta get out of here.
[Gina Continues Sobbing]
Come on, Gina.
Nooo.
Here we go.
lt's gonna be okay.
- You got her?
- l got her.
No! Nooo!
This is Tony's place! Let me go!
No! No!
No! Don't!
[Screaming]
No-oo! No!
[Sobbing Continues]
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
We put some pills into her.
She's gonna be all right, Tony.
She's cooling down.
Right, Ernie?
- She's gonna be fine, Tony. Just fine.
- Right.
What are we gonna do now?
Do?
We're gonna war.
That what we're gonna do.
We're gonna eat that Sosa
for breakfast!
Close that fucker down!
[Snorting]
Hey, Tony.
Take it easy.
All right, Ernie. Let's go.
We'll take care of the house.
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
[Sniffles]
[Panting]
[Tiger Growling]
Come on. This cocksucker's
gonna run all over you.
Míralo.
- ¿Qué vamos a hacer con él?
- ¡lmposible!
- ¿Sabes qué? Mira hacia el puente.
- Okay. Okay.
- ¡Y pela el ojo!
Come on.
l bury these cocksuckers.
Okay.
[Clears Throat]
We gotta get organized here. Huh?
[Sniffles]
Come on.
All right.
Fuck!
Oh, fuck, Manny.
How the fuck l do that?
How the fuck l do that,
Manny?
[Gasping]
[Grunts]
[Men Shouting]
[Groans]
Manolo.
[Snorting]
[Door Opens]
[Gina]
Tony?
[Sniffing, Clears Throat]
Gina?
[Closes Door]
ls this what you want, Tony?
Huh, Tony?
You can't stand for another man
to be touching me.
So you want me, Tony, huh?
Huh?
What you talkin'?
Oh, is that it?
[Chuckles]
Huh?
- Here l am, Tony.
- Fuck!
l am all yours now, Tony,
you see?
[Chuckling]
l'm all yours now.
- Gina.
- [Giggling]
- You better come and get me now.
- Gina.
- Hold it. Come on.
- Come and get me. Come on!
Come on. Come and get me, Tony.
You do it now before it's too late.
- Ow! Ooow!
- [Laughs]
- Ow!
- Come on, Tony.
Oh, come on, Tony.
Fuck me, huh?
Fuck me, Tony!
- Gina!
- Fuck me. Come on and just fuck me!
- [Shouting]
- [Screams]
[Gasps]
[Screaming]
Die! Die!
¡Vámonos!
[Whistling]
Tony! They're all over the place!
Get out of here!
[Men Shouting]
Gina!
¡Fuego! ¡Fuego!
[Body Falls]
[Man Shouts]
Come on. Look at your face.
lt's all dirty.
- [Machine Gun Firing]
- Gina.
[Sobbing]
Please--
Please talk to me.
Come on.
Don't be mad at me.
Oh, please. Gina.
Come on.
l-- l love Manny, you know?
l love him.
[Panting]
And l love you too, you know?
[Machine Gun Continues]
¡Ahora!
¡Vámonos! ¡Vámonos!
[Gunfire]
- [Loud Gunfire]
- Gimme a smile, okay?
They're coming from everywhere!
Tony, open up! Open the fuckin' door!
Please! Tony!
Let me in, boss! Please!
Tony, open the fuckin' door!
Tony!
- ¡Coño, Tony!
Open the fuckin'--
- [Machine Gun Firing]
[Groaning]
[Tony Sighs]
Okay.
- ¡Órale!
- [Gunfire]
Okay.
You wait here, okay?
l'll be with you. l be back.
You wait for me.
l coming back.
Okay.
Okay, Sosa.
You wanna fuck with me?
[Shouting ln Spanish, lndistinct]
Okay.
You're fuckin' with the best!
Come on.
You wanna fuck with me?
Okay.
Okay, you cockroaches.
Come on!
You wanna play games?
Okay, l play with you.
Come on!
Okay. You wanna play rough?
Okay!
Say hello to my little friend!
[Men Screaming]
Okay, you wanna play rough?
Okay!
- There! Okay. You like that?
- [Man Coughing]
Huh? You want more?
- [Gasping]
- Huh?
- [Screaming]
- Come on! Okay!
Okay! You whores!
Cowards!
[Screams]
- [Gunfire]
- [Screams]
[Groaning]
[Screams]
Wanna fuck with me?
[Men Screaming]
Go ahead!
[Coughs]
Die!
Hey, how'd you like that?
Huh? You fuckin' maricón!
Hey!
You think you can take me?
You need a fuckin' army,
you gonna take me!
Ya hear? Come on!
l take you all to fuckin' hell!
Come on. Come on.
Come to me!
Okay! Who you think you fuckin' with?
l Tony Montana!
You fuck with me,
you fuckin' with the best!
[Screams]
l'm still standin', huh!
Fuck!
[Screams]
Come on!
l take your fuckin' bullet!
- ¡Parada! ¡Parada!
- Come on! l take your fuckin' bullet!
You think you kill me with bullets?
l take your fuckin' bullets! Go ahead!
[Screams]
(Subtitles ripped by T101)