Miss.
What do you want?
I told you not to come here to bother Benito.
Benito!
You are a criminal and my
baby won't be a criminal like you.
Benito is not coming out!
Or I'll call the police to take you to jail,
that's what you want, you asshole.
Grandma.
You shut up and go back inside!
You aren't going out I told you,
don't you understand spanish
Let this be our secret my friend...
...keep the secret here, ok?
Lil' Mago wants to see you.
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten...
Eleven...
Twelve...
Twelve... Twelve...
...Thirteen.
Congratulations little Homie!
Casper, look at the kids smile.
The gang who controls "Salvatrucha" gang.
Your dad is waiting for you.
Look, I know why you
want to do this trip, but...
...I don't know why I have to do it.
If you don't want to go,
grandma can not make you go, but...
...my brother won't come back for you again.
Look, I don't need anyone, I can go
to the north by myself if I wanted to.
Come with us, it won't be easy over
there, but at least we will be together.
There is nothing for you here, Sayra.
Nothing.
She is here.
Damn, if I didn't know I wouldn't recognize her.
She is a lady now.
Now you can recover your lost time.
We will do that on the way mother.
Tomorrow before sunrise we will grab the bus.
Don't worry, she will be ready.
"The Bombilla" Tapachula, Southern Mexico.
Here is Lucrecia with her products.
Casper, how have you been, now you
are a pederast?, the smaller the more idiots.
Look how you beat him up, you are a barbarian.
Tortillas, coffee, baleadas,soups!
Thank you!
Slow baby, slow..
Stop it.
Martha Marlene.
I am bored.
why?
Can you take me somewhere?
Where do you want to go?
I don't know, wherever you want to,
where you go when you are not here.
You have another girl in your neighborhood, right?
Of course not.
You better not, because if I
realize that you have other girl...
What?
It shrinked...
Oh, it's normal, look...
...now it will be refreshed.
Do you think she will have a friend for me?
Be careful my friend "Smiley"...
...don't say anything that
we left from the "Bombilla"
Don't say anything at all,
so Lil' Mago won't notice.
Ok?
Yes.
Not a fucking word!
Little Homie, you will first earn your letters,
hitting on a "Kiddo"...
...then after that, you will conquer a girl.
Welcome to the destroyer.
- What's up, homie?
- Cool, brother.
What's up Casper you dog!
What, did he kill a "kiddo" yet, uh?
This is the "Naughty" and the "Smoky"...
...they just arrived, they come and
go to see what's going on here.
They are "Guanacos".
Are you thirsty?
This guy is "gold" we call him "the buttocks"...
...and this is the "Querubin".
He can't sit, his ass is bleeding...
...he has hemorroids.
This you have to earn it...
for the moment you have to share.
What's for the gang is for the gang.
He is the one that has the second voice.
Hey, my dogs are here.
How was it?
Did you go to the "Bombilla"?
Yes, but we didn't find anything.
The "Sol" found him with
another group of "chickens"...
...in the "Bombilla".
Take him out.
Don't worry, nothing is happening,
now that dog that scares you will die.
You fucked up "Kiddo",
you got in the train of the gang.
I'm only going to the north, please, please!
You are already worthless you fucker...
...we will cut you in 18 pieces
and we will feed the dogs.
I have a family...
and I'm not a gangster anymore.
"kiddo" will always be a "kiddo"
Casper, give "Smiley" a hand.
Both of you, get him.
Point to his head.
This is for the fallen Homies, you fucker.
To the count of three...
One...
Two...
...Three.
The first time is like this
little Homie, don't chicken out.
The scareness goes away,
but the gang is forever.
Now you belong to a family
with thousands of brothers...
...wherever you go, there will
always be someone that protects you
Food is here!
You were not in the "Bombilla" today.
The "Sol" didn't see you.
I was there the whole day,
and I didn't see him neither.
You are not playing gay, right Homie?
It has been many times already,
now the "Sol" didn't see you.
Forget what I said Homie...
...the homies are getting altered.
I love you dog, from my heart.
3 days later.
9085550187... again.
we learned it already.
repeat it.
I told you we learned it already.
you have to learn that number, if something
goes wrong, Yessenia can help you out.
Horacio, how much time left man?
Around 6 hours.
Are you tired?
Yes.
You have to see it as an adventure brother,
we are going to an adventure.
repeat the number one more time.
Guatemala-México Border.
Welcome to México.
Your documents.
You don't have, right?
everyone come this way.
First you are going to empty your pockets
and take out everything that has some value...
...after that, take off your clothes and put it
in front of you... start with the shoes.
We walked too much!
We need to buy some water for her...
With what money?
Bring two big bottles.
Your second toe is bigger than the others...
...that means you run fast.
This is what we have walked today.
If there is no immigration
we will be here in two weeks.
- Two weeks?
- Maybe three.
Where is New Jersey?
It's not in the map.
Look, not even half of them will arrive to the U.S.
...but we are going to get there.
Yessenia is not as pretty as your Mom was...
...but she has a big heart.
The girls are beautiful.
Keep it, now they are your family also.
I don't want a picture of your family.
You are taking me in this trip,
and I thank you for that.
I will go call home.
Look at him,
I remember him more handsome.
No, the handsome one in the family is me.
Don't tell me you are not a little happy.
If he was not deported, he wouldn't be here.
- Don't think in that bullshit.
- It's not bullshit.
Do you see that train?
That's our train, what do you say if
we grab it and go all the way to Texas?
I can take you to six flags.
Tell me one more time that you love me.
I love you.
Tell me that you won't hide me anymore.
It's not that.
Of course, you hide from me.
You already know all that is worth it.
Martha Marlene.
You think I don't realize what you
do the whole day with your friends?
You get high with other girls,
and fool around the whole day.
Homies you two go to the trains.
Casper, Smiley.
What's up "Sol"?
What's up?
Who is this girl?
Martha Marlene, he is the "Sol".
Is she your girl?
No, she is just a friend.
We have meeting tomorrow
at the cemetery, in the afternoon.
Be careful, ok?
Hey, be aware Homie,
the entrance is full of "kiddos"...
...who knows who is sneaking in with the people.
I'll take you home.
Friend... you idiot.
Homie, wait here Smiley.
Wait for me.
Let's go.
There will be no train.
The train went off the rail ahead,
there were many dead people.
Where did you hear that?
Some "Salvadorians" told me.
There will be no train!
We need more money to buy the
defense for the homies that are in jail.
finally, some Homies have
screwed up in their obligations...
...and the "kiddos" are getting in the territory.
We cannot allow those dogs bringing
their garbage in the neighborhood...
There will be "cut" for Casper and Smiley.
They fooled me...
...and you know that you cant lie to the leader...
worst, lie to the neighborhood.
Now I want to hear your version.
Where did you go after the "Bombilla"?
Smiley, where did you go?
Ok, your gun.
that's all.
"Salvatrucha" gang, the gang who
controls the "Salvatrucha" gang.
What are you doing here?
You have to go!
Now!
Why? is it a private party?
What's up Casper? who is this girl?
A friend.
From where?
I am from downtown.
Oh, sorry, I confused you.
I was going to take her to the exit.
No.
It won't take time Homie.
If you want I can take her...
...or she can stay and watch.
But you don't go anywhere Homie.
Take her directly to her house Homie.
13 seconds of cut for being a liar.
One...
Two... Three...
Smiley, you also have 13 seconds
for not saying anything against Casper.
This is the largest tree in Tapachula, if you
go to the top, you can see very far away.
Why Willie couldn't come?
Willie?
Do you refer to Casper?
Ohh, I get it now.
You are the reason for him being abscent.
Sit down, I want to talk to you.
Closer.
Don't be shy, I won't bite you.
So...
...you and Casper are more than friends.
I have to go.
Has he told you anything about us?
Do you know what are the most
important rules to keep a friendship?
Honesty, respect, and generosity.
hey girl...
Where is Martha Marlene?
She left.
To her house?
The beast took her.
You will find another one.
We are going to make a trip to Tonala...
...you and smiley will go with me.
Homie, one more thing...
...you lie to me again...
...and I will kill you myself.
Horacio, they already cleared the railway...
...the train goes this night thank god.
Give me the money!
Fast, fast!
give me the money!
Give him the money fast, fast.
That's enough!
Turn around!
Dad, Dad!
Smiley, get off the train!
but.. Casper.
Get off man!
Go Smiley, Go!
He is dangerous.
Are you ok?
He is not doing anything to us.
He is a gangster man.
We have to knock him off the train.
Immigration! immigration!
Raise your spawn "Salvatrucha" gang.
Homies...
...we have to talk about Casper.
We should all go and get him at once.
No Homie, water is not ready for beans yet.
Much less with so many fucker around.
They can attack the neighborhood...
...we have to run the voice, even we don't catch
him now, sooner or later the sun will light him
when that happens...
I am not a sissy, that's why I returned.
Then you are lucky I don't kill you smiley.
You seem not to have feelings
for the neighborhood, right?
If you didn't have the balls to kill Casper,
how do I know you didn't help him escape?
That's what happened right, you fucker?
I didn't do anything!
I will dissapear you from
the neighborhood, you fucker!
Show me you are not a sissy, show me!
Send me, send me so I can show you
that I have feelings for the neighborhood.
Send me so I can look for him, and kill him.
Calm down "Sol", hold it, hold it man.
Get going now.
Go and kill him if you want to stand out.
if you don't kill him, then don't even
dare to come back to the neighborhood.
Son of a bitch, he doesn't
even know where his dick is!
We have to communicate it
to all the gangsters in L.A.
That dog cannot have even a shadow to hide!
You going to die.
Thank you.
My name is Sayra.
I am Willie.
He killed Lil' Mago...
...he got warned, there is green light
to kill him, those are the rules.
And how are you going to kill him?
Wow!, thats so pretty! how many you got?
Enough to kill you all.
Kill him but hiding.
Sleep, I will stay awake.
You see, my family is very poor, we barely
had a little bit of beans to eat once in a while.
You are not going to wash yourself?
It feels good.
I don't know, maybe later.
When there is less people.
And what will you do later?
I don't know.
Will you stay here tonight?
If i find food around I will bring you later.
What were you talking with him?
We can help him.
Are you crazy?
we have to stay away from him.
No, you don't understand.
He is a killer.
- He is in trouble.
- I am ordering you.
But he is in trouble!
I don't care about him, I care
about you and my brother Orlando.
Look, we still have a long way to get there.
We have to be aware, we
can't let anyone separate us, ok?
Who is the boss?
I am.
I am Smiley from the Confetti neighborhood.
Who is the boss now in the Confetti?
The "Sol".
we knew what happened...
...are you hungry or thirsty?
Have you ever got into one of those?
...me neither.
In a road heading to Texas, I saw
a factory where they build them.
There was a letter board,
very big, with the world shape...
...and it was shiny, so beautiful.
I wanted to get on it.
when I go through there, I will
see it and it will remind me of you.
If you make it all the way.
I will make it... I am sure.
In Tegus I went with my friend Clarissa,
to my neighbor's house...
...a crazy old lady called Leonor...
...she was a witch.
She told me with scared voice,
you will make it to the U.S.
...but not holding god's hand,
but holding the devil's spawn.
if you come with us, you can show me
the letter board you are talking about...
...we are heading to New Jersey.
They are coming for you right?
I think so, sooner or later they will find me...
...the gang has good memory.
Are you afraid?
To be killed?
No, I live by the day.
What worries me is not knowing
what time and which day they will kill me.
- So you have not seen him?
- No.
He has a teardrop tatooed here.
No, I haven't seen anyone tatooed,
since 5 days ago until now you guys.
Hey, sons of a bitch!
I know about that guy you are looking for...
...he has a tear drop tatooed here.
Thank you!
We have to get down...
What?
We have to get down.
why?
In this station, immigration is
always fucking up...
...and sometimes the police also.
So what do we do?
We get down and surround the train fast,
we must be alert!
Good day for running, uh?
Me and Smiley will go the other way...
...we see each other in the other side of the station.
Hey, what's up, ese?
The "M", what's your neighborhood, fucker?
Hey, look at the guy, he is from the other gang.
Take out your fucking gun Smiley!
Don't worry Homie, these
guys always miss the target...
...except this one.
Where the fuck were you Homies?
...didn't you hear the gunshots?
Yes Homie, but we almost catch Casper.
You left us behind with those
assholes, and.. where is Casper?
In the train.
I want to take that fucker down.
Get on, Smiley, you go in the front.
You are leaving just like that?
So what do you want?
Go with you.
Oh, God! She fucked up!
I can't take care of you.
I am not asking you for it.
For god sake Sayra,
realize that I am a dead man!
...don't you get it?
Don't worry Willie.
Everything will be ok.
You messed up, you don't have
any idea about the mess you are in.
Horacio, Sayra is not here.
Oh Casper, why the fuck you came here?
You are just putting me into trouble.
I can do what you are asking for,
but really, it's trouble.
I have to do some things first.
you guys hungry?
You can stay sleeping in the sofa.
Do you guys want to take a shower?
You are a little one.
Well, let me see what I've got.
I thought you didn't have family.
I don't, she is not my aunt...
...I used to take people on her territory.
And she will take us to the border?
Are you coming with me?
Let's see, try this on..
I hope it fits you.
The shower is over there...
...but don't get close to the window, ok?
I don't want anyone to know you are here.
What are you going to do with the girl?
I'll help her get to the border
so she can find her family over there.
And what do you get with all this?
Nothing.
Ok, Casper.
Going straight to the border...
...you know what awaits for you.
Did you know they already called me?
And what did you tell them?
Nothing, the truth, that I haven't seen you...
but they called me yesterday.
You are not going to tell them, right?
I always do the right thing.
Maybe she went down to
take a pee and the train left her.
She left.
So, we wait here.
We can't wait.
We have to go
or we won't get there either.
Ok, fuck!
Take this.
Thank you, aunt.
Don't thank me.
"Sol", it's a pleasure to hear you.
Are you afraid?
No, if I am with you I am ok.
The opposite, while you
are with me you are not ok.
I don't care, I trust you.
This scar here...
...my gang sent me to leave
a "chicken" to the border...
...and in Tamaulipas, a cop started to shoot me...
...and here, one from the 18,
there was a fight in their territory.
This scar here is from the night that the
Homies that I have defended all my life...
...killed my love.
And I couldn't do anything for her.
Do you still trust me, Sayra?
We both know what a loss is.
All that I know, is that my
whole life has been worthless.
And that I can ruin your life too.
Get off, go away!
I love you!
Come on, say it with more feeling.
It's just that I love you so much
that I don't even know what to tell you.
I don't know how to express it.
if you can measure it with
your hands, how much would it be?
It wouldn't be possible, I would need many miles...
...or the whole universe to
tell you how much I love you.
Get off, you assholes!
Hide, hide, hide there.
Ok, this card is your pass,
it's only valid for 3 nights...
...then you have to leave to give
space to the people that just arrived.
You have two meals everyday, lunch and
dinner and please respect the rules in the wall.
We don't want low life people like
you here, you fucking gangster.
Not now.
That's the least, you can't be here!
Let him go kid, let him!
Hey, I can't believe that you are here.
Have you seen my dad and my uncle?
What?
Your uncle was deported, and...
...your father is not with us anymore.
When we are in the other side,
I want you to promise something.
What?
That no matter what, you
will look for your family in New Jersey.
Now you have to little sisters
that have no father anymore.
I would be trouble for them,
as I am for everyone.
Not for me.
But you have to help them
in something, working.
Are you coming with me?
Yes.
I am looking for a boat.
Do you want to cross?
Come on!
I can only pass one at the time.
The money?
When we cross we give it to you.
Go on fast.
Turn around.
Hurry up and get in the water.
No... we have to go back!
Let me go!
Smiley...
The gang is forever, Homie.
Collect call, please.
Sayra.
Hello?
Yessenia?