[SIREN]
[GUNSHOT]
AAH!
[SIREN]
COME ON, DOC.
YOU STAYING DOWN HERE?
YEAH.
CHECK THIS OUT.
PRINTS RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE REPORTING
TO YOU LIVE
FROM THE NEAR-NORTHSIDE HOME
OF DR. RICHARD KIMBLE,
A RESPECTED
VASCULAR SURGEON
AT CHICAGO
MEMORIAL HOSPITAL.
DETAILS ARE SKETCHY
AT THIS HOUR,
BUT WE UNDERSTAND
DR. KIMBLE'S WIFE HELEN
WAS FOUND MURDERED
THIS EVENING.
RIGHT NOW,
AREA SIX DETECTIVES
ARE BRINGING OUT
DR. KIMBLE.
WE ASSUME THEY'RE GOING
TO BE TAKING HIM
TO A POLICE STATION,
PROBABLY AREA SIX,
WHERE THEY HOPE
HE CAN SHED SOME LIGHT
ON WHAT HAPPENED.
NOW, SHE WAS FOUND
SHORTLY BEFORE MIDNIGHT.
WE KNOW SHE MADE,
APPARENTLY, A 911 CALL,
INDICATING THAT
THERE WAS AN INTRUDER
OR SHE WAS
BEING ASSAULTED.
DETAILS ARE VERY SKETCHY.
WE DO KNOW THAT HE AND HIS
WIFE WERE AT A FUND-RAISER
AT THE FOUR SEASONS HOTEL
EARLIER TONIGHT--
A FUND-RAISER
FOR THE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH FUND.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HEY.
HEY, RICH.
REMEMBER CARA?
HI, CARA.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
ENJOY
THE EVENING.
STRAIGHTEN THAT ARM,
OR YOU'RE
GOING TO SLICE.
GOLF PRO
TEACH YOU THAT?
NO. MY WIFE.
OH, BEFORE I FORGET.
HERE, THANKS
FOR THE LOANER.
ANY GAS IN IT?
YEAH, ENOUGH.
ALEC, RICHARD KIMBLE.
OH, DR. KIMBLE.
GUESS
THAT WORKS, TOO.
ABSOLUTELY.
ANYTIME.
I THINK
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA,
FOR YOU TO TRY
THAT PROJECT.
YOU GUYS
KNOCK IT OFF,
AND YOU
COME WITH ME.
EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU.
I WAS JUST DOWN
TO MY LAST JOKE.
[DR. KIMBLE]
YOU LOOK REALLY
BEAUTIFUL TONIGHT.
THANKS, HONEY.
I KNOW
YOU HATE THESE THINGS,
BUT I LOVE
SEEING YOU IN A TUX.
I JUST FEEL I LOOK LIKE
A WAITER OR SOMETHING.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
HELLO.
DR. KIMBLE?
YES.
SORRY TO BOTHER YOU,
BUT DR. STEVENS
JUST WENT INTO
EMERGENCY O.R.
AND ASKED
IF YOU COULD HELP.
ALL RIGHT, TELL HIM
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU.
YEP. THANK YOU.
GOOD NIGHT.
I'LL WAIT UP FOR YOU.
...WAIT UP FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS,
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
RICHARD,
THANKS FOR COMING.
A 58-YEAR-OLD GUY.
JUST PULLED HIS HOT
GALL BLADDER. BLEEDING.
IT'S ALL
IN THE LIVER BED.
WHAT ARE HIS COAGS?
P.T.'S 36,
AND THE REST
ARE OFF THE WALL.
WHERE'D WE GET
THIS GUY?
LENTZ'S NAME'S
ON THE CHART.
WE PAGED HIM.
NO ANSWER.
O.K., GUYS,
LET ME IN THERE.
JUST GIVE ME SOME ROOM.
MARIA, GIVE ME A CLAMP.
GIVE ME SOME SUCTION.
HAVE YOU BEEN GETTING
ANY THREATS AT WORK?
CO-WORKERS,
STAFF AT THE HOSPITAL,
ANYTHING LIKE THAT
AT ALL?
NO.
ANYTHING UNUSUAL
GOING ON
AS FAR
AS PHONE CALLS,
PEOPLE HANGING UP,
UH, PEOPLE COMING
TO THE DOOR,
TRADESPEOPLE?
NOT THAT I KNOW OF.
NOW, DOC, UH,
ON THIS FIGHT
WITH THIS GUY
WITH THE ONE ARM,
DID IT HAPPEN UPSTAIRS
OR DOWNSTAIRS?
UPSTAIRS.
UH-HUH. AND HE HAD--
WHICH WAS IT,
THE RIGHT OR LEFT ARM,
HAD THAT LITTLE GIMMICK
ON IT?
RIGHT ARM.
WAS IT ONE OF THOSE
WITH THE HOOKS OR...
NO. HE HAD A C--
HE HAD A COSMETIC HAND.
IT'S A PRETTY GOOD
SECURITY SYSTEM
YOU GOT
IN YOUR HOUSE.
ANYONE HAVE
THE CODING
BESIDES YOU
AND YOUR WIFE?
O-OUR MAID...
KNOWS WHAT THE CODE IS
AND HAS A KEY
TO THE HOUSE.
THOSE SCRATCHES
ON YOUR NECK--
DID THE ONE-ARMED GUY
DO THAT?
HELEN SCRATCHED ME
WHEN I TRIED TO MOVE HER.
IS THAT BEFORE OR AFTER
YOU FOUGHT
WITH THE ONE-ARMED GUY?
I TOLD YOU...
DO YOU OWN A GUN, DOC?
DO YOU OWN A GUN?
YES, WE HAVE A GUN
IN THE HOUSE.
IS IT REGISTERED TO YOU?
YES.
WHERE DO YOU USUALLY
KEEP THAT GUN--
THE ONE YOU OWN?
IT'S IN HELEN'S TABLE.
BEDSIDE TABLE.
DO YOU KEEP JEWELRY
IN THE HOUSE--
HELLO.
HIS FINGERPRINTS ARE
ALL OVER THE LAMP,
GUN,
AND THE BULLETS,
AND THE GOOD
DOCTOR'S SKIN
IS UNDER
HER FINGERNAILS.
YOUR WIFE,
SHE'S GOT THE MONEY IN
THE FAMILY, DOESN'T SHE?
HELEN COMES
FROM A WEALTHY FAMILY...
YES.
IS SHE INSURED?
YES, SHE IS.
WHO'S THE BENEFICIARY?
I AM.
THE SOLE BENEFICIARY?
YES.
FINANCIALLY,
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
BE HURTING AFTER THIS,
ARE YOU?
SHE WAS WORTH
QUITE A BIT OF MONEY.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT I KILLED MY WIFE?
YOU'RE SAYING
THAT I CRUSHED HER SKULL
AND THAT I SHOT HER?
HOW DARE YOU!
WHEN I CAME HOME,
A MAN WAS IN MY HOUSE.
I FOUGHT WITH THIS MAN.
HE HAD A MECHANICAL ARM.
PLASTIC?
YOU FIND THIS MAN.
HOW TALL WAS HE?
HE TOOK EVERYTHING
FROM ME.
OH, JESUS.
WHAT DID HE WEIGH?
WHAT COLOR
WAS HIS HAIR?
WHAT COLOR WERE HIS EYES?
WE CAN'T HELP YOU
UNTIL YOU HELP US.
BOOK HIM.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
OF THE JURY,
YOU WILL HEAR
IRONCLAD PROOF
OF RICHARD KIMBLE'S GUILT--
INDISPUTABLE
SCIENTIFIC EVIDENCE
THAT ON THE NIGHT
OF JANUARY 20th,
RICHARD KIMBLE DID,
IN FACT, VICIOUSLY...
ATTACK AND BRUTALLY MURDER
HIS WIFE.
[GUNSHOT]
BUT YOU WILL HEAR
MORE THAN THAT.
YOU WILL HEAR A VOICE
FROM THE GRAVE--
THE VOICE OF HELEN KIMBLE
IDENTIFYING HER KILLER--
HER HUSBAND,
RICHARD KIMBLE.
DETECTIVE KELLY,
CAN YOU TELL US
WHAT YOU OBSERVED
AT THE VICTIM'S HOME
THE NIGHT
OF THE MURDER?
NO FORCIBLE ENTRY WAS FOUND.
FROM THE BEGINNING
OF THE INVESTIGATION,
THERE DIDN'T APPEAR
TO BE A BREAK-IN.
NOTHING WAS MISSING.
HONEY, I'M HOME.
[DIAL TONE]
WHO WON THE GAME?
THE DEFENDANT'S PRINTS WERE
ON THE GUN AND BULLETS.
NO OTHER SETS WERE FOUND,
OTHER THAN THE HOUSEKEEPER
AND THE DECEASED.
THE FRACTURING
OF MRS. KIMBLE'S SKULL
CAUSED A MASSIVE HEMORRHAGE
TO THE BRAIN.
IT TOOK LESS
THAN FIVE MINUTES
FOR HER TO DIE.
[GASPING FOR AIR]
YOUR HONOR,
WE'D ASK TO PLAY
HELEN KIMBLE'S
911 EMERGENCY CALL,
PREVIOUSLY IDENTIFIED
BY A CHICAGO POLICE
DEPARTMENT DISPATCHER.
[BEEP]
EMERGENCY 911.
PLEASE HELP ME.
WHAT SEEMS TO BE
THE PROBLEM, MA'AM?
HE'S...HERE,
STILL IN THE HOUSE.
DID I HEAR YOU RIGHT?
SOMEONE'S IN YOUR HOUSE?
[GASPING]
HE'S TRYING
TO KILL ME.
WOULD YOU
REPEAT THAT, PLEASE?
[GASPING]
MA'AM?
HE'S TRYING
TO KILL ME.
MA'AM?
MA'AM, IS YOUR ATTACKER
STILL IN THE HOUSE?
MA'AM?
RICHARD.
HE'S TRYING TO KILL ME.
[DIAL TONE]
MR. KIMBLE...
HAVING CONSIDERED
ALL THE FACTORS
AND AGGRAVATION
AND MITIGATION
IN THIS CASE
AND FOUND
THE OFFENSE WAS BRUTAL
AND INDICATIVE
OF WANTON CRUELTY,
IT'S THE JUDGMENT
OF THIS COURT
THAT YOU BE REMANDED
TO ILLINOIS STATE
PENITENTIARY,
WHERE YOU WILL
AWAIT EXECUTION
BY LETHAL INJECTION
ON A DATE
TO BE SET FORTH
BY THE ATTORNEY GENERAL
OF THIS STATE,
AND MAY GOD HAVE MERCY
ON YOUR SOUL.
CARLSON.
HERE.
PARTIDA.
YEAH.
COPELAND.
WHAT?
COPELAND,
YOU BE NICE.
KIMBLE?
YEAH.
LET'S GO, GENTLEMEN.
FOUR PRISONERS
COMING OUT.
PRISONERS COMING OUT.
LET'S GO, GENTLEMEN.
KIMBLE, YOU'RE HERE.
CARLSON,
RIGHT OVER THERE.
PARTIDA,
UP FRONT, LEFT.
COPELAND, YOU'RE
BACK HERE WITH ME.
YEAH, RIGHT.
COME ON, MAKE
YOURSELF COMFORTABLE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU KNOW
THE ROUTINE, GENTLEMEN.
I'M TIRED.
MMM.
20 MILES FROM MENARD.
WE SHOULD BE THERE
IN ABOUT 40 MINUTES.
I'LL BE GLAD
TO GET RID OF THIS LOAD.
LET McKENZIE
TAKE CARE OF 'EM.
ALWAYS GOT SOMETHING
GOOD TO EAT THERE.
I'M STARVING.
AW, ME, TOO.
HAD ENOUGH
OF THAT PRISON CHOW.
OHH, MAN.
HEY, OLD ED HERE,
HE DON'T CARE.
HIS OLD LADY'S
GOT HIM ON A DIET.
[VOMITING]
[COUGHING]
HEY, SOMEBODY GET
IN HERE QUICK!
GET A HACK IN HERE!
HE'S GETTING SICK
BACK HERE.
HE'S FOAMING AT THE MOUTH.
WE'RE ALMOST
TO THE PRISON.
HE'S CHOKING!
COME ON.
JUST WAIT.
AAH!
OH.
OH, SHIT.
OH, MY GOD.
KIMBLE!
KIMBLE, GET OVER HERE!
YOU'RE A DOCTOR!
DO SOMETHING!
UNLOCK ME.
HERE.
HANG IN THERE.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE O.K.
[TRAIN WHISTLE]
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
OH, SHIT!
AAH!
GIVE ME A HAND WITH HIM.
OH, THE HELL WITH YOU.
COPELAND, GIVE ME
A HAND WITH THIS MAN.
KISS MY ASS, DOC.
OH, JESUS.
NOW, YOU LISTEN.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
WHICH WAY YOU GO.
JUST DON'T FOLLOW ME.
GOT THAT?
YEAH.
HEY, COPELAND...
BE GOOD.
[SIREN]
MY, MY, MY, MY, MY.
WHAT A MESS.
IT'S A CIRCUS.
[RENFRO]
NEWMAN, YOU GOT MY BAG?
[BIGGS]
POINT OF IMPACT
RIGHT HERE.
YEAH, THE FIRST ENGINE
UNCOUPLED.
THE REST OF THE TRAIN
JUMPED THE TRACK.
ABOUT
A HUNDRED YARDS?
YEAH. YOU GOT TO GET
SOME NEW BOOTS.
I TOLD YOU NOT
TO WEAR THE HEELS.
WELL, NEXT
TRAIN WRECK.
WHY WE ALWAYS
MOTHERING HER?
SHE LOVES US.
HOW'D YOU LIKE TO BE
THE GUY WHO DROVE THIS?
I'LL BET HE DID
A CASEY JONES.
HI. WHO'S IN CHARGE?
SHERIFF ROLLINS.
ROLLINS?
JUST FOLLOW
THE TV LIGHTS.
GOOD. GOOD.
SHERIFF ROGERS.
ROLLINS.
BIGGS, DO
A LOOK-AND-SEE THERE
AND TAKE NEWMAN.
RIGHT. COME ON, NOAH.
TIME TO GO TO WORK.
THE BUS ROLLS OVER
SEVERAL TIMES
BEFORE IT SETTLED
AT THE BOTTOM
OF THE HILL HERE.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I PASSED OUT,
BUT WHEN I LOOKED UP,
THE TRAIN WAS BEARING
DOWN ON US...FAST.
I DON'T KNOW HOW,
BUT SOMEHOW I GRABBED HIM,
AND I PUSHED HIM
OUT OF THE BUS.
YOU'RE A BRAVE MAN.
YOU COULD'VE
BOTH BEEN KILLED.
HE'S MY PARTNER.
HE WOULD'VE DONE
THE SAME FOR ME.
I'M DEPUTY UNITED STATES
MARSHAL SAMUEL GERARD.
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU.
I'LL BE WITH YOU
IN JUST A MINUTE.
O.K.
ONE MORE TIME,
JUST FOR THE RECORD,
THESE THREE ARE DEAD...
AND, UH, THIS ONE?
WELL, EVERYTHING
HAPPENED SO FAST, I...
NO, I DON'T THINK
HE MADE IT.
WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU CAME A LONG WAY
FOR NOTHING.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
I'D LIKE TO RECOMMEND
CHECKPOINTS
ON A 15-MILE RADIUS
AT I-57, I-24,
AND OVER HERE--
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WAIT A MINUTE.
THE PRISONERS
ARE ALL DEAD.
THE ONLY THING
CHECKPOINTS ARE
GOING TO DO
IS GET A LOT OF
GOOD PEOPLE FRANTIC.
WELL, SHIT, SHERIFF,
I'D HATE TO
SEE THAT HAPPEN,
SO I GUESS I'LL TAKE OVER
YOUR INVESTIGATION.
YOU...
ON WHAT AUTHORITY?
GOVERNOR OF
THE STATE OF ILLINOIS,
THE UNITED STATES
MARSHAL'S OFFICE,
FIFTH DISTRICT,
NORTHERN ILLINOIS.
ALL RIGHT. FINE.
YOU WANT JURISDICTION
OVER THIS MESS,
YOU GOT IT.
O.K., BOYS,
GATHER AROUND HERE
AND LISTEN UP!
WE'RE SHUTTING IT DOWN.
WYATT EARP'S HERE
TO MOP UP FOR US.
VERY FUNNY.
SAM.
OH, WOW, GEE WHIZ,
LOOK HERE.
YOU KNOW,
WE'RE ALWAYS FASCINATED
WHEN WE FIND LEG IRONS
WITH NO LEGS IN THEM.
WHO HELD THE KEYS, SIR?
ME.
WHERE ARE THOSE KEYS AT?
I DON'T KNOW.
CARE TO REVISE
YOUR STATEMENT, SIR?
WHAT?
DO YOU WANT TO CHANGE
YOUR BULLSHIT STORY,
SIR?
HE MIGHT'VE GOT OUT.
A MINUTE AGO,
YOU WERE TELLING ME
HE'S PART
OF THE WRECKAGE,
AND NOW HE MIGHT'VE
GOT OUT?
LISTEN UP,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN!
OUR FUGITIVE HAS BEEN
ON THE RUN FOR 90 MINUTES.
THE AVERAGE FOOT SPEED
OVER UNEVEN GROUND
IS 4 MILES AN HOUR.
THAT GIVE US
A RADIUS OF 6 MILES.
WHAT I WANT
OUT OF EACH OF YOU
IS A HARD TARGET SEARCH
OF EVERY GAS STATION,
RESIDENCE,
WAREHOUSE, FARMHOUSE,
HENHOUSE, OUTHOUSE,
AND DOGHOUSE IN THAT AREA.
CHECKPOINTS GO UP
AT 15 MILES.
YOUR FUGITIVE'S NAME
IS DR. RICHARD KIMBLE.
GO GET HIM.
[SIREN]
LOOK, PLEASE, DON'T
GIVE ME SHIT, RENEE.
I GOT THREE VERY UNHAPPY
DEAD PEOPLE HERE.
STEVENS, IT'S COSMO.
I'M GOING TO HAVE
SATELLITE TELEPHONE
HOOKUP IN TWO SECONDS.
CHESTER POLICE
JUST FOUND A BLOOD TRAIL.
2 MILES. SOUTHWEST.
ROBERT, TYPE THAT BLOOD.
MATCH IT AGAINST
ALL FOUR PRISONERS.
RENFRO.
YO!
GET A FAX I.D. ON KIMBLE
TO EVERY LOCAL HOSPITAL
AND FOLLOW IT
WITH TROOPERS.
NEWMAN.
YES?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M THINKING.
WELL, THINK ME UP
A CUP OF COFFEE
AND A CHOCOLATE
DOUGHNUT WITH
SPRINKLES ON TOP.
WE GOT A BODY OVER HERE!
WE GOT A LIVE ONE!
WE GOT A LIVE ONE
RIGHT DOWN HERE!
WE GOT A LIVE ONE!
HANG IN THERE, BROTHER.
WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU
OUT OF HERE.
YOU GOT IT?
YEAH.
WATCH YOUR STEP THERE.
GET THAT AMBULANCE
DOWN HERE!
DR. JOHNSON, LINE 1.
DR. JOHNSON,
PLEASE PICK UP LINE 1.
IS THIS WHAT
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR?
THAT'S IT.
I'M GOING TO MAKE
SOME COPIES.
GOOD MORNING,
MR. JOHNSON,
I HAVE YOUR BREAKFAST
FOR YOU.
MY, WE ARE THIRSTY
TODAY, AREN'T WE?
NOW EAT UP
BEFORE THIS GETS COLD.
IT REALLY DOES GET DRY
IN HERE, DOESN'T IT?
HERE YOU ARE.
NOW YOU EAT SOMETHING,
MR. JOHNSON.
YOU NEED YOUR STRENGTH.
Shit!
DOC, WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A PRISONER
FROM THAT BUS-TRAIN WRECK
A COUPLE OF HOURS AGO.
MIGHT BE HURT.
WHAT DOES HE LOOK LIKE?
6'1", 180, BROWN HAIR,
BROWN EYES, BEARD.
SEEN ANYONE
LIKE THAT AROUND?
EVERY TIME I LOOK
IN THE MIRROR, PAL,
EXCEPT FOR THE BEARD,
OF COURSE.
DOC.
YEAH?
THANKS.
[SIREN]
I'LL GIVE YOU A HAND.
THANKS, DOC.
IT'S--
HOW'S HE DOING?
GOOD, CONSIDERING
WE HAD TO DIG HIM OUT
FROM UNDER A TRAIN.
TELL THE ATTENDANT
HE'S GOT A PUNCTURE
IN THE UPPER
GASTRIC AREA.
HOW COULD HE TELL THAT
BY LOOKING AT HIS FACE?
[TIRES SCREECH]
BACKGROUND JUST
CAME IN FROM CHICAGO!
LET ME SEE THAT.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT?
"RICHARD DAVID KIMBLE.
VASCULAR SURGEON."
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
SOMEBODY THAT MAKES
MORE MONEY THAN YOU.
"CONVICTED OF
FIRST-DEGREE MURDER
IN THE KILLING
OF HIS WIFE."
SAYS A ONE-ARMED MAN
DID IT.
LOTS OF FRIENDS,
DOCTORS,
HOSPITAL STAFF.
I WANT PHONE TAPS.
WE'RE STARTING
WITH HIS LAWYER FIRST.
YOU'RE NEVER GETTING THAT.
CALL JUDGE RUBIN.
I WANT PHONE TAPS.
I'LL CALL HIM LATER
AND TELL HIM ON WHO.
SAM,
WE JUST GOT A CALL
FROM HARRIS
COMMUNITY HOSPITAL.
THE WOUNDED GUARD
SWEARS HE SAW KIMBLE.
THAT'S HOT.
AND AN AMBULANCE
IS MISSING.
WHERE THE HELL'S HE GOING
IN AN AMBULANCE?
SHIT.
[SIREN]
[TIRES SCREECH]
SAM!
SAM, AMBULANCE
JUST SPOTTED
2 MILES WEST
OF DOVERVILLE,
HEADING NORTH,
STATE HIGHWAY 53.
HE'S RUNNING
OUT OF MAP!
GET YOUR MAPS OUT, RENFRO.
CHECK, CHECK. SOUND CHECK.
RENFRO, GET YOUR MAPS OUT.
I WANT TO KNOW ALL ROUTES
IN AND OUT OF THAT TOWN.
[TIRES SCREECH]
[SIREN]
WE'RE HEADED NORTH
ON ROUTE 13
TOWARD THE BARKLEY DAM.
SON OF A BITCH!
[SIREN]
DON'T YOU LOSE
THAT AMBULANCE, RENFRO!
WE HAVE A VISUAL LOCATION
OF AN AMBULANCE
HEADED NORTH ON ROUTE 13
TOWARD BARKLEY DAM.
HE WILL PASS THROUGH
A VIADUCT.
COSMO, GET ON THE HORN.
BRING BIGGS AND NEWMAN IN
FROM THE SOUTH SIDE
OF THAT VIADUCT.
IS THERE A TUNNEL
BETWEEN HERE AND THERE?
GOOD.
THE MAP WILL TELL YOU
HOW TO GET THERE.
[SIREN]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
WE GOT HIM.
RENFRO, WATCH OUT,
WATCH OUT, WATCH OUT!
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON HERE?
GET BACK
IN YOUR CAR, SIR!
NEWMAN! ROCK 'N' ROLL!
COME ON!
REMAIN IN YOUR CARS.
PUT A LIGHT IN THERE!
BIGGS, WHAT DO YOU GOT?
I GOT NOTHING.
TALK TO US.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
YOU GOT TO BE
KIDDING ME!
[SAM]
SHIT!
[COSMO]
ALL RIGHT, SEAL OFF
THE TUNNEL!
SEAL IT OFF!
WE GOT A GOPHER.
AW, SHIT!
I JUST BOUGHT
THESE SHOES.
SHUT UP, COSMO.
WHICH WAY, SAM?
[THUD]
AAH!
I DIDN'T KILL MY WIFE.
I DON'T CARE.
[WATER RUSHING]
PUT THAT GUN DOWN!
NOW!
HANDS UP!
OVER YOUR HEAD!
TURN AROUND!
RICHARD, DO YOU
WANT TO GET SHOT?
PAY ATTENTION!
GET DOWN ON YOUR KNEES
RIGHT NOW!
SAM!
YO!
WHOA!
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE'D HE GO?
THE GUY DID A PETER PAN
RIGHT OFF OF THIS DAM.
WHAT?
YEAH. BOOM!
HOLY SHIT!
ALL RIGHT, CAN WE
GO HOME NOW?
NO.
NO. COME ON.
HOLY SHIT.
[SHOUTING]
THERE'S NO WAY
OUT OF THIS PLACE.
WE GOT TO GO DOWN
THAT WAY.
GO UP THE STAIRS!
MOVE, MOVE!
GET THEM DOWN HERE NOW!
HELICOPTERS! DIVERS!
TELL THEM TO TURN
THAT WATER OFF.
PUT TWO PATROL CARS
ON THAT BRIDGE.
HAVE THEM GLASS
THIS RIVER,
UPSTREAM AND DOWN.
I WANT TO SEE
A HELICOPTER
COME 100 FEET
OFF OF THIS RIVER.
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR MIND?
HE'S DEAD!
THAT OUGHT TO MAKE HIM
EASY TO CATCH.
I WANT HOUNDS ON BOTH
BANKS OF THIS RIVER
FOR 2 MILES
UPSTREAM AND DOWNSTREAM.
YOU GUYS GOT
A SEARCH-AND-RESCUE TEAM
IN THIS COUNTY?
GET THEM DOWN HERE
AND DRAG THE BOTTOM
OF THIS SPILLWAY.
HOW COME THEY HAVEN'T
TURNED OFF THE WATER?
SOMEBODY FROM COUNTY'S
WORKING ON IT.
HURRY! WE'RE RUNNING
OUT OF DAYLIGHT!
[SIREN]
[YELLING]
NO. BRING IN
THE HELICOPTER NOW.
COME ON, FOLKS,
WE'RE OUT OF HERE!
THERE'S
NOTHING TO FIND.
FIND IT ANYWAY.
YOU'VE GOT LIGHTS AND
GENERATORS COMING TONIGHT.
I DON'T WANT
TO TELL YOU HOW
TO DO YOUR JOB.
PUT THE HELICOPTER
ON THE BRIDGE.
ONLY ONE PERSON
IN A MILLION CAN
SURVIVE THAT FALL.
THAT GUY IS FISH FOOD.
O.K., GET A CANE POLE,
CATCH THE FISH
THAT ATE HIM.
TELL STEVENS
WE'RE ON THE WAY IN.
[PANTING]
[DOGS BARKING]
[HELICOPTER]
COME ON, BOYS,
COME ON! GET HIM!
[DOG BARKING]
JESSE, JESSE,
LET'S GO, BABY.
LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE GETTING HOT.
[SHIVERING]
HA HA HA!
[KIMBLE]
THAT MAN TOOK
EVERYTHING FROM ME.
WE CAN'T FIND THE GUY.
[KIMBLE]
YOU FIND THAT MAN!
FIND THAT MAN!
THE GENERATORS
AND THE SEARCHLIGHTS
ARE THERE NOW.
THEY'LL CONTINUE
THE BODY SEARCH
THROUGHOUT THE MORNING
AND INTO THE NIGHT.
THANK THOSE GUYS IN KENTUCKY
FOR THE DOGS.
REMEMBER,
OPERA AIN'T OVER
TILL THE BIG DOG HOWLS.
RUFF RUFF!
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[HORN HONKS]
DO YOU NEED A RIDE?
[POOLE]
YEAH, UH-HUH.
WE NEED
ALL THE VITALS.
ALL RIGHT,
WE GOT HIM!
HE'S SHACKED UP
WITH SOME BABE
OVER IN WHITING.
SHE LEFT WORK
TONIGHT AND TOOK
HIM HOME.
ALL RIGHT, THEY JUST
SPOTTED HER CAR
OUTSIDE HER HOUSE.
DOES SHE RUN WITH
ANYBODY IN THE AREA?
NONE THAT
WE COULD FIND.
NO FAMILY EITHER.
HAVE SOMEBODY
SIT ON THE CAR.
NOBODY MOVES
TILL WE GET THERE.
WE'LL GO IN THE MORNING.
CALL YOUR COUSIN.
WE NEED HIS TRUCK.
[COUGHS]
O.K.
BE DRUNK, NEWMAN.
YEAH.
STAY CLOSE, ROOKIE.
RIGHT ON YOUR ASS, BUDDY.
NEWMAN, I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GET LOST IN THERE.
YOU STAY WITH ME.
RIGHT.
UNITED STATES MARSHAL!
EVERYBODY DOWN!
AAH!
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE!
SHOW ME THOSE HANDS!
[SOBBING]
KEEP 'EM UP!
COME HERE!
COME ON, GET
YOUR ASS IN THERE!
I GOT YOUR MAN!
I GOT YOUR MAN,
YOU HEAR ME?
I WANT OUT OF HERE!
I GOT YOUR MAN!
[SOBBING]
I GOT YOUR MAN,
AND I'M GOING TO
BLOW HIS BRAINS OUT!
NO! NO!
AAH! AAH!
YOU HEAR ME?
I WANT OUT OF HERE!
NOW, LISTEN!
WE CAN
WORK THIS OUT!
SHUT UP!
YOU HEAR ME?
NOW, LISTEN!
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I WANT!
I WANT A CAR
OUT FRONT!
HOLD IT!
DON'T SHOOT!
IT'S OVER!
[SIGHS]
[WOMAN]
AAH!
SHUT UP.
[POOLE]
THIS WAY.
IF YOU WANT
TO GO WITH THEM,
YOU'RE FREE TO.
I CAN'T HEAR
ANYTHING.
MY--
MY EARS, UH...
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU DID THAT.
YOU THINK
I SHOULD'VE BARGAINED
WITH THAT GUY?
YEAH, I DO.
YOU COULD'VE MISSED.
YOU COULD'VE
KILLED ME.
YEAH.
HOW BAD'S THAT EAR?
IT'S TERRIBLE.
I'M GOING TO
HAVE PERMANENT
HEARING DAMAGE.
LET ME SEE IT.
COME HERE.
CAN YOU HEAR WHAT
I'M SAYING NOW?
YEAH.
I don't bargain.
YOU HEAR THAT?
YEAH.
O.K.
[SIREN]
[CROSSING BELL CLANGS]
WALTER, THIS IS RICHARD.
RICHARD, JESUS.
WHY DID YOU RUN?
RUNNING ONLY MAKES
YOU LOOK GUILTY.
I WASN'T WORRIED
ABOUT APPEARANCES.
WHERE ARE YOU?
I CAN COME MEET YOU.
YOU CAN TURN
YOURSELF IN.
I NEED HELP.
I NEED MONEY.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO HARBOR AND AID
A CONVICTED FELON.
I CAN'T HELP YOU THAT WAY.
MY ADVICE,
BOTH AS YOUR FRIEND
AND LEGAL COUNSELOR,
IS FOR YOU
TO GIVE YOURSELF UP.
NOW TELL ME,
WHERE ARE YOU?
ST. LOUIS.
GIVE ME AN ADDRESS,
AND I'LL GET THERE
AS SOON AS I CAN.
MR. COPELAND WAS A BAD MAN.
HE WAS GOING TO KILL
ONE OF MY KIDS.
YOU CAN BLAME ME.
I'M THE ONE
THAT SHOT HIM.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO HARBOR AND AID
A CONVICTED FELON.
I CAN'T HELP YOU
THAT WAY.
RAYMOND.
TAKE CARE OF THAT.
GIVE YOURSELF UP.
NOW, TELL ME,
WHERE ARE YOU?
ST. LOUIS.
SO HE SHOWED UP
NOT DEAD YET.
LET THAT BE A LESSON.
DON'T EVER ARGUE
WITH THE BIG DOG.
AROO AROO AROO!
[POOLE]
YEAH, YOU'VE BEEN
RIGHT BEFORE.
ALL RIGHT.
WALTER,
THIS IS RICHARD.
RICHARD, JESUS.
WHY DID YOU RUN?
RUNNING MAKES YOU
LOOK GUILTY.
I WASN'T WORRIED
ABOUT APPEARANCES.
WHERE ARE YOU?
I CAN COME MEET YOU.
YOU CAN TURN
YOURSELF IN.
I NEED HELP.
I NEED MONEY.
THAT TRAIN SOUNDS
LIKE AN EL.
ST. LOUIS DOESN'T HAVE
ELEVATED TRAINS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
IT'S ELEVATED?
I LIVED UNDER AN EL
FOR 20 YEARS.
EXPLAIN THE DIFFERENCE
IN THE SOUND
OF AN ELEVATED TRAIN
AS OPPOSED TO A TRAIN
THAT'S RUNNING
ALONG THE GROUND.
PLAY THAT BACK.
WHAT CITIES HAVE ELs?
NEW YORK...
WE DO.
PHILLY...
MILWAUKEE.
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE.
THERE'S A GUY ON A P.A.
DROP EVERYTHING BUT
THE GUY ON THE P.A.
YEAH. I'LL TRY IT.
WALTER,
THIS IS RICHARD.
RICHARD, JESUS.
RIGHT THERE.
WHY DID YOU RUN?
WHAT'S HE SAYING?
IT SOUNDED LIKE
"NEXT STOP."
DO THAT AGAIN.
RUNNING ONLY MAKES
YOU LOOK GUILTY.
NEXT STOP.
MERCHANDISE MART.
SON OF A BITCH,
OUR BOY CAME HOME.
THAT BELL IS ON
THE WELLS STREET BRIDGE.
I KNEW THAT WAS
AN ELEVATED TRAIN.
YEAH, BIG DOG,
YOU'RE NEVER WRONG.
I'M GOING TO CALL
THE CPD.
THIS IS HIS
CHICAGO FILE.
ANDIAMO, BAMBINI.
WHEN I DIE,
I WANT TO COME BACK
JUST LIKE YOU.
OH, YOU MEAN
HAPPY AND HANDSOME?
I'LL NOTIFY THE PRESS.
NO PRESS.
CHICAGO.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
HI, BILLY.
HOW'S IT GOING, SIR?
GOOD. HOW ARE YOU?
ALL RIGHT.
HERE YOU GO, BILLY.
SEE YOU.
SPARE CHANGE?
NO. PLEASE.
I DON'T WANT IT.
NO, THANK YOU.
NO, I--
OH, MY GOD, RICHARD.
HOW ARE YOU, CHARLIE?
JESUS, YOU'RE BACK.
I NEED SOME MONEY.
SURE, SURE, GET IN.
I CAN'T.
WHATEVER YOU GOT.
YOU'RE HOT, PAL.
IF YOU'RE NOT NOW,
YOU WILL BE.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
[SIREN]
YOU GOT A GREEN LIGHT.
MOVE ON.
I'LL CALL YOU.
RICHARD--
SO WHY DID
RICHARD KIMBLE
KILL HIS WIFE?
FOR MONEY.
HE'S A DOCTOR.
HE'S ALREADY RICH.
SHE WAS MORE RICH.
IS THIS THE ENTIRE
CHICAGO POLICE
DEPARTMENT FILE?
I WANT TO DO THESE
INTERVIEWS AGAIN.
THE LIST OF HOSPITAL STAFF,
IS IT IN THE FILE?
SURE IS.
SO YOU DON'T WANT
TO USE THE MEDIA?
NO. WE WANT HIM TO RELAX,
MAKE HIMSELF COMFORTABLE,
TRY TO REENTER
HIS LIFE SOMEWHERE.
[SPEAKING POLISH]
HERE IS THIS APARTMENT.
HERE IS HEATER,
WHERE YOU WILL HAVE WARM.
HERE IS KITCHEN, SINK,
THE BATHROOM,
AND HERE IS THE ROOM.
IS NICE BED.
PLENTY SPACE.
YOU CAN LOOK IT.
[SPEAKING POLISH]
DA.
SO, YOU LIKE THE PLACE?
IT'S O.K. WITH YOU?
IT'S PERFECT.
ALL RIGHT, PEOPLE,
AS OF THIS MORNING,
WE WERE NOTIFIED BY
THE U.S. MARSHAL'S OFFICE
THAT DR. RICHARD KIMBLE
IS ALIVE AND WELL
AND BACK HOME
HERE IN CHICAGO.
NOW, YOU ALL KNOW
WHAT HIGH REGARD
WE HOLD THIS SCUMBAG.
SO I'M DONATING A BOTTLE
OF 12-YEAR-OLD SCOTCH
TO WHOEVER PUTS
THE COLLAR ON THIS QUACK.
DETECTIVE ROSETTI
IS PASSING OUT BULLETINS.
PAGING MRS. FRAN KIEFER.
PLEASE PICK UP THE PHONE.
GUNSHOT WOUND TO
THE LEFT SHOULDER.
GET HIM INSIDE.
120 OVER 60,
CAN'T GET A PULSE.
PUMP UP THE I.V.s.
HELP YOU?
EL LUGAR ES CORRECTO.
GRACIAS.
DR. GARCIA, LNEA DOS.
DR. GARCIA, LNEA DOS,
POR FAVOR.
DR. FOX,
DR. FOX TO ICU.
UN PAR
DE OJITOS NEGROS
CIELITO LINDO
DE CONTRABANDO
ESA LUNAR QUE TIENES,
CIELITO LINDO...
YOU WENT TO MEDICAL
SCHOOL TOGETHER?
YES, WE DID.
THE CLASS OF '73.
DO YOU KNOW
MORTON FEINBERG?
I DO.
NICE GUY.
WHEN DID YOU
SEE HIM LAST?
WHO, RICHARD?
YEAH.
O.K.,
I SAW RICHARD
THIS MORNING.
YOU SAW HIM
THIS MORNING?
HE STOPPED ME
IN MY CAR.
I GAVE HIM
SOME MONEY.
YOU'RE KIDDING.
WHERE WAS THIS?
OUTSIDE
MY TENNIS CLUB.
DID HE ASK YOU
FOR HELP?
I VOLUNTEERED.
HE WOULDN'T
ACCEPT THAT.
HOW MUCH MONEY
WAS IT?
WHAT I HAD
ON ME.
WELL, HE WON'T
GET FAR.
WHY DID HE COME BACK?
HE DIDN'T TELL
ME THAT, SIR.
I'M SURE HE'S TRYING
TO PROTECT YOU FROM
HAVING TO LIE FOR HIM,
OF COURSE, BUT...
DR. NICHOLS,
YOU WANT TO HELP HIM
AND BE HIS FRIEND?
YOU'RE GOING TO HELP US
BRING HIM IN UNHARMED.
WHY?
SO HE CAN GO BACK
TO PRISON?
TSK TSK TSK.
IF YOU WANT HELP,
GENTLEMEN,
YOU'VE COME TO
THE WRONG MAN.
RICHARD IS INNOCENT.
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND HIM.
HE'S TOO SMART.
OH, WE'RE SOME
SMART GUYS.
YEAH, WHAT ABOUT US?
LAST TIME I LOOKED.
WE'RE SMART.
HOW SMART
COULD HE BE?
IS HE AS SMART
AS YOU ARE?
SMARTER.
PERIPHERAL
VASCULAR SURGERY--
FIXING THE ARTERIES
AS THEY COME OUT OF
THE HEART.
HOW LONG HAVE
YOU KNOWN KIMBLE?
10 YEARS.
SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE.
THAT'S A LONG TIME.
WHAT KIND OF MEDICINE
DID HE PRACTICE HERE
AT THE HOSPITAL?
YOU SHOULD KNOW THAT
I BELIEVE RICHARD KIMBLE
TO BE INNOCENT.
WOULD HE ASK
FOR HELP?
IF HE ASKED ME,
I WOULD HELP HIM,
BUT HE WOULDN'T
COME TO ME.
THAT'S NOT HIS STYLE.
A WARRANT REMAINS
OUTSTANDING FOR CHICAGO
SURGEON RICHARD KIMBLE.
THIS IS WHERE
THE ONE-ARMED GUY
STRUGGLED AND FELL
DOWN THE STAIRS.
A MAN WITH TWO
ARMS COULD FALL
DOWN THESE STAIRS.
IF I FELL DOWN
THESE STAIRS,
I'D BE A GONER.
I'D BE DEAD.
WHAT A WASTE.
[KIMBLE]
WHEN I CAME HOME,
THERE WAS A MAN
IN MY HOUSE.
RICHARD.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
POLICE!
WE'RE THE POLICE!
WHERE IS HE?
GET HIM! GET HIM!
GET HIM!
FREEZE!
WHERE YOU GOING?
[SPEAKING POLISH]
IT'S OVER.
YOU LIKE
STRINGING OUT
12-YEAR-OLD GIRLS?
WHAT YOU DO
TO MY BABY?
YOUR BABY'S
A DRUG DEALER, LADY.
WHAT THEY DO?
WHAT THEY DOING
WITH MY BABY?
COME ON.
IT'S GOING TO
BE CRAZY HERE TONIGHT.
HOW MANY?
THERE'S
LOTS OF KIDS.
ON ROOSEVELT
AND HALSTED.
THEY GOING TO BRING
THEM ALL IN HERE?
YEAH, BIG BUS CRASH.
THEY'RE COMING
HERE TO COUNTY.
HI.
HI, HI, HI.
I'VE COME TO
DO THOSE BLINDS.
O.K.,
I'LL GET THE DOOR.
DR. SMITH,
TO THE EMERGENCY ROOM.
I'LL START
IN HERE, HUH?
OH, O.K.
ALL RIGHT, LELAND,
LET'S GO OVER IT
ONE MORE TIME.
WHAT TIME
DID HE ARRIVE?
ABOUT 10:30
IN THE MORNING.
AND HE WAS ALONE?
YEAH.
YOU GOT
A GOOD LOOK?
YEAH, I GOT
A REAL GOOD LOOK.
YOU BETTER BE
STRAIGHT WITH ME.
THIS IS
THE GUY STAYING IN
YOUR MOTHER'S BASEMENT?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TELLING YOU.
MOVE THEM OUT.
KIMBERLY, THE I.V.
X-RAY, SURGERY HERE.
OHH...
I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU WANT A MASK.
IS SHE STABLE?
JUST BARELY.
JUST BREATHE. STAY CALM.
I NEED A DOCTOR
OVER HERE.
WATCH THE BAG!
O.K., WE GOT
A PULSE RATE.
CALL VASCULAR AND ORTHO
AND CALL HER PARENTS
FOR CONSENT.
O.K.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
IT HURTS.
HELLO, MARSHAL.
[SPEAKING POLISH]
TAKE IT EASY.
EVERYTHING'S GOING TO
BE ALL RIGHT.
EXPLAIN IT TO HER.
I NEED AN I.V.
MY CHEST HURTS.
AL, CHECK THE FILM
ON THAT KID.
I NEED AN I.V. SET UP.
TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
INHALE, EXHALE.
AGAIN.
SLOWLY.
CHECK THE FILM.
TAKE IT EASY,
TAKE IT EASY.
IT HURTS.
CHECK THE FILM.
AL, WHAT'S THAT
KID'S STATUS?
POSSIBLE
FRACTURED STERNUM.
HE'S STABLE.
COME HERE.
MAKE ROOM. WE'RE
COMING THROUGH.
GIVE US A HAND HERE.
BRING
THIS KID DOWN TO
OBSERVATION ROOM 2.
YEAH, YOU. COME ON.
HELP US OUT, O.K.?
HOW ARE YOU DOING,
CHAMP?
MY CHEST HURTS.
YEAH?
DOES IT HURT
WHEN YOU BREATHE?
YES.
THAT'S GOOD.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
JOEL.
HMM...
AH. LOOK AT THIS.
WE'RE EATING ORANGES,
AND WE'RE MAKING I.D.s.
"C-C-H." WHAT
THE HELL IS THAT?
COOK COUNTY HOSPITAL.
YOU JUST HANG ON, O.K.?
IT HURTS.
YOU'RE GOING
TO BE O.K., PAL.
TO BE JUST FINE.
HOLD THAT ELEVATOR.
WATCH OUT.
THANK YOU.
HEY, JOEL. HOW YOU
DOING, KIDDO?
MY CHEST HURTS.
YEAH?
WHERE'S YOUR MOM, PAL?
I DON'T KNOW.
IS SHE AT HOME?
I THINK
SHE'S WITH MY BROTHER.
YOUR BROTHER?
THEY DOWNSTAIRS?
I DON'T KNOW.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
WE'LL GET A HOLD
OF HER FOR YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU,
A FOOTBALL PLAYER?
A BASEBALL PLAYER?
FOOTBALL.
[BELL RINGS]
HOLD ON, SON.
UM...
UH...
HEY, DOCTOR.
UH, THEY SENT THIS ONE
FROM DOWNSTAIRS.
BOB, GET THIS ONE
INTO ROOM 4, STAT.
BYE-BYE, JOEL.
GLADYS, WHERE'S
THAT BOY I SENT
WITH THE JANITOR?
WHAT BOY?
THE ONE WITH
THE FRACTURED STERNUM.
HE NEVER CAME
THROUGH HERE.
HE DIDN'T?
NO, HE DIDN'T.
HEY. DO YOU HAVE
A PARTICULAR INTEREST
IN OUR PATIENT'S X-RAYS?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I SAW YOU LOOKING AT
THAT BOY'S CHEST FILM.
IT'S A HOBBY OF MINE.
REALLY?
YEAH.
WHAT ARE
YOUR OTHER HOBBIES,
BRAIN SURGERY?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
HOW DID THAT BOY
END UP IN SURGERY?
LOOK, I'M A JANITOR.
I DO WHAT I'M TOLD.
THAT'S BULLSHIT.
WHO CHANGED
THOSE ORDERS?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
YOU STAND RIGHT THERE.
MARIE!
CALL SECURITY!
HEY!
EXCUSE ME.
TELL STEVENS
TO GET A HOLD
OF THAT GUY KELLY
OVER AT CPD.
A GUY DISGUISED
AS A JANITOR
ORDERS AN EMERGENCY
MEDICAL PROCEDURE,
AND THE ONLY THING
YOU DO TO HIM
IS TAKE AWAY
HIS I.D. CARD?
NO. I CALLED SECURITY,
AND HE TOOK OFF
DOWN THE HALL.
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED
TO DO?
LISTEN, UH, MR...
DEPUTY.
GERARD.
I'M REALLY TIRED.
I'D LIKE TO GO HOME NOW.
O.K. HOW'S THE BOY DOING?
HE SAVED HIS LIFE.
THANK YOU.
"DESMONDO JOSE RUIZ"?
WHOA!
WHERE YOU AT, DESMONDO?
SAMMY,
THIS IS MY PROBLEM.
WHAT I CAN'T
FIGURE IS,
THE PLACE
IS CRAWLING
WITH COPS, RIGHT?
YEAH.
EVERYBODY'S LOOKING
FOR RICHARD KIMBLE.
SO WHY WOULD A GUY
BE STUPID ENOUGH
TO HANG OUT
IN A TRAUMA WARD?
EXCUSE ME.
YEAH. SORRY.
YOU GUYS HAVE
A PROBLEM?
NO.
UH, NO PROBLEM AT ALL.
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
COULD WE HAVE A WORD
WITH YOU, PLEASE?
HELLO. YES.
UM, THIS IS DR. ELWAY
AT COOK COUNTY HOSPITAL.
I'M DOING FOLLOW-UP WORK
FOR THE PROSTHETIC CLINIC
ON, UH...
MATTHEW ZELICK.
OH, HE DID, HUH?
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
RIGHT OR LEFT?
RIGHT.
AGE?
35 TO 45.
UM, THIS IS TED RILEY
WITH THE HIGH SCHOOL
REUNION COMMITTEE.
25 YEARS IS
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER,
AND, UH, CLIVE IS ON OUR
LIST OF MISSING IN ACTION.
INFORMATION
GAVE ME A NUMBER,
BUT WHEN I TRIED IT, IT--
OH.
UH...
NO KIDDING.
ARMED ROBBERY.
HE'S WHERE?
POINT OF ATTACHMENT?
MID-HUMERUS.
THAT GIVES US 47 POSSIBLES.
47?
ROBERT, CROSS-CHECK
THESE PEOPLE
FOR CRIMINAL RECORDS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
HAPPY ST. PATRICK'S DAY
TO ALL OF YOU.
[ELEVATOR BELL RINGS]
HOW YOU DOING?
HEY, MARGE.
YEAH.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
DRISCOLL, CLIVE R.
ONE-ARMED MAN,
ARMED ROBBERY.
THAT'S FUNNY.
[METAL DETECTOR DINGS]
LET ME ASK YOU
A QUESTION.
IF THEY CAN DYE
THIS RIVER GREEN TODAY,
WHY CAN'T THEY DYE IT BLUE
THE OTHER 364 DAYS?
BIGGS, DO I KNOW?
SO, WHAT ARE YOU,
IRISH THERE, SIR?
WHO ME? NO. NO, NO.
ARE YOU?
[CHUCKLES]
NO, MAN.
MAN, YOU THINK
I'M CRAZY?
LOOK, THIS IS
STANDARD PROCEDURE.
NAME OF INMATE?
CLIVE DRISCOLL.
DRISCOLL, CLIVE.
I.D., PLEASE.
DRISCOLL, CLIVE R.!
2-0-1-0!
BE ADVISED THAT UNDER
FEDERAL COURT RULING,
YOUR CONVERSATION
CAN BE RECORDED.
SIGN HERE, PLEASE.
HE'S A COLLEGE GRADUATE.
HE WENT TO MEDICAL SCHOOL.
HE WON'T COME THROUGH
ALL THIS SECURITY,
GO TO THE COUNTY LOCKUP
TO FIND SOMEONE
HIS PEOPLE SAY
DOESN'T EXIST. HINKY.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN,
HINKY?
STRANGE.
WHY DON'T YOU SAY
STRANGE? HINKY
HAS NO MEANING.
WELL, WE SAY HINKY.
I DON'T WANT YOU GUYS
USING WORDS
THAT GOT NO MEANING.
I'M TAKING THE STAIRS.
HOW ABOUT BULLSHIT?
HOW ABOUT BULLSHIT,
SAM?
VISITOR FOR DRISCOLL.
COME ON.
LET'S GO, LET'S GO.
OVER THERE.
[EXHALES]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
LET'S GO, DRISCOLL.
YOU GOT FIVE MINUTES.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
UM...LOOK, I'M SORRY.
I MADE A MISTAKE.
SHIT, YOU GOT ME
DOWN HERE.
MIGHT AS WELL
TALK ABOUT SOMETHING.
AIN'T GOT NO ENTERTAINMENT.
AIN'T NO CABLE HERE.
LISTEN, PAL,
I WISH I COULD,
BUT I CAN'T.
I'M SORRY.
RICHARD!
OFFICER, OFFICER, THERE'S
A MAN IN A BLUE TOPCOAT,
WAVING A GUN AND SCREAMING.
STOP THAT MAN!
HE'S A U.S. MARSHAL!
LET HIM GO!
CLOSE THE GATE! GO!
LOCK IT NOW!
[GATE BUZZES]
HOLD IT!
THE DOOR!
OPEN THE DOOR!
SAM, WE'RE ON THE ROOF!
WE'RE ON THE ROOF!
TAKE SOME MEN!
LOOK DOWN THERE!
JESUS! HE'S IN
THE PLAZA, SAM!
HE'S HEADING EAST
THROUGH THE PLAZA!
EAST?
WHERE?
TOWARD THE PICASSO?
EAST TOWARD
THE PICASSO!
THE RIVER FOREST GOLDEN INGOT
PRIZE MARCHING BAND!
WE WANT YOU TO GIVE
ALL OF THESE GROUPS
A BIG ROUND OF APPLAUSE.
THEY'VE BEEN WAITING
A LONG TIME
TO GET IN THE PARADE,
AND THEY'RE COLD
JUST LIKE THE REST OF YOU.
HIS SON WAS THE SHAMROCK?
WE GOT TO DRESS THE OLDER
ONE UP AS A SHAMROCK
ONE OF THESE YEARS.
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US.
HAPPY ST. PATRICK'S DAY
TO ALL OF YOU.
THERE'S DEFINITELY
NO ARTHRITIS IN THIS GROUP.
DEPUTY GERARD,
WHY DO YOU FEEL
THAT DR. KIMBLE CAME BACK
TO CHICAGO?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
YOUR DEPUTIES
WERE AT COUNTY
HOSPITAL TODAY.
WAS DR. KIMBLE
AT COUNTY HOSPITAL?
NO COMMENT ON THAT ONE.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
I HAVE THE CHRONOLOGY
STRAIGHT.
THE SUSPECT WAS TRIED,
CONVICTED, INCARCERATED,
ESCAPED, PRESUMED DEAD,
AND IS PRESENTLY
AT LARGE IN CHICAGO,
IS THAT CORRECT?
YEAH, EXCEPT FOR THE PART
ABOUT BEING PRESUMED DEAD.
DETECTIVE KELLY,
DO YOU BELIEVE KIMBLE'S
ARMED AND DANGEROUS?
I BELIEVE
HE'S DANGEROUS, YES.
HE'S TAKING ALL
THESE CHANCES COMING
BACK TO CHICAGO.
DO YOU FEEL PERHAPS
HE'S INNOCENT?
NO, HE'S NOT INNOCENT.
HE WAS CONVICTED
IN A COURT OF LAW.
HE'S GUILTY.
WHAT'LL YOU DO NEXT
TO TRY TO CATCH HIM?
WE HAVE NO FURTHER COMMENTS
AT THIS TIME.
DEPUTY, PLEASE.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
[RING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEC.
RICHARD KIMBLE.
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
GOOD. DR. KIMBLE.
LENTZ.
[LENTZ]
SORRY. WE'VE BEEN
TRADING PHONE CALLS
THE LAST FEW DAYS.
[KIMBLE]
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO CATCH UP WITH YOU.
AH, A CRUISE SPONSORED
BY DEVLIN MacGREGOR.
HI. ENJOY.
HI.
CANCUN, RICHARD.
SPORT FISHING...
PIA COLADAS.
WHAT DOES THE HOSPITAL
HAVE TO BUY?
WHAT'S THE CATCH?
SAILFISH.
NO, THERE'S NO
STRINGS ATTACHED,
DR. KIMBLE.
SO WHAT DO YOU SAY?
BOY, THIS GUY'S
BLEEDING FROM EVERY
NEEDLE PUNCTURE.
YOU SAY LENTZ
SENT THIS GUY IN?
HE'S ON
THAT WONDER DRUG?
HE'S ON THE RDU-90
PROTOCOL.
PROVASIC.
DRUG OF THE FUTURE, BOYS.
CLEAN OUT THOSE ARTERIES.
GOING TO PUT US
OUT OF BUSINESS.
"PARADE MASTER OF CEREMONIES
ED O'FLANNERY
"SAID HE DID NOT RECALL
A MORE LIVELY PARADE
SINCE HE BECAME
INVOLVED WITH THE EVENT
20 YEARS AGO."
WHERE'D HE GET
THOSE CLOTHES?
"KIMBLE'S SOME KIND OF LAD
RUNNING INTO THE CROWD."
LAD?
YEAH, LAD.
"MAYBE HE'S A LEPRECHAUN
OR SOMETHING." HOLD ON.
NO, LISTEN.
I'M QUOTING HIM.
SOME GUY'S
ON LINE THREE.
CLAIMS HE'S
RICHARD KIMBLE.
WHO?
ANOTHER KIMBLE
ON LINE THREE.
HENRY, LET ME
SEE THAT PHONE.
WHAT LINE?
THREE.
ASK HIM IF HE
ENJOYED THE PARADE.
YEAH, THIS IS GERARD.
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT I TOLD YOU
IN THE TUNNEL?
WE OUGHT TO BE
SIPPING SOME WHISKEY.
IT'S HIM.
UH, YEAH, I REMEMBER.
WELL, IT WAS NOISY.
I THINK YOU SAID
SOMETHING LIKE, UM...
YOU DIDN'T
KILL YOUR WIFE.
REMEMBER
WHAT YOU TOLD ME?
I REMEMBER YOU WERE
POINTING MY GUN AT ME.
YOU SAID,
"I DON'T CARE."
He's on the southside.
YEAH...RICHARD.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I DON'T CARE.
I'M NOT TRYING
TO SOLVE A PUZZLE HERE.
I AM TRYING TO
SOLVE A PUZZLE.
Five seconds to location.
AND I JUST FOUND
A BIG PIECE.
RICHARD.
RICHARD?
HELLO, RICHARD.
HE DIDN'T HANG UP.
WHERE'S HE AT?
HERE IT COMES.
256 SOUTH ST. LAWRENCE.
ERIC, GET THE CPD
OVER THERE.
WE GOT A CAR THERE NOW.
GET A COUPLE OF SHOTS
OF THAT.
FREDRICK SYKES.
45, EX-COP...
AND QUITE A CLOTHES HORSE.
DEPUTY, YOU WANT
TO TAKE A LOOK AT THIS?
YEAH.
KIMBLE'S PRINTS
ARE ALL OVER.
THE MAIN
CONCENTRATION'S
AT THE DESK.
HE SURE HAD
SOME INTEREST IN
THESE PHOTOGRAPHS.
HE FLIPPED THROUGH
THEM, PAUSED HERE.
NEGATIVES THERE?
RIGHT THERE.
[RADIO]
CAMERA BOY'S ON HIS WAY.
WE GOT YOU, ROBERT.
HOW YOU DOING? MR. SYKES?
I'LL BE DOING FINE
IF YOU TELL ME
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
WE HAD
A LITTLE PROBLEM.
MY PLACE
OR THE PLACE UPSTAIRS?
YOUR PLACE.
WELL, NOW.
STEP RIGHT IN,
MR. SYKES.
EVERYBODY KNOWS
MY NAME HERE.
BIG HAPPY FAMILY, HUH?
MM-HMM.
WHAT IS THIS,
A TRENCH COAT
CONVENTION?
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON?
WHO ARE YOU GUYS?
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
YOU HAD A BREAK-IN,
MR. SYKES.
I SURE HOPE
YOU'RE A COP.
NO, I'M SAMUEL GERARD,
UNITED STATES
MARSHAL'S OFFICE.
THIS MORNING, A FUGITIVE
NAMED RICHARD KIMBLE
MADE A TELEPHONE CALL
FROM THIS APARTMENT.
WHY WOULD HE DO THAT?
I DON'T KNOW
ANY RICHARD KIMBLE.
YEAH, O.K. I GOT IT.
THE DOCTOR WHO KILLED
HIS WIFE, RIGHT?
KEPT BLAMING SOMEBODY
FOR IT,
SOMEBODY WITH
A PROSTHETIC LIMB.
HE'S COMING AFTER ME?
DOES HE HAVE A REASON TO?
YES. I HAVE
A PROSTHETIC ARM.
I MUST'VE MURDERED
HIS WIFE, RIGHT?
GIVE ME A BREAK.
I WENT THROUGH THIS
A YEAR AGO.
YOU KNOW THAT.
THEY QUESTIONED ME
ABOUT EVERYTHING.
I WASN'T IN CHICAGO
THAT NIGHT.
I WAS ON
A BUSINESS TRIP.
15 PEOPLE
VERIFIED IT.
WHAT LINE OF BUSINESS
ARE YOU IN, MR. SYKES?
SECURITY.
WHO DO YOU WORK FOR?
A PHARMACEUTICAL
COMPANY.
WHICH ONE?
DEVLIN MacGREGOR.
I HANDLE
SECURITY FOR ALL
THE TOP EXECUTIVES.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHY RICHARD KIMBLE
WOULD BE INTERESTED
IN THESE PHOTOGRAPHS?
NO.
WELL, NOW...
WHERE WERE THEY TAKEN?
JEEZ, THAT'S A BIG FISH.
CANCUN, MEXICO.
IT WAS A JUNKET
THE COMPANY PAID FOR
FOR SOME DOCTORS.
KIMBLE GO WITH YOU?
YOU SEE HIM
IN THE PICTURES?
NO. I TOLD YOU
I DON'T KNOW HIM.
DO YOU MIND IF I SEE
IF ANYTHING'S MISSING?
NO, I DON'T MIND.
HOW'D YOU LOSE
THAT ARM?
IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
WHEW.
COSMO, THIS GUY'S DIRTY.
YEAH, SAM.
YEAH, HE IS.
YOU WANT US
TO PUT OUR PEOPLE
ON HIM?
YEAH. I WANT YOU TO BUILD
A CAMP RIGHT HERE. HENRY.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
NOAH, SEE THIS PICTURE
WITH THE FINGERPRINTS
ON IT?
FIND OUT WHO THE GUY IS
SITTING NEXT TO SYKES.
FIND OUT HIS NAME,
HIS AGE, HIS WEIGHT,
HIS SOCIAL SECURITY
NUMBER, HIS LOCATION,
RELATIVES, PETS,
EVERYTHING.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
I'M SO SORRY, DOCTOR.
THEY SAID
IT WAS AN EMERGENCY.
THANK YOU.
EXCUSE ME.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
HELLO?
MR. BOLTON?
CHUCK.
RICHARD?
YEAH. CAN YOU TALK?
YEAH, I'M ON
A HOTEL PHONE.
HOW ARE YOU?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I FOUND HIM, CHUCK.
I FOUND THE MAN
WHO KILLED HELEN.
WHAT?
IT WAS ME THEY WERE AFTER.
WHO? WHO ARE "THEY"?
DEVLIN MacGREGOR
AND LENTZ.
LENTZ WAS SUPERVISING
THE PROTOCOL FOR RDU-90.
HE KNEW I FOUND OUT
IT WAS CAUSING LIVER DAMAGE.
IT WAS LENTZ.
RICHARD, LENTZ IS DEAD.
WHAT?
HOW?
HE DIED
IN A CAR ACCIDENT
LAST SUMMER.
RICHARD?
YEAH?
CAN YOU PROVE THIS
ABOUT THE DRUG?
I THINK SO.
I NEED YOUR HELP, CHUCK.
CALL BONES AT THE HOSPITAL.
TELL HIM TO GIVE ME
WHATEVER HELP I NEED,
ALL RIGHT?
SURE. I'LL CALL HIM
RIGHT AWAY.
O.K., THANKS.
DR. NICHOLS.
HEY! HOW ARE YOU DOING?
GOOD, GREAT.
DR. NICHOLS, HI!
CAN WE ASK YOU
A FEW MORE QUESTIONS?
MR. GERARD.
YEAH. COSMO,
YOU GOT A COPY
OF THAT PHOTOGRAPH?
UNITED STATES
MARSHAL SERVICE.
EXCUSE US.
DR. NICHOLS, THIS IS,
UM, FREDRICK SYKES.
HE'S A SECURITY SPECIALIST
AT DEVLIN MacGREGOR
PHARMACEUTICALS.
RICHARD KIMBLE BROKE
INTO HIS APARTMENT.
DO YOU KNOW
THIS MAN?
NO.
DON'T KNOW HIM.
YOU'RE GETTING
PRETTY DESPERATE,
AREN'T YOU, MR. GERARD?
OH, YEAH.
I TOLD YOU
YOU WOULDN'T FIND RICHARD.
HAS HE BEEN TO SEE YOU?
NO. IT SEEMS LIKE
WE'VE BEEN OVER
THIS GROUND BEFORE,
HAVEN'T WE?
YEAH.
SO, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME...
SURE.
THANKS, DOC.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
DR. NICHOLS. SORRY.
I WANT TO ASK YOU
ONE MORE QUESTION
ABOUT THE PHOTOGRAPH.
SEE THIS GUY HERE
IN THE PURPLE SHIRT
STANDING
ON THE RIGHT SIDE
OF THE FISH?
YOU EVER SEE HIM
BEFORE?
NO. I'VE NEVER
SEEN THAT PERSON
IN MY LIFE BEFORE.
O.K.
I'M SORRY.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU,
DOCTOR.
O.K.
ENJOY THE REST
OF THE CONVENTION.
THANK YOU.
"ALTERNATIVES
TO CARDIO...
"NONINVASIVE ARTERIAL
PLAQUE-REDUCING THERAPY.
KEYNOTE SPEAKER--
CHARLES NICHOLS."
BET YOU THEY LINE UP
TO HEAR THIS ONE.
[SIREN]
IF YOU WERE
RICHARD KIMBLE,
WHY WOULD YOU HUNT
FOR A ONE-ARMED MAN
YOU SAY KILLED
YOUR WIFE,
BREAK INTO
HIS HOUSE, CALL US,
AND THEN SPLIT?
IT DOESN'T
MAKE ANY SENSE.
I SHOULD'VE BEEN
A DOCTOR.
LOOK AT THIS BLOWUP.
THIS GUY IN THE PICTURE
WITH SYKES, ON HIS SHIRT...
CHICAGO MEMORIAL.
KIMBLE'S HOSPITAL.
I WANT TO GO THERE.
GO.
WAIT.
YOU KNOW, DEVLIN MacGREGOR
DID $7.5 BILLION NET SALES
LAST YEAR ALONE.
THAT COMPANY'S A MONSTER.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
YEAH, TALK TO ME.
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S A LIVER SAMPLE
FROM A PATIENT
IN THE RDU-90
DRUG STUDY.
21st OF JANUARY.
JANUARY 21st.
AH!
LAST ONE.
1-7-4-3-0?
1-7-4-3-0.
YOU GOT IT.
THANKS, BONES.
I'LL MAKE SURE THIS STUFF
GETS BACK TO YOU.
IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
SAY, WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO THAT THING
WITH YOUR WIFE?
IT'S NOT OVER YET.
[SIREN]
HEY, ROSETTI,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HOW THE HELL
SHOULD I KNOW?
I THINK HIS NAME
IS ALEC LENTZ,
A PATHOLOGIST.
I ONLY REMEMBER HIS NAME
BECAUSE HE DIED LAST SUMMER.
OH, MY GOD. RICHARD.
OH! WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
HI, KATH.
HAVE A LOOK.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
COLD NORMAL.
CLEARLY NOT
THE SAME TISSUE...
AND NOT ONLY
DID THEY ALL COME
FROM HEALTHY LIVERS,
THEY ALL CAME
FROM THE SAME LIVER.
KATH, YOU BEAUTY.
[HUMMING]
EXCUSE ME.
MR. ROOSEVELT?
YES.
I'M DEPUTY BIGGS,
DEPUTY NEWMAN.
WE'RE UNITED STATES
MARSHALS.
ABOUT A DR. LENTZ,
WHO USED TO BE
ON STAFF HERE...
DID HE KNOW
OR EVER HAVE CONTACT
WITH A DR. RICHARD KIMBLE?
I HAVEN'T SEEN
DR. KIMBLE.
THAT'S NOT WHAT
I ASKED, SIR.
WELL, I WOULDN'T KNOW.
IF YOU GENTLEMEN
WOULD EXCUSE ME,
I HAVE SOME
PRIOR OBLIGATIONS.
MR. ROOSEVELT?
YES?
I THINK YOU'RE
LYING TO US.
YOU THINK LENTZ
IS THE BAD GUY?
YEAH. WHY NOT?
HE WAS ONE
OF THE ORIGINAL
PATENT HOLDERS
ON RDU-90.
I WAS SENDING HIM
MY TISSUE SAMPLES.
HE WAS REPLACING THEM
WITH HEALTHY SAMPLES,
ISSUING THE PATH
REPORTS ON THEM,
AND SHIT-CANNING
MY STUFF.
PIECE OF CAKE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
LENTZ DIED AUGUST 21st.
YEAH.
HALF OF THE SAMPLES
HE APPROVED
WERE SIGNED...
THE DAY HE DIED.
YOU'RE KIDDING.
SOMEONE ELSE MUST HAVE
BEEN MANIPULATING THIS...
SOMEONE WITH ACCESS.
THANKS, KATH.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO SEE A FRIEND.
THIS IS GIVING ME
A HEADACHE.
WHERE DID MR. ROOSEVELT SAY
THE GOOD DOCTOR WAS GOING?
HE SAYS HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHERE KIMBLE WAS GOING.
YOU BELIEVE HIM?
YES. HE SAYS HE WAS
PICKING UP TISSUE SAMPLES.
WHAT?
FOR A DRUG STUDY.
BUT, LISTEN. GET THIS.
THE RELEASE WAS APPROVED
BY DR. CHARLES NICHOLS.
NICHOLS ALSO KNEW LENTZ.
HE WAS LENTZ'S BOSS.
THAT MEANS HE WAS
COVERING FOR KIMBLE.
SEND THE CPD OVER NOW.
NOAH, WE'RE SENDING YOU
A BUNCH OF COPS.
MAKE SURE THEY TURN
THAT PLACE INSIDE OUT.
DON'T TAKE ANY SHIT
ABOUT YOUR PONYTAIL,
EITHER.
WELL DONE, YOUNG MAN.
MY PLEASURE, SIR.
HENRY, DR. NICHOLS
LIED TO ME.
GO FIND HIM.
I'M ON IT.
O.K. IT'S GONE BY NOW.
I LOOKED EVERY PLACE
YOU TOLD ME TO LOOK,
AND I DIDN'T SEE HIM.
IF HE WAS IN THE HOSPITAL,
I'D HAVE FOUND HIM.
WHAT SHOULD I DO?
HUH? HOLD ON.
WAIT A MINUTE.
NO. I GOT HIM NOW.
DR. ALEXANDER LENTZ.
"A NOTED PATHOLOGIST
AT CHICAGO MEMORIAL HOSPITAL
"WAS ON HIS WAY
TO HIS DAILY TENNIS MATCH
"WHEN AN UNIDENTIFIED
VEHICLE SWUNG AROUND A CURVE,
"SLAMMED HIS BODY
INTO THE BARRIERS
THAT SEPARATE THE DRIVE
FROM LAKE MICHIGAN."
YUCK!
SAM. SAM, YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO BELIEVE THIS.
I CHECKED SYKES' RECORDS
FOR THE PAST TWO YEARS
AGAINST KIMBLE
AND FOUND NOTHING.
IT WAS A THOUGHT.
BUT WHEN I CROSS-CHECKED
KIMBLE'S PHONE RECORDS,
ONE CAME UP.
KIMBLE CALLED SYKES.
GET SYKES IN HERE NOW.
ON THE NIGHT
OF HIS WIFE'S MURDER,
7:30 P.M.,
FROM HIS CAR PHONE.
COSMO, DO YOU HAVE
THAT ARREST REPORT
ON KIMBLE?
HERE, SAM.
7:30 P.M.
1930 HOURS.
SAM, THEY JUST WENT IN.
SYKES IS GONE.
HE'S NOWHERE TO BE FOUND.
WHAT?
HE'S GONE.
UH, THIS IS TRANSIT UNIT
NUMBER 23.
I GOT A POSSIBLE SIGHTING
OF RICHARD KIMBLE.
THE NORTHBOUND EL...
[GUN COCKS]
MOVE TO THE DOOR, DOC.
NEXT STOP, BALBO STATION.
BALBO.
THIS IS MY STOP.
IT'S MY STOP, TOO.
KIMBLE!
AAH!
[GUNSHOT]
[GROANS]
AAH!
YOU MISSED YOUR STOP.
WHY IS IT
STOPPED DOWN THERE?
SAM. SAM.
A TRANSIT COP SPOTTED
KIMBLE ON THE EL.
HE'S HEADED TOWARD BALBO.
THE CPD IS ON THE WAY.
[SIRENS]
ATTENTION, ALL UNITS.
TRANSIT POLICE REPORT OFFICER
DOWN AT BALBO STATION.
KIMBLE IS SUSPECT.
REPEAT, OFFICER DOWN.
WHAT,
DID HE SHOOT A COP?
CHICAGO PD
WILL EAT HIM ALIVE.
IT IS A JOY
AND A PRIVILEGE
TO INTRODUCE TONIGHT'S
KEYNOTE SPEAKER.
FOR THE PAST FOUR YEARS,
HE HAS SERVED
AS THE A. JUDE ROBINSON
FELLOW
AND ADMINISTRATIVE
CHIEF OF PATHOLOGY
AT CHICAGO
MEMORIAL HOSPITAL.
WHICH WAY ARE
THE EMERGENCY EXITS?
SUSPECT SEEN ENTERING
HILTON TOWER MALL,
LOWER LEVEL.
REPEAT, SUSPECT ENTERING
HILTON TOWER MALL...
YOU DON'T THINK--
YEAH. I KNOW
WHERE HE'S GOING.
BIGGS, NEWMAN, COME IN.
WHERE ARE YOU?
HE HAS BEEN APPOINTED
TO THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS
OF DEVLIN MacGREGOR
PHARMACEUTICALS.
WILL YOU ALL PLEASE
GIVE A WARM WELCOME
TO DR. CHARLES NICHOLS?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
MY FRIENDS AND COLLEAGUES.
IT'S GREAT YOU'RE
ALL HERE TONIGHT.
CPD JUST REPORTED
AN OFFICER DOWN
AT BALBO STATION
AND A GUY WITH TWO GUNS--
KIMBLE DO IT?
HE ENTERED THE HOTEL
FROM THE SUBWAY.
THAT'S MY MAN!
NOT ANYMORE HE'S NOT.
STAY THE HELL OUT!
ARREST US.
I WANT IT LOCKED UP!
START WITH
THE LOWER LEVEL.
[ALARM BELL RINGS]
ALL UNITS REPORT WHEN
LOWER LEVEL IS SECURE.
ALL UNITS SECURE,
ALL LOWER LEVEL EXITS.
NOAH, FIND THE HOTEL
SECURITY OFFICE.
STAY IN TOUCH WITH ME
ON THE RADIO. COME ON.
[NICHOLS]
NOW A NEW DRUG,
ON THE CUSP OF APPROVAL
BY THE FOOD AND DRUG
ADMINISTRATION,
IS POISED TO CHANGE
THESE OLD METHODS FOREVER.
ROB, DEPUTY NEWMAN,
U.S. MARSHAL.
HOW YOU DOING?
GOOD. SAM, I'M IN.
THROUGH THE NORMAL METABOLIC
PATHWAYS OF THE LIVER,
AND THE DRUG'S NAME
IS PROVASIC.
AS I WILL
SHOW YOU TONIGHT,
PROVASIC IS
REMARKABLY EFFECTIVE
AND HAS NO SIDE EFFECTS
WHATSOEVER.
IT IS ALSO NOTEWORTHY
THAT THIS DRUG...
THAT THIS DRUG
WAS DEVELOPED
IN COOPERATION,
NOT COMPETITION,
WITH THE CHICAGO
MEMORIAL HOSPITAL
IN WHAT WE HOPE
WILL BE THE MODEL
FOR A CONTINUED
DISHONEST--
EXCUSE ME--FOR HONEST...
OPEN JOINT VENTURES
BETWEEN ACADEMIC
MEDICINE AND...
THE PHARMACEUTICAL...
INDUSTRY--
RICHARD.
I'M SORRY. I'M IN
THE MIDDLE OF THIS SPEECH.
YOU ALMOST GOT AWAY
WITH IT, DIDN'T YOU?
I KNOW ALL ABOUT IT.
I CAN PROVE IT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
MY FRIEND RICHARD KIMBLE
DOESN'T FEEL WELL...
OBVIOUSLY, SO IF
YOU'D JUST GO ON
WITH YOUR DESSERT
AND COFFEE, UH...
RICHARD, DO YOU MIND TO
STEP ASIDE, AND LET'S TALK.
O.K.
SO, UH, I'LL BE BACK
IN...JUST A SECOND.
YOU CHANGED THE SAMPLES,
DIDN'T YOU, HUH?
YOU SWITCHED
THE SAMPLES...
AFTER LENTZ DIED.
RICHARD, LET--
[HOST]
LET'S STAY--
STAY CALM, PEOPLE.
AFTER LENTZ DIED,
YOU WERE THE ONLY ONE
WHO HAD THE ACCESS.
YOU SWITCHED THE SAMPLES...
AND THE PATHOLOGY REPORTS.
YOU KILLED LENTZ,
TOO, HUH?
SECURITY, PLEASE.
DID YOU?
HE FALSIFIED
HIS RESEARCH...
SO THAT RDU-90 COULD BE...
APPROVED, AND...
DEVLIN MacGREGOR COULD
GIVE YOU PROVASIC.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S ALL OVER, FOLKS.
LET'S JUST,
UH, STAY CALM.
[HELICOPTER]
YOU NEVER GIVE UP,
RICHARD, DO YOU?
YOU NEVER GIVE UP!
WHY HELEN?
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
WHICH WAY DID THEY GO?
PRESIDENTIAL SUITE.
WHERE'S THAT?
SOUTHEAST CORRIDOR.
EXITS FROM THIS ROOM?
TOTAL OF FOUR--
TWO IN THE EAST,
TWO IN THE WEST.
KIMBLE'S
ON THE ROOF!
COSMO, THAT WAY.
[HELICOPTER BULLHORN]
STOP. STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
THIS IS THE CHICAGO POLICE.
PUT YOUR HANDS IN THE AIR.
THE BUILDING IS
TOTALLY SECURE.
I REPEAT, DO NOT MOVE.
PUT YOUR HANDS
IN THE AIR.
I REPEAT,
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
[HELICOPTER]
ALL RIGHT, NEWMAN.
TALK TO ME!
THEY'RE HEADED TO
THE NORTH END
OF THE ROOF.
TO THE NORTH!
NEWMAN, YOU GOT TO
GET THAT HELICOPTER
OUT OF HERE!
WHEN YOU GET
A CLEAN SHOT,
YOU TAKE HIM OUT.
NEWMAN, GET RID
OF THE HELICOPTER!
WHY?
I DON'T WANT TO
GET SHOT!
CPD, THERE'S
A U.S. MARSHAL
OUT ON THE ROOF.
HOLD YOUR FIRE
AND CALL OFF
THE HELICOPTER.
[ELEVATOR MOTOR STARTS]
SAM! SAM!
DON'T SHOOT.
THIS GUY EVER QUIT?
FIND OUT WHERE
THAT ELEVATOR STOPS.
NEWMAN! NEWMAN!
NORTHWEST ELEVATOR!
TELL ME WHERE IT STOPS!
WHERE'D THEY GO?
THEY'RE ON
THE FIFTH FLOOR!
WHAT IS ON
THE FIFTH FLOOR?
THE LAUNDRY.
COSMO, SAM, THEY STOPPED
AT THE LAUNDRY.
BIGGS, POOLE, WE'RE
ON THE FIFTH FLOOR
AT NINE.
WHAT'S YOUR 20?
ONE STEP BEHIND YOU.
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON HERE, SAM?
YOU GOT TO
KEEP CPD OUT.
THEY'RE MUCH TOO HOT
TO SUIT ME.
GET RID OF ALL
THESE PEOPLE, O.K.?
COSMO,
YOU COME WITH ME.
[HELICOPTER]
DR. RICHARD KIMBLE!
THERE'S NO WAY OUT
OF HERE, RICHARD!
THE ENTIRE BUILDING
IS LOCKED DOWN!
GIVE IT UP, RICHARD!
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY TIME!
CHICAGO POLICE DEPARTMENT
THINKS YOU'RE A COP KILLER!
THEY WILL SHOOT YOU
ON SIGHT!
RICHARD, I KNOW
YOU'RE INNOCENT!
I KNOW ABOUT
FREDRICK SYKES!
DR. CHARLES NICHOLS!
RICHARD,
HE BORROWED YOUR CAR
THE NIGHT OF
YOUR WIFE'S MURDER!
HE HAD THE KEYS!
NO FORCED ENTRY,
RICHARD.
HE TELEPHONED SYKES
FROM YOUR CAR, RICHARD.
RICHARD, GIVE IT UP!
RICHARD, I'M EITHER LYING
OR I'M GOING TO SHOOT YOU!
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
[PICKS UP METAL PIPE]
GIVE IT UP!
IT'S TIME TO STOP RUNNING!
AAH!
THEY KILLED MY WIFE.
I KNOW IT, RICHARD.
I KNOW IT...
BUT IT'S OVER NOW.
WHEW! YOU KNOW,
I'M GLAD.
I NEED THE REST.
WHO KILLED KIMBLE'S WIFE?
FAR AS I KNOW,
KIMBLE DID IT.
HE SAYS IT WAS
THE ONE-ARMED MAN.
YOU'VE GOT ONE
IN CUSTODY. IS THAT HIM?
NO IDEA.
HOW MANY ONE-ARMED MEN
ARE THERE AROUND?
PLENTY.
COULDN'T YOU HAVE
MADE A MISTAKE?
[REPORTER]
THE ONE-ARMED MAN
IS ALSO THERE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT MUCH
POLICE ACTIVITY.
YOU GOT A DEADLINE,
PLAY THE WEATHER AGAIN.
TELL SAMUEL GERARD
I'M GOING HOME NOW.
I'M TAKING MY VACATION.
CLEAR THIS AREA!
EVERYBODY CLEAR, CLEAR.
THERE'S THE MAN!
DR. KIMBLE!
DR. RICHARD KIMBLE!
[YELLING QUESTIONS]
WATCH YOUR HEAD.
GERARD,
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
ARE YOU ARRESTING
KIMBLE AGAIN,
OR IS HE GOING
TO BE RELEASED?
POOLE,
WHERE IS THAT THING?
LET ME SEE
THOSE HANDS, DOCTOR.
I THOUGHT
YOU DIDN'T CARE.
I DON'T.
HEY, DON'T TELL
ANYBODY, O.K.?
[BANGS ON ROOF]