One small fact.
You are going to die.
Despite every effort,
no one lives forever.
Sorry to be such a spoiler.
My advice is, when the
time comes, don't panic.
It doesn't seem to help.
I guess I should
introduce myself properly.
But then again,
you'll meet me soon enough.
Not before your time, of course.
I make it a policy
to avoid the living.
Well, except sometimes.
Once in a very long time...
I can't help myself.
I get interested.
I don't know exactly what it
was about Liesel Meminger.
But she caught me.
Mama.
And I cared.
Do you want to say a few words?
Goodbye my darling
She would have kept you
if she could have.
You know that, don't you?
Here we are. Come, Liesel.
Meet your new parents.
Come.
Hans Hubermann.
Heinrich.
Where is the boy?
He died.
What do you mean?
On the way here.
They had to bury him by the tracks.
They promised us two children,
with two allowances.
Rosa, you cannot
blame the boy for dying.
No, I blame his mother.
Dragging them across the
country unfed, unwashed!
She was running for her life.
Have you seen that girl?
Filthy.
Everything they say about communists
is true. Dirty and stupid.
I'll speak as loud as I want.
Come.
Come!
What is the matter with her?
Your Majesty.
What are you brats looking at?
This is Heaven Street,
your new home.
Hey, lover boy! Can we get
on with the game now?
Please, go in.
Well, go on.
What do you say?
They have given us a mute.
Go upstairs.
Where is it?
That one.
It's for you.
Hans!
Ja, my sunshine?
Good morning, Your Majesty.
Would you stop that racket?
What do you say?
Thank you.
It speaks?
Now, listen, from now on
you call me "Mama," ja?
Say it.
Mama.
Good.
And that Saukerl,
that lazy pig over there...
you call him "Papa."
Understood?
Papa.
Who is that?
Who is it?
Rudy Steiner, Frau Hubermann.
What do you want?
My mother says you've
got a daughter now.
What's it to you?
I'm here to take her to school.
Why can't people ever
mind their own business?
Hello, Rudy.
Hello!
And what makes you think you are
good enough for my daughter?
Rudy.
I'm almost 12.
Liesel, eat your soup
and go and get dressed.
Stay outside, you filthy Saukerl.
Hurry up, Liesel.
Do you like to run?
I bet I could beat you.
No one has ever
beaten me in a race.
You don't say much, do you?
Is that one spit, "Yes,"
and two spits, "No"?
I'm glad we
understand each other.
My mother didn't really tell
me to come and get you.
I just thought
you might need a friend.
Danke schön!
Rudy!
What are you up to?
Nothing, Papa.
Then get to school.
Come on.
You are?
Frau Hubermann's new daughter.
I was not addressing you, Steiner.
Girl, speak.
Liesel Meminger.
Chalk, board, name.
Come, girl.
We don't have all day.
Write it.
Silence.
Silence!
Back to your seat, now.
Silence.
Dummkopf!
Dummkopf! Dummkopf!
Hey, Dummkopf.
Can't you even read yet?
Go on. Read one word.
Read something.
Dummkopf.
She's killing him!
I bet that wasn't your first fight.
Franz Deutscher hasn't
been hit like that...
since he peed in
Tommy Muller's lunchbox.
Franz Deutscher
doesn't sound very smart.
He's the dumbest kid in school.
But he shaves.
You remember how to get home?
Just because I can't read
doesn't make me stupid.
All right.
I'll follow you, then.
You could join our
soccer team, you know?
Look, you should probably just
stop trying to be my friend...
because I won't be
here long enough.
Why not?
I'm running away.
That's why not.
Where to?
None of your business.
Well, let me know when.
Why?
So I can come with you.
You don't understand.
I'm serious.
I have to find my mother.
Frau Hubermann?
Nein, Dummkopf.
My real mother.
Great.
I'd like to meet her.
What are you doing now?
Racing you.
I'll bet you a kiss I can beat you.
Why would I want to kiss you?
I don't know.
What does that matter?
I'm the one who's going to win.
Just to the end of the street.
And what if I win?
You don't have to kiss me.
Ever?
What do you care?
You're not sticking around, right?
Hey! Saumensch!
You cheated.
So what?
I beat you.
Did not.
It was a draw.
Draw means I get the kiss.
You can stick your kiss.
Oh, my God.
She's going to kill you.
Who?
If you think that I am
some kind of pushover...
you are very much mistaken.
Do you hear?
I have just come to say good night.
What is this?
Is it yours?
Why would a nice girl like you
want to read such a thing?
Are you sure this is yours?
It wasn't always mine.
It belonged to my brother.
I see.
Your brother...
his name was Pieter Strauss?
Do you know what this says?
Do you want to know what it says?
I'm not such a good
reader myself, you know.
We will have to
help each other out.
Ja?
We better get started.
"The Gravedigger's Handbook."
Raise the red flags
for German effort
we want to pave the way to freedom
For German effort
We do not create a brother pact
with Jews or non-Germanics
Because they falsify
the liberty certificate
of Germany's people
Walter.
Listen, he told me
he can only take one.
Take Max.
No, Mama.
Take him! Go!
I won't leave without you.
Yes, you will.
Upon your father's grave, you will.
There's no time for heroics, Max.
One or none.
Come.
The papers are inside.
They don't look great,
but they'll have to do.
Go find him.
Forgive me.
When I finally caught up
with Max Vandenberg's soul...
it was this moment
that haunted him the most.
For leaving his mother.
For feeling that awful,
light-headed relief...
that he would live.
Jesse Owens is
the fastest man on earth.
Hey, watch out, you two.
What are you doing, Papa?
Working, for once.
I thought you painted signs,
not scraped them off.
Well, the scraping-off
business is picking up, Rudy.
What can you do?
"Accountant."
You make me proud, girl.
She's clever, Rudy.
Ja, sir.
What's an accountant?
Something we will never need.
"We wish you...
"every success...
"with your...
"career...
Mmm.
"In the funeral...
"Business."
"Funeral business."
We made it.
Your first book.
Congratulations.
So, promise me one thing, Liesel.
If I die anytime soon,
make sure they bury me right.
Ja?
Ja.
No skipping chapter six.
Can we start again?
Tomorrow.
But it is tomorrow.
You sleep now.
His name was Werner.
Come.
I have a surprise for you.
It's very dark here.
We had better turn on the light.
It's a dictionary.
Some of the words we have learned.
Add as many as you like.
It's yours.
Thank you, Papa.
He's done it!
He's made history!
Jesse Owens...
the fastest man alive!
Hey!
What is this?
Ow!
You want to remain a member?
Teach your son!
Why?
Why Jesse Owens?
He's the fastest man on earth.
The fastest man on earth!
The boy is crazy.
- Ow! That hurts.
- Sit still, Rudy.
It's even in his earholes.
Barbra...
Fine, you deal with him.
Son...
you can't go around painting
yourself black, you hear?
Why not?
Because you shouldn't
want to be black people.
Why?
Because I say so. Ja?
"Dear Mama, today is the
Fuhrer's birthday.
"I wish it was mine.
"Maybe then you
could come and see me.
"I miss you all daylong.
"Sometimes, I think
I see you in the street.
"But it's never you.
"My new mama is like a thunderstorm.
Always rumbling. "
Hans, where did you put the flag?
If we don't find it, it's going to
look like we're saying something.
All right, all right, all right.
I'm going to look in the basement.
God in Heaven.
Liesel, I know you
like it down here...
but don't you think
you should be outside a bit?
I'm writing Mama a letter.
Well, that's very good.
Please tell her, from me, I could
do without all the nagging.
Not that mama.
I see.
What are you telling her?
Everything.
About you und Mama und Rudy.
Can you send it for me?
Well...
You could give it to the woman
who brought me here.
Frau Heinrich? Ja.
I'm sure she would do
her best to pass it on.
Ah, found it.
What is she doing writing
to her mother, anyway?
She's her mother.
I'm not going to
waste good money...
on a stamp for a letter that's
never going to be answered.
What was I to say?
Hans?
Alex.
Good man.
Are you ready to go?
Of course he is.
Liesel!
Come on, Liesel,
we'll miss the parade.
Right.
Come on, let's go.
Saumensch.
Hello, Rudy.
During this National
Socialist revolution
as much as our nation prospers,
we should not decrease
our determination to
cleanse ourselves morally
and intellectually from within
Education, theater,
films, literature, the press
these are the supporting pillars
which shape the unique
personality of our nation
And that is why we
have gathered here tonight
to free ourselves from
any intellectual dirt
We will exterminate the illness
that infected Germany
for the last twenty years
We will completely
destroy the chains
that were forged to enslave us
We will fight our
enemies and if that means war
then we will stand by our
Fuhrer until the final victory
Such a war will see
our nation restored
and bring an end to our enemies
The end of plutocrats
The end of communists
And the end of Jews
To our great German Empire
and to our beloved Fuhrer,
Adolf Hitler
- Sieg!
- Heil!
Hey, Jesse Owens.
Push off, Franz.
Leave him alone.
Did you like the speech, Dummkopf?
Were you listening?
What about it?
Your mother was one, wasn't she?
A communist?
That's what they say.
Who's "they"?
You even look like one.
What are you talking about?
I'm not talking
to you, Steiner.
She knows.
Burn a book.
Go on, burn a book.
Go on! I'll be watching.
Both of you.
What was that about?
Nothing.
Liesel.
Where have you been? I said
to meet me at the church.
Sorry, Papa.
Let's go now.
What is it?
Nothing.
Are you sick?
Nein. I'm fine.
Tell me, what is the
matter with you?
What the hell is this?
You stole it?
Sorry, Papa.
Are you going to tell Mama?
Papa?
Did anyone see you?
I'll tell you what.
Let's make this our secret.
We'll read it like the other book.
In the basement.
Thank you, Papa.
Good, now.
We better get back before Mama worries.
We don't want that.
Liesel, come.
What is it?
Liesel?
My mother isn't
coming back, is she?
Is she a communist?
Who told you that?
Is she?
Did the fuhrer take her away?
Then I hate the fuhrer.
Nein.
You can't say that.
Don't ever say that.
Understand?
Come.
"The Invisible Man
by H.G. Wells."
Sounds good.
"Chapter one.
"The Strange Man's Arrival.
"The stranger came early in Feb..."
"February." Ah.
Good girl.
Who's that?
Papa, who is it?
Hans Hubermann?
Ja.
Do you still play the accordion?
Quickly.
Papa!
Liesel, go to bed!
What is this?
Max.
No. No.
Help me.
We'll put him upstairs.
Liesel, everything is fine.
Here we go.
I'll warm him some soup.
Who is he, Papa?
I have something very
important to tell you, Liesel.
You must listen.
That is not my accordion.
The man who owns that accordion
is this boy's father.
You stole it?
Nein.
I've been looking after it.
Did he die?
Ja.
Many years ago.
Before you were born.
I saw him die.
In a war.
You were in a war?
Ja.
His father gave up his life...
for me.
And I made a
promise to the family...
if ever I could help them, I would.
I gave them my word.
Now, I need you to promise me.
I need you to give me your word
that you will not tell
anyone about our visitor.
Nobody. Not a soul.
Not even Rudy.
I mean it, Liesel.
Not a soul.
Understand?
Ja.
A person is only as good
as their word, Liesel.
Do I have yours?
Ja, Papa.
I promise.
Did you talk to her?
Ja.
She can't tell a soul.
She knows.
Can we trust her?
She's our daughter.
She's a child!
Rosa.
We have no choice.
He looks like death.
He's probably forgotten
what food tastes like.
What are we going to feed him on?
We barely have enough
to feed ourselves!
We will make do.
"We will make do."
We have always known
that one day this may happen.
We could turn him in tomorrow.
The authorities would understand.
We could say
that it was late at night...
Rosa.
I know.
He came to us.
I owe his family everything.
I know.
Then, that's all.
We'll just go about things
as normally as possible.
Hello.
What were you dreaming about?
My mother.
Is that your book?
Ja.
Nein, it...
it wasn't always mine.
Did you steal it?
Nein.
Can I see it?
It's...
It's not for children.
Ah.
Good morning, Max.
You have met Liesel?
Liesel.
Don't worry.
She's a good girl.
Not a word.
Good, Saumensch.
What's the rush?
I have to get home.
Race you.
I have to go inside.
What do you want?
My permission?
Nein. I'm just telling you.
Fine.
See you, Saumensch.
Where have you been?
You're late.
I ran as fast as I could.
And you mentioned
nothing to no one?
Nein, Mama.
Rosa...
Liesel! He's asleep.
Mmm.
At least someone knows how
to appreciate my cooking.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Is he going to be all right?
Of course.
You're a curious girl.
I didn't mean to.
It's all right.
What is it about?
Hitler.
Are you hiding from Hitler?
Ja.
Are you a communist?
I'm a Jew.
Did he take away your mother?
Probably.
Don't worry.
I cried a lot
when I first came, too.
The soup is terrible, isn't it?
You may find this
hard to believe, but...
it's the best thing
I've ever thrown up.
Liesel!
I have a job for you.
And don't forget to
count the money.
Come back with the right amount
or don't bother coming back at all.
The Bürgermeister's house.
Are you sure?
Do you see any other houses
looking like this?
He had dinner with the fuhrer once.
Laundry.
Come in.
Go on.
Wait.
Danke schön.
So, you like books?
Come.
"The Dream Carrier."
Rudy.
I have to go.
You can come back
whenever you want.
It will be here.
Ja, Frau Hermann.
Call me "Ilsa."
What shall I call you?
Liesel.
You are a brave girl, Liesel.
Come back, Saumensch!
Catch me!
Hey, Dummkopf! Did you hear?
England declared war on us!
We're at war with England!
We're at war!
England declared war!
It's always been the same,
the excitement and rush to war.
I've met so many young men
over the years...
who have thought they were
running at their enemy.
When the truth was,
they were running to me.
Ja!
Excellent.
You should look
where you're going next time.
Drop dead, Franz.
What's up, Jesse Owens?
I thought you liked being black.
Who is Johann?
He used to love to read.
And he was brave.
Just like you.
This is all him.
Everything he knew.
All here.
All in its place.
They never found his body.
If they could have shown me his
body, I would have believed them.
But how can a mother give up?
A mother never
gives up on her child.
I have to go.
Do you think my mother
really loved me?
Of course.
Every mother loves her child.
Even Hitler's.
Do you think she writes to him?
"Dear fuhrer...
"just wait until
your father gets home.
"Love, Mama."
"Dear fuhrer, clean up your mess."
"Dear fuhrer, who cut your hair?"
"You're not going
out in that, are you?"
"What's that growing on your lip?"
"Don't raise your voice at me."
"Stop spitting when you yell."
Hans...
he's getting bedsores.
Then he needs to get up
and move about.
He can't just walk around.
Why not?
Because people will see in.
He can't lay still forever.
He needs to be moved.
Why?
The mouth on it!
Because I say so.
Rosa.
And what do you propose?
"Propose"?
Listen to this one.
I propose that we
put him downstairs.
It's not good, we know that.
I'm sorry.
Please don't apologize. I've
put you all in such danger.
It's more than I deserve.
Liesel's lessons.
It is a dictionary.
I tried to make it as
comfortable as I could.
I'm sorry, there's no bed.
If anyone saw, you know?
You feel free to do your
lessons whenever you want.
Make sure you knock first.
I'm just downstairs.
I'm not going anywhere.
Promise.
Don't give me that look.
"Jellyfish."
Jellyfish.
Tell me, where do you
get these words?
It's a secret.
And who would I tell?
The Bürgermeister's wife.
She lets me read her books.
I memorize them.
"Memory is the scribe of the soul."
Do you know who said that?
A man called Aristotle.
Can you do me a favor?
Can you describe the day for me?
What's it like outside?
It's cloudy.
No, no, no.
Make the words yours.
If your eyes could speak...
what would they say?
It's a pale day.
"Pale." Good. Go on.
Everything's stuck behind a cloud.
Lind the sun...
doesn't look like the sun.
What does it look like?
Like a silver oyster?
Thank you. I saw that.
We're hiding a Jew.
Johann?
Nein.
It's Liesel.
What's the meaning of this?
Lind he didn't say why?
I don't understand it.
I've always ironed his shirts
in exactly the same way.
Maybe they can't
afford it any longer.
They can't afford it?
We can't afford it.
It's another customer gone.
And four mouths to feed.
Well.
It's two meals a day
from now on, not three.
That's all there is to it.
I've made you a suit.
I want you to wear it
on your 14th birthday.
You'll be back then, Papa.
Won't you?
Hans!
Rosa...
I'm asking you, I'm begging you...
would you please keep your
mouth shut for five minutes?
I brought you something.
Is this today's?
Ja.
A gift from Franz Deutscher.
That boy doesn't know
how generous he is.
"Hitler poised to take Moscow."
The world has turned mad.
But...
aren't we winning the war?
Max?
Where's my weather report?
You're full of wonders.
I've got an idea.
What on earth are you doing?
Go, go, go!
Max.
I have no more snow!
Get him, Max!
What in God's name are you
Saukerle doing down here?
Rosa!
There's a madwoman on the battlefield!
Nein, nein!
I'm unarmed!
This is the stupidest thing
that I have ever done.
Lind look how happy you are.
What do we do when it melts?
You mop it up, Saumensch.
It won't melt.
It's freezing down here.
I don't know how
you do it every night.
Please, don't think about me.
Nonsense.
We all think about you.
This is the best Christmas.
This is my first Christmas.
Now you know what you've
been missing out on.
We should call it a night.
Nein, Papa. Please.
Listen to your father.
You can stay a little longer.
Oh, you're too soft on that girl.
I've made you a Christmas gift.
It's all I had.
But...
Open it.
"For Liesel...
"from Max."
What does it say?
"Write."
In my religion...
we're taught that
every living thing...
every leaf, every bird...
is only alive because it contains
the secret word for life.
That's the only difference between
us and a lump of clay. A word.
Words are life, Liesel.
All those blank pages...
they're for you to fill.
My God.
Is he going to die?
Shut up!
I won't have that talk in this
house. Do you understand?
I haven't starved us all for the
better part of two years...
just so that he could die.
It's my fault.
Why is it your fault?
It was my idea
to build that snowman.
Why did we build it?
Because we had to.
You said you weren't
going anywhere, Max.
You promised.
"The Invisible Man...
"by H.G. Wells."
"The stranger came
early in February...
"one wintry day...
"through a biting wind
and a driving snow.
"The last snowfall... "
"And none other
will know of them...
"until he dies."
"The End."
Max?
"Chapter One."
Ilsa?
"The eyes in the faces he
passed on the street...
"seemed to look inside him
and finger his guilt.
"But things were
out of his control.
"He had cut himself loose...
"and was drifting faster and
faster towards his fate.
"...was the dustiness
of the floor...
"the feeling that the clothes were
more next to her than on her...
"and the sudden realization that
this would all be for nothing."
- Did you lose something?
- Rudy!
What are you doing?
Spying on you, obviously.
Give me that!
So, let me guess. You forgot
where the front door was.
I've got to hand it to you,
Saumensch, you've got guts...
stealing from the Bürgermeister.
Keep it down.
I'm not stealing.
I'm borrowing.
Whatever you are "borrowing"...
I just wish you let me in on it.
It's not what you think.
Then...
What is it?
I'm borrowing books.
That's all.
Books? Are you nuts?
We are starving out here
and you're stealing books?
Stop using that word.
How about food? Did you ever even
think of looking in the kitchen?
Nein.
We could have planned this
better if you told me.
I'm sorry. I couldn't.
You know, for a best friend,
you keep a lot to yourself.
What's that supposed to mean?
Who's Max?
Who is he?
Liesel!
Tell me what's going on!
Tell me, Saumensch, who is he?
Is he your boyfriend?
What?
Is that what you think?
Then what?
Tell me, who is he?
I can't.
Why not?
It's a secret.
You don't trust me?
It's not like that, Rudy.
I can't.
If I...
If I told you, I'd have to go away.
Papa would have to go away.
God knows what would happen to him.
"Him"?
You're hiding someone?
You're hiding someone, aren't you?
Liesel!
One spit, "Yes."
Two spits, "No."
I knew it.
No one can know, Rudy.
I mean it.
You can trust me.
Don't worry.
I won't tell anybody.
You won't tell anyone what?
Hello, Steiner.
Hello, Dummkopf.
What's that behind your back?
Give it to me.
Leave him alone!
I said, give it to me!
Give it to me!
What was that?
What was it?
None of your business, Deutscher.
Leave him!
You're done for, Steiner.
I'm reporting you.
For what?
Having a diary?
I know you're up to something.
Come on!
What are you doing?
I know where it is!
I watched it!
It's freezing, Rudy.
You'll die in there.
Rudy!
Rudy?
Rudy, I can't swim!
Rudy!
Please!
I got it!
Rudy!
I thought you were...
Never mind.
Trust me now?
Ja.
Then, how about that kiss?
Come on.
You're going to freeze.
Good night...
book thief.
Good night, fish.
I told Rudy.
Here, come on!
I'm here!
Look!
What are they doing?
Checking basements. They checked
my cousin's last night.
For what?
Can we get on with it now?
Come on!
Here! Pass it!
Are you nuts?
I have to go inside.
Oh, great.
She's hurt.
Never stopped her before.
I'm fine.
Mama!
Why are you shouting?
They're coming.
Who?
They're checking basements.
Hans, come quickly!
What is it?
Somebody is coming.
They are checking basements.
We have to hide him.
Get him up here, under the bed.
Max!
Come on. Come on.
So, do they give you a gun
when you join the army?
Mama!
Oh, my God.
Hans, leave that!
Wolfy. What a surprise.
How are you?
You want Hans?
Hans!
Nein, nein, nein. We're just
checking people's basements.
Oh, Liesel,
will you get Herr Edel...
a glass of water?
No need.
This shouldn't take a second.
You should bandage that.
Oh, my God, Liesel! Ja!
Oh, would you do me a favor...
and get me the medicine chest?
It's just on that...
Where is the man trap?
The what?
The door to your basement.
Ah!
Wolfa.
I heard you were coming.
I've been working, tidying up.
Heard from who?
Who was it collecting our washing?
Frau Schneider.
Frau Schneider, ja.
She mentioned it.
Come.
Is there a light in here?
Ja, of course.
I should probably
throw most of this stuff out.
You wouldn't believe what we
find in some people's basements.
Oh, it wouldn't surprise me.
Liesel, she is always
playing down here.
I keep telling her to
get out in the fresh air.
What is this about, anyway?
What's this?
My brushes.
You should look after them better.
Liesel, you know,
she never listens to me.
Still no work, eh, Hans?
Not a lot.
You should have taken my
advice and joined the party.
Then your wife wouldn't
have to break her back...
washing people's
underwear to feed you.
Isn't that right, Rosa?
Ja.
What's wrong with you?
I've never heard you
turn down an opportunity...
to give this one some lip.
Well...
if the Saukerl would get off
his lazy backside and help...
then maybe I would have the energy
to give him all the lip
that he deserves.
I don't know how you live with her.
Neither do I.
Never too late to join, Hans.
So, how's our basement?
Perfectly useless.
The ceiling is too low.
What for?
Air raid shelters.
Every street has to have one.
You should be more careful.
Ja, Herr Edel.
Hans...
What if he does die?
We can't just leave him there.
The smell will give us away.
Hans, I'm afraid.
Look, if it happens...
if he dies...
we'll simply have to find a way.
He's not dead yet.
All right?
Frau Hubermann?
I need to speak to Liesel.
Of course. Liesel?
Ow!
What did you do with it,
you little thief?
What, Mama?
Don't "what" me.
I have told you a hundred times
to leave that thing alone,
but do you listen?
Back to work.
I'm sorry.
Mama, what is it?
It's Max, isn't it?
He said that this belongs to you.
Who said?
He woke up.
He's going to live!
Mama!
Careful.
I'm sorry if I hurt you.
I couldn't think of
any other way to tell you.
I know it's silly of me.
I know.
Nein, Mama, it's not.
Thank you.
Well, you'd better wipe
that smile off your face.
Just go back in there...
and act like I'm the witch,
you know? Ja?
Ja.
Just know that...
that I...
Go on.
Do you need a bit of
help with that smile?
If I ever catch you...
doing that sort of
thing again, so help me...
I will string you up by your toes.
Do you hear me, Saumensch?
Understood?
Max!
I knew you'd live.
With all that reading, you
wouldn't leave me in peace.
You heard me?
Of course.
Thank you.
So...
How's Rudy?
I don't know.
Rudy's a pain in the neck.
The only thing worse than a boy you
hate is a boy you like, right?
Liesel, it's an air raid!
Go on, then.
What about you?
I'm here. I'll be fine.
It's a basement, isn't it?
Did you hear me, Saumensch?
Ja, Mama.
While 10,000 souls hid their
heads in fear and trembled...
one Jew thanked God for the
stars that blessed his eyes.
It's all I have.
I'm sorry.
I was saving it for
my husband's return, but...
Thank you. Very much.
He's a Jew.
They found his birth certificate.
He's a "Lehman" with one not two.
Please!
My son is in the army!
He's fighting on the front!
Please.
In the car!
Please!
You know me.
You know me! Please!
I'm German!
Please...
I've known this man my
whole life. We all have.
He's a good person.
What's your name?
Hans Hubermann.
Please! He's a good man.
Get back!
Papa!
Liesel!
Rudy!
Rudy.
Keep still.
What was I thinking?
He took my name.
Christ on the cross,
what have I done?
I've ruined us!
I'm sorry, Rosa.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
What did he do so wrong?
He reminded people
of their humanity.
Can't he apologize?
To who?
Hitler?
Will they take him away?
I don't know.
But...
if they come and find me here...
they'll take all of you away.
No, Max.
I have to, Liesel.
I'm sorry.
But you promised.
It's for your own good.
For your family.
But you're my family.
You've kept me alive, Liesel.
Don't ever forget that.
I can't lose someone else.
I'm not lost to you, Liesel.
You'll always be able
to find me in your words.
That's where I'll live on.
Max...
please.
Thank you.
Here.
It's two blankets
and a pair of socks.
And a nice piece of cheese
that I've been saving.
Rosa...
It's yours.
Come. Liesel.
Leave her.
Hans?
I'll get my coat.
You are Herr Steiner?
What?
I'm here to talk
about your son, Rudy.
Rudy Steiner.
He lives next door.
What do you want with him?
He's been selected
for elite training.
He starts in the summer.
I'm sorry, Barbra.
Hans Hubermann?
What's "conscripted"?
Look how you've grown.
I had not noticed.
I will miss you.
Everyone's leaving.
Even Rudy.
Rudy is going to be fine.
Look after your Mama, ja? She's not
as strong as she makes out.
I know.
Good girl.
Papa?
Come home.
What do you think?
The shoes let you down.
And the face.
Coming?
Where are you going?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm running away.
Have you thought this through?
Ja.
I don't want to die.
There.
All thought through.
Rudy, where are you going to stay?
"You"? What about "we"?
I didn't think
you were this serious.
What do you call this?
Packed lunch?
Is there anything in there
besides your soccer ball?
I miss my dad.
I don't even know
if he's alive.
I'm not ready.
I want to grow up before I die.
So did my brother.
I'm sorry.
I didn't ask for this.
Who would?
I hate Hitler.
Me, too.
I hate Hitler!
Hitler is a monkey's ass!
Stick you, Hitler!
You're all I've got, Rudy.
Let's go home.
The bombs were coming thicker now.
It's probably fair to say...
that no one was able to serve
the fuhrer as loyally as me.
There once was
a ghost of a boy...
who liked to live
in the shadows of things...
so he wouldn't frighten people.
What was that?
Who's speaking?
What are you doing?
Telling a story.
Why?
Whose boy?
She's telling a story.
Speak up.
Start again.
There once was a ghost of a boy...
who liked to live in the shadows,
so he wouldn't frighten people.
His job was to wait for his
sister, who was still alive.
She wasn't afraid of the dark...
because she knew
that's where her brother was.
Go on.
At night, when darkness
came to her room...
she would tell her brother
about the day.
She would remind him how the
sun felt on his skin...
and what the air
felt like to breathe...
Or how snow felt on his tongue.
And that reminded her...
that she was still alive.
Gentlemen...
how is everybody?
Look at this one. They are starting
to conscript grandfathers.
Hey, old man. Old man,
are they your own teeth?
Together, they sat in the forest...
and watched the sun rise.
And as he disappeared
back into the shadows...
she waved goodbye
for the last time.
Oh, Liesel.
Max?
Max!
Saumensch!
What are you up to?
Max?
Liesel!
Do you know Max?
Max?
Get out of here, you stupid girl!
Liesel!
I won't forget you.
I won't forget you, Max.
Liesel!
Go out!
You're too much like your
father, you know that?
What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
Hey, Saumensch, want to play?
Nein, not today.
Then let's steal something.
I don't steal. I borrow.
Then let's go borrow Franz Deutscher's
bike und get out of here.
Can't you see I'm reading?
Are you still angry with me?
For what?
Saving you.
Nein, Rudy.
You're very brave.
Papa!
You're home!
What is it, my girl?
My girl.
It's nice to hear you play.
I can't hear properly.
I'm going to bed.
Don't stay up too late, you two.
Your mama told me what you did.
I shouldn't have.
Maybe you had to.
I keep thinking about Max.
Wondering where he is.
Me, too.
I'm not sure what it all meant.
Everything he went through.
Everything we did.
We were just being people.
That's what people do.
Liesel...
you are all grown up.
All I have learned is that
life makes no promises.
So I had better get started.
I have always
tried to ignore it...
but I know this all
started with a train...
and some snow...
and my brother.
Outside the car, the world was
thrown inside a snow-shaker.
Und on a place
called Heaven Street...
a man with an accordion heart und
a woman cloaked in thunder...
waited for their new daughter.
He lived under our stairs like
a quiet owl with no wings...
until the sun forgot
what his face was.
The book floated
down the river...
like a red fish being chased
by a yellow-haired boy.
For Max, who gave me eyes.
Good night, Your Majesty.
I've always quite liked the
image of me with a sickle and cape.
Dark and formidable.
Unfortunately, I'm far more
ordinary and commonplace.
No one intended to destroy
a street named after Heaven.
It was a misread on a map.
No sirens that evening.
First were Rudy's brothers.
I read their simple dreams.
Then, I kissed his mother.
And stole the meanness
from Franz Deutscher's heart.
Rosa, I caught mid-snore.
I could swear I heard
her call me a Saukerl.
Then I felt her regrets for not
sharing more of her very big heart.
As for Hans, his soul was
lighter than a child's.
I felt his itch for one last
tune on his accordion...
and heard his final thought...
"Liesel."
Over here!
Just over.
Your hand.
Mama? Papa?
Papa?
Papa.
Rudy?
Saumensch.
Liesel.
I need to tell you...
Don't speak.
I need to say it.
I...
Rudy?
Rudy, nein.
Rudy, wake up.
Rudy, nein!
Wake up, Rudy!
Rudy, wake up!
Rudy, kiss me.
Rudy, his soul just
rolled into my arms.
In my job, I am always finding
humans at their best...
and their worst.
I see their ugliness,
and their beauty...
and I wonder how the
same thing can be both.
Liesel!
Max!
I have seen a great many things.
I've attended all the
world's worst disasters...
and worked for the greatest of villains.
And I've seen the greatest wonders.
But it's still like I said it was.
No one lives forever.
When I finally came for Liesel...
I took selfish pleasure
in the knowledge
that she had lived
her 90 years so wisely.
By then, her stories
had touched many souls.
Some of whom I came
to know in passing.
Max, whose friendship lasted
almost as long as Liesel.
Almost.
In her final thoughts...
she saw the long list of lives
that merged with hers.
Her three children.
Her grandchildren.
Her husband.
Among them, lit like lanterns...
were Hans and Rosa...
her brother...
and the boy whose hair remained
the color of lemons forever.
I wanted to tell the book thief
she was one of the few souls...
that made me wonder
what it was to live.
But in the end,
there were no words.
Only peace.
The only truth I truly know...
is that I am haunted by humans.