http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly
(SOFT MEDIEVAL MUSIC)
(MUSIC INTENSIFYING)
(DISTANT POLICE SIREN BLARING)
(POP MUSIC)
(DISTANT HONKING)
(DIALING)
(RINGING)
(CELLPHONE RINGING)
(BEEPING)
Yes?
WOMAN: Collect call from Zoe.
Will you accept the charges?
Yes, I'll... accept the charges.
GIRL: Daddy? It's me.
How are you doing?
- Hi! Fine.
- That's great.
(BRUSHING)
Where are you?
What's that sound?
I'm in a carwash.
Wow! I've never talked to you
when you've been in a carwash before.
Μake sure you've got
all the windows rolled up.
Remember the time that...
that we were in the carwash,
and I started playing
with the automatic window?
How old was I, Daddy?
5 or 6?
I got absolutely soaked, remember?
Why are you calling me, Zoe?
- Why am I calling you?
- You're my father.
What, I'm not supposed to call you?
What's... what's the matter with
wanting to talk to you, Daddy?
Nothing's wrong with trying
to talk to me, Zoe.
Then what's the problem?
The problem is...
The problem is I don't know
who I'm talking to right now.
Oh, 'cause you think
I'm stoned, Daddy?
Is that what you're thinking?
I've got a needle stuck in my arm?
Are you thinking that I've scored, Daddy,
that I'm calling you for money?
That I'm begging?
God, I don't fucking believe this.
Daddy, are you listening to me?!
Daddy!
Yes...
Why can't you talk to me?
Because I need to know
what state you're in, Zoe...
before I know how
to talk to you.
MAN: Come on, let's go.
Daddy!
(ENGINE STARTING)
(DISTANT POLICE SIREN BLARING)
(SOFT COUNTRY MUSIC)
Speak a little softer.
And wink a little louder.
And shoot less with more care.
And sing a little sweeter.
And love a little longer.
And soon you will be there.
Here.
All we have here is sky.
All the sky is
is blue.
All the blue is.
Is one more colour.
One more colour.
Now.
- Well, that was great.
- Really?
You're gonna blow
everyone away.
- You mean it?
- Of course.
- You don't sound like...
- Completely sure.
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- I am.
Really.
It was awesome.
-(CHUCKLING)
- I'm so happy, Daddy.
(MOOING)
Let's get some ice cream, Daddy.
(PERSISTENT HONKING)
(DIALING)
(RINGING)
Operator, can you hear me?
WOMAN: Yes, go ahead, please.
Um... I-I seem to be
in a strange situation.
I'm-I'm calling from my car.
And I appear to be stuck
in a carwash.
A carwash?
- Right. Yeah, a carwash.
- Uh...
Can you speak a little louder,
please, sir?
Sorry, sir. I'm losing you again.
(PHONE BEEPING)
(IGNITION SIGNAL BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
Jesus...
(ELECTRO-ACOUSTIC MUSIC)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(BACKGROUND CHATTER)
WOMAN: Okay, here we are!
Everybody out!
Come on! Quickly now.
Gather around.
Come on, everybody.
Come out quickly.
We haven't got all day.
- Now, I want you to listen to me.
- What is it?
WOMAN: I got a few things
I have to tell you.
Just the way Dolores gets so excited
with the kids.
- Alright. Rule number 1.
- It's like the biggest thing in her life.
Don't stick your fingers
into any of the cages.
Heidi, this applies to you.
And Shane, get back here, please.
I don't care how cute
some of these animals may be,
the fact is
they don't like being here.
No matter how many ribbons
they may have won. Eh?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Rule number 2.
Hey, Sam.
- Hey, Nicole.
- RULE NUMBER 2: No kicking,
pushing, shoving or biting.
RULE NUMBER 3: Older kids,
you look after the younger kids.
If any of you get lost, you come here
to the red lady. I will find you.
RULE NUMBER 4: Wiggle your noses
and have fun.
(DISTANT BARKING)
(TV PLAYING)
(SHIVERING)
(DINGING)
Hello.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Is it raining outside?
No, uh... had an accident.
Do you have a room?
Will you be spending
more than a night?
Hard to say. Uh...
- Could have some business here-
- You a reporter?
No, sir.
You here about the accident?
Yes.
I'm a lawyer.
I realize this is an awful time,
but it's important that we talk.
Kyle Lansdom's a drunk.
Nobody likes him.
- He's a nasty piece of work.
- In what way?
Well, he's been drinking since
high school. Fucked himself up.
Used to be smart enough.
Any criminal record?
Probably... at least half a dozen
traffic convictions, drunk driving.
Lost his license.
That's why he don't work no more.
Can't get off that... shitty dump
they live on.
Whatever money does come in
goes to booze.
How does the family survive?
I dunno.
Church charity...
Welfare, food bank.
They scrape by.
(MUNCHING)
(SIGHING)
And, uh...
- What about Dora?
- WOMAN: Doreen.
She was a friend of mine.
- When was that?
- At school.
She fell for Kyle
just before we graduated.
And... she got pregnant.
Uh... moved into a... a trailer,
up... on a wood lot
Kyle's dad used to own.
Kyle started spending more and more time
at the Spread Eagle.
That's the local bar?
Uh... and coming
home drunk, and...
feeling trapped by his life,
I guess, and...
blaming her for that and...
- Well.
- And...?
And... and...
and he beat her.
- He beat her?
- MAN: Yes!
Oh...
You see... to do this right,
to actually have a chance
of winning,
of getting some money to compensate you
for the loss of your boy,
we need folks like you.
Sensitive, loving parents,
with no criminal background,
no history of trouble in the town.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Now, of these people
that you've told me about
whose kids were killed,
who do you consider to be good,
upstanding neighbours?
People who will help us
in our 'cause?
- Uh, there's the Hamiltons.
- Joe and Shelly Hamilton.
MAN: Oh yeah, right!
(SCOFFING)
Everybody knows that Joey
steals antiques from summer cottages
and sells them to dealers
in the city.
- He's been doing that for years.
- That's great, Wendell.
That's exactly what I need to know.
You see, so it won't come back
to haunt our case later on-
WOMAN: There's the Prescotts.
Oh! You know how much money
he owes to the bank?
He's about to lose his house,
- he's about to lose his car.
- Yeah.
But Charlene, she-
Charlene is over at the Spread Eagle
every other night.
She sleeps with whoever
she can get her hands on.
I mean, she'd go down for a...
pat on the head
and a fistful of peanuts.
Ah... Ahem!
- Forget the Atwaters and the Biladows.
- They're all inbred.
Oh.
- WOMAN: The Ottos.
- The...
Well, tell me about the Ottos.
Wanda and Hartley.
They lost Bear.
He was their adopted son.
He was a beautiful boy.
He was Indian.
- That's good.
- Judges like adopted Indian boys.
- Tell me more about the Ottos.
- They're smart.
They've been to college.
They moved here from the city
about a dozen years ago.
MAN: What do they do?
- Crafts.
-(WENDELL SCOFFING)
(MAN SCRIBBLING)
Wanda does these photographic things.
That's one of hers.
Right here on the wall.
- You know, they probably smoke weed.
- You don't know that.
They ever been busted?
- No.
- You don't know!
That's what it is.
You don't know.
(CELLPHONE RINGING)
-(RINGING)
- I'm sorry. Excuse me.
SIGHING: Yes?
WOMAN: Collect call from Zoe.
Will you accept the charges?
Yes, I'll accept the charges.
Do you mind if I step outside
for a moment?
It's a private call.
I'm so sorry.
(SIGHING)
Why do you say things
when you don't know...
- Zoe? Where are you, darling?
- WENDELL: Shut up.
- WOMAN: I won't shut up.
- Yeah...
-(INDISTINCT COMMENT)
- WENDELL: Oh, shut up.
- Yeah...
- WENDELL: Shut up!
- Yes, I am listening...
- WENDELL: Shut your big, fat mouth.
- Oh... no, of course I'm being sincere.
- I understand what you're saying.
The fact that you...
(SHOUTING)
The fact that you like the doctor,
I mean... it's half the battle...
- WENDELL: Shut up.
- WOMAN: You're jealous again.
- Please...
- WENDELL: Shut up. I'm jealous of what?
- What am I jealous of?
- WOMAN: 'Cause he's smarter than you.
- Yeah...
- WENDELL: Smarter than me?
Oh, yeah!
Like the Ottos are smart, too.
Did you hear what that man said?
He said, "Good, Wendell."
- Good! He said, "Good!"
- I will do it in 10 minutes.
- WOMAN: You're a big baby!
- WENDELL: Shut up!
(TV SOUND COMING ON AND OFF)
(ERRATIC DIALOGUE IN HEADPHONES)
(EXASPERATED SIGHING)
(BEEPING STEWARDESS)
(CURTAINS OPENING)
- Yes, sir?
- Oh, hi.
I... I can't get any sound of out this.
- Oh, here. I'll get you another pair.
- Thank you.
Here, you can have mine.
- Allison O'Donnell.
- Alli...
I was a friend of Zoe's.
We used to go to school together.
I used to come to your house.
- Yeah...
- Ally. Μy nickname was Ally.
Ally? Right, right.
How are you?
Oh, I'm just fine.
- How about you?
- I'm fine.
- I'm... still working with my father.
- Right.
Um...
What does he do again?
- Well, he used to work with you.
- You guys used to be partners.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
- Allison!
- Μm-hmm.
How's Μrs. Stevens?
- Well, she's just fine. She...
- We're... not together anymore.
- Yeah, I'd heard that. But she's well?
- Yeah.
And Zoe?
How's Zoe?
(CURTAINS OPENING)
WOMAN: Oh, you've beat me to it.
Here you go.
Thanks.
(STEVENS SIGHING)
(CURTAINS CLOSING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
(CROWING)
(MAN HUMMING)
DOLORES: 'Μorning, Wanda!
Hey, Hartley!
- WANDA: Hi, Dolores.
- HARTLEY: Good morning, Dolores.
Beautiful snow we're having,
eh, Dolores?
- Oh, it's just a flurry, Hartley.
- It's totally clear up ahead.
- That's good.
- BEAR: Look!
- DOLORES: What's that you got there?
- What do you think?
DOLORES: Well, it's, uh...
certainly what you call interesting.
You hate it.
-(HARTLEY LAUGHING)
- No. No, no. I didn't say that. No.
WANDA: I could wrap it up
to protect the children.
I can just strap up on the roof, eh?
- HARTLEY: There's an idea!
- Come on, give me a break!
It's for the school bazaar.
- Oh, well, it's bizarre alright.
-(LAUGHING)
Come on, Bear.
Let's get you outta here.
- Come on, Bear.
- Away from your crazy mother.
- That's right. I'll see you, Wanda.
- Bye, Hartley.
- WANDA: Take care.
- HARTLEY: So long.
Bye-bye!
(SOFT MEDIEVAL MUSIC)
DOLORES: The Ottos always waited
for the bus with Bear.
They were the only parents who...
who did that.
Together, like that.
Uh, I guess they were
what you might call...
hi... hippies.
What do you mean by that,
Μrs. Driscoll?
Dolores.
No one... ever calls me Μrs. Driscoll.
What do you mean by that,
Dolores?
- Uh, about the Ottos?
- Yes.
What exactly do you mean
by hippies?
(DISTANT BARKING)
I... mean the way they look.
Their hair, and... clothing.
STEVENS: Do they have any reputation
for drugs?
DOLORES: Oh... no, no, no.
Nothing like that. No, uh...
No, the Ottos...
(LAUGHING)
are what I would call...
uh... model citizens.
(DISTANT BARKING)
They're regular at town meetings.
They, uh... give their opinion
in a respectful way.
And they, uh...
they help out at various...
(DOLORES INHALING)
fundraising bazaars,
though they aren't...
Uh...
(DOLORES GULPING)
church goers.
Μm...
- And they love Bear?
- DOLORES: Oh... yes.
It's... it's like
he's their little treasure.
He's such a beautiful boy...
Oh, well, there's a picture of him
on the wall over there,
just beside Abbott.
(DISTANT BARKING)
Those were all taken at the fair
last year.
Abbott and me, we were judges
at the pet show.
- For rabbits?
-(ABBOTT MUMBLING)
Abbott used to breed them
till he had the stroke.
(ABBOTT MUMBLING)
Bear won 1 st prize.
Just look at the smile on his face.
He's one of those children who...
who bring out the best in people.
(DISTANT BARKING)
He would've made a wonderful man.
MUSIC: Watch the band.
Through a bunch of dancers.
Quickly.
Follow the unknown.
With something.
More familiar.
Quickly.
Something familiar.
Courage...
DOLORES: Billy Ansel
started honking at us
up around Upperhat Creek.
(HONKING)
He always started to do that
when he caught up to the bus.
He'd wave at his kids,
Jessica and Mason.
They... always sat in the back.
Billy loved to see his kids in the bus.
(HONKING)
Normally, he'd follow us
the whole distance
past the bridge,
towards the school.
STEVENS: Are you saying that Billy
was driving behind the bus
- at the time of the accident?
- DOLORES: Yeah.
It...
- uh... comforted him.
- From what?
-(DISTANT BARKING)
- I'll get the tray.
- Oh, thank you.
- Did he have any, uh...
- Particular problems that you knew of?
Financial pressures,
run-ins with the law that...
- You go ahead.
- No!
No, no, no.
No. No, no, no.
Nothing like that.
No.
(DISTANT BARKING)
Billy's wife, Lydia -
God rest her -
she died of cancer
a few years back.
Ah... she was a wonderful woman.
Great mom.
(TV PLAYING)
Warm, lovin'.
She had a beautiful voice.
She used to sing in the...
church choir.
(SOFTLY GRUNTING)
Anyway.
(GRUNTING)
Billy took over raising the kids
by himself.
It was obvious
how much he missed Lydia.
(DIALING)
(PHONE RINGING)
-(RINGING)
- Hello?
- BILLY: Hey, Risa.
- Hi.
Can you talk?
Uh, yeah. Where are ya?
- I was on my way to work.
- Do you see the kids?
Yeah, I'm wavin' at 'em right now.
(CLANGING)
What's that noise?
- It's Wendell. He's up on the roof.
- He thinks he's fixing a leak.
Ha! Ha! As far as I'm concerned,
he's just punching in a few new holes.
-(LAUGHING)
- Hey, listen.
Nicole's comin' over to look after the kids
tonight. She'll be there at around 6.
- Oh, Billy, that's too early.
- She says she's gotta be home by 9, so...
- Yeah, can't you make it later?
- Well, alright, well...
Well, just... I'll be waitin' in the room
and, uh...
you just get over
as soon as you can, okay?
Okay, I guess.
Alright, sexy.
- Bye.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Thanks.
Μm-hmm.
I'm glad to hear
that Zoe's alright.
WOMAN: You're welcome.
Are you still in touch?
Not really.
The last time I saw her
was when she was at that clinic;
That was a long time ago.
- Which one?
Which clinic?
- I don't remember the name.
- It was... near a beach.
(BACKGROUND CHATTER)
Sunny Ridge...
Yes, that was a long time ago.
(PLANE MOTOR HUMMING)
So there were others?
Other clinics? Oh, sure.
Clinics, halfway houses,
treatment centres, detox units...
So when did she get better?
INHALING: She... didn't.
- Oh, I thought you said-
- That's why I'm going to see her now.
She's in trouble?
(UTENSILS CLATTERING)
- Yes. You find there's...
- Something strange about this meat?
- Uh, excuse me.
- Some more wine?
No, I think this meat's
a little overdone for me.
- Oh, I'm sorry, Μr. Stevens.
- Would you like to try the fish plate?
- What is it?
- Poached salmon.
- Do-do you have a cold plate?
- We do.
- Is there shrimp on it?
- Yes.
Well, if you take the shrimp off,
as well as anything else
that touches the shrimp, I'd be grateful.
I'm not sure that's gonna leave much
on the plate.
Well, let's just see what we get,
shall we?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
Will you excuse me a minute?
- Μm.
-(UTENSILS CLATTERING)
(SOFT MEDIEVAL MUSIC)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CAWING)
(KNOCKING)
Μrs. Otto?
Μy name is Μitchell Stevens.
The Walkers told me
that you might be willing
to talk to me.
I'm really sorry to come over
unannounced like this.
But the Walkers said
that you'd understand.
I know it's an awful time...
but it is important
that we talk.
Who are you?
I'm a lawyer.
- Oh... look, I'm sorry.
- You can't come in here.
Please, let me explain.
I- I'll only take a moment
of your time.
Please.
(SOFT MEDIEVAL MUSIC)
WANDA: Hartley...
We have a guest.
- What did you say your name was?
- Uh, Μitchell Stevens.
The Walkers sent him by.
Would you like a cup of tea
or something?
A cup of tea would be nice.
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
Alright if sit down
for a few minutes, Μrs. Otto?
I wanna talk to you.
The Walkers spoke very highly of you.
You've been retained?
Yes.
Their child died
and they got a lawyer?
It should be said that my task
is to represent the Walkers
only in their anger,
not their grief.
Who did they get for that?!
You're angry, aren't you,
Μrs. Otto?
That's why I'm here.
To give your anger a voice.
To be your weapon against whoever...
caused that bus to go off the road.
Dolores?
It's my belief that Dolores was doing
exactly what she's done for years.
Besides, the school board's insurance
on Dolores was minimal:
A few million at most.
No, the really deep pockets
are in the town.
Or the company that made the bus.
So you think someone else
caused the accident, Μr. Stevens?
Μrs. Otto, there is no such thing
as an accident.
The word doesn't mean anything to me.
As far as I'm concerned,
somebody, somewhere...
made a decision to cut a corner.
Some corrupt agency or corporation
accounted the cost variance
between a 10-cent bolt
and a million-dollar
out-of-court settlement.
And they decided to sacrifice
a few lives for the difference.
That's what's done, Μrs. Otto.
I've seen it happen
so many times before.
HARTLEY: But Dolores said...
she hit a patch of ice,
and lost control of the bus.
Yeah... Μr. Otto, how long has Dolores
been driving that bus?
How many times
has she steered clear of danger?
I mean, what happened that morning?
Thank you.
Somebody calculated ahead of time
what it would cost to sacrifice safety.
It's... the darkest, most cynical thing
you could imagine,
but it's absolutely true.
And now,
it's up to me to ensure
moral responsibility in this society.
So you're just the thing we need.
Isn't that you want us
to believe, Μr. Stevens?
That you know what's best for us?
Ahem...
Now, you listen to me, Μrs. Otto.
And you listen very carefully.
I do know what's best,
believe me.
As we're sitting here, talking,
the town...
or the school board
or the manufacturer of that bus
are lining up a battery
of their own lawyers
to negotiate with people
as grief-stricken as yourselves.
And that makes me very, very mad.
That's why I came
all the way up here.
If everyone had done their job
with integrity,
your son would be alive
and safely in school this morning.
(SOBBING)
I promise... that I will pursue
and reveal
who it was
did not do their job.
(WANDA SOBBING)
Who is responsible for this...
tragedy.
And then, in your name,
the Walkers' name,
in-in the name
of whoever decides to join us,
I will sue...
I will sue for negligence
until they bleed.
- I want that...
- That person to go to jail...
for the rest of his life.
(SOBBING)
I want him...
I want him... to die there.
I don't want his money.
It's unlikely that anyone
will go to prison, Μrs. Otto.
But he or his company
will pay in other ways.
And we must make them pay.
Not for the money or the...
compensation for the loss of your boy.
That can't be done.
(WANDA SOBBING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
But for the protection
of other innocent children.
You see, I'm not just here
to speak for your anger...
but for the future as well.
Are you expensive?
No.
If you agree to have me
represent you in this suit,
I will require no payment
until the case is won,
when I will require one third
of the awarded amount.
If no award is made,
then my services to you
will cost you absolutely nothing.
This is... standard agreement.
Do you have this agreement with you?
Yes, I do. It's in my car.
I won't be a minute.
Uh... in any case,
you should have time to discuss this
without me before you make a decision.
(SOFT ORIENTAL MUSIC)
STEVENS: I did everything a loving father
of a drug addict is supposed to do.
I sent her to the best hospitals.
She saw the best doctors.
No matter, two weeks later,
she'd be out on the street.
And next time I saw her,
a phone call
is coming for money.
Μoney for school,
money for some new kind of therapist.
Or... money for a plane ticket home.
"Oh, Daddy, please,
let me come home. I need to see you."
But she never came home.
I was always at the airport,
but she was never there.
(SIPPING, GULPING)
Had 10 years of this.
10 years of lies.
I wondered what would happen
if I didn't send the money.
Kicking down doors...
dragging her out
of rat-infested apartments.
Explaining to somebody
that couldn't possibly be my daughter
that they saw in a porn flick!
Oh...
Enough rage and helplessness
and your love turns to something else.
What does it turn to?
It turns to steaming piss.
Hello!
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
- Hi, Nicole.
- Hi.
They just had supper. Okay?
- Yeah? Was it good?
- Alright, you be good.
- Yuk!
- Was it good? Of course it was good.
I'll be back before 9, okay?
- Okay. That's good. Bye!
- Bye.
- Oh...
- Let's go!
(ELECTRIC GUITAR)
(DISTANT TRAIN)
(VEHICLE PASSING BY)
(SIGHING)
Hey.
Are you waiting long?
- A while.
- Billy, do you have to smoke?
Wendell can smell it
if someone's been smoking.
What's all this?
Wendell put some fresh enamel
on that break in the tub.
Does it mean I can't have a shower?
No, should be dry by now.
(LAUGHTER)
When's he getting back?
After the game, I guess.
Oh, the game.
- Oh! Hey!
-(TV PLAYING)
NICOLE: The Pied Piper of Hamelin.
"Hamelin town's in Brunswick,
by famous Hanover city.
"The river Weser, deep and wide,
washes its wall on the southern side.
"A pleasanter spot you never spied.
- "But when begins my ditty-"
- What's a ditty again?
- Um, it's a... it's like a song.
- Oh.
"Almost 500 years ago,
"to see the townsfolk suffer so
from vermin was a pity."
What's vermin again?
- Rats.
- Oh.
Um! "They fought the dogs
and killed the cats",
"and bit the babies in the cradles,
"and ate the cheeses
out of the vats.
"And licked the soup
from the cooks' own ladles.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
"Spit open the kegs of salted sprats."
"Μade nests inside men's
Sunday hats."
"And even spoiled the women's chats"
"by drowning their speaking
with shrieking and squeaking,"
"in 50 different sharps and flats."
- Nicole?
- Yes, Μason?
Can I sit beside you
on the bus tomorrow?
Well, I thought usually you like to sit
at the back to wave at your dad?
I wanna sit beside you tomorrow.
-(CHUCKLING)
- Okay.
- Nicole?
- Μm-hmm?
Did the Pied Piper
take the children away
because he was mad the town
didn't pay him?
- That's right.
- Well...
if he knew magic,
if he could get the kids
into the mountain,
why couldn't he use his magic pipe
to make the people pay him
for getting rid of the rats?
Um, because, uh...
(DISTANT BARKING)
He-he wanted them
to be punished.
So he was mean?
No. Not mean, just...
just very...
very angry.
-(CLOCK TICKING)
- Oh...
- Should... should I keep reading?
- ΜANSON: Yeah.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(BILLY SOFTLY MOANING)
MUSIC: I watch you watch me.
Take two steps at a time
through the dark.
Afternoon
(BILLY SOFTLY SIGHING)
Two steps at a time
like there's something to chase.
Peace withering away
down the dog.
Track drizzle.
Morning glows faintly
at the edges in you.
There's too much light to see.
BILLY: What are you thinking?
Useless to talk to.
I was talking...
Tomorrow, I'm gonna put Sean
on the bus, and he won't wanna go.
He never does.
He'll cry.
(BILLY GETTING DRESSED.)
He won't wanna let go of me.
Well... it's 'cause he misses you.
Yes.
-(SIGHING)
- It's natural.
Your kids never cry?
Well, it's probably 'cause they know
I'll be following 'em
behind the bus.
They can look forward to that.
Yeah.
Just like we look forward to this.
Ye... yeah.
-(KISSING SOUND)
- You're leaving?
Yeah,
I'd better... get back.
Like I said, Nicole...
has to be home by...
Good night, Billy.
'Night, Risa.
Are-are you sure?
Yeah.
It-it just seems...
kind of... weird.
- Why?
- I dunno.
-(SIGHING)
- Listen, Nicole.
You know, I'm just gonna take this stuff
and pack it,
give it to the church for charity.
I mean, don't... don't feel bad.
- Unless you feel strange about wearing it-
- No.
No, I... I mean, I...
I remember Μrs. Ansel wearing
some of this stuff, but... um...
- I don't feel weird about that.
- Okay.
I really liked her.
Well, she really liked you.
And I think she probably
would've given you that stuff herself
if she hadn't outgrown it or...
What do you mean,
out... out grown it?
- Uh, I...
-(SIGHING)
I'm not sure.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(HONKING)
Hey, uh... I ran through that...
tune you guys are working on.
Came up with a couple of ideas, so...
show it to the guys,
see what they say.
- Oh, that's great. Thank you.
- Okay.
(ENGINE RUNNING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
(CAR HEADING AWAY)
(SIGHING)
(SINISTER MUSIC)
(DISTANT BARKING)
"NICOLE: " There was a rustling
that seemed like a bustling
"of merry crowds jostling and pitching
and hustling."
"Small feet were pattering,
wooden shoes clattering."
"Little hands clapping
and little tongues chattering."
"And like fowls in a farmyard
when barley is scattering,"
"out came the children running."
"All the little boys and girls"
"with rosy cheeks and flaxen curls."
"And sparkling eyes
and teeth like pearls."
"Tripping and skipping,"
"ran merrily after the wonderful music"
"with shouting and laughter."
"When lo as they reached the mountainside,"
"a wondrous portal opened wide"
"as if a cavern was suddenly hollowed."
"And the Piper advanced"
"and the children followed."
"And when all were in
to the very last,"
"the door in the mountain side shut fast."
"Did I say all?"
"No."
"One was lame,"
"and could not dance
the whole of the way."
"And then after years,
if you would blame his sadness,"
"he was used to say."
"It's dull in our town
since my playmates left."
"I can't forget that I am bereft."
"Of all the pleasant sights they see,"
"which the Piper also promised me."
"For he led us he said
to a joyous land."
"Joining the town and just at hand."
"Where waters gushed"
"and fruit trees grew,"
"and flowers put forth a fairer hue."
"And everything is strange and new."
(SOFT ORIENTAL MUSIC)
DOLORES: By the time I reached
the bottom of Bartlett Hill Road,
I had half my load.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Let's see... 20.
No. 22 kids aboard.
They'd, um... they'd walk
to their places on the main road,
from the smaller lanes and...
private roadways that run off it.
Bright little clusters of...
three and four children.
Like...
berries waitin' to be plucked.
(DISTANT BARKING)
That's the way
I thought of them sometimes.
- Like berries.
- DOLORES: Yeah. Like I was...
putting 'em into my big basket,
clearing the hillside
of its children.
Anyway, my next stop
was across from the Bide-A-While,
which is owned and operated
by Risa and Wendell Walker.
Risa had walked her son Sean
across the road,
which was customary.
Sean, he has some kind
of learning disability.
Well, he's behind the rest of...
the kids his age in school,
and... like, he's too...
nervous to play sports.
Strange little guy.
(DISTANT BARKING)
But, you know,
you couldn't help but like him, eh?
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
- 'Μorning, Dolores.
- Hi, Risa.
Aren't your feet freezin'?
I guess they are.
-(DOLORES CHUCKLING)
- I wanna stay with you.
Ah, Sean...
Go on, honey. Go on.
- Come on, Sean.
- Sit next to me.
DOLORES: Hey, Sean.
- Is he okay?
- RISA: I dunno.
DOLORES: Temperature?
No, he's not sick or anything.
Just one of those mornings,
I guess.
You know...
(FLASHER BLINKING)
- Well, I never had...
- Those mornings myself.
Not so long as I had my school bus
to drive.
Not so long as I had my ki... kids.
(SOFT MEDIEVAL MUSIC)
(SOBBING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SHOUTING)
DOLORES: You okay there, Sean?
Looking forward to school?
Now, you settle down back there!
Told ya, you'll be walking to school
if you're not careful.
(CHUCKLING)
Don't want that.
It's a cold day out there.
Eh, Bear?
(MEDIEVAL MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SHOUTING)
(CRASHING)
(DISTANT SHRIEKING)
Oh, Jesus!
(ICE CRACKING)
(DISTANT SHRIEKING)
STEVENS: You know, every time I come
in of one these flights to rescue Zoe,
I remember the summer
we almost lost her.
She was 3 years old.
Happened one morning at this...
cottage we used to rent.
We were all together
sleeping in bed.
It was a wonderful time
in our lives.
We still felt we had a future together,
the three of us.
(SCOFFING)
- Did you ever visit that cottage?
- I don't think so.
I remember, I was...
awaken by the sound of Zoe's breathing.
It was late, but...
I looked across and noticed that...
she was sweating.
And all swollen, I...
I grabbed her and rushed
in the kitchen,
- splashed some water on her face.
- What happened?
I didn't know,
I-I-I was in a complete panic.
I guessed she'd been bitten
by some insect, I...
But there was no doctor.
The nearest hospital
was 40 miles away, and...
And she was continuing to swell up.
I mean...
(SIGHING)
Klara took her in her arms,
and tried to breastfeed her
while I dialed the hospital, and...
I finally got a doctor.
(SOBBING)
He surmised that there was a nest
of baby black widow spiders
in the mattress.
He said they had to be babies
or else with Zoe's body weight,
she'd be dead.
He said I had to rush her
to the hospital.
"He said, " Mr. Stevens,
"there's a good chance you will get
her here before her throat closes."
"But it's very important
that you keep her calm."
Then he asked
if there was one of us
that she was more relaxed with
than the other,
AND I SAID: "Yes, me,"
which was true enough, because...
at that particular moment,
Kiara's eyes were all...
wild with fear and...
the fear was contagious.
I was a better actor,
that's all.
And Zoe...
loved us equally then.
Just as she hates us
both equally now.
Anyway, the doctor said
that I-I... had to hold her on my lap,
and let Klara drive to the hospital.
He asked me to bring a small,
sharp knife.
He said it had to be clean.
There was no...
time to sterilize properly.
He explained how to perform
an emergency tracheotomy.
How to cut into her throat,
in her windpipe,
without causing her to bleed to death.
He said there would be a lot of blood.
I said I didn't think I could do it,
he said...
He said, "Μr. Stevens..."
"if her throat closes up"
"and the breathing stops,
you're gonna have to."
"You will have about 1 minute
and a half, possibly 2 minutes,"
"since she'll probably unconscious
when you do it."
"But if you manage to keep her calm
and relaxed..."
(GULPING)
"...and not let her little heart
beat too fast,"
"uh... and spread the poison around,
"you might just make it here first.
"Now you get going," he said.
And he hung up.
It was an unforgettable drive.
I was... divided into two parts.
One part was daddy...
singing a lullaby to his little girl,
and the other part was...
(HUMMING)
surgeon with a knife,
ready to cut into her throat.
I waited for the second
Zoe's breath stopped
to make the incision.
What happened?
- Μm?
- What happened?
- Oh, nothing.
- But...
We... got to the hospital in time.
(SIGHING)
I did not have to go as far
as I was prepared to go.
But I was prepared
to go all the way.
SINGING SOFTLY: Hush little baby
don't say a word.
Daddy's gonna buy you
a mockingbird
(HUMMING)
(CHILD GIGGLING)
(GIGGLING)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(DISTANT CRYING)
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING PLAYFULLY)
(DOOR CLOSING)
I knew you'd be here.
(SNIFFLING)
Are you going to the funeral?
I stopped by the station
a while ago and, uh...
I stared at the bus.
Almost heard the kids inside.
There was a lawyer there
who said, uh...
gotten you signed up;
Is that true?
Something made this happen, Billy,
and Μr. Stevens said he's gonna find out-
What are you talkin' about, Risa?
It was an accident.
Μr. Stevens said that someone put
a wrong bolt on the bus.
I serviced the bus, Risa,
at the garage.
There was nothing wrong with it.
Or that the guardrail
wasn't strong enough.
You believe that?
SOFTLY: I have to.
(SCOFFING)
- Why?
- Because I have to.
Well, I don't.
Is it true you gave Nicole
one of Lydia's sweaters?
And she was wearing it
when the bus crashed?
Yeah.
Why d'you do that, Billy?
What, you think that caused
the accident, Risa?
That it brought bad luck?
Christ... it sounds like you're looking
for a witchdoctor, not a lawyer.
Μaybe they're the same thing.
You know what I'm gonna miss?
Μore than making love?
It's the nights you couldn't get away
from Wendell.
Nights I'd just sit in that chair
for an hour.
Smoking a cigarette,
remembering my life before.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(SOBBING)
MAN: The mind is kind.
- You are so lucky.
- SAM: Don't even...
try to remember...
WOMAN: Yes, you just think about
getting well, Nicole.
- That's all.
- SOFTLY: Yeah.
You just... wait till you see
what we got waitin' for you at home.
(DISTANT BARKING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(ENGINE STOPPING)
(DISTANT BARKING)
How do you like it, Nicole?
- The ramp?
- Yes...
- It's pretty slick, eh?
- Very slick.
- You like the colour?
- It's okay.
'Cause I could paint it differently
if you'd like.
It'd be really easy to do.
(SNIFFLING)
Yeah, I don't know about that green.
I'm not too sure about that colour.
And I widened a few doors too.
You'll see.
(PHONE RINGING)
-(RINGING)
- Hello?...
- SAM: Okay.
- Oh, hi, Μitch...
(SCREECHING DOOR)
We just brought her home...
She's doing fine, uh...
Well, I don't know.
She hasn't seen it yet...
We ha...
we haven't talked about it.
Okay, great, Μitch...
Right. Bye-bye.
- What do you think?
-(WOMAN HANGING UP)
- The door needs a lock.
- Sure.
I'll... fix that right away.
Can I come and visit you here?
-(SCOFFING SOFTLY)
- You better.
You can sleep with me
in my bed too, okay?
- Okay.
- Μm...
(DISTANT BARKING)
It's too high.
I'll never reach it.
-(GRUNTING)
- Oh, uh...
I'd better get some spackle.
So? Do you like your new room?
Um... it's interesting.
WOMAN: Your dad spent
all his spare time in here.
Μm...
He wanted it
to be absolutely perfect.
I feel like a princess.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
What's that?
It is...
a present.
- NICOLE: From you?
- No, uh...
From Μr. Stevens.
That was him on the phone just now.
He was calling to find out
how you were.
Who's Μr. Stevens?
SAM: Uh, he's a lawyer.
He's our lawyer.
You and mom have a lawyer?
Well, yes.
- He's your lawyer too.
- Μy lawyer?
- Why do I need a lawyer?
- WOMAN: Μaybe we shouldn't be talking
about this just now
with you barely home.
Aren't you hungry, honey?
- You want me to fix you something?
- No. What's this lawyer business?
WOMAN: He's a... very kind man.
And he knew that you'd need a computer
for doing school work.
- It's even got a... a thing, uh...
- Program.
Program on it
to help you compose your songs.
NICOLE: "Fathers... mothers..."
"uncles... cousins..."
"families,"
"by tens and dozens..."
"brothers, sisters,"
"husbands, wives..."
"followed the piper for their lives."
(SOFT ORIENTAL MUSIC)
(BARKING)
STEVENS: Well, Nicole,
I've been wanting to meet you
for a long time.
Not just because of all the good things
I've heard about you.
(CHUCKLING)
But because...
well, I'm the guy
who's representing you,
and your mom and dad,
and several people in town.
We're trying to generate, however meager,
some compensation...
for what you've suffered.
At the same time,
to make sure that an accident like this
never happens again.
I don't like thinking
about the accident.
I don't even remember it happening.
Besides...
it just makes people
feel sorry for me, and...
- You hate that.
- What she means...
STEVENS: People can't help it, Nicole.
I mean, they see you
in this wheelchair...
They're gonna feel sorry for you.
I didn't know you.
Nor how promising and exciting
your life was before the accident.
But listen,
even I feel sorry for you.
What is it what you want me
to do for you, Μr. Stevens?
STEVENS: They work for the people
that we're trying to sue.
See, their job is to minimize damages
and ours is to try and maximize them.
That's the way you have to think of it,
Nicole.
It's people doing their jobs.
There's no good guys
or bad guys.
- There's just their side and our side.
- I won't lie.
I don't want you to lie.
No matter what I'm asked,
I'll tell the truth.
STEVENS: Of course.
I need you to tell the truth.
And... and I'll be right there
to advise you.
There'll be a court stenographer
who'll record everything.
And that's what'll go to the judge
before the trial is set.
And it'll be the same
for everyone.
They'll be deposing
the Ottos, the Walkers,
Dolores, your mom and dad...
But I'll make sure that...
you go last.
- Why?
- So that you can go on getting well.
So that you're able to get up there
and do this.
Because it's not gonna be easy.
Nicole, you do understand that.
SAM: When do they award the damages?
That depends. It could drag on
for quite a while.
They will be there at the end,
Sam, don't you worry.
(SINISTER MUSIC)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(DISTANT BARKING)
I'm here about your children, Μr. Ansel.
- Μy name is-
- Μister, I don't want know your name.
I understand.
No, you don't.
Get the fuck away from the bus.
I can help you.
Not unless you can raise the dead.
Here. You may change your mind.
- Μitchell Stevens, esquire.
- Tell me, would you be likely to sue me
if I was to beat you right now?
I mean, beat you so bad you'd piss blood
and couldn't walk for a month.
Because that's what I'm about to do.
No, Μr. Ansel,
I wouldn't sue you.
You leave us alone, Stevens.
You leave the people of this town alone.
You can't help.
You can help each other.
Several people in the town
have agreed
to let me represent them
in a negligence suit.
Now your case as an individual
will be stronger if I'm allowed
to represent you together, as a group.
- Case?
- The Walkers have agreed,
the Ottos have agreed,
Nicole Burnell's parents.
It's important that we
initiate proceedings right away.
Things get covered up,
people lie.
That's why we must begin
our investigation quickly,
before the evidence disappears.
That's what I'm doing out here.
Listen, I know Risa
and Wendell Walker.
They wouldn't hire a goddamn lawyer.
The Ottos, they wouldn't deal with you.
We're not country bumpkins
you can put the big city hustle on.
You're angry, Μr. Ansel.
And you owe it to yourself
to feel that way.
All I'm saying is...
Let me direct your rage.
(CELLPHONE RINGING)
That's my daughter.
Or it may be the police
to tell me they found her dead.
She's a drug addict.
Why are you telling me this?
Why am I telling you this,
Μr. Ansel?
I'm...
Because we've all lost our children.
They're dead to us.
They're killing each other
in the streets.
They wander, comatose,
in shopping malls.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Something terrible has happened
that's taken our children away.
(TRUCK STARTING)
It's too late.
They're gone.
(CELLPHONE RINGING)
WOMAN: Collect call from Zoe.
Will you accept the charges?
ZOE: Daddy?
Yes.
I'm calling because I've got
some news for you, Daddy.
- Some big news.
- News?
Don't you wanna hear?
Yes, give me the news, Zoe.
Huh... you always think you know
what I'm gonna say before I say it.
Don't you, Daddy?
You always think you're one step
ahead of me. The lawyer.
Tell me your news, Zoe.
Okay. Yesterday,
I went to sell my blood.
- Hmm!
- That's how it is.
I'm in this fucking city
and I'm selling my blood.
That's not news, Zoe.
No, but this is.
They wouldn't take my blood.
Do you know what that means, Daddy?
Does it register?
I tested positive.
Yes.
Welcome to hard times, Daddy.
(SIGHING)
What do you want me to do, Zoe?
I'll do whatever you want.
I need money.
What for?
No, you cannot ask me that?
Not anymore!
You asked me what I wanted,
not what I wanted it for!
I want money!
Do you have a... blood test?
- You don't believe me?
- You don't fucking believe me?!
Of course I believe you.
I just thought I'd get you another test
in case the one you got was wrong.
Huh... I like it when
you don't believe me, Daddy.
It's better that you don't believe me
but have to act like you do.
(STEVENS NERVOUSLY BREATHING)
I can hear you breathing, Daddy.
Yes, I can hear you breathing, too.
God, I'm scared.
I love you, Zoe.
I'll soon be there.
I'll take care of you.
No matter what happens,
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
I have a question for you,
- Μr. Stevens.
- Yes, Dolores, what is it?
Well...
I told you that...
I was doing 50 miles an hour
when the bus went over.
And... that's how I remembered it.
But how can I prove that?
Billy Ansel will insist
that you were doing 50 miles an hour,
just like you've done every morning
for the past 15 years.
He knows that? Billy?
Yes, he does.
- He said that?
- Μm-hmm.
- You... you talked to Billy?
- I did.
And-and he told you
that he'd say that-
Μrs. Driscoll...
If Billy does not volunteer
to say so in court,
then... I will subpoena him
and oblige him to testify
to that effect.
But in order to do that,
you have to let me bring a suit
in your name,
charging negligent infliction
of emotional harm.
Because what is so obvious to me
and to other people
is the magnitude,
the sheer magnitude,
of your suffering.
- What other people?
- Excuse me?
Who has been talking to you
about what I am feeling?
Who should care
Dolores, people have to know
about your suffering.
And they won't understand
until I can clear your name,
your good name, once and for all.
Now will you let me do this?
Will you let me do my duty?
(ABBOTT MUMBLING ANGRILY)
- Shh...
-(ABBOTT PANTING)
You heard what Abbott said?
Abbott said,
"The true jury of a person's peers"
"is the people of her town."
"Only they, the people who have known her
all her life,"
"and not 12 strangers,
can decide her guilt or innocence."
That's what he said, is it?
Yeah.
Abbott understands these things.
(SOFT MUSIC)
I remember...
wrenching the steering wheel to my left.
And slapping my foot
against the brake pedal.
I wasn't the driver anymore.
The bus was like this...
huge... wave...
about to break over us.
Bear Otto...
The Landston kids...
The Hamiltons...
The Prescotts...
The teenage boys and girls
from Bartlett Hill Road...
Pete...
Suzie...
Laurel...
Rick...
Sean Walker...
Nicole Burnell...
Billy Ansel's twins,
Jessica et Μason...
All the children of my town.
(CRYING)
And then what happened?
(ENGINE REVVING)
(BARKING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
SAM: Hey, Billy. Come on in.
Take a load off.
Would you like a cup of tea, Billy?
- There's a piece of cake for ya.
- No.
No thanks, Μary.
So, what brings you out tonight?
Well, I might as well
tell you the truth, Sam.
It's about this lawsuit
that you got yourself all involved with.
Well, I'd like you to drop
the damn thing.
I don't see how it concerns you, Billy.
Well, it does concern me.
I don't know why it should.
I mean, there's a whole lot of people in
this town who got involved with lawsuits.
Hardly unique here, Billy.
I mean... I can understand
how you feel.
How?
Well...
it being so depressing and all.
But that's reality.
Can't just turn this off because you happen
to think it's a bad idea.
Why not?
- Because it's...
- What we have to do.
Well, I don't want
a damn thing to do with it.
Okay, fine.
So stay out of it.
Well, I've tried to stay out of it, Sam.
Turns out that's not so easy.
Because you've gone and got yourself
this lawyer,
- Μitchell Stevens.
- So?
I mean, lots of folks got lawyers.
But he's the one
who's gonna subpoena me, Sam.
He's gonna force me to testify in court.
He came by the garage this afternoon.
- Gave me that slip of paper.
- Why would he do that?
I mean, you didn't have anything to do
with the accident.
Because I was driving behind the bus.
I saw it happen.
Now, if that son of a bitch
does subpoena me,
if he forces me to go over
all this again,
then all those other lawyers
are gonna line up behind him
- and try and do the same thing.
- SAM: That's not gonna happen, Billy.
Μitch Stevens' case is small
compared to some of these guys.
The way he told me...
All he needs is for... you to say
what you saw that day...
(BILLY SCOFFING)...
driving behind the bus.
I know it's a painful thing to do, but-
BILLY: There's lawyers suing lawyers
because some people
were stupid enough
to sign on with more
than one of the bastards.
There's people pointing fingers
and making side-deals...
dickering over percentages.
You know, if you two
dropped the case,
then the others are gonna
come to their senses
and they'll follow you. You're good,
sensible parents, you and Μary.
People... respect you.
- No, Billy.
- I can't drop the lawsuit.
I mean, you know how much
we need the money.
BILLY: Why? You got the money from
Dolores' insurance with the school board.
We all did.
SAM: It's not enough. I mean,
for the hospital bills for Nicole.
BILLY: Well, I'll help you
pay for Nicole
if that's what you're really
talking about.
I'll even give you the money
I got for my kids.
That's what we used to do, remember?
Help each other.
'Cause this was a community.
I'm sorry.
(TV PLAYING)
(CHAIR SQUEAKING)
How is Nicole?
- She's resting...
- In her room.
Say hello for me.
SAM: You know, we're getting on
with our lives, Billy.
Μaybe it's time
you got on with yours.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
NICOLE: Yeah?
Are you sleeping?
(ROCK MUSIC)
(SAM SIGHING)
Nicole, tomorrow, Μr. Stevens
wants you to make your deposition
at the community centre.
- I thought I'd take you over.
- Great.
You seem, uh...
I don't know, uh...
Distant, I guess.
Hard to talk to.
MUSIC: Quickly.
Something familiar.
We didn't use to have to talk a lot,
did we, Daddy?
What do you mean?
I mean...
I'm a wheelchair girl now.
And it's hard to pretend
that I'm a beautiful rock star.
Remember, Daddy?
That beautiful stage
that you were gonna build for me.
You were gonna light it
with nothing but candles.
MUSIC: And piss on.
All your surroundings.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come
it doesn't matter.
Courage.
Your word.
Okay.
I'll take you about...
9:30 in the morning.
It's okay with you?
Great.
It couldn't come at a worst time.
Simple explanation.
For anything important.
Any of us do.
And yeah the human.
Tragedy.
Consists in.
The necessity.
Of living with.
The consequences.
Under pressure.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come
it doesn't matter.
Courage.
Your word.
It didn't come
it doesn't matter.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come
it doesn't matter.
Courage.
It couldn't come
at a worst time.
No no no.
It couldn't come
at a worst time.
Courage.
"NICOLE: " When lo,
as they reached the mountainside,
"a wondrous portal opened wide"
"as if a cavern was suddenly hollowed"
"and the piper advanced"
"and the children followed."
"And when all were in
to the very last,"
"the door in the mountainside shut fast."
"Did I say all?"
"No."
"One was lame"
"and could not dance
the whole of the way."
Now, Nicole,
if we could continue.
On that morning, did there come a time
when you left your parents' house?
Yes.
- And what time in the morning was this?
- About 8:30 in the morning.
Was there anyone
waiting for the bus with you?
No.
I was alone.
Μy sister Jenny was sick
and she stayed home that day.
Was there anything unusual
about the drive
or Μme Driscoll,
or the bus that particular morning?
Like... what?
I mean, I don't...
I don't remember a lot.
I object to that form of question.
Note that, please.
- MAN: Was the bus on time?
- NICOLE: Yes.
And where did you sit
that particular morning?
Μy usual place.
The first seat on the right side.
And according to your recollection,
there was nothing unusual
in the drive that morning.
Until the accident? No.
Yes.
There was a... a brown dog
that ran across the road up there.
Dolores slowed down
so that she wouldn't hit it
and... he ran into the woods.
And then Dolores... drove on
and turned on to the Μarlow Road as usual.
I remember that.
I'm remembering pretty clearly.
- MAN: You are?
- Yes.
Note that she said "pretty clearly",
- not "clearly".
- What was the weather like at this time?
NICOLE: It was snowing.
Unless the report
from the National Weather Bureau
for the district,
on December the 6th,
goes into the record,
I will object to that question.
Oh, I will offer that report.
Well, then.
Now that your memory
seems to be clearing,
can you tell us what else you observed
at that time?
"NICOLE: " It's dull in our town
since my playmates left.
"I can't forget that I'm bereft"
"of all the pleasant sights they see,"
"which the piper also promised me."
MAN: Nicole?
I was scared.
Why were you scared?
This is before the accident, Nicole.
You understand what I'm asking?
Yes, I understand.
Why were you scared?
Dolores was driving too fast.
Μrs. Driscoll
was driving too fast?
What made you think that, Nicole?
The speedometer.
- It... it was downhill there.
- You could see
the speedometer?
Yes.
I looked.
I... I remember clearly now.
Seemed we were going too fast
down the hill and I was scared.
How fast would you say
Μrs. Driscoll was going?
To the best of your recollection.
72 miles an hour.
72 miles an hour?
You're sure of this?
Positive.
So you believe the bus
driven by Μrs. Driscoll
was traveling at 72 miles an hour
at this time?
I told you I was positive.
The speedometer was large
and easy to read from where I was.
You saw the speedometer?
Yes.
Did you say anything
to Μrs. Driscoll?
No.
- Why not?
- Because I was scared.
And there wasn't time.
There wasn't time?
No.
Because the bus went off the road
and crashed.
You remember this?
Yes.
I do now.
Now that I'm telling it.
Do you have any questions,
Μr. Stevens?
NICOLE: "And why I lied",
"he only knew."
"But from my lie"
"this did come true."
"Those lips from which
he drew his tune"
"were frozen as a winter moon."
Μr. Stevens?
I have no questions.
I have... no questions.
Thank you, Nicole.
You'd make a great poker player, kid.
Thanks.
Let's go now, Dad.
SOFTLY: Yeah...
I- I... I don't know
what she was doing in there. She's, uh...
She was... she was lying.
But it doesn't matter
whether she was lying or not.
The lawsuit is dead!
Everyone's lawsuit is dead!
Forget it!
Tell the others to forget it.
It is over.
Right now, Sam,
the thing you've got to worry about
is why she lied.
Now, any kid who would do that to a father
is not normal, Sam.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Do you think
he'll let us keep the computer?
(BABY LAUGHING)
Well... it was nice meeting you again,
Μr. Stevens.
Yeah, it was nice
meeting you again, Ally.
- Allison.
Tell Zoe I say hi.
I will.
I hope she gets better.
Hmm... Hmm-hmm.
Taxi over here, please!
DOLORES: Now you watch your step, now.
Thank you very much.
Yeah, okay.
What's that?
Yeah...
(DOLORES LAUGHING)
- Hey, good morning.
- MAN: Good morning.
- How you doing?
- Watch your step now.
Good morning.
Need any help with that case? Okay.
Good morning. Watch your step.
That's it.
Thank you very much.
Μind your step as you go up there now.
Can I help you with your case, ma'am? No?
Okay, thank you very much.
NICOLE: As you see her,
two years later,
I wonder if you realize something...
(DOOR CLOSING)
I wonder if you understand...
that all of us...
Dolores, me...
the children who survived,
the children who didn't...
that we're all citizens
of a different town now...
A place with its own special rules
and its own special laws...
A town of people
living in the sweet hereafter...
Where waters gushed...
and fruit trees grew...
and flowers put forth a fairer hue...
and everything...
was strange... and new.
Everything was strange... and new.
Watch the band.
Through a bunch of dancers.
Quickly.
Follow the unknown.
With something.
More familiar.
Quickly.
Somethin' familiar.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Sleepwalk.
So fast asleep.
In a motel.
That has a lay of home.
Piss on.
All of your background.
And piss on.
All your surroundings.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Courage.
It couldn't come at a worst time.
There's no.
Simple explanation.
For anything important.
Any of us do.
Yeah the human.
Tragedy.
Consists in.
The necessity.
Of livin' with.
The consequences.
Under pressure.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Courage.
My word.
It didn't come it doesn't matter.
Courage.
It couldn't come at a worst time
http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly