[Wind Blowing]
[Thunder]
MEDITERRANEAN SEA
60 MILES SOUTH OF MARSEILLES
[Speaking Italian]
THE BOURNE IDENTITY
[Grunting]
What a mess.
You've never seen a dead man before?
Put a blanket on him. Cover him.
I'm coming.
Be careful.
One minute. I'll be right there. Cover him.
[Grunts]
What the hell
are you doing to me?
[Speaking Italian]
What are you doing?
[Muffled]
Goddamn it! Where am I?
A boat.
A fishing boat.
You were in the water.
We pull you out.
What water?
You were shot.
See? There are the bullets.
Ohh. Look. There is
a number for a bank.
Why was it in your hip?
My hip?
Yeah. In your hip
under the skin.
Uh. Oh, God!
You need to rest.
Wait. Please. Slow down.
I'm a friend.
I'm your friend. Huh?
My name is Giancarlo.
Who are you?
What's your name?
Uh, I don't know.
- Oh, God.
- [Thud]
CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY
LANGLEY, VIRGINIA
[Chattering]
It's been confirmed, sir.
Mission failed.
[Chattering]
BOURNE: [In French]
Do you know who I am?
I do not know who I am.
BOURNE: [In Dutch]
Tell me who I am.
If you know who I am...
Please stop messing around...
...and tell me.
[Speaking Italian]
If you want to eat,
you better get in there.
Based on these charts, I think
I may have been closer to the coast.
What's this?
You tied these knots?
So it start
to come back, huh?
No, it doesn't start to come back.
The knot's like everything else.
I just found the rope
and I did it.
The same way I can...
I can read, I can write.
I can add, subtract.
I can make coffee. I can shuffle cards.
I can set up a chessboard.
Yes, yes. It will come back.
No, it's not coming back,
goddamn it! That's the point!
I'm down here
looking through all this shit.
For two weeks I'm down here.
It's not working. I don't
even know what to look for.
You need to rest.
It will come back.
What if it doesn't come back?
We get in there tomorrow,
I-I don't even have a name.
It's not much,
but it should get you
to Switzerland.
Thank you.
[Woman On P.A., Indistinct]
[Speaking German]
Hey.
Can't you read the signs?
On your feet...let's go...right now.
The park is closed.
There's no sleeping in the park.
All right.
Let's see some identification.
No. I-I don't...
Come on...your papers.
I don't have any papers.
I lost...
[Speaking German]
I've lost them...my papers...they are lost.
Ok...let's go...put your hands up.
...I just need to sleep...
[Commands angrily in German]
[Gun Cocking]
These people have threatened
my family, my babies.
So I'm telling you,
when the evidence is clear...
I will have a nice story
for you to read about.
And all my friends out there,
you will read about yourselves.
'Cause if you want
to play this game...
after I've been reasonable,
I will show you.
That's Nykwana Wombosi speaking
in Paris the day before yesterday.
He was an irritation
before he took power...
he was a problem when
he was in power and he's been
a disaster for us in exile.
He's writing a book about
the agency's history in Africa.
He's going to name names.
It's basically a shakedown.
He's demanding the agency's help.
He wants us to put him back
in power in six months or else.
This interview, and I'll
make the tape available
to anyone who wants it...
he goes on to claim
that he's just survived
an assassination attempt.
He says it's us.
He says he's got proof.
The director wants to know
if there's any possible shred of truth
in this accusation.
I've already assured him
there's nobody that reckless
on my senior staff.
[Elevator Dings]
I was recalling a conversation
we had some time ago,
talking about Treadstone.
I seem to remember
Nykwana Wombosi's name
might have come up.
I'm not sure
what we're talking about.
Someone tried to take him out.
Tried and failed.
Was this Treadstone?
You're asking me
a direct question?
Yes.
I thought you were
never gonna do that.
What happened?
Well, we, uh, lost
communication with our man.
This was almost
two weeks ago.
We've been working
around the clock, the whole unit.
We've been sleeping down there.
Believe me, we're doing
everything we can.
And you don't
let me know this?
You never wanted to before.
You never made
a mistake before.
GEMEINSCHAFT BANK
ZURICH SWITZERLAND
[Typing]
What can I do for you?
Uh, yes. I'm here about
a numbered account.
If you just enter your account
number here, I'll direct you
to an appropriate officer.
[Elevator Beeps]
[Speaking German]
[Beeps]
My name is Jason Bourne.
I live in Paris.
[Man Speaking German]
[In German]
I'm trying to think...
How long's it been since I was here last?
I'm not sure.
It must be three weeks.
[Dialing]
[Bourne's Voice]
Yes. In Paris. Do you have
the number for a Jason Bourne?
[Woman's Voice]
Yes, sir. Would you
like me to connect you?
Yes. Please.
[Ringing]
[Beep]
[Bourne's Voice]
This is 4-6-9-9-0-3-8-4.
Leave a message at the beep.
[Bourne's Voice, Speaking French]
[Siren Blaring]
[Horn Blowing]
[Speaking German, Faintly]
[Siren Blaring]
I'm an American.
Okay.
Hold it. Wait.
You have no jurisdiction here.
[Speaking German]
No. Excuse me. No. This is
not my current address, okay?
This was my current address
until two days ago...
when I started standing
in line outside.
Now, I lose my apartment,
okay? That means no address,
no phone, no money, no time.
- I still have no visa.
- Miss Kreutz, I'm gonna have to
ask you to keep your voice down.
[Kreutz]
Excuse me. But where's the guy
that I talked to last week?
Every week it's a new person.
How am I supposed to...
I don't know
who you saw last week.
Well, let me help you.
- I'm sure I have it. Hold on.
- Could I have your attention
for a moment, please?
[Kreutz]
It's right here. Look at it.
[Man Speaking, Indistinct]
This is a student visa now.
It's not about a green card anymore.
- It's completely different.
- It's not a menu, Miss Kreutz.
You donít just
pick what you want.
You! Red bag! The red bag!
Stop right there!
Put your hands up!
[Gasps]
[Screaming]
[Alarm Blaring]
I'm on the east... Ohh!
[Man's Voice]
Move it! Now! Now!
Check. Clear!
[Man's Voice]
Bravo Unit moving up staircase.
Proceeding to second floor.
[Alarm Continues Blaring]
[Man's Voice In Earphone, Indistinct]
- [Woman Screams]
- On the floor! Down!
Clear!
[Man] Go! Go! Come on!
He's in Zurich now?
Right now?
Yes. It just came in.
But they're sure?
Sure it's him?
Yes. He went to the bank.
Our source at the bank,
that's who called.
- Come on.
- He's got to assume we're
watching the bank, right?
I don't know. Come on.
I mean, he cleaned out
the box. He left the gun.
What does that mean?
I said I don't know.
I liked it better
when I thought he was dead.
[Mumbling, Indistinct]
Oh, Scheiﬂe.
What are you looking at?
I heard you inside.
What?
The consulate. I heard
you talking. I thought maybe
we could help each other.
How's that?
You need money.
I need a ride out of here.
I'm not running a car service
just now. Thank you.
I'll give you $10,000
for driving me to Paris.
[In German]
What, do you think I'm a fool?
You'd be a fool not to take it.
What is this, a joke?
Some kind of scam?
No, it's no scam.
And I'll give you another ten
when we get there.
[Siren Blares]
Jesus.
- Is that for you?
- Look. You drive, I pay.
It's that simple.
Scheiﬂe.
I got enough trouble, okay?
Okay. Can I have
my money back?
[Man] All right, go.
Keep going. Go.
There. Wait.
[Man #2] No. It's
got to be near the end.
Oh, come on, folks.
We caught a break here. Let's go.
Okay, I'm up.
We're getting grids.
Airline, train, hotels...
Did you get the address?
The street?
Gemeinschaft.
- Here we go.
- I got it. I think I got it.
Is it him?
Unreal.
This is 38 minutes ago.
Hey, Zurich police are looking
for an American man carrying
a red bank bag.
He just tore up the embassy,
and he put two cops
in the hospital last night.
Get everybody up. Do it now.
I want them all activated.
All of them?
At the same time?
You heard me. I want Bourne
in a body bag by sundown.
Let's get a map up here.
Come on, folks. Work it.
Take a look.
The grids are good info.
[Beeping]
[Kreutz's Voice, Indistinct]
[Kreutz] Which was fine for me,
because I was ready.
You know, because, I mean,
after six months in Amsterdam...
you're not sure if you've been
there 20 minutes or 20 years,
if you know what I mean.
So I went and I took
all the money I had...
and I went in with friends
and we took over this really
cool surf shop outside Biarritz...
um, which was
right by the water;
it was amazing.
It was just amazing
for about three months...
until it turned out
that this, uh, jerk who
had found us the lease...
was actually shining
everyone on and... [Sighs]
And what?
What do you mean what?
Listen to me.
I've been speed-talking
for about 60 kilometers now.
I talk when I'm nervous.
I mean, I talk like this
when I'm nervous.
I'm gonna shut up now.
No. Don't do that.
I haven't talked
to anybody in a while.
Yeah, but we're not talking.
I'm talking.
You've said, like, ten words
since we left Zurich.
Well, listening to you,
um, it's relaxing.
I haven't slept
in a while and...
and I've had this headache.
It's like a constant thing
inside my head.
And it's just starting
to move to the background, so...
keep going.
Really. If you want,
please keep talking.
Okay.
[Chuckles]
What kind of music
do you like?
Huh? What do you like?
Come on.
Um...
[Turns On Radio]
You know what, never mind.
No. It's fine. Tell me.
[Switching Channels]
What do you want
to listen to?
I don't know.
Come on.
It's not that hard.
What do you like?
Tell me.
I don't know.
[Turns Off Radio]
Who pays $20,000
for a ride to Paris?
Fuck it. I can't remember anything
that happened before two weeks ago.
Lucky you.
No. I'm serious.
I don't know who I am.
I don't know where I'm going.
None of it.
What, like, amnesia?
Yes.
Amnesia?
Great.
- That's the best angle of the courtyard?
- That's the only angle.
Well, what do they have
of the streets or the area?
They must
have something.
Hang on.
[Typing]
Oh, what is he doing?
Is it a game?
Is he warning us? Is it a threat?
Sir, look at this.
What's that?
It's an angle of the street.
It's some sort of alley.
Just enhance it.
[Typing]
Who the hell is that?
Marie Helena Kreutz.
She's 26.
Born outside of Hannover.
Father was a welder.
He died in '87.
Still don't have the mother.
The grandmother,
she's still there in Hannover...
and looks like
she's the anchor for this
little domestic disaster.
And there's a stepbrother.
It's tough. The girl's a gypsy.
She pops up on the grid
here and there,
but it's chaotic at best.
She paid some electric bills
in Spain, '95...
had a phone in her name for
three months in Belgium, '96.
No taxes, no credit.
I don't like her.
I want to go deep.
Get a phone log for granny
and the half brother...
anybody we can cross-file.
I want to know every place
she's slept in the past six years.
Have Paris get these
out in the field.
TREADSTONE SAFE HOUSE
PARIS, FRANCE
[Typing]
[Bourne]
I'm not making this up.
These are real.
Okay.
Who has a safety
deposit box full of...
money and six passports
and a gun?
Who has a bank account number
in their hip?
I come in here...
and the first thing I'm doing
is I'm catching the sight lines
and looking for an exit.
I see the exit sign too.
I'm not worried.
I mean, you were shot.
People do all kinds
of weird and amazing stuff
when they're scared.
I can tell you
the license plate numbers
of all six cars outside.
I can tell that
our waitress is left-handed...
and the guy sitting up at
the counter weighs 215 pounds
and knows how to handle himself.
I know the best place
to look for a gun is the cab
of the gray truck outside.
And at this altitude, I can
run flat-out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
Now why would I know that?
How can I know that
and not know who I am?
Hey.
Ah, I slept.
I can't believe it.
Yeah. Well, you were tired.
I haven't slept.
Oh. Here. For 20,000,
I like to throw in breakfast.
Did you stop for gas?
[Sighs]
You were
pretty out of it.
Yeah.
Ohh.
So, do you think there's,
like, a family waiting for you?
I don't know.
I haven't thought about it.
[Kreutz] Is that it?
104. Yeah, that's it.
That's the address.
No, no. Keep going.
Keep going.
Okay.
Where?
Just, uh, just take a left.
Go on over here.
So this is it, right?
Yeah. I guess.
Yeah, but I don't
recognize any of this.
Okay. You should go.
Jason.
Oh, God. Money. Right.
Yeah.
Here.
Danke, okay?
Thanks for the ride.
Anytime.
Well, you could come up
and you can...
Or you could wait here.
I can go check it out,
but you could wait...
Uh, no, no. No, no.
Um, with you, you would
probably just forget
about me if I stayed here.
How could I forget about you?
You're the only person I know.
Yeah. That's true.
[Buzzes]
I guess you're not home.
[Bourne rattles door]
Monsieur Bourne, there you are.
CONCIERGE: [In French]
Monsieur Bourne, I was wondering--
I haven't seen you.
Uh, here I am.
BOURNE: [In French]
I think I forgot my key.
[Church bells ring in distance]
Hello?
You sure this is all yours?
I guess.
[Beeping]
[Clanks]
This is my kitchen.
- Any clues?
- I think I'm in the shipping business.
So it's all coming back, huh?
Do you mind
if I use the bathroom?
- Uh, sure.
- Okay.
[Beeps, Dialing]
[Woman Speaking French]
Uh, yeah. Hello? Hello?
Yes, sir.
Hotel Regina, Paris.
How may I direct your call?
Yeah. You're in Paris?
Yes, sir.
I'm looking for
a, uh, guest there.
Uh, Jason Bourne.
One moment, please.
Thank you.
I'm afraid I have no one
by that name registered, sir.
Uh, okay. Uh, thank you.
Uh, wait. No, no, no.
Uh, are you there? Hello?
Sir?
Uh, can you check another,
uh, name for me, please?
Uh, bear with me one second.
Um...
uh, John Michael Kane.
Kane with a "K."
One moment, sir.
Thank you.
[Man]
You call about Monsieur Kane?
John Michael Kane?
Uh, yeah. That's right.
You are a friend of his?
Uh, uh-huh. Yep.
I have some very
bad news for you, sir.
I'm terribly sorry
to tell you this...
but Monsieur Kane
has passed away
almost two weeks ago.
There was an accident
on the motorway.
Apparently,
he was killed instantly.
Really. I'm terribly sorry
to be the one to tell you this.
When they came for his things,
people made note for us, you see?
- Who-Who came?
- His brother.
Did his, uh, brother leave
a number or a way to get
in touch with him?
I think not.
So I'm sorry...
[Water Running]
[Kreutz]
Uh, Jason?
There's no hot water.
It's freezing.
Uh, I'll go, uh, try
the water in the kitchen.
Why don't you just stay
in the bathroom? I'll-I'll
see if I can... get it hot.
Yeah, it's really
cold in here too.
The water is still cold.
Yeah, it's cold
in the, uh, kitchen too.
I got it running though.
So...
What?
Nothing.
- Are you okay?
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
What is it?
Something wrong?
[Machine Gun Fire]
Jason!
Open that! Open that!
Tell me what's inside. Who are you?
Who are you?
[Speaking French]
[Bourne Speaking French]
Oh, my God.
- [Bourne Speaking German]
- Ohh.
[Bourne]
Answer me! Who are you?
- He's got my picture.
- All right. Just... stop.
[Babbling, Indistinct]
No, no, no!
I don't... How...
Where did you get this?
Stay there! Stay there!
How did you get my picture?
Marie, stay there. Come on.
Where did you get this from?
How did you get...
Don't do this. I'll do this.
You stay there. Stay there.
[Grunts]
But he...
[Thud]
[Tires Screeching]
[People Screaming]
[Horns Honking]
Where are your shoes?
Get your shoes.
Sure. Yeah. Sure.
Uh, he went out the window.
Why would someone do that?
We can't stay here.
It's not safe.
Look, I can get us out of here,
but we got to go.
We got to go right now.
Okay. Look, uh, you could wait.
You could wait
for the cops. It's okay.
You just wait for them
to get here, but I can't.
I got to go.
[Siren Approaching]
Marie?
[Kreutz]
Ohh! Ohh!
Quiet. Quiet.
[Vomits]
- Don't look.
- [Siren Approaching]
[Dialing]
[Man's Voice] Code in.
Alpha 37509.
[Rings]
Yeah?
Hang on.
Bourne, he went to Paris.
He went to the apartment.
We got him? Tell me.
[Woman]
He killed our man.
What? In the apartment?
Yeah.
Well, you got to clean that up.
No, I can't clean it up.
There's a body
in the streets.
So?
There's police.
This is Paris.
Put up the scanners.
Get as much radio
information as you can.
Okay. You stay here. I'll go
find a place for this money.
I'll be back in ten minutes.
[Woman On P.A. Speaking French]
Hey. I told you
to stay in the car.
Jesus Christ.
I told you to stay in the car.
I needed a drink.
I didn't think you would
come back anyway.
You got to go to the cops.
Right now.
You got to go before
this gets any worse.
By myself?
It's gonna be okay.
Take my passport, okay?
You show this to them.
You have that picture.
You have the 20,000.
You tell them everything
that happened. Everything.
They're gonna believe you.
They have to believe you.
Marie, you can't just sit here.
It's not safe here.
Safe? This is from
inside the embassy.
Who can do this?
This is from yesterday.
I-I don't know.
How can they even know
that we're together?
Look, I'm trying to do
the right thing for you, okay? Just...
Try... How are you gonna
make this right...
by sending me there alone?
Do you think I want you
to go to the cops?
You think that's good for me?
You want to go, fine.
You go to the cops, I gotta run.
You tell them what happened.
I don't know what happened!
I don't know who this guy was!
I don't know about that picture!
I don't know who I am!
Look, I'm... You're acting like
I'm trying to burn you here.
- I'm just trying to do the right thing.
- Nobody does the right thing.
Look, I can't
run with you. I can't...
We run... I gotta live
like this. I gotta...
I don't even know
who I'm hiding from.
These people know who I am.
Now I gotta...
I gotta stay here.
I gotta figure this out.
So figure it out.
You take care of this car?
What do you mean?
Tires felt a little splashy
on the way over here.
It pulls a little to the right.
[Siren Approaching]
Last chance, Marie.
[Horn Honking]
[Siren]
So...
What?
Uh, we got a bump
coming up.
[Screaming]
[Horn Honking]
Turn your head away.
[Horns Honking]
- Ohh!
- [Yelling]
[Turns Engine Off]
You can never
come back to this car.
You understand?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. We're gonna clean it out,
and I'll wipe it down
and we walk away.
That's it. Okay.
Okay.
And I'll find a place
for us to rest,
and I gotta think.
Do you have a hat
or a scarf or something?
For my hair?
Yeah. Just until
we can change it.
Yeah. Sure. Okay.
Okay.
HOFFENMElN MORGUE - PARlS, FRANCE
Shh! Shush! Shh!
Hush up.
[Chattering]
Shh! Shh!
[Chattering Stops]
Monsieur Kane.
Ah, Monsieur Kane.
[Speaking French]
It's not him.
This man was not shot.
[Speaking French]
[Phone Dialing]
[Ringing]
[Man]
What do you have?
[Woman]
Wombosi went to the morgue.
He saw the body.
He didn't buy it.
Where is he now?
[Woman]
I told you I'm not staffed for this.
[Man] Where is he now?
Right now, where's Wombosi?
They were leaving the morgue.
They just left.
Sir, what do you
want to do?
[Beeping]
[Water Running]
[Turns Off Water]
I need to get that pile.
[Bag Thumps On Floor]
[Chattering,
Laughing In Distance]
Laughing Continues]
[Bourne]
Hey.
You've already
cleaned the room?
I wiped the whole place down
for fingerprints.
Can I walk around,
or is that gonna leave
any footprints?
You can... walk around.
It's no problem.
But we'll just keep track
of everything we touch.
I just think it's better
if we leave a room that we're
not gonna leave a trail.
Why? Where are we going?
I need to go to the hotel
where John Michael Kane stayed...
the Hotel Regina.
Um, if I was him...
then they're gonna have
some records.
We need that hotel bill.
Okay.
It gets slightly
complicated though.
Because you're dead.
Right.
[Turns On Faucet]
[Man] Sir, please.
[Wombosi]
They want war?
Then we will give them war.
If they want to kill me, they
better kill me the first time.
They better kill me dead.
- They better kill me in my sleep.
- Nykwana, listen to me.
We need these people.
It's hard enough getting
people we know to help us.
We need
to be careful.
We?
No, you.
You need to bring me back
that bastard Kane's head...
put it in front of this house
and show them what kind of war
we are fighting.
[Gunshots]
[Yells]
[Man Yelling]
[Men Yelling In Distance]
[Bourne Speaking, Indistinct]
I want a reference check
before we go.
Okay.
What's the pay phone number?
616-2468.
Exits?
There's three.
Service at the back,
um, side goes to the street
past the shops.
Front is the best.
If I think I'm being followed,
I walk out with the bag
over my right shoulder.
And if there's no taxi?
I keep on walking...
don't look back
until you make contact.
What?
We need this, right?
Okay.
[Thinking: Counting In German]
[Bourne's Voice]
I need distances.
You walk in, you pick a spot...
some midpoint in the lobby.
I want you to count
your steps to that spot
and then remember that number.
Because after I call you,
I can get you moving.
You understand?
I also need a head count
from the time you walk in
until you get to the desk.
How many hotel employees are there?
And obviously security.
And it might not be that
easy to see who they are.
I'll call you.
You give me the layout.
We'll take it from there.
[Line Ringing]
[Woman Speaking French]
Yes, the house phone in the lobby.
[Line Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
[Knocking On Glass]
What happened?
Did something go wrong?
I've got the records.
This guy at the front desk
was smiling at me.
I thought... all this trouble...
maybe it's easier to just ask for them.
Do you have the bill?
He made me a photocopy.
You just asked for it?
I said I was Mr. Kane's
personal assistant.
Oh.
[Laughs]
Okay. Good thinking.
Reschedule a meeting...
Sir, can I...
[Phone Ringing]
Wombosi was assassinated
in his house in the middle of Paris.
Yeah, we just heard.
It's him. It's Bourne.
We're almost positive.
He had an assignment.
He failed.
He obviously felt compelled
to finish the task.
Shit. Jesus.
We think he'll
come back in now.
I mean, it's routine.
It's like behavioral software.
He's following a protocol.
Now that he's completed the mission,
we think he'll come back in.
They always do.
When?
How long
till he checks in?
Twenty-four hours.
Twenty-four hours?
Yeah. It's usually
something like that.
Then what?
I told you we'd clean this up.
It will be clean.
[Bourne's Voice]
I understand you're a dive shop,
but where are you located?
Marseilles?
[Dialing Phone]
[Police Radio, Distorted]
[Man Speaking French, Distorted]
[Man Continues]
[Man Speaking French]
What specifically
does your company supply?
I am sorry.
What did you say
your name was, monsieur?
[Phone: Disconnect Signal]
[Chattering In French]
COP: [ln French]
You've been here for three hours
and you still can't find a print?
[Knocking]
What?
The Paris police
found the vehicle.
[Electronic Beeping]
[Beeps]
[Man] You've reached the office
of Simon Rawlins...
at Alliance Securite,
Maritime Division.
The Paris office hours
are from 8:00 a.m. To 5:00 p.m.
I got a lead in Paris.
The rest were
Marseilles and...
In Paris it's what?
Uh, Alliance Securite.
Simon Rawlins. I got a machine.
[Bell Dings]
[Doors Open]
[Phones Ringing]
[Chattering]
Monsieur.
[Woman Continues In French]
[Woman #2]
Mr. Kane?
[Ringing Continues]
Mr. Kane.
How are you?
I'm good. I'm good.
Oh, Mr. Kane.
Come right in.
Please, have a seat.
Thank you.
So, this is
the Palmer Johnson tri-deck.
I'm assuming you're still in the market.
It's still the same vessel.
Yes.
[Chattering]
[Chattering In French]
[Chattering Continues]
So I'm Kane.
Hey.
I just had
a meeting as Kane.
They said...
No. I'm definitely Kane.
I just had a meeting as Kane.
And he knew me as Kane.
So I'm definitely Bourne.
I'm also definitely Kane.
This is all just boats.
I got blueprints and cameras.
I just found
John Michael Kane's body.
In a morgue here in Paris.
But if you are John Michael Kane,
whose body do they have?
##[Woman On Radio,
Singing In French]
What was name again?
[Bourne]
Kane.
John Michael Kane.
[Papers Shuffling]
##[Singing Continues]
Kane.
It's number 121.
- I want to see the body.
- Our boss could come back.
I'm not supposed to do that.
Come on.
Is this it?
Wh-Where is he?
I... I don't know where.
[ln French]
What's going on?
This guy has come to see the American.
But the body has disappeared.
They came yesterday evening...his brother.
He's not in the register.
Who are you?
What's going on here?
Where's the body?
I said someone came last night.
I know.
Where'd they take the body?
Look, this is not
a carnival, okay?
People call,
they make an appointment
and they follow the rules.
Everyone signs in and out.
This is a serious place...
serious work.
It's not just to come in
whenever you like!
You're right. We didn't sign in.
Get the hell out of here.
Fine, fine.
I'm just gonna go sign in.
Go.
##[Woman On Radio,
Singing In French]
Is this it?
This is it, right?
You can't take the book.
It's okay.
There's a pencil in here.
Honey, why don't you
go wait outside?
Oh, here it is.
We cannot have...
Excuse me.
Jason, what just
happened in there?
What are you looking for?
Nykwana Wombosi.
Wombosi went to the morgue
to visit Kane.
See?
So?
So, look. He's in
the Alliance Securite
brochure. Same guy.
This guy knows.
[Chattering]
[Siren Wailing]
[Chattering Continues]
[Woman Yelling
In Foreign Language]
[Yelling Continues]
[Man On Police Radio,
Speaking French]
[Woman Wailing]
[Kreutz Mumbling]
My French sucks. I can't...
It says something
about a boat or...
I don't understand.
What does it say? You read it.
Huh? Tell me. Wha...
It says that three weeks
before he was killed...
Mr. Wombosi told police that
a man came on to his yacht...
five miles off the coast of Marseilles
and tried to kill him.
It says that he chased
the man off the boat
and shot him twice in the back.
It says I'm an assassin.
[Papers Rustling]
[Siren Wailing]
[Vehicle Approaching]
[ln French]
Stop the car.
But no...you said Rue de l...
we're almost there.
Just right here, this is good.
l said stop.
What's going on?
[Tires Skid]
Well...what's going on?
[Kreutz]
What are you doing?
[Bourne]
Go. Go.
You gave me too much.
We're blown.
Come on.
Blown? What is "blown"?
Monsieur...your change, your change.
Sir, please...You can't stay here...
You have to leave.
Ow.
Keep walking.
What do you think
they're doing there?
They're onto the hotel.
No, you don't know that.
Trust me.
Just keep walking.
[Speaking French]
[Whistle Blowing]
[Siren Wailing]
[Chattering In French]
[Chattering Continues]
[Speaking French]
Are you crazy?
What are you doing now?
Jason!
This. This is "blown."
[Siren Wailing In Distance]
Marie.
Get away.
Marie, stop.
Get away from me.
Stop.
What are you gonna do,
kill me?
Is that what's next?
Listen... Stay calm.
Stay calm.
Whatever we do,
we have to do it together.
We?
The only thing we had
in common was that neither
of us knew who you were.
We're past that now.
Marie, listen to me!
The police will find us,
and the people who took
that picture in the embassy...
the people who killed Wombosi...
they are gonna kill us.
The people who you work for.
I will take you
wherever you need to go.
I will take you there.
I will leave you there.
You can do whatever you want.
You never have to see me again.
But not here.
If we stay here, we die.
[Man Coughing]
Great police work.
Really brilliant.
Why don't they just
hang out a banner that says
"Don't come back"?
Jesus Christ.
What is the French word
for stakeout, huh?
Hmm.
Okay. This was 16 minutes ago.
This is our starting point.
They can't fly.
Trains are risky. Nicky?
[On Speakerphone] Yes.
I need to know everything
Paris's finest is doing on this.
I'm on it.
[Man's Voice]
You said 24 hours,
and he's not back.
[Man #2's Voice]
No. We've got a good idea
where he is.
[Man #1's Voice]
You've got a black ops agent
who's off the reservation.
He's trashed an American consulate.
He's on the run in Europe.
You don't know why.
I've gotta stand before an
oversight committee. What am I
gonna tell 'em about Treadstone?
You're worried about
a budget meeting?
We don't take care of this,
we don't make it to the men's room.
Is that clear enough for you?
We will burn for this.
We will both of us burn.
I want two teams.
Daryl, Ray, stay on the grids.
Brian, Harris, Steve...
I want to work on this girl.
Where do we stand with
this residency pattern?
- Uh, we started it.
- Get it out.
[Line Ringing]
[Truck Passing]
[Man] We cross-referenced
numbers from the grandmother
and the stepbrother.
Whenever we found convergence,
we back-checked those numbers
and ran a search merge...
with any other data we had on her,
which wasn't much, but...
These pins. These are
all the places we think she's
lived in the last six years.
One, two, three, four, five.
That's our pool.
No answer.
How many times did you
let it ring?
Look, if you don't
wanna go, I'll hitch.
I said I'd take you.
[Man]
Those are the targets.
Beg, borrow, hack, tap, bypass...
I don't care what you do.
I want to know everything
you can tell me about what's
going on at those locations.
How do you know
he still owns this?
Eamon always had money.
He would never sell this.
[Grunts]
Scheiﬂe.
Marie.
What?
We gotta go.
Oh, Scheiﬂe.
I thought...
[Car Approaching]
[Car Door Opens]
Oh, shit. That's Eamon.
I'll talk to him.
We're leaving.
Eamon. Hey.
Surprise. It's me... Marie.
Wow, uh, God...
There's a really good
reason for this.
There bloody well better be.
[Girl] Daddy!
Hang on. Just hang on.
I had no idea
you would be here.
Well, why would I be here?
It's only my bloody house, right?
Yeah.
[Sighs]
Did she get you into this?
It was just
gonna be for a day.
Daddy, Alan
has to go to pee.
All right. Come on.
Get out of the car.
[Barking]
Come on, Alan.
[Groans]
I'm sorry. I thought it was...
would be okay.
But I guess I was wrong.
Let's find Mummy.
Mummy is away
for two days, thank God.
[Barking]
You've got yourself
all tied up. Okay.
[Girl Yelling]
What's he do for a living?
He used to be in shipping.
Uh-huh.
Is he good for you?
Are you happy?
You know me.
I try too hard.
[Sighs]
Here you go.
Sleep well.
Good night.
I'll sleep on the floor.
[Door Closes]
This was when?
11:45 a.m.
Which is definitely within
the driving range of Paris.
- The call came from a highway
rest stop, southbound side.
- What's this yellow pin?
She spent a couple of months
there in 1997.
Closest town is Riome.
We took her family's
phone records and collated
the international calls.
They were in Paris
at 2:00 a.m.
They can't fly.
Train's too dangerous.
He knows better than to go
anywhere we might track him.
So this is our best guess.
[Sighs]
[Whispering]
What are you doing here?
[Whispering] The kids...
I was worried.
You're gonna wake them up.
We gotta...
I don't wanna know
who I am anymore.
Shh.
I don't care.
I don't wanna know.
Come on. We'll...
Everything I found out,
I wanna forget.
It's okay.
I don't care who I am
or what I did.
It's okay.
We have this money.
We can hide.
Could we do that?
Is there any chance
you can do that?
I don't know.
Come on.
[Girl]
Guy. Guy.
Here, boy.
[Girl]
Here, boy. Here, boy.
Morning.
Christ, you're up early.
Bless you for making coffee.
[Girl Chattering In Distance]
One night.
You weren't kidding.
[Door Opening]
For a change.
[Door Closes]
He's not there either.
[Eamon]
You looked by the car?
He's not anywhere.
All right.
Let me get dressed.
Who?
[Eamon Sighs]
Bloody dog's gone missing.
Does that happen a lot?
That mutt miss his breakfast?
Not a chance.
It's always something, right?
Get in the basement.
What?
- Get everyone in the basement.
- What the hell are you talking about?
We're in danger.
Your family's in danger.
I don't have time to explain.
- What the...
- Eamon, you should go.
What the hell have you done?
It's not her. It's me.
You need to get out of sight
and in the basement
as quick as you can.
Daddy.
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
The phone is dead.
Yeah.
Jason, who's out there?
Who is it?
[Speaking German]
Scheiﬂe. Scheiﬂe.
What are you doing?
We should never have
come here. I... These children...
That's not gonna happen.
- [Snaps Shotgun Shut]
- [No Audible Dialogue]
[Gunshots]
[Bird Cawing]
[Birds Twittering]
[Wings Flapping]
[Twittering Continues]
[Cawing]
[Cawing Continues]
- [Gunshot]
- [Groaning]
[Grunting]
[Grunting Continues]
[Groans]
- [Gunshot]
- [Yells]
[Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
Where is it?
Where's the weapon?
[Grunting]
Who else is out here?
How many you got with you?
I'm not gonna ask you again.
I work alone, like you.
We always work alone.
What do you mean?
Who are you? Bonn?
Paris?
Treadstone... both of us.
Treadstone?
Which one?
Paris. I live in Paris.
Do you still get the headaches?
Yeah.
I get such bad headaches.
You know at night
when you're driving a car?
Maybe it's something to do
with the headlights.
What is Treadstone?
Treadstone...
said, "Pioze..."
They said, "Go to Paris."
Is Treadstone in Paris?
[Groaning]
Look at this.
Look at what
they make you give.
[Groans]
[Leaves Rustling]
All right. All right.
Right, get in the front,
put your belt on.
We're just gonna
put you in the back.
Get in the front, Polly.
I'm not waiting, Marie.
One minute, Eamon.
I'm not waiting!
Please!
[Car Door Closes]
Take it.
[Engine Starts]
I took out 30 grand.
The rest is yours.
- That's it?
- That's all I got.
No, that's not what I meant.
This is not gonna stop, Marie.
You gotta get out now,
away from me.
You gotta get out.
You gotta start running.
You get low. You stay low.
No more friends. Nothing familiar.
There's enough in there
for you to make a life.
[Engine Revving]
Any life.
[Eamon]
I'm out of here, Marie.
Hey.
Get in the car.
You gotta go.
What are you gonna do?
I'll end it. Go ahead.
Please.
[Door Closes]
[Vehicle Pulls Away]
[Beeps]
[Line Ringing]
[Phone Ringing]
[Electronic Beep]
[High-Speed Dialing]
[Ringing]
[Snapping Fingers]
Code in, please.
Code in.
[Speakerphone Feedback]
[On Speakerphone]
Code in.
[Bourne]
Who is this?
Who the hell are you?
[Bourne]
The man you sent is dead.
So whoever this is,
you better start talking.
[Man]
Hello, Jason.
So what are we into now?
Come on. It only
goes two ways, Jason.
Come in and let us make this right,
or we're gonna keep going
until we're satisfied.
You mean until you kill me.
I can't fix this if I don't know
what the problem is.
So tell me what we're into,
and I'll do the best I can.
Why don't you talk
to Marie, Jason?
Let's ask Marie
what she wants to do.
I don't think she gives a shit.
She's dead.
I'm sorry to hear that.
How did that happen?
She was slowing me down.
Jason, listen.
All we've been doing right from...
Enough. Enough.
5:30 p.m. Paris.
Today. Pont Neuf.
You come alone.
You walk to the middle
of that bridge.
You take off your jacket.
Face east.
I'll redial this number.
Jason, wait.
First flight out.
Tell Nicky I'll call from the car.
Tell her to find Picot now. Go.
[High-Speed Dialing]
[Line Ringing]
So... what are we gonna do?
I told you I'd clean this up.
That's what I'm doing.
Can you really bring him in?
I think we're past that, don't you?
Do you have a better idea?
You've given me nothing but
a trail of collateral damage.
I don't think
I could do much worse.
Why don't you go upstairs
and book a conference room?
Maybe you can
talk him to death.
[Man On Earphone]
The bus. The tour bus.
[Man #2 On Earphone]
Negative.
[Man #1]
Position one.
[Man #3] Negative.
[Man #1]
Position two.
[Man #4] Negative.
[Static On Earphone]
[Speaking French]
[Man On Earphone,
Speaking French]
[Man #1]
Position three... motorcycle.
[Continues In French]
[Man #5]
Negative.
[Earphone Static]
[Cell Phone Rings]
En position.
- Jason?
- I told you to come alone.
I guess that was
too complicated.
So try this... I'm gone.
[Beeps]
[Cell Phone Beeps]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Man]
Get Nicky on the phone.
[Dialing]
[Line Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
[Buzzing]
Yeah.
[Man] How long
does it take to wipe the room
down and get it moved?
- Get rid of everything?
- [Man] Yeah.
[Nicky]
Two to three hours.
All right. Get started.
[Slow Electronic Beeping]
Listen, no breaks.
Two men outside, one in the lobby
and keep your eyes open.
[Beeping Quickly]
- [Man] Keep the truck?
- Keep the truck. I'm gonna
close this unit down.
We'll move the gear
in the truck.
They were covering Spain,
Malta, Morocco. Yes, all
local police radio traffic.
[Nicky] No. For northern Europe
we need an authorized directive.
Yeah. Okay. They're on it.
We'll have a satellite download
in 30 minutes.
[Beeping Slowly]
[Electronic Beeps]
[Street Cleaner Approaching]
[Car Alarm]
[All Car Alarms Going Off]
[Alarms Continue]
[Speaking French]
[Alarms Stop]
[Typing]
Where's your field box?
[Electronic Beeping]
[Beeping Continues]
[Typing]
- Where's your field box?
- It's right there.
- [Beeping Continues]
- [Nicky]
The system's gone haywire.
That's this window right here.
Dining room window?
[Cocks Gun]
I don't get...
[Phone Clattering In Cradle]
[Beeping Continues]
Dead.
The phones are dead.
[Electricity Powering Down]
It's Bourne, isn't it?
Just quiet.
[Lamp Rattles]
You move, you die.
- Bourne.
- Gun down.
In there.
Okay, so what do you want?
[Groans]
Treadstone.
You better take a look around.
There's not much left.
Are you Treadstone?
Am I Treadstone? Me?
What the hell
are you talking about?
[Man]
He's lost it.
You better start filling in
the blanks, 'cause I thought
we were on the same side.
Whose side is that?
You don't know what you're
doing, do you, Jason?
- You don't have a goddamn clue.
- Who am I?
You're U.S. Government property.
You're a malfunctioning,
$30 million weapon.
You're a total
goddamn catastrophe.
By God, you're gonna
tell me how this happened.
Why are you trying to kill me?
- What happened in Marseilles?
- Why are you try...
You sent me to kill Wombosi.
Kill Wombosi?
We can do that anytime we want.
I can send Nicky to do that,
for Christ's sake.
Mr. Wombosi was supposed to
be dead three weeks ago.
He was supposed to have
died in a way where the only
possible explanation was...
that he'd been murdered
by a member of his own
entourage.
I don't send you to kill.
I send you to be invisible.
I send you
because you don't exist.
I want to know what
happened in Marseilles.
I don't remember
what happened in Marseilles.
Bullshit! This is
unacceptable, Soldier.
You hear me? You failed.
Unacceptable?
You failed! You failed,
and you're gonna tell me why.
I can't tell you. I don't re...
You brought
John Michael Kane to life.
You put together
a meeting with Wombosi.
You found the security company.
You broke into the office.
You're the one who picked
the yacht as the strike point.
You picked the boat.
You picked the day.
You tracked the crew,
the food, the fuel.
You told us where.
You told us when.
[Girl Giggling]
You hid out
on that boat five days.
You were in, Jason.
You were in. It was over.
[Girl Giggling In Distance]
[Bourne Breathing Heavily]
[Gunshot]
No, you do remember.
Don't you?
I don't wanna do this anymore.
I don't think that's
a decision you can make.
[Grunts]
[Groans]
Jason Bourne is dead.
Do you hear me?
He drowned two weeks ago.
You're gonna go tell 'em
that Jason Bourne is dead.
Do you understand?
Where are you gonna go?
[Groans]
I swear to God, if I even
feel somebody behind me...
there is no measure to how fast
and how hard I will bring this
fight to your doorstep.
I'm on my own side now.
[Earphone Feedback]
[Wood Creaking]
[Grunting]
[Groaning]
[Gunshot]
- [Shell Casings Rattling On Floor]
- [Door Opens]
[Man Speaking French]
[Woman Speaking French]
[Grunts]
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Muffled Gunshot]
It's done.
Shut it down.
[Typing]
[Man] The Treadstone Project
has already been terminated.
It was designed primarily as
a sort of advanced game program.
We'd hoped it might build
into a good training platform...
but, quite honestly,
for a strictly theoretical exercise...
the cost-benefit ratio
was just too high.
It's all but decommissioned
at this point.
All right.
What's next?
Okay.
This is... Black Briar.
Black Briar is a joint D.O.D.
Communications program...
that we really feel
has good traction.
It's got legs.
It'll run and run.
It combines elements of...
[Fading]
This your store?
Yeah.
It's nice.
It's a little hard to find, but...
Think I could rent a scooter?
You have I. D?
Not really.
##[Techno]
#Extreme ways are back again #
#Extreme places I didn't know #
#I broke everything new again #
#Everything that I'd owned #
#I threw it out the windows
came along #
#Extreme ways I know will
part the colors of my sea #
#Perfect color me #
#Extreme ways that help me #
# They help me out late at night #
#Extreme places I had gone #
#But never seen any light #
#Dirty basements, dirty noise #
#Dirty places coming through #
#Extreme worlds alone #
#Did you ever like it planned #
#I would stand in line for this #
# There's always room in life for this #
# Oh, baby #
# Then it fell apart #
#Fell apart #
# Oh, baby #
# Then it fell apart #
#It fell apart #
# Oh, baby #
# Then it fell apart #
#It fell apart #
# Oh, baby #
# Oh, baby
Like it always does #
#Always does #
#Extreme songs that told me #
# They helped me down every night #
#I didn't have much to say #
#I didn't get above the light #
#I closed my eyes and closed myself #
#And closed my world
and never opened up to anything #
# That could get me along #
#I had to close down everything #
#I had to close down my mind #
# Too many things to cover me #
# Too much can make me blind #
#I've seen so much in so many places #
#So many heartaches, so many faces #
#So many dirty things #
# You couldn't even believe #
#I would stand in line for this #
#It's always good in life for this #
# Oh, baby #
# Then it fell apart #
#It fell apart #
# Oh, baby #
# Then it fell apart #
#It fell apart #
# Oh, baby #
# Then it fell apart #
#It fell apart #
# Oh, baby #
# Oh, baby
Like it always does #
#Always does ##