[Engine dies]
What the hell?
Goddamn
son of a bitch...
Goddamn son of a...
What the hell?
Hey, my turn!
Me.
Come on.
Hey, what's wrong
with this picture?
Nice night
for a walk, eh?
for a walk.
Washday tomorrow.
Nothing clean,
right?
Nothing clean. Right.
I think this guy's a couple
cans short of a 6-pack.
Your clothes.
Give them to me.
Now.
Fuck you, asshole!
Uhh!
[Siren]
Man: Hey, sugar,
how about it?
[Slurred] I don't have to
put up with that bullshit, man.
She's always after me.
I don't...I don't...
Uhh! Uhh...
Hey, buddy.
Did you just see
a real bright light?
Policeman:
He the guy?
Hold it right there!
He's rabbiting.
Hey! I said hold it!
Go!
That son of a bitch
took my pants!
[Siren]
What day is it?
The date!
The 12th...Of may.
Thursday.
What year?!
What?
[Siren]
He's got my gun!
Let's go!
[Siren]
[Police radio transmitting]
Police radio: Uh, 3831,
they lost the suspect.
[Siren]
[Turning pages]
Guard it for me,
big buns.
Hi.
Hi. I'm late.
So am I.
[Punch]
[Engine starts]
I'm in it.
So am I.
Honey, could I have
that coffee now, please?
Yes, sir.
Ok, who gets
the burly beef?
Uh, I ordered
barbecued beef.
I think that's mine,
but I didn't order fries.
Woman: He gets
the barbecued beef.
Mine's the chili
beef deluxe.
Ok, who gets
the burly beef?
Woman: Miss, we're
ready to order now.
Yes, ma'am.
[Drink spills]
Aah!
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Oh, lord.
This isn't real
leather, is it?
This special sucks.
Nice going, kid.
Ought to
give you the tip.
Look at it this way--
in 100 years,
who's going to care?
The 12-gauge
auto-loader.
That's Italian.
You can go pump
or auto.
The .45 long slide,
with laser sighting.
These are brand-new.
We just got them in.
That's a good gun.
Just touch the trigger,
the beam comes on,
and you put the red dot
where you want
the bullet to go.
You can't miss.
Anything else?
A phased plasma rifle
in the 40-watt range.
Just what you see, pal.
The uzi 9mm.
You know your weapons,
buddy.
Any one of these is
ideal for home defense.
So, uh...
Which will it be?
All.
I may close early today.
There's a 15-day wait
on the handguns,
but the rifles
you can take now.
You can't do that.
Wrong.
[Cocks rifle]
Man: Hi, baby.
Yeah, yeah, it's me.
Listen, I need you
to come pick me up.
My bike just broke down.
I don't care what you're doing.
Come and get me. What the--
hey, man, you got
a serious attitude problem.
[Dog barking]
Sarah Connor?
Yes?
I'm on my break, Chuck.
Carla's got my station.
Sarah, come here!
It's about you.
I mean, sort of.
It's so incredible.
You're not gonna believe this.
Sit down. You are
going to love this.
Shh!
What?
...has been compiled
from several witnesses.
Once again, Sarah Connor,
35, mother of 2,
brutally shot to death
in her home this afternoon.
You're dead, honey.
In other
late-breaking news,
teamster representatives
have issued a statement...
[Car engine starts]
[Radio plays]
[Gunfire]
Uhh! Uhh!
Aah!
Radio: Yes, friends,
if you're into stereo
and you're into sound,
for the greatest
sound around you,
come to Bob's stereo
at 25000 sepulveda boulevard.
Yes, we've got woofers,
tweeters,
the newest in digital audio
and compact laser discs.
We've got
graphic equalizers
and sound balancers that
adjust the sound to fit--
♪ in love again
♪ drivin' on
the inside shoulder ♪
Sorry.
♪ Won't be enough for you
to smooth things over ♪
♪ hang on...
[Telephone rings]
[Ring]
Hello.
First, I'm gonna rip
the buttons off your blouse,
one by one,
and then run my tongue
down your neck
to your bare,
gleaming breasts,
and then slowly,
slowly
pull your jeans off...
Inch by inch.
Ha!
Ginger, it's Matt!
...and lick your belly
in circles
further and further down,
and then pull your panties off
with my teeth.
Who is this?
I--I, uh...Sarah?
Ha ha!
Oh, Jesus. I'm sorry.
I thought you were...
Can I talk
to ginger, please?
Sure, bunky.
♪ Ow, o-oo-ooh
it's the creep.
Hello.
First, I'm gonna rip
the buttons off your blouse,
one by one...
Grr!
You fuckin' pigs!
Wait till I get
my hands on you!
Get off of me!
Sit down, fella.
Ed.
What do you got?
Dead girl.
I can see that.
Sarah Ann Connor,
secretary, 35,
shot 6 times
at less than 10 feet.
Large caliber weapon.
You know, these work.
What's this?
Dead girl 2,
sent over from
valley division
this afternoon.
I'm sure there's a point
to all of this.
Look at the name, ed.
Sarah Louise...Connor.
Is this right?
You're kidding me.
The press is going to be
short-stroking it
all over the place.
A one-day
pattern killer.
I hate
the weird ones.
So...
Better than
mortal man deserves.
Ginger,
have you seen pugsley?
No, not lately.
Did you check messages?
Uh-uh.
I thought you did.
[Answering machine rewinds]
[Beep]
Hi, Sarah,
this is your mom...
There you are,
young man.
You mind
your mother.
...so call me back,
will you, dear? Uh, bye.
[Beep]
Hi, Sarah.
Dan moorski.
Uh, something's come up,
and it looks like I won't
be able to make it tonight.
Just can't get out of it.
Look, I'm really sorry.
I'll make it up to you.
Call you in a day or so, ok?
Sorry. Bye.
Tch. That bum. So what
if he has a Porsche?
He can't
treat you like this.
It's Friday night,
for Christ's sake!
I'll live.
I'll break his kneecaps.
Well...Pugsley
still loves me,
don't you, baby?
God. It's disgusting.
I'm gonna go to a movie,
kiddo.
Ok.
You and Matt
have a good time.
We will. You, too.
Ok.
[Gasps]
Damn it, Matt!
[Engine starts]
Oh, shit.
Lieutenant, are you aware
that these 2 killings
occurred in the same order
as their listings
in the phone book?
Now, what can I tell you guys?
No comment.
But, lieutenant,
we've got 2 murders--
that coffee's
2 hours cold.
Mm-hmm.
I put a cigarette
out in it.
Did you reach
the next girl yet?
No. I keep getting
an answering machine.
Send a unit.
I sent a unit. There's
no answer at the door,
and the apartment
manager's not home.
Call her.
I just called her.
Call her again.
Give me a cigarette.
[Dialing]
[Ring]
Ginger: Hi there.
Ha ha ha. Fooled you.
You're talking to a machine,
but don't be shy, it's ok.
[Music playing]
[Turns up volume]
[Answering machine beeps]
Same shit.
I can hear it now.
He's going to be called
the goddamn "phone book killer."
I hate
these press cases,
especially the weird
press cases.
Where you going?
To make a statement.
Maybe make these jackals
work for us for a change.
If I can get on the tube
by 11:00,
maybe she'll call us.
Well...
How do I look?
Like shit, boss.
Your mama.
Lieutenant!
This just in.
Police have announced
the name of the victim
in the second of 2
execution-style murders
which took place today.
Incredibly, the names
of the 2 victims
are virtually identical.
2 hours ago, 35-year-old
Sarah Ann Connor
was pronounced dead at the scene
in her Santa Monica apartment...
Can we change this?
Sure.
Sarah Louise Connor
was slain...
Sarah: Don't touch it!
...in her home.
Now, police
are refusing to speculate
on the apparent similarity
between these
shooting deaths,
and no other connection
between the 2 victims
has been established
as of yet.
Of course, we'll have more
on this late-breaking story
as it comes in.
A spectacular fire
fueled by solvents, oils,
and other flammable liquids
swept through an oil company
on north spring street
just northeast of Chinatown
Wednesday night...
[Loud rock music plays]
♪ On the run,
I'm a moving target ♪
♪ on the town,
it's hit-and-run... ♪
♪ caught in a photoplay
hey, you got a phone?
It's in the back!
Hey! 4.50.
♪ Photoplay
[singing continues
indistinctly]
You have reached
the Los Angeles police
department emergency number.
All our lines are busy.
If you need a police car
sent out to you,
please stay on the line.
Police radio: 2-11 in progress
at Bob's liquor,
corner of third and Cameron.
[Turns music on]
♪ Intimacy
♪ intimacy
♪ ya ya ya ya
♪ ya ya ya ya...
♪ I've got to...
Aah!
Pugsley, shoo!
Go on.
I'm going to make a belt
out of you.
Whoa!
Don't make me
bust you up, man!
♪ Intimacy
♪ ah yah
♪ ...is some intimacy
♪ ya ya ya ya
uhh!
Aaahh!
Oh...
[Crying]
[Ring]
Ginger: Hi there.
Ha ha ha. Fooled you.
You're talking to a machine,
but don't be shy, it's ok.
Machines need love, too,
so talk to it,
and ginger, that's me,
or Sarah will get back to you.
Wait for the beep.
[Beep]
Ginger,
this is Sarah!
Pick up
if you're there!
I'm at this place
on pico boulevard
called technoir.
I'm really scared.
I think that there's
somebody's after me.
Uh, I hope that you
play this back soon.
I need you and Matt
to come and pick me up
as soon as possible.
The police keep
transferring me around.
I'm gonna give them
another try.
The number here
is 555-9175.
Call me, kiddo.
I need your help.
Detective:
It's her.
Sarah Connor? It's
lieutenant Traxler.
Look, lieutenant,
don't put me on hold
and don't transfer me
to another department!
Don't worry. I won't.
Now, just relax.
Can you tell me
where you are?
I'm in this bar
called technoir.
Yeah, I know. It's on pico.
Are you all right?
Yeah, but I don't
want to leave.
I think there's a guy
following me.
All right, now,
listen, miss Connor,
now, listen carefully,
you're in a public place,
so you'll be safe
till we get there,
but stay visible.
Don't go outside
or even to the rest room.
I'll have a car there
in a hot minute.
Ok.
♪Ohh♪
♪ I'm taken, and you'll
never let me go ♪
♪ I'm your prisoner
♪ I feel the heat
of your desire ♪
♪ touch that pistol, fire
♪ you've got me burnin'
hey,
that guy didn't pay.
[Crack]
♪ You've got me burnin'
♪ you've got me burnin'
♪ in the third degree
[clattering on floor]
♪ Can't stop,
my body's achin' ♪
[Singing continues
indistinctly]
♪ You've got me burnin'
♪ you've got me burnin'
♪ in the third degree
♪ you've got me burnin'...
[Crowd screaming]
Aah!
Come with me
if you want to live.
Come on!
Aah!
This is 1-l19.
I got a hit-and-run felony.
Suspect vehicle--
late model gray Ford,
headed westbound on 7th.
He's really moving,
punching lights all the way.
I'm going to need
an ambulance
at 7th and Broadway
right now.
Hold it!
Aah!
Dispatcher: All units watch
for a late-model gray Ford,
last seen westbound
on 7th and Broadway.
Hold on.
Are you injured?
Are you shot?
No!
Do exactly
what I say.
Exactly.
Don't move
unless I say.
Don't make a sound
Do you understand?
Do you understand?!
Yes! Yes!
Please, don't hurt me.
[Honks horn]
I'm here to
help you.
I'm Reese,
sergeant techcom,
bn38416,
assigned
to protect you.
You've been targeted
for termination.
Police dispatcher:
Attempt to intercept, 1-l19.
[Imitating policeman]
This is 1-l19.
Westbound on olympic
approaching overland.
This is a mistake.
I didn't do anything.
No, but you will.
It's very important
that you live.
This isn't true.
How could that man
just get up after you--
he's not a man.
A machine.
A Terminator.
A cyberdine
systems model 101.
A machine?
Like a robot?
Not a robot. A cyborg.
A cybernetic organism.
No. He was bleeding.
Just a second.
Get your head down!
All right, listen.
The Terminator's
an infiltration unit--
part man, part machine.
Underneath,
it's a hyperalloy
combat chassis--
microprocessor
controlled,
fully armored,
very tough.
But outside, it's
living human tissue.
Flesh, skin, hair, blood--
grown for the cyborgs.
Look, Reese, I don't know
what you want from me--
pay attention!
I got to ditch
this car.
The 600 series
had rubber skin.
We spotted them easy.
But these are new.
They look human--
sweat, bad breath,
everything.
Very hard to spot.
I had to wait
till he moved on you
before I could zero him.
Look...
I am not stupid,
you know.
They cannot make things
like that yet.
Not yet.
Not for about 40 years.
Are you saying
it's from the future?
One possible future.
From your point
of view--
I don't know
tech stuff.
Then you're from the future,
too, is that right?
Right.
Cyborgs don't feel pain.
I do.
Don't do that again.
Just let me go.
Listen!
And understand.
That Terminator
is out there.
It can't
be bargained with.
be reasoned with.
It doesn't feel pity
or remorse
or fear.
And it absolutely
will not stop.
Ever!
Until you are dead.
Can you stop it?
I don't know.
With these weapons,
Police radio:
All units. All units.
Gray Ford suspect
vehicle's been found
in a parking structure
at 4th and beaudry.
Reese.
Why me?
Why does it want me?
There was
a nuclear war...
A few years
from now.
All this...
This whole place.
Everything.
It's gone.
Just gone.
There
were survivors.
Here.
There.
Nobody even knew
who started it.
It was
the machines, Sarah.
I don't understand.
Defense network
computers.
New...
Powerful...
Hooked
into everything.
Trusted
to run it all.
They say
it got smart--
a new order
of intelligence.
Then it saw all
people as a threat,
not just the ones
on the other side.
Decided our fate
in a microsecond--
extermination.
Did you see this war?
[Tires screech]
No.
I grew up
after it...
In the ruins.
Starving...
Hiding from hks.
Hks?
Hunter-killers.
Patrol machines built
in automated factories.
Most of us
were rounded up,
put in camps
for orderly disposal.
This was burned in
by laser scanner.
Some of us
were kept alive...
To work...
Loading bodies.
The disposal units
ran night and day.
We were that close
to going out forever.
There was one man
who taught us to fight,
to storm the wire
of the camps,
to smash those metal
motherfuckers into junk.
He turned it around.
He brought us
back from the brink.
His name is Connor.
John Connor.
Your son, Sarah.
Your unborn son.
[Engine won't turn over]
[Engine starts]
[Gunshot]
Drive!
Reese!
No, Reese! No! No!
No! They'll kill you.
Policeman:
You in the Cadillac!
Let me see
your hands now!
Get out of the car!
Drop to your knees!
Out of the car.
Drop to the ground.
Sarah...
Sarah, try to drink
some of this.
Are you sure it's them?
Maybe I should look
at the bodies.
No. They've
been identified,
and there's
no doubt.
Oh, God.
God!
Ginger!
Sarah.
Sarah, this is Dr. Silberman.
Hi, Sarah.
I want you to tell him
everything
that Reese told you.
Do you feel up to that?
Yeah. I guess so.
You're a doctor?
Criminal
psychologist.
Is Reese crazy?
Well, that's what
we're gonna find out.
[Distant siren]
[Whirring]
So, you're a soldier,
fighting for whom?
With the 132nd,
under Perry.
From 21 to 27.
That's the year 2027?
That's right.
And I was assigned...
This is
fucking great.
...the last 2 years
under John Connor.
Who was the enemy again?
A computer defense system
built for--
[beep beep beep]
Oh, damn. Sorry.
Built for sac-NORAD
by cyberdine systems.
I see.
And this, uh, computer
thinks it can win
by killing the mother
of its enemy,
killing him, in effect,
before
he's even conceived,
a sort of
retroactive abortion?
That guy Silberman
cracks me up.
Last week, he had this guy
in here that burned his Afghan.
He screwed it first,
then he set it on fire.
Hey, shut up.
Why didn't the computer
just kill Connor then?
Why this elaborate scheme
with the Terminator?
It had no choice.
Their defense grid
was smashed.
We'd won.
Taking out Connor then
would make no difference.
Skynet had to wipe out
his entire existence.
Is that when you
captured the lab complex
and found that--
uh, what is it called?
The time displacement
equipment?
That's right. The Terminator
had already gone through.
Connor sent me to intercept,
and they blew the whole place.
How are you
supposed get back?
I can't.
Nobody goes home.
Nobody else comes through.
It's just him...And me.
[Cocks rifle]
Why didn't you
bring any weapons,
something
more advanced?
Don't you have
ray guns?
Ray guns.
Show me a piece of
future technology.
You go naked.
Something about the field
generated by a living organism.
Nothing dead will go.
Why?
I didn't build
the fucking thing!
Ok, ok.
But this...
[Sighs] Cyborg,
if it's metal--
surrounded
by living tissue!
Oh. Right,
right--
this is great stuff.
I could make a career
out of this guy.
You see how clever
this part is?
How it doesn't require
a shred of proof?
Most paranoid delusions
are intricate,
but this is brilliant.
Why were the other
2 women killed?
Most of the records
were lost in the war.
Skynet knew almost nothing
about Connor's mother.
Her full name, where she lived.
They just knew the city.
The Terminator was
just being systematic.
Uh-huh. Well,
let's go back to--
look, you have heard enough!
I have answered your questions!
Now I have to see
Sarah Connor!
I'm afraid
that's not up to me.
Then why am I
talking to you?
Because
I can help you.
Who is in
authority here? Reese--
shut up!
You still don't
get it, do you?
He'll find her.
That's what he does!
That's all he does!
You can't stop him!
He'll wade through you,
reach down her throat,
and pull
her fucking heart out!
Doc.
Let go of me--
sorry.
So, Reese is crazy?
In technical
terminology--
he's a loon.
Sarah, this is what
they call body armor.
Our tac guys wear these.
It'll stop
a 12-gauge round.
This other individual
must have been wearing one
under his coat.
Feel that. Go ahead.
What about when he punched
through the windshield?
He was probably
on PCP.
Broke every bone
in his hand
and wouldn't feel it
for hours.
There was this guy once--
you see this scar?
Here.
Thank you.
There's a couch
in this other room.
Why don't you stretch out
and try to get some sleep?
It'll be at least an hour
before your mother gets here
from big bear.
I can't sleep.
Try.
Well,
it may not look it,
but that couch
is very comfortable.
You'll be
perfectly safe.
We got 30 cops
in this building.
Thank you.
Good night.
[Buzz]
[Beep beep beep]
I'm a friend
of Sarah Connor.
I was told that she's here.
Could I see her, please?
No. You can't see her.
She's making a statement.
Where is she?
Look,
it may take a while.
If you want to wait,
there's a bench over there.
I'll be back.
Man: What the hell
was that?
Man: Gunshot!
What is it,
terrorists?
Woman: Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Stay here.
Let's get out of here!
Come on!
He's got
an automatic weapon!
Move it, move it,
move it, move it!
Man: What the hell
happened to the lights?
Watch him.
[Machine gun fire]
[Breathing heavily]
Automatic weapons!
Lock and load!
Let's go!
Fire! Fire!
Ed.
Hey!
Sarah!
Reese!
This way.
[Car engine starts]
Car radio:
Kflb news time 4:36.
In the top story
of the hour,
the largest single
law enforcement mobilization
in California history
is currently underway.
[Engine sputters]
Police in
5 Southern counties
are engaged in a massive manhunt
for an unident--
take this.
All right, let's get this
off the road.
You cold?
Freezing.
Reese...
You got a first name?
Kyle.
Kyle...
What's it like
when you
go through time?
White light.
Pain.
It's like
being born maybe.
Oh, my God.
I caught one
back there.
You mean
you got shot?
It's not bad.
We got to get you
to a doctor.
It's ok. Forget it.
What do you mean, forget it?
Are you crazy?
Take this off.
Jesus.
See, it passed
right through the meat.
Oh, this is going
to make me puke.
Would you just
talk about something?
What?
I don't know.
Anything. Just talk.
Tell me about my son.
He's about my height.
Aah!
He has your eyes.
What's he like?
You trust him.
He's got a strength.
I'd die for John Connor.
Well...At least now I know
what to name him.
I don't suppose
you know who the father is,
so I won't tell him
to get lost when I meet him.
John never said
much about him.
I know he dies
before the war--
wait!
I don't want to know.
So, was it John
that sent you here?
I volunteered.
Why?
It was a chance
to meet the legend--
Sarah Connor.
Taught her son
to fight, organize,
prepare from
when he was a kid.
When you were in hiding
before the war...
You're talking about things
that I haven't done yet
in the past tense.
It's driving me crazy.
Aah!
Are you sure
you have the right person?
I'm sure.
Come on.
Do I look like
the mother of the future?
I mean, am I tough,
organized?
I can't even
balance my checkbook.
Look, Reese, I didn't
ask for this honor,
and I don't want it!
Any of it!
Your son gave me a message
to give to you.
Made me memorize it.
Thank you, Sarah,
for your courage
through the dark years.
I can't help you with
what you must soon face
except to say that
the future is not set.
You must be stronger
than you imagine you can be.
You must survive,
or I will never exist.
That's all.
That's a good
field dressing.
You like it?
It's my first.
[Car passes]
Get some sleep.
It will be light
soon.
Ok.
Talk to me some more.
About what?
Tell me about
where you're from.
All right.
You stay down by day,
but at night
you can move around.
You still
have to be careful
because the hks
use infrared.
But they're
not too bright.
John taught us ways
to dust them.
That's when
the infiltrators
started to appear.
The terminators
were the newest...
The worst.
Man over radio: Traversing
your sector in search mode.
750 meters north
of your position.
Second man: Understand.
750 meters north.
Let's go.
Man over radio:
Intercept. Over.
Second man: Take it easy.
They are scavenger teams
in that quadrant.
Avoid contact.
Repeat, avoid contact.
We'll get them later.
Man over radio:
Roger, echo leader.
Sector niner,
what's your status?
Situation normal.
We're coming in.
Roger.
Firebase,
what's your status? Over.
Reese.
Bn384...
Right.
Let him in.
Radio: Any infiltrators
at the shopping mall?
Radio: No problem.
They were clean.
We're cutting short
the patrol. Over.
Roger, yankee-1-7.
You are clear to return.
[Boy imitating
gunfire]
[Woman coughing]
[Sobbing]
[Squeaking]
[Dogs barking]
Terminator!
[People screaming]
[Birds chirping,
dog barking in distance]
I was dreaming about dogs.
We use them
to spot terminators.
Your world
is pretty terrifying.
[Fly buzzing]
[Knock on door]
Hey, buddy,
you got a dead cat
in there, or what?
[Knocking]
Fuck you, asshole.
God damn!
Thank you.
[Horn honks]
Uh, is this enough?
Yeah, it's enough.
I don't want to ask
where you got it.
I'm coming.
We need a room.
All right.
With a kitchen.
Do you have one
with a kitchen?
Mmm.
I am dying
for a shower.
We should check
your bandage, too.
Later.
I'm going out
for supplies.
Keep this.
[Door opens
and closes]
Sarah: No, I can't tell you
where I am, mom.
I was told not to say.
Oh, but, honey, I need
to know where I can reach you.
You tell me
to hide out up here
at the cabin
like some fugitive,
and you won't tell me
what's going on?
I am worried sick,
dear.
Ok.
Ok, here's the number.
Ready?
Yes. Go ahead.
It's 408-555-1439.
Room 9.
Got it?
I've got it.
I've got to go.
I'm sorry I can't
tell you more right now.
I love you, mom.
I love you, too,
sweetheart.
Tiki motel.
Give me
your address there.
Sarah:
What have we got?
Mothballs.
Corn syrup.
Ammonia.
What's for dinner?
Plastique.
Mmm, that sounds good.
What is it?
Nitroglycerin,
basically.
It's
a bit more stable.
I learned to make it
when I was a kid.
Make sure there's none
on the threads.
Like this.
Screw the end cap on.
Ah. Very gently.
You must have had
a fun childhood.
That's good.
All right.
6 more like that,
and I'll get started
on the fuses.
He'll find us,
won't he?
Probably.
It'll never be over,
will it?
Look at me.
I'm shaking.
Some legend, huh?
You must be
pretty disappointed.
No. I'm not.
Kyle...
The women
in your time,
what are they
like?
Good fighters.
That's not
what I meant.
Was there
someone special?
Someone?
A girl. You know.
No.
Never.
Never?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
So much pain.
Pain can be controlled.
You just disconnect it.
So you feel nothing?
John Connor gave me
a picture of you once.
I didn't know why
at the time.
It was very old...
Torn...
Faded.
You were young
like you are now.
You seemed just
a little sad.
I used to always wonder
what you were thinking
at that moment.
I memorized every line,
every curve.
I came across time
for you, Sarah.
I love you.
I always have.
I shouldn't
have said that.
Think fast!
[Dog barking]
[Barks]
Trade places!
Faster!
Drive faster!
[Horn honks]
Uhh!
Kyle!
Oh, my God!
Aah!
Kyle.
Whoa!
Son of a bitch!
You stay here.
Let's get out of here.
Get out.
Kyle.
Come on, get up.
He's coming.
Kyle?
Come on!
Help me!
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
Come on!
Come on.
Faster!
Don't stop! Run!
Sarah!
Kyle!
Oh, Kyle.
Kyle.
We did it, Kyle.
We got it.
No!
Wait!
What are you doing?
Cover, so he can't
track us.
Come on!
Come on.
No, Kyle!
Come on!
Leave me here.
Get up!
Move it, Reese!
On your feet,
soldier!
On your feet!
Move it!
Back. Go back.
Run, Sarah.
No.
Run!
Come on,
you motherfucker.
Ohh!
Aah!
No, no.
You're terminated,
fucker.
[Siren]
Kyle.
Police radio: 6450
bellingham Avenue, super trader.
6450 bellingham Avenue.
[Radio indistinguishable]
Tape 7, November 10.
Where was I?
What's most difficult for me
is trying to decide
what to tell you
and what not to.
But I guess
I have a while yet
before you're old enough
to even understand these tapes.
They're more for me
at this point,
just so that
I can get it straight.
Gasolina, por favor.
¿Cuanto?
Llena El tanque.
Fill her up, sí.
Should I tell you
about your father?
Boy, that's a tough one.
Will it affect your decision
to send him here,
knowing that he is
your father?
If you don't send Kyle,
you can never be.
God, a person
could go crazy
thinking about this.
I suppose
I will tell you.
I owe him that.
Maybe it'll help if...
You know that in the few hours
that we had together...
We loved a lifetime's worth.
Usted es muy hermosa,
señora,
y tengo que decirle
que necesito
cinco dolares americanos,
pero si no,
mi padre me va a pegar.
What did he just say?
He says you're very
beautiful, señora,
and he's ashamed
to ask you
for 5 American dollars
for his picture,
but if he doesn't,
his father
will beat him.
Pretty good hustle, kid.
Cuatro.
Sí, sí.
Gracias.
¡miren, miren!
¡allá!
Iviene la tormenta!
What did he just say?
He said there's
a storm coming in.
I know.
[Thundering]