Excuse me, Mr. Filby!
I say...
- I say, it's outright rude of the man!
- He's merely being detained, that's all.
This is such a confounded waste of time!
If he's not coming, I have any
number of more important things to do.
Well, speak up. What is it, woman?
Well, are we or are we
not invited for dinner?
Apparently, we are.
- How long has he been gone?
- Well, I can't rightly say, sir. Several days.
I've hardly seen him for some time.
And he never leaves the laboratory.
He only comes in and picks at his food.
But he did tell me about dinner tonight,
sir, and left those instructions.
Thank you, Mrs. Watchett.
- Well, what does it say, Filby? What's wrong?
- Oh, nothing, really.
George merely says that if he's not here by
8 o'clock, then we're to begin without him.
Walter, what time is it?
Dinner is served, gentlemen.
First sensible thing
I've heard all evening.
This is peculiar. He's usually
most prompt, precise and punctual.
He's making fools of us by
inviting us here and then
not showing up. It's not
the behaviour of a gentleman.
- To say nothing of a waste of time.
- Yes. To say nothing of a waste of time.
It's one thing I like about our George: he's
got the best cellar in the southern England.
And Mrs. Watchett is the
finest cook in the world.
Yes, I think I'll drink to that.
- Good Lord! What's happened?
- I'm all right.
Some food.
A drink.
- I didn't recognize you.
- Mrs. Watchett.
Well, can't you speak,
man? What happened to you?
- Leave him alone, can't yo?.
- It's all right.
- I've got to tell it now,
David, while I still remember it.
Relax. Try to relax.
You've all the time in the world.
You're right, David.
That's exactly what I have.
All the time in the world.
Ever since we were
together five days ago,..
...the last day of 1899.
There in that box rests the
result of two years' labor.
I wanted to finish the job
before the new century began.
I barely made it.
- Cheers, gentlemen.
- Marvelous, old boy.
Yes, but what is it?
Well, it has to do with time.
Oh, I've always maintained
that what this nation needs...
...is a reliable timepiece.
The navy needs one.
The army needs one for
the artillery, you know.
You couldn't do better, George. So
that's why you've been in hiding, huh?
That's very clever of you, indeed.
I don't think George is referring
to a new type of timepiece.
No, David.
When I speak of time, gentlemen, I'm
referring to the fourth dimension.
Go on, George.
Well, the difficulty in explaining the fourth
dimension is that it cannot be seen or felt.
If you don't mind, George, would you
refresh me on the first three dimensions?
Really, Filby. Surely they
taught you something at school.
Suppose you explain it, doctor.
Certainly.
For example, when I move in a
straight line, forward or backward...
...that's one dimension.
And when I move to the left or right
- two dimensions.
And when I move up or down
...three dimensions.
For instance, that box.
Well, that box has three dimensions:
length, breadth and height.
Yes, but what is the fourth dimension?
That's mere theory. No one really knows
what the fourth dimension
is or even that it exists.
On the contrary, Doctor.
The fourth dimension is as real and true
a dimension as any of the other three.
In fact, they couldn't exist without it.
What do you mean?
Let's take that box.
It has the first three
dimensions, as you said.
- All right. But what's in that box?
- I'm coming to that.
Let's consider this first.
Why is it that we usually
ignore the fourth dimension?
Because we have no freedom
of movement within it.
You see, we can move in the other three:
up, down, forward, sideways,
backward, as the Doctor said.
But when it comes to
time, we are prisoners.
Do you follow me, Bridey?
No.
George, you've given the most lucid explanation
of all, but I'm afraid I don't quite understand.
Walter, look, there are many things in this
world you don't understand, aren't there?
Yes, quite... quite a number.
Well, you don't refuse to believe
in them because of that, do you?
- No, not if I can see
the proof with my own eyes.
Good, Walter.
Gentlemen, all I'm
asking you to do now...
...is to witness a demonstration
of the possibility of movement...
...within the fourth dimension.
- Doctor, can I have your help?
- Oh, certainly, certainly.
It's beautiful!
- It's remarkable.
- Very nice, George.
Fascinating.
What is it?
This is only a small
experimental model, of course.
- To carry a man, a larger edition is needed.
- To carry a man? Where?
Into the past or into the future.
This is a time machine.
All right, George, now
you've had your little joke.
Suppose you tell us what
this contraption's really for.
I've already told you, Doctor.
The larger model can be used to carry
a passenger on a journey through time.
Not through space, mind
you, but through time.
I say, George, if you're gonna
start floating about in the future,
how'd you gonna rather mess
things up for the rest of us?
Well, the future's already there.
It's irrevocable and cannot be changed.
I wonder.
Now, that's the most important question
to which I hope to find an answer.
Can man control his destiny? Can he
change the shape of things to come?
Now, look here, George, if you've
gone out of your head, I forgive you.
- But if you've made us waste all this time,..
- No, Doctor! You're here as witnesses.
- To see, not to listen.
- To see? What?
The experiment I am about to perform.
First, let me tell you how it works.
Here, in this compartment, you see the
saddle, where the time traveller sits.
And in front of him are the controls.
Let's do this properly. You can
spare a cigar, I trust, Doctor?
Now, let us imagine that this cigar...
...is the time traveller.
Now, in front of him is the
lever, which controls movement.
Forward pressure sends the
machine into the future,..
...backward pressure
- into the past.
And the harder the pressure,
the faster the machine travels.
Of course, our little experiment
can be performed only once.
If it succeeds, I lose my model
forever. That's why I need witnesses.
Go ahead, George.
All ready, gentlemen?
Doctor, would you
here lend me your hand?
I'll be damned!
It worked.
- But where did it go?
- Go?
Nowhere, in the usual
sense. It's still here.
But it's no longer in the present.
Do you realise? It's travelling through
time. To the future, to be exact.
Do you really expect us
to believe such a story?
Well, you've just... Certainly.
- But you yourself just said
that it hadn't really moved.
That's correct.
Well, then why can't we see it?
Because we're in this room on
the 31st of December, 1899...
...but the model we just saw is
perhaps a hundred years away by now.
This room, even this whole house
may not be here in a hundred years.
But the time machine occupies
the same space that it did...
...a moment before it
went off on its journey.
Well, if it's occupying the
same space, why can't I feel it?
You must remember that the space you're
putting your hand through is today's space.
You can't put your hand
into the space of tomorrow.
Space doesn't change!
The same space that's here now should be here
in a hundred or even a thousand years from now.
No, Philip, time changes space!
Look, this flat ground we're
stading on could've been
at the bottom of the
sea a million years ago.
And a million years from now, it could
be the interior of a huge mountain.
All right, suppose, what
you say is true, what do you
expect to do with such a contraption?
Contraption?
For my part, I intend taking
a journey into the future.
Well, perhaps the doctor
would volunteer to go?
Well, look here, George...
...suppose you do and go off and get
lost in the 50th century or something.
- How you're gonna get back?
- That's a risk I'm prepared to take.
Now, look here, George.
I don't know what you think us
for, but we're not fools, you know!
We're practical men, businessmen.
No, now, the question I
want to put you is this:
Even if you had invented a time machine,
or what have you called it, what of it?
What use would it be to anyone?
Who would want to buy it?
And how much would they
be willing to pay for it?
Yes, George, have you thought
of the commercial possibilities?
No, I really haven't.
George...! There's a war on,
you know, in South Africa.
The Boers are putting
up a pretty stiff fight.
Now, George, the country
needs inventors like you.
I can put you in touch with
the War Office if you wish.
What do you think, David?
Oh, I think Dr. Hillyer
has a good point, George.
Now, we're becoming more sensible.
I'll see to it first
thing in the new year.
Good Lord! It's time to go, gentlemen.
Yes, I'm sure we all have
our plans for tonight.
- Are you all right, George?
- Yes, I'm all right, Bridey.
Coming, Bridewell?
Thank you for coming.
- Good night, George.
- Happy New Year, George.
- Happy new century, George.
- Good night, Bridey.
Happy New Year!
I thought I'd better stay.
Well, You shouldn't have troubled
yourself, David. I'm all right.
No, you're not.
You've been behaving
oddly for over a month now.
I'm not leaving here until you
tell me what's on your mind.
Look, David, I appreciate the gesture,
but I just wanna be left alone, that's all.
You've changed, George. Enormously.
I'm sorry.
Will you answer me
one question, honestly?
Yes, I'll try.
Why this preoccupation with time?
Why not?
Don't go simple on me, George.
All right, if you want to know the truth, I
don't much care for the time I was born into.
It seems people aren't
dying fast enough these days.
They call upon science...
...to invent new, more efficient
weapons to depopulate the Earth.
And I agree with you.
I agree, George. But here we are
and we have to make the best of it.
You may have to. I don't.
All right. Take your
journey on your contraption.
Who would you become?
A Greek? A Roman?
- One of the pharaohs?
- I prefer the future.
You're not seriously
saying you can do it?
David, you saw the experiment
this afternoon, didn't you?
I saw a toy machine vanish.
I'm certain that there are any
number of ways of doing that trick.
Any magician with a hippodrome
could probably do it.
It wasn't a trick!
- Would you like to see the
full-scale model? - No, I would not.
I have no desire to tempt
the laws of Providence.
And I don't think you should.
- It's not for man to trifle with.
- You carry on like Hillyer and Kemp now.
There is something to say about
their common-sense attitude to life.
George, I speak to you as a friend.
More. As a brother.
If that machine can do what
you say it can, destroy it.
Destroy it, George,
before it destroys you!
You must have plans for New Year's
Eve, David. Don't let me keep you.
Mary wasn't well. We thought
we'd stay home with the baby.
Why don't you come home with me? You
haven't seen wee Jamey for a long time.
I'm sorry, I can't, David.
What's stopping you?
Well... Look, I just want to see the
old century out by myself, that's all.
Have it your way, George.
George, will you promise you'll
not go out of the house tonight?
I promise you I won't walk out the door.
Davy, I'm sorry. Please don't
think me unkind or unfriendly, I...
- Look, just come over to
dinner next Friday, will you.
Very well.
- Fine. Bring the others with you.
- As you say, George.
- Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year, David.
- Having supper in tonight, sir?
- I don't think so, Mrs. Watchett.
Why don't you take the
evening off and celebrate?
Well, thank you, sir, but
if you're not need in me,
I think I'll turn in earlier
and get some sleep,.. if I can.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Oh, Mrs. Watchett, I've invited Mr. Filby
and the others to dinner next Friday night.
Oh, yes, sir.
- Happy New Year, Mrs. Watchett.
- Happy New Year, sir.
At first, I pushed the lever
forward ever so slightly...
...and the laboratory
grew faint around me.
I stopped.
No change.
Everything exactly
as it had been before.
But no! The clock said 6:31 when
I started, and now it was... 8:09?
And the candle, shorter by inches!
And yet by my watch, which was in the machine
with me, only a few seconds had passed.
It was disconcerting to see the
sun arc in less than a minute.
To see a snail race by.
My flowers flinging wide their
petals to embrace the new day.
And the hours speeding
across the face of my sundial.
And the flowers closing
their eyes for the night.
It was wonderful!
Changes that normally took
hours occuring in seconds.
Dear Mrs. Watchett...
...always able to tell
me what tie to wear...
...but never able to decide to
wear anything more stylish...
...than the type of clothes
she's worn all these years.
And as yet I was traveling very slowly.
What if I went faster?
It became intoxicating.
So I pushed the lever on
toward even greater speed.
As I went along I gained
experience in handling the machine.
I found that I could stop for a day, an
hour, or even for a second to observe.
Then go ahead a year or two.
Thus, I was able to see the changing
world in a series of glimpses.
Good heavens. That's a dress?
This was intriguing.
I wondered just how far women
would permit this to go.
I began to grow very
fond of that mannequin.
Maybe because, like me, she didn't age.
Thirteen years have passed.
Fourteen, fifteen, sixteen...
and then suddenly the light
was gone. What had happened?
In the year of 1917, I stopped.
Filby!
Well, what are you doing?
Are you in a masquerade party?
You look rather silly without
your mustache, old man.
- Were you addressing me, sir?
- Filby, it's George!
Well, I must say I expected a little
more enthusiastic a greeting...
I think you're confusing
me with my father, sir.
Yes, there was quite a
resemblance. I'm James Filby.
"Was"?
- Were you a friend of Father's?
- Yes.
Yes, I've been away.
He was killed in the war. A year ago.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
- What about the gentleman across the street?
- Oh, him, the inventor chap?
He disappeared around
the turn of the century.
Look, here, if you're interested in that
house, sir, I'm afraid you can't buy it.
- Can't even get inside.
- Why is that?
Well, my father was executor of the inventor's
estate and father just refused to liquidate it.
I often chided him on that account...
...but he felt positive the
owner would return some day.
People hereabouts think
it's haunted, but...
Who are you, sir?
Just a stranger who
once knew your father.
Have you been at the front?
Front? What front?
What the... the war, of course.
What war?
Good heavens!
You mean you don't know we've been
at war with Germany since 1914?
I thought you'd just
returned from France perhaps.
Or perhaps...
...perhaps a cup of tea might
make you feel better, sir?
Won't you come in?
No, no, thank you.
Are you sure you're all right, sir?
Yes, I'm quite all right.
Then goodbye, sir.
Goodbye, Jamey.
Suddenly, in 1940, I began to
be buffeted from side to side.
My first thought was that the machine had a
mechanical defect or if a quark had worn out.
The last time I had stopped
was in 1917, 23 years ago.
And the war with Germany was still waging.
Now in the air with flying machines.
Then I realized the truth of
the matter. This was a new war.
I decided to push on into time
and see the outcome of this.
Then my house was hit!
The flames shot up into the sky.
And my home was gone in an instant.
And I found myself in the open air.
The years rolled by,
everything unfamiliar.
Except the smile of
my never-aging friend.
But what was this? Weird sounds
all around me. What could it be?
My curiosity compelled me to stop.
At first, I wondered if my machine
I was the cause of the panic.
Well, I was soon to
find out that we weren't.
Keep it moving here! Shove it on!
Come on, into the shelter.
Come on, young man! Come on! Come on!
- Filby?
- The name is Mr. Filby.
- And didn't you hear the air raid siren?
- You mean the horrible screeching?
It wasn't constructed for its
aesthetic value, young man...
...but to warn silly young fools
like you to get into the shelter.
- Now, come along, come along.
- But I'm perfectly comfortable here, Mr. Filby.
I've got to talk to
somebody. This is fantastic!
Your store is magnificent!
The achievements!
- The gigantic strides that man kinded!
- Come along, young man! Come along! Come along!
You better hurry or the
mushrooms will be sprouting!
Mushrooms?
You look familiar. Haven't
we met somewhere before?
Indeed we have, Mr. Filby.
Right there. Many years ago.
I was sure of that.
But the exact time escapes me.
It was two wars ago. 1917.
Now I recall. The chap who
inquired about my father...
...and the house that used
to stand across the way.
But no... No, that's impossible!
You haven't changed.
You're not a day older.
And your clothes!
Don't worry, Filby. It'll take
a little time to explain, but...
That's the last alert! Hurry! Hurry!
- Listen, this is important.
- Look!
An atomic satellite,
zeroing in. That's important.
- But I've got to talk to you!
- Come on!
Hurry!
Till the all clear!
But, Filby, I've got to talk to you!
The labor of centuries,
gone in an instant.
And then mother Earth,
aroused by man's violence...
...responded with volcanic
violence of her own.
Only my speed through time saved me from being
roasted alive and encased in stone forever.
The molten rock cooled.
I prayed...
...wondering how many centuries,
how many eons must pass...
...before the wind and rain could wear
away the mountain that enclosed me.
Darkness.
Darkness for centuries.
I wondered if there was still a war
being waged on the ground above me...
...if man would still exist on
Earth when I saw the sun again.
The centuries rolled by.
I put my trust in time...
...and waited for the rock
to wear down around me.
I was free again!
Thousands of centuries had passed
but the Earth had stayed green.
There was no winter, no wars.
Had man finally learned to control
both the elements and himself?
I had to stop and find out.
But I'd stopped too fast.
Magnificent!
Flowers. Beautiful flowers everywhere!
Natural splendor beyond compare.
The whole landscape, one vast garden
without any sign of weeds or briars.
Trees and vines laden with fruit
of strange shapes and colors.
Nature tamed completely...
...and more bountiful than ever before!
At last I'd found a paradise.
But it would be no paradise
if it'd belong to me alone.
Unrepaired for centuries.
Maybe unlived-in for as long.
Anybody here?
So this is man's future: to bask in the
sunlight, bathe in the clear streams...
...and eat the fruits of the Earth, with
all knowledge of work and hardship forgotten.
Well, and why not?
Don't just sit there! Help her!
Are you all right?
Thank you.
- Why did you?
- Why did I what?
Come after me.
Sit down.
I did it to save your life.
That doesn't seem to mean much to
you, or anybody else around here.
It doesn't.
Do you realize that there were about
twenty of your friends watching you drown.
Not one of them so much as
lifted a finger to save you.
That's a very curious attitude.
Very curious world.
Aren't you the least bit interested
in who I am? Where I come from?
Should I be?
I think, perhaps, you better take me to
somebody a little older. Somebody I can talk to.
There is no one older.
Do you mean nobody ages
in this land of yours?
- Well, what's your name?
- Weena.
How do you spell it?
- Spell?
- Spell, write. Can't you write?
Look.
- What are your people called?
- Eloi.
Come. We must go now.
- Why, what's wrong?
- It's getting dark.
Hello.
I don't mind telling
you, I'm quite hungry.
And I've come a long, long way.
You know, in my time,
a berry that size...
...would've been big news
all over the civilized world.
Excuse me, sir?
Sir?
Perhaps curiosity is died. Perhaps...
...even courtesy is died, but I have come a
long way and I would like to know a few things.
Why?
Well, because I shall return to my time,
and my people will ask me questions.
Such as:
Well, what kind of
government rules your world?
We have no government.
Well, you must have a body of
men who pass and enforce laws.
Laws? There are no laws.
Where do you get food and clothing?
Doesn't anybody work?
No.
Well, where does all that come from?
- It grows. It always grows.
- Yes, I know, but it must be...
...cultivated and
planted and nurtured...
Well, unless you...
...well, you may have an economy so
well-developed that you
can spend all your time...
...studying and
experimenting? Is that right?
You ask many questions.
Well, that is the only way that
man has learned and developed.
I wish to learn.
I want to learn about you,
about your civilization.
Perhaps you... Do you have books?
Books?
- Yes, we have books.
- Ah, wonderful!
I can learn all I want about you from books.
Books will tell me what I want to know.
Could I see the books?
Yes, they do tell me all about you.
What have you done?
Thousands of years of building and
rebuilding, creating and re-creating...
...so you can let it
all crumble to dust!
A million years of sensitive
men dying for their dreams.
For what?!
So you can swim and dance...
...and play!
You! All of you!
I'm going back to my own time! I won't again
bother to tell of the useless struggle...
...the hopeless future. But
at least I could die among men!
- Weena, what are you doing?
- I hear you pounding. I came to warn you.
- Weena, how do you open that panel?
- No one opens it. Only the Morlocks.
The Morlocks? But who are the Morlocks?
They give us the food we eat and the
clothes we wear. We must obey their command.
Why'd they taken my machine?
Weena, you've got to tell me!
But... it is night. We
mustn't be out in the dark.
Only little children are
frightened by the dark.
And you are a little child, aren't you?
- Well, don't be frightened, I'll light a fire.
- Please, let us go.
Weena, I can't. My machine
is inside there. I've got to
wait here until morning and
find some way of getting it out.
- No, you mustn't.
- Come on. Help me gather some wood.
That's a girl.
Where are you from?
As a matter of fact,
I'm from right here.
That's where my house used to be...
...many thousands of years ago.
You see there?
From there up to those
panels was my laboratory.
Then beyond the panels was
where my garden used to be.
Right there.
That was my library.
Where I once sat talking
with friends about...
...the time machine.
You know, Weena,..
...I'd hoped to learn such a great deal.
I'd hoped to take back the knowledge and
the advancement that mankind had made.
And instead, I find vegetables.
The human race reduced
to living vegetables.
They're gone. Are you all right?
- That was a Morlock, was it?
- Yes.
Oh, don't you worry. The
fire seems to keep them away.
What are you doing? Why did
you put your hand in the fire?
I never saw it before.
No knowledge of fire?
No books? No...
I'm terribly sorry.
I'm sorry I was angry with your
people. I had no right to be.
No more than if I'd visited the
island of Bali in my own time.
But, you know, Weena...
You were safe inside your great house, and
yet you came out into the night to warn me.
The one characteristic which distinguished
man from the animal kingdom...
...was the spirit of self-sacrifice.
And you have that quality.
I think all your people have it really.
It just needs someone to reawaken it.
I should like to try, if you let me.
Will you?
I do not understand you...
...but I believe you.
That's as good a start as any.
Try to tell me. The Morlocks
- who or what are the Morlocks?
Are they animals or people?
Well, what about yourself?
The past. Don't your people
ever speak of the past?
There is no past.
Well, do they ever
wonder about the future?
There is no future.
Well, the past,..
...man's past,..
...is mainly a grim
struggle for survival.
But there have been moments when
a few voices have spoken up...
...and these rare moments have made
the history of man - man's past -..
...a glorious thing.
I refuse to believe it's dead and gone.
We've had our dark ages before. And
this is just another one of them.
All it needs is for someone
to show you the way out.
I'm only a tinkering mechanic, but...
...I'm sure there must be this
hidden spark in one of your people.
If only I can kindle that spark...
...my coming here
will have some meaning.
My efforts next morning to
open the panel were fruitless.
I had to find another way
to retrieve my machine.
Listen.
Weenie, you hear that?
Yes.
Machines?
- No, Morlocks.
- Wait.
You mean those animals run machines?
They are Morlocks.
- But, have you ever seen the machines?
- No, only heard of them.
- But, who told you?
- The rings.
- What sort of rings?
- Rings that talk.
Could you show me these talking rings?
Come, this way.
- These are the talking rings?
- Yes.
They speak?
Of what?
Things no one here understands.
Make it talk.
The war between the East and West,
which is now in its 326th year,..
...has at last come to an end.
There is nothing left to fight
with and few of us left to fight.
The atmosphere has become so
polluted with deadly germs...
...that it can no longer be breathed.
There is no place on this
planet that is immune.
The last surviving factory for the
manufacture of oxygen has been destroyed.
Stockpiles are rapidly diminishing...
...and when they are gone, we must die.
My name is of no consequence.
The important thing you should know is that
I am the last who remembers how each of us...
...man and woman, made his own decision.
Some chose to take refuge
in the great caverns...
...and find a new way of life
far below the Earth's surface.
The rest of us decided to take
our chances in the sunlight...
...small as those chances might be.
From the talking rings I learned
how the human race divided itself...
...and how the world of the
Eloi and the Morlocks began.
By some awful quirk of fate...
...the Morlocks had became the
masters and the Eloi, their servants.
The Morlocks maintained
them and bred them like...
...like cattle...
...only to take them below
when they reached maturity.
Which explained why there were
no older people among them.
Now I knew I must go below.
It was the only mean to
finding a way up into the
Spfinx to reach my machine...
...and find out what happened to the
little people when they did go below.
Don't go!
- You won't come back!
- I'll be back.
Weena?
Weena, answer me!
Where are you?
What's happening?
What's the matter with you all?
Weena, stop!
Stop!
Well, what happens to them?
Don't stand there like fatted
cattle! Will you answer me?
- What is wrong?
- There is nothing wrong. It is all clear.
- What do you mean, all clear?
- All clear.
In the middle-1900s, the falling bombs,
the people calling out, "All clear!".
No!
That's gone! That's passed!
There are no more flying machines!
No more bombs! No more wars!
The rings have told us that story.
But you didn't listen!
You didn't learn anything!
It was ages ago that men were taught to
hide below the ground when the sirens blew...
...to run from the reigning
death, but it's over!
Those men are dead. The men
who slaughtered them are dead!
But there is nothing to
fear. It is all clear.
What about the ones who went below?
How do you think they gonna come back?
They never come back.
- Nobody can bring them back.
- You can try. You can try!
Won't even one of you try?!
Well, I'll try!
So this was the destiny of the Eloi.
They were being bred by the Morlocks...
...who had degenerated into
the lowest form of human life:
Cannibalism!
Weena, wake up! Come to
your senses! All of you!
Burn.
Give me something to
burn. It's my last match.
Get up the stairs! That's
the way out! Quickly!
The torch!
Weenie, get the torch!
Get up the steps! Hurry up!
All right, get all the
deadwood! Come on! All the wood!
That's fine. Come on, throw it down!
All the deadwood!
Throw it down! Do the
same to the other wells!
All the wood down the wells!
All right, to the river!
Come on! Back to the river!
All right, let's go!
Another night was coming, but
this night no Eloi needed to fear.
The underworld of the
Morlocks was gone...
...and so was the life
of leisure for the Eloi.
But then what of me?
I was imprisoned in a world...
...in which I just did not belong.
Are you sorry?
- Sorry? Sorry for what?
- That you have to stay?
Yes.
I'm sorry because I could tell so
much to the people of my time, Weena.
I could let them know...
...about the sorrow and the happiness
that the future has installed for them.
Maybe they could learn from it.
Or could they?
- You don't want to stay, do you?
- It isn't that.
It's just that I don't really fit here
any more than you would in my time.
I would love to see your time.
You wouldn't be very happy there.
Do you have someone
there? Someone like me?
No, no one like you.
I have friends, of course,
friends who'll miss me.
As a matter of fact, I'm
probably late already.
Women?
No.
As a matter of fact, there is one woman.
But she looks after my house for me.
And she's 62 years old and all wrinkled.
How do they wear their hair?
- Who?
- The women of your time.
- Up.
- Up?
Up how?
I don't know. Kind of...
...up, like that.
Show me!
Would I be pretty?
Yes, you would. Very pretty.
Oh, Weena, I wish we
could go back to my time.
Or even into time before
that, when the world was young.
- We could be so very happy.
- Look!
My machine!
Come on, Weena!
I was going the wrong way!
Back! I had to go back!
Well, It's the most ridiculous story
I've ever heard. Absolutely preposterous!
Well, there's one thing I'll say for you,
George, you always could tell a good yarn.
You're a truly great inventor, George.
I think you ought to retire, sir.
Truthfully, George, where
have you been the past week?
You shouldn't ask such questions.
It's not hard for a man to lose
a little week now and again.
I can understand your doubt, my
friends. Take it as a lie if you wish.
I scarcely believe it
myself, now that I'm back.
David, there's the flower Weena gave me.
A present for you. You were
always interested in botany.
Try and match that with
any species known today!
I don't think I can.
Well, time to go, Bridewell.
- Yes, it is getting late.
- Good night, George.
Good night, George.
You look exhausted, George.
You really should get some rest.
Good night, George. It's
grand having you back.
Goodbye, David.
Thanks for being such a
good friend, David. Always.
What do you think, Filby?
One thing is certain.
That flower couldn't possibly
have bloomed in the wintertime.
You don't really believe
that story is true, do you?
Good night.
Go on, driver.
- Mr. Filby, what..?
- He's gone!
Why, look!
I think I understand.
You see the imprint?
This is where the time
machine originally stood.
But the Morlocks moved it.
They dragged it across the lawn...
...right into the Sphinx. Right there.
And Weena was standing
here when he last saw her.
Right here! The same
space in a different time.
So he dragged his heavy
machine back in here...
...scratching the floor...
...so that he could appear
outside the sphinx again...
...and help the Eloi build a new world.
Build a new world for himself.
- Right where he left her.
- Yes.
It's not like George
to return empty-handed.
To try to rebuild a
civilization without a plan.
He must have taken something with him.
Nothing.
- Except three books.
- Which three books?
I don't know. Is it important?
I suppose not.
Only...
...which three books
would you have taken?
Mr. Filby, do you
think he'll ever return?
One cannot choose but wonder.
You see, he has all
the time in the world.