(WINDSHIELD WIPERS SWISHING)
CONKLIN: (ECHOING)
This is not a drill, soldier.
We clear on that?
This is a live project,
and you're a go.
You're a go.
Training is over.
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(GUN FIRING)
BOURNE: I'm okay.
It's fine.
It's just a headache.
MARIE: You're burning up.
(FAUCET SQUEAKS)
(WATER RUNS)
BOURNE: It's okay.
Just a headache.
MARIE: Anything new?
BOURNE: No.
(EXHALES) It's just
bits and pieces.
I can hear Conklin's voice
and there's that
photograph, but...
I just can't stay with it.
MARIE: But you're sure it's
not just a bad dream?
BOURNE: It happened.
It was a mission.
And I was there.
You should write it down.
Now, two years we're
scribbling in that notebook.
It hasn't been two years.
It's always bad
and now it's just the same
thing over and over again.
But that's why
we write it down.
MARIE: Because sooner or later,
you remember something good.
BOURNE: I do remember
something good.
All the time.
PAMELA: I want
one final go around.
MAN: All teams listen up.
We are standing
By for final green.
MAN 1: Survey Two, I need to
know when you've got eyes.
(OVER RADIO) This is
Survey Two. I have eyes.
MAN 1: Copy that.
Survey One, this is Hub.
Do you have visual contact?
Hub, this is Survey One.
Mobile One is in motion.
WOMAN: Survey Three,
that is good.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hub. MAN 2: Director
Marshall from Langley.
Langley.
Stand by, please.
Martin?
I'm here. So is Donnie
and Jack Weller.
We understand you're using the
full allocation for this buy.
PAMELA: It's where we came out.
It's a lot of money, Pam.
For a thief, a mole.
If it does nothing more than
narrow the list of suspects,
it's a bargain at
10 times the price.
HuB, this is Survey Two.
Escort is Breaking off.
MoBile One is
entering the Building.
PAMELA: Gentlemen, I have the
seller on-site and in play.
Quite frankly, there's nothing
much more to discuss.
All right, Pam. Your call.
Go.
We're on.
Audio contact only.
Switching to channel one now.
MAN: Copy that.
It's affirmative.
(CLICKING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
MAN: Hub, Mobile One and seller
have entered the office.
Copy that.
This is everything?
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BEEPING)
(MUFFLED GUNSHOTS)
PAMELA: Those were shots.
Survey One, come in.
Survey One, I need to
know what happened.
What do you see?
Do you see any movement?
Do you see any shadows?
MAN: I see nothing.
WOMAN: What is your visual?
Get some men in there. Get
some men in there right now.
Pull it up, Kurt.
Eye contact. I don't
care if it's visual.
Mobile One,
can you copy, please?
Are you there, Mobile One?
Damn it. I'm sorry.
WOMAN: What do you see,
Teddy?
(ALL CLAMORING)
MAN: Eyes up the whole way.
MAN ON TV:...Petroleum Association's
annual conference here in Berlin
is Pecos Oil chief executive
officer Yuri Gretkov.
In just six years,
Gretkov has turned Pecos
into an oil empire,
which in turn...
He's Become one of the
wealthiest men in Russia,
after consolidating drilling
rights in the Caspian Sea
and gaining
control of one of the...
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
MARIE: How much?
- Good morning, sir.
- Morning.
KIRILL: He is my friend. There's
been a death in the family.
And I wonder if
you've seen him.
MARIE: Hey.
BOURNE: Get in.
MARIE: What's wrong?
BOURNE: We're blown.
How?
BOURNE: We pushed it. We got lazy.
MAN: Idiot!
(HONKING HORN)
BOURNE: All right. That's twice
now I've seen the same guy.
I saw him in town. He was
at the telegraph office.
MARIE: Are you sure?
How can you be sure?
BOURNE: It's just wrong. The guy, the car he's
driving, what he's wearing, it's just wrong.
MARIE: But, Jason,
let's stay calm.
This is real.
It could be anybody.
BOURNE: This is real.
That's him.
That's him right there.
Get your head down. Silver Hyundai.
Get your head down.
(HORN BLARING)
BOURNE: How far is he?
How far?
MARIE: A hundred meters.
BOURNE: Here, take the wheel.
You're gonna drive.
Switch.
Just head to the bridge.
Turn here.
Cut through the field.
Hang on.
BOURNE: All right, you keep
going to the shack.
I'll meet you
there in one hour.
I'm gonna bail out on the
other side of this bridge.
It's the only way
he can follow us.
MARIE: What if it's not
who you think it is?
BOURNE: It"s them.
It"s Treadstone.
Jason, don't do it.
BOURNE: Look, Marie, I warned them.
I don't want you to do it.
I told them what would happen
if they didn't leave us alone.
It's never gonna
be over like this.
I don't want...
BOURNE: We don't have a choice.
MARIE: Yes, you do.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GRUNTING)
Thank you.
MAN: Two of these
explosive charges placed
on the power lines,
and one of them failed.
The fingerprint's from the
one that didn't go off.
PAMELA: And the Germans
can't match it?
MAN 1: No.
Nobody's got it.
We checked out every
database we could access.
But we're hooked
into Langley now.
- Run it.
- Okay.
PAMELA: What the hell's Treadstone?
All right. Get me a flight.
We're going to Langley.
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
MARTIN: Two men dead.
Three million in cash gone,
no Neski files
and all very public.
This is still a
clandestine agency, no?
PAMELA: I don't view this
event as a failure.
You call it a success?
We have a lead.
A fingerprint
left by the assassin.
It"s one of us.
MARTIN: Who is it?
What can you tell
me about Treadstone?
Treadstone?
PAMELA: That's where
the trail dead-ends.
If you want an answer, you're
going to have to give me
a level five SCI access.
We have a lead, Marty.
MARTIN: All right.
You've got your clearance.
But you're on
a very short leash.
And you'll give a full
report to the group.
I wanna know where
you're going with this.
Sir.
(PHONE RINGING)
PAMELA: Ward?
Yes?
Pamela Landy.
ABOTT: Hey, Pam.
What can I do for you?
PAMELA: I was hoping you
had some time for me.
ABOTT: Time for what?
PAMELA: I'm free right now, actually.
That sounds ominous.
Let me check my schedule.
Excuse me, I need to...
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm here
to see Mr. Abbott.
20 minutes? See you.
Operation Treadstone.
Never heard of it.
That's not gonna fly.
ABOTT: With all due respect,
Pam, I think you might
have wandered a little
past your pay grade.
That's a warrant
from Director Marshall
granting me unrestricted access
to all personnel and materials
associated with Treadstone.
So, what are we looking at?
I wanna know about it.
ABOTT: Know about it?
It was a kill squad.
Black-on-black.
We closed it down
two years ago.
Nobody wants to
know about Treadstone.
Not around here.
So I think you better
take this back to Marty
and let him know
exactly what you're doing.
PAMELA: He does. I've been
down to the archives.
I have the files, Ward.
Let's talk about Conklin.
What are you after, Pam?
You wanna fry me?
You want my desk.
Is that it?
- I wanna know what happened.
- What happened?
ABOTT: Jason Bourne happened.
You got the files.
Then let's cut the crap.
Conklin had these guys wound so
tight, they were Bound to snap.
Bourne was his number one.
The guy went for a job, screwed
the op, never came Back.
Conklin couldn 't fix it, couldn
't find Bourne, couldn 't adjust.
It all went sideways.
PAMELA: So you had Conklin killed?
I mean,
if we're cutting the crap.
ABOTT: I've given 30 years and
two marriages to this agency.
I've shoveled shit
on four continents.
I'm due to retire next year.
But if you think
I'm gonna sit here
and let you
dangle me with this,
you can go to hell.
And Marshall, too.
It had to be done.
PAMELA: And Bourne?
Where is he now?
ABBOTT: Dead in a ditch.
Drunk in a Bar in Mogadishu.
- Who knows.
- I think I do.
I had a deal going
down in Berlin last week.
And during the Buy, Both our case
officer and the seller were killed.
They were killed by
Jason Bourne.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
They're ready for us upstairs.
(BEEPING)
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(DOOR SLAMMING)
PAMELA: Seven years ago, $20
million of CIA funds disappeared
during a wire transfer
through Moscow.
In the investigation
that followed
we were contacted by a Russian
politician, Vladimir Neski.
Neski claimed we had a leak and that
we'd been ripped off by one of our own.
And were we?
We never found out.
We were negotiating a meet with
Mr. Neski when he was killed.
- By who?
- His wife.
PAMELA: The case had gone cold until
a month ago when we found a source.
Another Russian in
Berlin who claimed
to have access to
the Neski murder files.
We thought we had
another bite at the apple.
Turns out the assassin was one
of our own, Jason Bourne.
Now I know Treadstone's not a
very popular subject around here,
but we found some interesting
things when we dug a little deeper.
This is Conklin's
personal computer.
His Treadstone files are bloated
with code keys and case files
that he neither needed
nor had clearance for.
Buried in the hard drive,
we found a deleted file
with an account number
to a bank in Zurich.
At the time of his death,
he was sitting on a personal
account in the amount of $760,000.
ABOTT: You know what
his budget was?
We were throwing money at him.
Throwing it at him and
asking him to keep it dark.
PAMELA: It was his own account.
He was up to something.
This is supposed
to be definitive?
PAMELA: What's definitive is that
I just lost two people in Berlin.
So what's your theory? Conklin's
reaching out from the grave
to protect his good name?
The man is dead.
No one's disputing that, Ward.
For Christ's sake,
Marty, you knew Conklin.
Does this scan?
I mean, at all?
MARTIN: Cut to the chase, Pam.
PAMELA: I think that Bourne and
Conklin were in business together,
that Bourne's still involved
and that whatever information
I was trying to buy in Berlin
was big enough to bring Bourne
out from hiding to kill again.
How"s that scan?
ZORN: Excuse me, sir, but
you're not gonna believe this.
Jason Bourne's passport just
popped up on the grid in Naples.
PAMELA: Okay. Contact Naples. They
need to know who they're dealing with.
Find out what kind of local
assets we have in place there.
No, it's nothing. Some guy's
name came up on the computer.
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
NEVINS: Yeah. Hey, listen, Tom,
I'm gonna call you back, okay?
All right.
Mr. Bourne, I'm John Nevins.
I'm with the US Consulate.
I just have a few
questions for you.
(CLEARING THROAT)
You're coming out of Tangiers.
Is that correct?
What's the nature of
your visit to Naples?
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
NEVINS: Look, I don't
know what you did,
and I don't know
who you're working for.
But I promise you this,
you're gonna play ball
one way or the other.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SIGHING)
NEVINS: This is Nevins.
CRONIN: This is Tom Cronin,
CI Operations Officer
calling from Langley, Virginia.
Do you have a Jason Bourne
in custody?
Yes, I do.
CRONIN: Listen, he's an
Agency priority target.
Detain him and call me Back
as soon as he's secure.
I understand.
CRONIN: He's been detained.
Here's the number.
He's being interrogated by a field
officer out of the Consulate.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPING)
Hello.
PAMELA: This is Pamela Landy,
CI Supervisor.
Where do we stand?
NEVINS: I think he got away.
CRONIN: Damn it.
Have you locked down the area?
Locked it down? No, no.
This is... This is Italy.
They don't exactly lock down.
How long have you
worked for the Agency?
Me? For four years.
PAMELA: Well, if you ever
wanna make it to five,
you're gonna listen
to me real close.
Jason Bourne is armed
and extremely dangerous.
Last week in Berlin,
he assassinated two men,
one a highly experienced
field officer.
I want you to secure that area.
I want any evidence secured,
and I want it done right now.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir... Ma'am.
PAMELA: I'm getting on a plane
to Berlin in 45 minutes
which means you're gonna
call me Back in 30.
And when I ask you where we
stand, I had better be impressed.
Berlin? I already have
a team in place there.
I doubt that Bourne's in Naples
ready to start a family.
You have no idea
what you're getting into.
PAMELA: Do you have any idea? From
the minute he left Treadstone,
he's killed and eluded every single
person that you've sent to find him.
ABOTT: So you read a couple of files on
Jason Bourne and that makes you an expert?
This is my case, Ward.
MARTIN: Enough. I want you
both on that plane.
We are, all of us, going to do
what we were either too lazy or
inept to do the last time around.
We're gonna find this son of
a bitch and take him down.
I'm not having Jason Bourne
destroy any more of this agency.
Is that
definitive enough for you?
Yes.
PAMELA: Jason Bourne is armed
and extremely dangerous.
Last week in Berlin,
he assassinated two men,
one a highly experienced
field officer.
I want that area...
he assassinated two men,
one a highly experienced
field officer.
I want that area secured. I want any evidence
secured, and I want it done right now.
(CLICKING)
CONKLIN: This is not a drill,
soldier.
This is not a drill, soldier.
Are we clear on that?
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(GASPING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
(BELL TOLLING)
CRONIN: You'd been working
at Treadstone for three years
and your cover at
the time was what?
NICKY: That I was an
American student in Paris.
CRONIN: And what exactly did your job
with Treadstone in Paris consist of?
NICKY: I had two responsibilities.
One was to coordinate
logistical operations.
The other was to monitor
the health of the agents.
- Health, meaning what?
- Their mental health.
NICKY: Because of what
they had been through,
they were prone to
a variety of problems.
PAMELA: What kind of problems?
NICKY: Depression, anger,
compulsive behaviors.
They had physical symptoms.
Headaches,
sensitivity to light.
- Amnesia?
- Before Bourne? No.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
CRONIN: The plane's ready.
ABOTT: There's a car
waiting for you.
Good luck.
PAMELA: No. You were
his local contact.
You were with him
the night Conklin died.
You're coming with us.
(BEEPING)
Langley pulled an image out of Naples.
It's uploading right now.
It's coming in now.
WOMAN: I need clearance.
He's not hiding,
that's for sure.
Why Naples? Why now?
Could be random.
WOMAN: Zoom in.
Maybe he's running.
On his own passport?
PAMELA: What is
he actually doing?
He's making his first mistake.
NICKY: It"s not a mistake.
They don't make mistakes.
They don't do random.
There's always an objective.
Always a target.
The objectives and targets
always came from us.
Who's giving them to him now?
Scary version?
He is.
(BEEPING)
BOURNE: I emptied it.
JARDA: It felt a little light.
Put it down.
Front.
JARDA: Sorry. Old habits.
BOURNE: Use your teeth.
JARDA: Word in the Ether was
you'd lost your memory.
You still should've moved.
What do you want?
Conklin.
JARDA: He's dead.
Shot dead in Paris.
Dead the night you walked out.
BOURNE: So who's running
Treadstone now?
Nobody.
They shut it down.
It's over.
We're the last two.
BOURNE: If it's over, then why
are they still after me?
I don't know.
Ever heard
the name Pamela Landy?
I don't know who that is.
Pamela Landy in Berlin.
What's going on in Berlin?
JARDA: I don't know.
Why would I lie?
I thought you
were here to kill me.
BOURNE: What'd you do?
I'm sorry.
Did you call it in?
Get up. Come on.
You have a car out front?
JARDA: The keys are
in my coat pocket.
But we should...
What? Go out the back.
I have another car.
(PHONE RINGING)
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(PANTING)
(HISSING)
(CAR ALARMS BLARING)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(PHONE RINGING)
(MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(BEEPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
Pamela Landy, please.
One moment, please.
Thank you.
(PHONE RINGING)
I wanted to call a guest.
Pamela Landy.
Just one second, please.
Hello?
PAMELA: Hello?
I'm sorry, sir.
The phone's busy right now.
I'll just call later.
Thank you.
PAMELA: Okay. Let's take a look at the timeline.
What's Bourne's objective?
Now, I wanna break
this out in boxes.
Naples outbound.
Check everything.
Flights, trains,
police reports.
That's box one.
Teddy, that's yours.
Got it.
PAMELA: Box numBer two.
Call it "Prior Connections."
I want to rerun all Bourne's
Treadstone material. Every footstep.
Kim, Box three. I want to
identify his method of travel.
Stay on the local cops.
We need a vehicle, a
parking ticket, something.
Langley's offered to upload
any satellite imaging we need.
So let's find
a target for them.
Danny, box four.
I need fresh eyes.
Review the buy where
we lost the Neski files.
Timeline it with what we know
about Bourne's movements.
Turn it upside down
and see what we find.
Come on, guys. We ran this guy's life
with total control for all those years.
We should be
a step ahead of him.
You wanna go home?
Find Jason Bourne.
(DIALING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Pamela Landy.
This is Jason Bourne.
Bourne?
It"s Bourne.
We need 90 seconds to
triangulate his position.
What do you want?
BOURNE: Are you running Treadstone?
Treadstone was closed down
two years ago.
You know that.
Then who's planning
the missions now?
There are no missions.
It's over.
BOURNE: Then what do
you want with me?
Berlin.
Have you forgotten
what happened in Berlin?
(ECHOING) You killed
two people, Bourne.
MAN: Vladimir Neski.
Bourne?
I wanna come in.
Okay.
How do you wanna do it?
MAN: We need 35 seconds.
I need someone I
know to Bring me in.
Who?
There was a girl in Paris.
She was part of the program.
She used to handle logistics.
Alexanderstrasse, 30 minutes,
under the World Clock.
Send her alone.
Give her your phone.
What if I can't find her?
BOURNE: It's easy. She's
standing right next to you.
There's just so many of them, sir.
Here it is.
MAN: It's the second quadrant.
Kurt, pull it up.
MAN 1: Where is it?
MAN: Get the second quadrant,
please, and pull it all the way up.
The clock is right here. Shit, he's put
her right in the middle of everything.
This is a security nightmare.
There is no way we are
going to get her covered.
ABOTT: Call a mayday
into Berlin station.
We need snipers, DOD,
whatever they've got.
PAMELA: No snipers. No snipers.
You put snipers on the roof and it'll
scare him off, and I need answers.
ABOTT: You can't really
believe he wants to come in.
PAMELA: He knows something
about the Neski case.
And I'm not gonna pass up this
chance to find out what it is.
Don"t be a fool.
Not when we"re this close.
Are we talking about protecting
Nicky or killing Bourne?
We're talking
about killing Bourne.
We're talking about
the next dead body.
It might be Nicky.
It will be someone.
You're not hearing me. Bourne
dead gives me nothing.
ABOTT: Can I talk to
you privately?
- What?
- I know how you're feeling.
You lost two men in Berlin, and
you want it to mean something.
But nothing Bourne gives you
will bring your men back.
Nothing in those files makes
their sacrifice worthwhile.
You have to let go.
We're professionals.
When an operation
goes bad, we tie it off.
If there's something you're
not telling me, I want it now
before I send
that girl out there.
Do you understand?
You talk about this stuff
like you read it in a book.
What do you want to do?
Put the snipers in place.
If things go bad,
we take him out.
You got it.
(WOMAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(CHANTING IN GERMAN)
Hub, this is Survey One.
We have a crowd moving in.
It's some sort
of protest march.
I'm sorry. This is
as close as I can get.
Survey Two, can you get
in any closer, please?
Kurt, make sure
the south end is covered.
KURT: Roger.
Affirmative.
Copy that.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
BOURNE: There's a tram coming
towards you. Get on it.
MAN: She's moving to the tram.
Where's it going?
MAN: The tram is going
to Alexanderplatz Station.
CRONIN: Alexanderplatz.
Survey Five, I can't see him.
I don't see him.
HuB, this is Survey Two,
she's getting on the tram.
She's getting on the tram.
Zoom in on the tram.
Bourne's on the tram.
I don't think he's on the tram.
He's on the tram.
Send them in to follow. Tell
them to keep their distance.
MAN: Okay, Delta, let's go.
Get on it.
Come on. Let's go.
PAMELA: Tell them to hurry.
ABBOTT: There's nothing
on the south side.
Alexanderplatz Station,
25 seconds.
This is Survey Three. There's
a lot of protesters here.
There's no way we can
cover her out there.
Get her out of there.
Go! Delta, move! Now!
She's not here.
She's gone.
God damn it!
They are not on the tram.
NICKY: Jason, please don't hurt me.
BOURNE: What were my words?
What did I say?
I said leave me alone,
leave me out of it.
NICKY: I did. I swear. Jason, I
told them that I Believed you.
BOURNE: I'm gonna ask you
some simple questions.
You're gonna
answer me honestly,
or I swear to God
I'm gonna kill you.
Delta, give me something.
I need something.
MAN: They're on it!
They're on it!
BOURNE: Who's Pamela Landy?
NICKY: She's a task force chief.
BOURNE: Is she running Treadstone?
NICKY: No,
she's the deputy director.
Why is she trying to kill me?
Last week
an Agency field officer
tried to make a Buy
off of one of her ops.
He was trying to sell out
a mole or something.
- And?
- And you got to him before we did.
- I killed him?
- You left a print.
And they were partial prints
that trace Back to Treadstone.
They know it was you.
That is insane.
Why are you doing this?
Why come back now?
Landy will find...
BOURNE: Just stop.
Last week I was 4,000 miles away
in India, watching Marie die.
They came for me, and
they killed her instead.
This ends now.
PAMELA: Find her.
What do you people want with me?
Why are you trying to frame me?
Please! I'm only here because of Paris.
Abbott dragged us...
Abbott? Who's Abbott?
Conklin's boss.
He shut down Treadstone.
- Is he here in Berlin?
- Yes.
BOURNE: Did he run Treadstone?
Did he run Treadstone?
Yes. Conklin reported to him.
Please. Please, I swear.
All right, what was Landy buying?
What kind of files?
NICKY: Conklin. Stuff on Conklin.
It was something to do
with a Russian politician.
BOURNE: Neski.
NICKY: What? What are
you talking about?
CONKLIN: Training is over.
Training is over.
BOURNE: When was I here in Berlin?
What are you talking about?
BOURNE: For Treadstone. You know my file.
I did a job here.
When? No, you never
worked in Berlin before.
My first job. In Berlin.
I did a job here.
You know my file.
No. You've never
worked Berlin before.
My first job!
No, your first
assignment was Geneva.
You fucking people!
BOURNE: I swear! I swear!
I know I was here, Nicky!
It's not in your file!
I know I was here!
No, I swear.
Oh, please!
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(GUN FIRING)
(SOBBING)
CRONIN: Pam, I want to show you something.
It's in Alexanderplatz.
We got three levels,
we got 15 tunnels.
They're all converging
in a five-block radius.
Over here, Luftschutzbunker.
That was an old war shelter.
PAMELA: How many men
are out there?
Two coming down
the back stairs.
The rest are
fanned out for a search.
What's our
security situation here?
Where, "here"? The ground?
Here, here.
In the building.
Check everything, and recheck all the
stairwells, all the hallways, everything.
It"s done.
Okay, let's go public.
Release his photo
to the Berlin police.
And check out his story about
the girlfriend in India, too.
I'm on it.
ABOTT: You're in a big
puddle of shit, Pamela,
and you don't
have the shoes for it.
PAMELA: He said he didn't
know anything about Berlin.
ABOTT: He knew that Nicky
was wearing a wire.
Don't you think that
was for our benefit?
PAMELA: He didn't sound like
a man in control to me.
We know he was in Berlin.
His mind is broken.
We broke it.
And now...
What now? Terminate him?
You've been pushing that
agenda ever since we got here.
He also said you were running Treadstone.
Should we believe that, too?
I'm convinced that
Bourne knows something.
He knows that you're after him
and in the interest of self-preservation
you might start with that.
Check on those photos.
Have they gone out?
DANNY: I need to
show you something.
(BEEPING)
All right, I
finished my box work
but I wanted to show you
before I showed Landy.
I came down here last night because
none of this is making any sense.
I mean, I'm with you. Conklin was a nut.
But a traitor?
I just can't get there.
What do you have, Danny?
DANNY: All right, you put a four-gram Kel on
here, it's gonna take out power to the building.
You know that.
There were two charges that were
supposed to go off simultaneously.
The second one,
the one over here,
didn't go off.
Now, first of all,
this is nothing.
It's a sub-line
for the breaker above.
And second, why put the
charge all the way down here?
If you're good enough to get
in here and handle the gear,
you're good enough to know
you don't need this.
Bourne would know.
It was staged?
Is it a slam-dunk? No.
But what if somebody were
trying to cover their tracks
by blaming Conklin and Bourne?
DANNY: What if Bourne didn't
have anything to do with this?
Show me again.
All right.
Well, you put...
(GRUNTING)
CONKLIN: Pull over.
He's getting out.
This is not a drill, soldier.
We clear on that?
This is a live project,
and you're a go.
I'll see you on the other side.
Good evening, sir.
How can I help you?
Yeah, hi. I want to get
a room for the night.
Do you have a reservation?
No.
Actually, is Room 645 available?
I've stayed there before.
I'm sorry, sir.
That room is occupied.
How about Room 644?
It's right across the hall.
Sir?
644?
That's fine. Thank you.
I just need your
passport and signature.
Right here, please.
Have a nice night.
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Where?
Brecker Hotel.
Okay, we're there. Take the van!
- Brecker? How far?
- About five, six minutes.
(ALL SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(WOMAN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(MAN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
(MUFFLED GUNSHOTS)
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
CONKLIN: Congratulations,
soldier.
Training is over.
(PHONE RINGING)
(SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(ALL SHOUTING)
Go!
(SHOUTING)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
Black coat, possibly leather,
dark T-shirt, dark pants.
The cops out there wanna corral all the
guests together out on the sidewalk
and check them out one by one.
PAMELA:
That will really work.
What the hell's he doing here?
Maybe he just
wanted to stay the night.
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(POLICE SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(GRUNTING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(DOOR HISSING)
- They missed him?
- Yeah, so far.
But they found Nicky.
She's back at the Westin.
Bourne let her go.
He let her go?
Yeah.
Where's Danny Zorn?
He ought to head over
there and debrief her.
Why did Bourne come here?
We don't know yet.
Landy's upstairs
in one of the rooms.
She said she'd call
you when she's done.
Okay.
ABOTT: I think I'll take
a cab back to the hotel.
CRONIN: So the room he checked
into was across the hall.
Why would he come in here?
What are you thinking?
PAMELA: I recognize this
room from a photo.
There was a chalk
outline right here
around the body
of Vladimir Neski.
CRONIN: This is where
his wife killed him?
PAMELA: Do you still think
CRONIN: Guess he got out
through this window.
We just got word
from the Berlin police.
They found Danny Zorn's body.
PAMELA: I want you two
to stay on Bourne.
Check everything
that's out there.
Call Abbott. Tell him to
wait for me in his hotel.
I'm coming to see him.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
GRETKOV: Da.
ABOTT: It's me.
They're onto Neski.
GRETKOV: This is not
a clean phone.
ABOTT: They can't prove
anything without Bourne.
Kill Bourne, and you
kill this investigation.
GRETKOV: I'm afraid, Ward, the time
has come for us to part company.
ABOTT: Listen, Yuri, you bought those oil leases
with $20 million in stolen CIA seed money.
You owe me.
GRETKOV: I gave you your cut.
We both got rich.
I don't owe you anything.
ABOTT: The plan can still be salvaged.
Just get Bourne. Do you hear me?
He's still out there.
Now get him.
Get Jason...
(DIAL TONE DRONING)
ABOTT: I don't suppose it'll do me
much good to cry for help, huh?
BOURNE: Not much.
You killed her.
ABOTT: It was a mistake.
It was supposed to be you.
There were files linking
me to the Neski murder.
If the files disappeared
and they suspected you,
they'd be chasing
a ghost for 10 years.
BOURNE: So we got in the way.
Is that why Neski died?
Is that why you killed Marie?
ABOTT: You killed Marie,
the minute you climbed
into her car.
The minute you entered
her life, she was dead.
BOURNE: I told you people to leave us alone.
I fell off the grid.
I was halfway around the world.
ABOTT: There's no place it
won't catch up to you.
It's how every story ends.
It's what you are,
Jason, a killer.
You always will be.
Go ahead. Go on.
Go on! Do it! Do it!
BOURNE: She wouldn't want me to.
That's the only
reason you're alive.
(PHONES RINGING)
(SIGHING)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
ABOTT: I'm a patriot.
I serve my country.
PAMELA: And Danny Zorn? What was he?
Unlucky.
Collateral damage.
PAMELA: So what do we do now?
I'm not sorry.
(GASPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
No, no, no, forget it.
Call me as soon as he's here.
No, that"s nothing.
We could synch-up.
Who's this guy?
WOMAN: Platform P.
ABBOTT: Go ahead. Go on.
Go on! Do it! Do it!
BOURNE: She wouldn't want me to.
That's the only
reason you're alive.
CRONIN: Got a call from Langley.
They're going through
Abbott's records
and Marshall wants to know
what's going on with Bourne.
Wait, Teddy. Teddy, who's this?
Look at this guy.
He's about to enter.
Right there! There!
Right through there.
That's Bourne.
Get down here! We got something!
We got him!
We got a sighting!
Check it out!
There. I got it on
the big monitor. Hold on.
There he comes again.
WOMAN: Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
He's just entered frame.
It "s the coat. That" s him!
What train is that?
That's the train to Moscow.
CRONIN: Why the hell
would he go to Moscow?
PAMELA: Get me the Russian
Interior Ministry.
(LOUD TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(PHONE RINGING)
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
(GUN FIRING)
(GRUNTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(YELLING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
(HORN BLARING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
IRENA: I speak English.
BOURNE: I'm not gonna hurt you.
I won't hurt you.
You're older.
Older than I thought you'd be.
That picture.
Does that mean a lot to you?
IRENA: It's nothing.
It's just a picture.
BOURNE: No.
It's because you
don't know how they died.
I do.
No, you don't.
I would want to know.
I would want to know that my...
That my mother
didn't kill my father,
that she didn't kill herself.
What?
BOURNE: It's not what
happened to your parents.
I killed them.
It was my job.
It was my first time.
Your father was
supposed to be alone.
But then your mother
came out of nowhere
and I had to change my plan.
It changes things,
that knowledge.
Doesn"t it?
When what you love
gets taken from you,
you wanna know the truth.
I'm sorry.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
PAMELA: Pamela Landy.
BOURNE: I hear you're
still looking for me.
PAMELA: Bourne?
BOURNE: What do you want?
PAMELA: I wanted to thank you
for the tape.
We got what we needed.
It's all tied off.
It's over.
I guess I owe you an apology.
BOURNE: Is that official?
PAMELA: No. Off the record.
You know how it is.
BOURNE: Goodbye.
PAMELA: Wait. Wait.
David Webb.
That's your real name.
You were Born 4-15-7
1 in Nixa, Missouri.
Why don't you come in,
and we'll talk about it?
Bourne?
BOURNE: Get some rest, Pam.
You look tired.
(FAST-PACED ROCK MUSIC)
♪ ♪ Extreme ways are back again ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Extreme places I didn't know ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I broke everything new again ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Everything that I'd owned ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I threw it out the windows
Came along ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Extreme ways I know
will part the colors of my sea ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Perfect color me ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Extreme ways that help me ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ They help me out late at night ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Extreme places I had gone ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ That never see any light ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Dirty basements, dirty noise ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Dirty places comin'through ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Extreme worlds alone ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Did you ever like it planned ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I would stand in line for this ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ There's always room
in life for this ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Then it fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Then it fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Then it fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Like it always does ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Always does ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Extreme sounds that told me ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ They held me down every night ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I didn't have much to say ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I didn't give up the light ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I closed my eyes and closed myself ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ And closed my world ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ And never opened up to anything ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ That could get me at all ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I had to close down everything ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I had to close down my mind ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Too many things to cover me ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Too much can make me blind ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I've seen so much in so many places ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ So many heartaches, so many faces ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ So many dirty things ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ You couldn't even believe ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ I would stand in line for this ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It's always good in life for this ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Then it fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Then it fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Then it fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ It fell apart ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Oh, baby ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Like it always does ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ Always does ♪ ♪