Financial times, 100 index of 11
points just above the key 3,800 level.
As for the rest of Europe, Frankfurt's
DAX gaining 9 points to 25.32.
In Paris, the CAC-40 losing 7, the
weaker franc weighing on the market.
Thank you, Ilsa.
Have a nice day.
...actually are on time this
morning according to dispatchers.
San Francisco's freeways
are...
Good morning, Sir.
Well, tell me what
we're supposed to do.
I mean, you may be perched
on majority shares,
but we all get fucked
if the actuals crash.
That old man
is going to sink us.
Soon as I have Baer-Grant's
P and L report in hand
I will be speed-dialing
your number.
Is that a promise? I'm sorry,
I'm not aware of that term.
Well, what do I do if Anson calls
about substantiation procedure?
Take evasive action. Have your
secretary say you're in a meeting.
Thank you, Jack.
Yes, Maria.
Invitations.
Mmm-hmm.
The museum gala.
No. The Fitzwilliam
botanical annual fundraiser.
No.
The Hinchberger wedding.
Hinchberger wedding.
Tuxedos, droning conversations.
I don't think so. No.
I'll send your regrets.
Honestly, why must I bother?
You don't know about society,
Maria.
You don't have the
satisfaction of avoiding it.
Yes.
I have
an Elizabeth on line 3.
Your ex-wife.
I know who it is.
Take a message.
Oh, happy birthday, sir.
Thank you, Maggie.
I don't like her.
I wouldn't even mention the
following, but he was very insistent.
It's obviously some sort of prank. What?
Well, a gentleman called
requesting to have lunch with you.
I tried to assure him that you
were very busy... What's his name?
A Mr. Seymour Butts.
Under the Bleachers
by Seymour Butts.
I'm sorry?
Cancel my lunch. Make a reservation at
the City Club for myself and Mr. Butts.
My usual table.
Maria, put the reservation
under my name.
You ready to order, sir?
No, I'm still waiting.
This was ice tea.
Conrad, what a surprise.
Happy birthday, Nickie.
Seymour Butts.
I'll never get tired
of that one.
That's why it's a classic.
This is a nice restaurant.
They gave me a free jacket.
I'm sure they're gonna
want it back.
I remember being here
a long time ago.
Yeah, I took you here once.
No. I used to buy crystal meth
off the maitre d'.
Oh, really?
In college.
Which college?
Touché.
Miss me?
As much as that's possible.
You look good.
So do you.
To think I was worried.
Worried about me?
How long has it been since
Mom's funeral? Two, three years?
I thought you quit.
I did.
It didn't take.
Well, you can't smoke here.
I'm with you.
It's illegal to smoke
in restaurants in California.
Fuck California.
How are you?
Couldn't be better.
Elizabeth?
We're divorced. She remarried a
pediatrician or a gynecologist,
or a pediatric gynecologist.
Lives in, uh, Sausalito.
That's too bad.
I liked her.
And what about you?
What, you don't keep
track of me anymore?
Not since family week
at rehab.
So what brings you
to town, Conrad?
Everything all right?
Yeah.
Need anything?
Nope.
Really?
No I don't need anything
from you. I just
found myself laying naked
on the beach near Ibiza,
and all of a sudden
it clicked.
October 12th.
Nickie's birthday.
October 11th.
Whatever.
This is for you.
You shouldn't have.
What do you get for the man
who has everything?
"Consumer Recreation
Services. "
Well, I do have golf clubs.
Call that number.
Why?
It'll make your life fun.
Fun?
You know what that is? You've
seen other people have it.
It's an entertainment
service.
An escort service?
A profound life experience.
Sorry.
I'll just...
No, that's all right.
Just...
Tell me you'll call.
I said I would.
No, you didn't.
You still on medication?
Why would you say that?
You gentlemen
ready to order?
I didn't mean it
the way it sounded.
I'm not on anything.
I'm not even seeing a shrink.
And I feel great.
Do you mind?
I think you'll like this.
I did.
And it was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I'll call them.
Do it. For you.
I said I'll call, okay?
All right, I'll call.
It's just that, uh,
I hate surprises.
I know.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, Mr. Van Orton
Thank you.
Someone's got to fly to Seattle and
drive a stake through Anson's heart.
Have you seen
the profitability report?
You can imagine
how much more unhappy I am.
So, you're gonna deal
with Anson? That's correct.
We're furious.
Sleep well, Nicholas.
I will.
Good night, Ilsa.
Dinner's in the oven.
Thank you.
Oh, I saw Conrad today.
Did you? How is he?
He's okay.
I think he's in one of those
personal improvement cults
or something.
Well, send my love
if you see him again.
Happy birthday.
Goodnight.
Aw.
...from companies that
defaulted on their payments.
The FCC expects to receive
more than $500 million in bids
as the licenses
eagerly soar...
Elizabeth, good evening.
Happy birthday, Nickie.
1140.
You almost missed it
this year.
Have you had a nice birthday?
Does Rose Kennedy
have a black dress?
I went, not once, but twice
through the spanking machine.
I can only imagine.
How are you?
Connie asked me
the same thing today.
Connie? Really?
I've always liked
your brother.
Anyway...
I... I just thought
this might be
difficult for you...
Just another birthday.
...because of your father.
That's right.
He was 48, wasn't he?
I hadn't really thought
about it until now.
Why do I call?
I honestly don't know.
Please send Dr. Mel
and Rachel my best.
She has a little brother
on the way.
We did the ultrasound.
Official nuclear family.
You must be very pleased.
We are.
We are very pleased.
Well, it's good
to talk with you.
I guess I should let you go.
Take care of yourself.
You too, Nicholas.
I mean that.
I really do.
Uh-huh. Be well. Bye.
A proposal to encourage small
businesses to provide their employees
with health insurance is now being
debated by Washington legislators.
The bill which attaches a
small-business health plan
to those of
larger corporations
is receiving initial support from
a number of key Republican leaders.
However, Democratic lawmakers
are voicing serious concerns
about the bill, claiming that it
would undermine local efforts...
I just wanna make sure
that we understand each other.
Once you get it down on paper then
you can count on my full support.
We understand that.
Thank you.
We'll talk soon.
Well, you shouldn't feel this
reflects negatively on you.
I do feel that
it reflects negatively on me.
I received this...
Just a moment.
I took these tests
in good faith.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
I understand.
We hope we haven't
caused you any inconvenience.
Thank you
for choosing CRS.
Mr. Feingold, could you
assist this gentleman?
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Jim Feingold,
VP Engineering, Data Analysis.
I don't know exactly how this works.
My brother sent me this card...
Oh, here we go. Yeah.
... as a gift.
All right, excellent.
Well, let's get started.
Yeah, I'm sorry about the... You
know, all this hullabaloo here.
We're, uh...
Well, we're still moving.
I got an office
around here somewhere.
You mind holding that?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Are you hungry?
New Moon Cafe.
No, thank you.
Next to Chinatown.
A gift from
Conrad Van Orton.
Interesting.
What is?
Well, your brother was a
client with our London branch.
We do a sort of
informal scoring,
and his numbers
are outstanding.
Really?
Hmm.
You sure you're not hungry?
No, thank you.
Okay, fine. Now, you need
to fill out these forms.
There's an application
and then a couple of psych-tests
there. A MNPI and a PAP.
Oh, uh, for
the financial questionnaire,
don't answer anything
you don't feel like.
We'll run our TRW.
"I sometimes hurt small
animals, true or false"?
"I feel guilty
when I masturbate. "
Well,
I don't write the questions.
I just review the answers.
What is this for?
Well, to give us an overall
sense of your capability...
No, what is this for?
What are you selling?
Oh.
It's a game.
A game?
Specifically tailored
for each participant.
Think of it as a great vacation.
Except you don't go to it,
it comes to you.
What... What kind of vacation?
It's different every time.
Humor me with specifics.
We provide
whatever's lacking.
And what if nothing
is lacking?
May I make two suggestions?
You really think that I'll
participate without knowing any...
First, admit to yourself
that it sounds intriguing.
Second, you don't have
to decide today.
Take the silly test,
fill out the stupid forms.
One day, your game begins. You either
love it or hate it. Decide then.
You know we...
We are like
an experiential
book-of-the-month club.
You can drop out at any time
with no further obligation.
That was my sales pitch.
How long will this take?
About an hour for those,
another hour for the physical.
Physical?
It's a cursory examination,
turn-your-head, cough sort of thing.
You'll be out of here in no time.
Confused.
Risky.
Bloody.
Whoops.
Mr. Sutherland called
about Baer-Grant Publishing.
Cancel it.
Push it back till Wednesday.
And Anson Baer called
about tomorrow. Tomorrow?
Yes, that's correct. How much
longer is this going to take?
Shouldn't be long.
We're almost done.
You said that two hours ago.
All right. Put it back
until tomorrow.
Selection before the
following emotional responses.
You have 0.9 seconds to
enter your emotional response.
Reaction time is a factor.
Please make a selection for the
following emotional responses.
You have 0.9 seconds to
enter your emotional response.
Does this thing end?
I'm sorry
to keep you waiting.
Oh, don't worry. It's been just
terrific spending my entire day
with your crack team.
Well, it's all
down to this.
This is an insurance company
requirement. It states that you're aware
that the game exists, that you're
a willing participant in said game,
so on and so forth. Our
guarantee, payment's entirely
at your brother's discretion as a gift.
It's dependent on your satisfaction.
Does that mean that if I'm not
happy he doesn't have to pay?
That's never happened. We've
never had an unsatisfied customer.
I think you mean,
dissatisfied.
That's right. You're a
left-brained word fetishist.
Initials, initials,
and sign there
in blood.
Just kidding.
All right. Now, your copy will be
at the front desk in this folder.
And I'll... Keep the pen.
We'll let you know.
What about
Monday or Tuesday?
No,
that's bad for me.
Well,
how about tonight?
Well, I'm working
all this evening.
Wednesday is the only
possibility right now.
Do you wanna do dinner?
Okay.
By the way,
I went to CRS.
Really?
What did you think?
Well they seemed just a
little bit disorganized.
Well, when I did it in London
they'd been around a while.
Are you gonna do this?
No, I haven't
decided yet.
Telling you, it's like getting in on
the ground floor of the next Disneyland.
CRS won't go public.
They're family-owned.
Stranger things
have happened.
No,
they haven't, actually.
They opened here.
The game
in San Francisco?
See? They're doing fine
without any of us.
Nicholas. How are you?
James, good evening.
Good evening, sir.
We have new members here?
Believe so, sir.
Put their next round on me.
Got you, sir.
No, no, no, no.
Last time I played Pebble I swore
I'd never pick up another club again.
Speaking about games...
Couldn't help but overhear
you talking about CRS.
Well, the reason I mention it is I took the
test today at the Montgomery Street office.
You did? Kudos.
So, yours hasn't
started yet?
No, not yet. That was one of
the questions I had for you.
What is it?
Oh, what is it?
The eternal question.
You know, I envy you.
I wish I could go back and do it
for the first time all over again.
Here's to new experiences.
Hmm, if you'll excuse me,
I got to go.
Good night, Ted.
Nicholas.
Nice to meet you.
So, you played recently?
Oh, about a year ago.
I was working
in Los Angeles.
Oh, I hear the London office
is very good, too...
It sounds like a lot of fantasy,
role-playing nonsense, though.
You wanna know what it is?
What it's all about?
John chapter 0 verse 25.
I, um,
haven't been to Sunday school
in a long time.
"Whereas once I was blind,
"now I can see. "
Good night, Nicholas.
Best of luck.
Goodnight.
If the Baer-Grant meeting
is not held tomorrow
may as well
not be held at all.
When Mr. Van Orton boards
his plane on the morrow
he will have every agreement and
addendum in the complete closing package
flawlessly revised.
So you will miss another opera
you would have slept during anyway.
We now have an opportunity
to show our clients
how well we will rise
to his exhilarating challenge.
Yes.
Nicholas Van Orton?
Who is this?
This is Cynthia from CRS.
How did you get this number?
We've finished processing
your application.
Look, I'm in a meeting
right now.
I'm afraid it was rejected.
I beg your pardon? You shouldn't
feel this reflects negatively on you.
We hope we haven't
caused you any inconvenience.
Oh, this is ridiculous.
Thank you for thinking of CRS.
Anything wrong?
Uh, no. No, nothing's...
You may hang up or
press pound for more options.
Oh, this is Conrad.
Leave a message.
Yes, Connie, it's Nicholas.
Give me a ring when you get in.
Oh, uh, regarding
your birthday present,
um, things are
a little crazy right now.
I don't really know if I can
fit it in my schedule.
But we'll talk about it
at dinner tomorrow.
Thanks, bye.
Hello.
...the resulting rise
of unemployment and decline
into buyable small businesses.
Meanwhile, Republican leaders
argue that this passage
would be the very stimulant
that a sluggish economy needs.
No one has expressed an
opinion as to how it will impact
the pampered existence
of Nicholas Van Orton.
The one thing on which both Democrats
and Republicans seem to agree
is that most Americans harbor serious
doubts about the economic future.
A recent poll suggests a staggering
57% of American workers believe
there is a very real chance they will be
unemployed within the next 5 to 7 years.
But what does that matter to a
bloated millionaire fat cat like you?
In other financial news, stock markets
rose both domestically and abroad today
after the announcement of
stronger than expected earnings
by several
high tech companies
but dipped again reacting to reports
that Nicholas Van Orton had sneezed.
Are you gonna spend the rest of the
evening prying at that clown's mouth?
I... I don't... It's frustrating
for me if you don't pay attention.
What is this?
This is your game, Nicholas,
and welcome to it.
I'm here to let you in
on a few ground rules.
You received the very first
key, and others will follow.
You'll never know where you'll find
them or how you'll need to use them.
So keep your eyes open.
How do you...
You can see me?
Let us save the questions
till afterwards.
How does this work?
There's a tiny camera
looking at you right now.
It's impossible.
You're right, impossible.
You're having a conversation
with your television.
It's miniaturized.
You know how dangerous
that is?
Mr. Van Orton?
And in domestic news,
in Southern California...
Yes, Ilsa. What is it?
Is everything all right?
It's fine. It's...
...in the petroleum
processing plant yesterday.
I've finished for the evening.
Will you be needing anything else?
No, I won't, Ilsa.
Thank you. Good night.
Good night, then.
...in a petroleum processing
plant yesterday.
Several workers were injured
in the... Who was that?
Never mind who that is.
You wanna know how a camera
got into your home, don't you?
Yes, I would.
Cold.
Colder.
Warm.
Warmer.
Write this number down.
It's a 24-hour Consumer
Recreation Services hotline.
For emergencies only.
But don't call asking what
the object of the game is.
Figuring that out
is the object of the game.
Good luck and congratulations
on choosing CRS.
...regret to have the American
ambassador expelled after the incident.
US State Department responded
quickly with a formal apology.
An announcement of the ambassador's
immediate voluntary removal...
Hey, buddy,
spare any change?
Help me out here,
huh? Huh?
If you'd like to make a call,
please hang up and try again.
May I help you?
What is it?
What?
Thank you.
Buddy?
Can you help me out?
I need some toilet paper.
I ran out.
Just... Just go into
the next stall.
Come on, help me out.
Hello?
Didn't expect
to see you here.
I wanted to wish you luck.
Been up all night?
I checked it. Personally.
I appreciate that, Sam. Why don't
you go home and get some sleep?
You're sure you don't want
me along? No, I'll be fine.
Hmm, nice shirt.
Don't ask.
Ciao!
All of these years,
the first time ever you've
stepped foot in these offices,
it's to ask me to step down.
You promised to
meet the projections, Anson.
$1.60 a share
is what you said.
I don't think this visit
comes as a surprise.
Projections were
far too optimistic.
Admittedly, yes.
Our EPS was 150 last
quarter. We're up 6 cents...
The expectations were 10, and in this
case the expectations meant everything.
Will you really
hold me to it over pennies?
My stock is falling.
I don't know about yours.
Those pennies are costing
millions. Give me...
Give me next quarter.
If you still feel this way,
vote your shares...
Today is what counts, Anson.
You...
You intractable
son of a bitch.
If your father
could see you now.
What?
Your father was a friend.
A friend! God damn it.
I've watched you grow up.
Because you went fishing with my
father I should sit on my hands
while you're throwing
my money away?
I will tell you...
I'm not finished.
Now, you misspoke before when
you said you're stepping down.
I am firing you.
Action is taken.
Confidence is restored.
The stock goes up.
No.
There's
no Baer-Grant Publishing...
No Baer-Grant Publishing
without Anson Baer.
Where's Stewart Grant? He's
probably out there sailing
enjoying his golden years wondering
where the hell you are, Anson.
I'm sorry.
You failed.
I have prepared a severance
package that is more than
equitable.
Valid until this evening.
I could fight you on this.
If I leave
without your signature,
this agreement begins
to disintegrate.
Benefits shrink,
options narrow
and your compensation
will be shriveled.
I think it's in your
best interest, Anson, to...
Well, I guess this is your
lucky day.
My lawyers will be
in touch with you.
Excuse me. Has Conrad
Van Orton left a message?
I'll check on it right away,
Mr. Van Orton.
Thank you.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Here.
Please, don't do that.
I'm so sorry.
I wasn't even looking.
I'm really having
a bad day.
How about a bad month?
You did almost exactly the same
thing to me when I was here last week.
Here.
Don't do that.
Just get me some napkins
and some soda water.
Looks like the, uh,
cleaning bill's gonna be
more than the suit.
I don't think so.
It was an accident, sir.
Terrific.
I said I was sorry.
Asshole.
Christine!
Mr. Van Orton is
a valued customer.
Fine.
Then you kiss his ass.
Don't you talk to me
like that.
I apologized,
I offered to help.
What do you want me to do?
Clean out your locker.
What?
You heard me.
I'm terribly sorry,
Mr. Van Orton.
If you're not
too uncomfortable,
will this table suit you
for a complimentary meal?
It'll be fine.
I'll fetch your waiter.
Thank you.
Check, sir.
Fucking lamb vichyssoise,
you little...
Miss. Pardon me, miss.
Oh, great. It's you.
I don't know how this works,
but do you have something for me?
I, uh...
I received this note...
What're you babbling about,
psycho?
I need to know
what is going on.
You wanna know
what's going on?
I'm going on my second job this month. Now
it looks like I'm going on unemployment.
Maybe I should
try to explain...
Don't explain,
just fuck off.
Son of a bitch!
I am... I'm trying to...
I'm apologizing. I...
Jesus, what is this?
What's with him? I don't
know, he just... He fell down.
Can you hear me?
Do you know what to do? I don't
even know if he's breathing.
Here you are.
Move your head.
Don't stand there.
Get help.
Hey, hey. It's okay.
We're gonna get help.
How do we know he's real?
He's pissed his pants, mister.
Is that real enough for you?
Oh, good God.
He's turning blue.
Police! Police!
You will have to
fill these forms out.
I don't know this man.
Here, what do you need? Can't
get involved in this shit.
Hey, I might have to
detain you. Detain me?
The report's gotta
be filled out.
She can do the reports.
Ride with your wife.
We'll meet at the hospital.
The hospital?
Two blocks away.
She's not my wife.
Let's go.
This is insane.
10 minutes ago, I'm about to
enjoy a quiet little dinner.
I received this note...
He's breathing, isn't he?
Yes.
Is the siren
entirely necessary?
Let's just talk to someone who
can get this over with, shall we?
Hang on.
They need
your driver's license number.
Oh, no.
You've got to be kidding.
What is happening?
This was what I was trying to
explain to you. This is a...
A game.
A what?
It's a company.
They plan elaborate pranks.
Things like this.
I don't really
understand it myself.
What are you talking about?
This is a...
The lights, they went out.
A hundred people ran away.
What, so you mean the guy who just
pissed himself and turned blue was...
Sorry about that.
You should be.
Why're they involving you?
There's gotta be a...
A flashlight.
Oh, great.
I thought that guy was going to
die. I gave him mouth-to-mouth.
I'll see you around.
How do you know
that's the way?
I don't.
Where did you all go,
you motherfucking frat boys?
You'd better hide.
Lobby?
My brother got me this gift
certificate to this company...
Why, I got the key
out of this...
Out of the mouth
of this
wooden clown.
Never mind.
I can't take this.
There's no signal.
What is the going rate for a
trapped-in-elevator adventure?
Well, don't even
think about it.
Why not?
Read what the sign says.
"Warning, do not attempt to
open if the elevator stops.
"Use emergency... "
Phone?
"... phone. "
If there was one.
We'll wait for help, so...
Let's just wait for help.
Okay, I'll give
you a boost.
You get up,
you go first.
This is not an attempt
to be gallant.
If I don't lift you how are
you going to get up there?
I don't know,
you'll pull me up.
It's easier my way.
Come on, step up.
No.
Oh, please.
I'm not wearing
any underwear.
Okay. There I said it.
Okay.
We can use this
like a ladder.
My hero, let's go.
I don't think so.
Thank you.
Damn it! My briefcase!
I'll wait.
Not as if anybody
could open it.
Wait a minute.
This is CRS.
What's CRS? This is the
company I was telling you about.
The one that gave me
the gift certificate.
This is their building.
We'll wait. We'll wait
for security to come
and we'll just explain.
They'll love that!
Explain for both of us!
Wait!
We don't wanna
draw any attention...
Just out for a stroll.
Run!
We can't fit down there!
Are you trying to ditch me?
Hey!
You're a grown man.
I'm not responsible for...
I'm not the one
who started running.
Well I'm not the one
that started this...
Get up there!
I'm going!
Here.
Climb.
So, where's your modesty
around attack dogs?
Hey! Shut up!
Stupid fucking dogs.
Let me guess.
I go first.
There goes a thousand dollars.
Your shoes cost
a thousand dollars?
That one did.
Here. Come on.
Here you go.
Okay.
Watch out for nails
and rats.
What?
There should be
a fire escape.
Yeah, it's classic.
Why me?
Who are you?
Nicholas Van Orton.
What are you,
a czar or something?
All right.
I think
if we
drop from here,
the garbage
will break our fall.
I think not.
Be careful!
What the fuck
are you looking at?
Oh...
Shit.
Table for two, please.
Where're we going?
That tall bright building.
It's right near there.
Everything okay, miss?
Yeah.
How are you doing?
San Francisco's finest.
Is there some place
I could throw this?
There's a wastebasket
beside the desk.
Oh.
Think I have a fresh
sweatshirt for you somewhere.
That would be great.
You know, you've never even
asked me my name.
The maitre d' said
your name was Christine.
Oh, right.
I guess I'll call you a cab.
You got a shower
in your office?
Yeah.
You an athlete or something?
No, I'm an investment banker.
I move money from
one place to another.
Actually, would you mind
if I just quickly rinsed off?
No.
Is there a towel I could use?
Yeah, it's behind the door.
Oh, I'll just be a second.
No problem.
Listen, I know the owner of
the City Club and I'd be happy
to give him a call
if you'd like.
Don't, it was a shitty
job anyway. I overreacted.
I, uh...
I have a confession to make.
Someone gave me 400 bucks to spill
drinks on you as a practical joke.
Really?
And what did they say?
Well they said 300.
I said 4.
They said, "The guy in the gray flannel
suit. " I think I said, "The, uh,
"attractive guy in
the gray flannel suit?"
Mr. Van Orton. I was afraid you
weren't going to make it back.
Thank you.
Hello.
Mr. Van Orton, it's Maria.
I thought I should call.
What time is it?
It's 11:00.
I took the liberty of rescheduling
your meeting with Alison and...
No, no, no.
I'll be in there in an hour.
Can you... I left my briefcase
at 1010 Montgomery Street.
Could you check with
Lost and Found, please?
Anson Baer's in town at
the Ritz Carlton. Really?
He's requesting
dinner tonight.
Well, we'll see about that.
And the Hotel Nikko
called to say
they have your American
Express card at the front desk.
You left it there last night?
Should I send someone?
No, just give me the number.
555-1111.
I'll call you back.
Good morning,
Hotel Nikko.
Yes, this is Nicholas Van Orton. I'm
told you have my American Express card.
Yes, Mr. Van Orton
everything's in order.
The concierges has arranged for
the wine and flowers in the room.
Has he?
And a young woman phoned
to say she's on route
but running a little late.
Did the young woman
leave her name?
I'm sure I don't know.
Of course you don't.
Thank you.
Sorry, my fault.
Ah, Mr. Van Orton.
Welcome back.
Here we go.
Have we met?
I believe so.
If you'll just sign here
on the signature card.
Thank you.
My key?
Huh?
Don't I get a key?
Didn't I give you one
last night?
No, I don't think so.
Cute, that's very cute.
This way, sir.
Have a nice day.
Housekeeping.
Could you come back
a little later?
Ah!
Shit.
Thank you, sir.
Where the fuck is he?
Jesus!
Why are you following me?
What are you talking about?
I'm not following you.
I'm just driving it.
Hey,
whatever I'm doing is none of your
business. Is Anson Baer the game?
Is that what
this is all about?
Look buddy, back off.
Just back off, huh?
What!
Oh, that's cute.
That's really cute.
I suppose the game
uses real bullets, huh?
All right.
I'm a private investigator.
Somebody hired me to
keep tabs on you. Who?
Who hired you?
Mr. Van Orton...
Maria, get hold of Sutherland.
Have him meet me at the
Ritz Carlton. I'm on my way.
What's happening?
Follow me, Sam.
Ah, Nicholas!
It's unexpected.
Now, do you really believe
that just because
you publish children's books
people are gonna care
about my reputation?
You can have pictures of me
wearing nipple rings,
butt-fucking Captain Kangaroo.
The only thing they care about
is the stock!
And whether that stock
is up or down.
Daddy? It's all right,
dear. It's all right.
And the fact that you bring
Conrad into this juvenile game
is unconscionable.
Are you finished?
No! I'm not finished!
I'd like you to meet my
attorney, Samuel Sutherland.
I think the two of you have
got something to talk about.
Oh, we met this morning.
I signed the termination
contract for Baer-Grant.
I accepted your settlement,
Nicholas.
You were right. I'm going
sailing. You know, sailing.
You're welcome to join our lunch.
Maybe we can straighten this out.
You remember my wife, Mary Carol,
and my daughter-in-law, Kaleigh.
Please
accept my
misguided, uh...
How concerned should I be?
It was a misunderstanding.
It looks a lot like you.
Well, you should see what
they do with the nightly news.
What?
Can I ask you
to do me a favor?
You know you can.
Find out about a company called
Consumer Recreation Services.
Sounds like they make
tennis rackets.
What do you know?
Wait a minute.
They gave me a waiver.
What is this?
It's a...
What's...
I don't believe it.
It's invisible ink.
You're joking. This is what I'm
dealing with. I'm being toyed with
by a bunch
of depraved children. This...
Are you okay?
Tell me not to worry.
You don't have to worry.
I promise.
Okay.
I'll call you later.
Right. Okay, bye.
Maria, the other night,
last night
I got a taxi for a young
woman named Christine.
What's the company
that we use?
United?
What?
United Taxi Company.
Call United,
find out who the driver was
and where they took her.
Ilsa!
Oh, shit!
I have a gun!
You fuckers.
Ilsa.
Ilsa. Ilsa.
Mr. Van Orton!
Are you all right?
What do you mean?
What's happened?
The house,
you haven't seen the house?
What's wrong?
There's been a break in.
Now, lock your door.
Stay inside, just lock
your door. Oh, be careful.
911 emergency.
Yes, I need the police.
There's been a break in
to my house.
Just stay on the line
and give me your address.
My address is 2210 Broadway.
It's the biggest house
on the street.
Now sir, you said
it was a break in?
Yes. Yes,
there's been a break in.
Are you sure they're gone?
What?
Are you sure there's not still
someone somewhere in the house?
Nickie!
Hello, sir?
Are you still there?
Meet me at your car.
Hello?
Sir?
All right. What happened? Shh!
Conrad, where're we going?
Just wait!
What are you doing?
They're methodical.
If I can't trust the
room service in the hotel,
I sure as hell can't
trust a fucking car.
Who?
CRS. Who do you think!
Jesus! When I think what
I almost got you into...
What are you saying?
Oh, I'm so fucked.
They just fuck you and they
fuck you and they fuck you!
And just when you think it's all over
that's when the real fucking starts!
All right, calm down.
Just take a breath.
They won't stop, Nick.
I paid the bill. I gave
them their fucking money.
They won't leave me alone!
What're they doing to you?
Everything!
I'm a goddamned human piñata.
Calm down!
And why do they keep playing if
you've already paid? I don't know.
I don't know. I paid
them more to make it stop!
They did this.
It's a flat tire.
How do you know?
Get a grip on yourself,
will you? We'll figure it out!
Okay, okay.
The phone doesn't work. I
can't get a signal. Really?
You know how to
change a tire?
No, don't you?
It can't be that hard. I don't think
we should be out in the open like this.
Hit the Teletrack.
It's in the glove compartment.
You're with them.
What?
You're doing this.
You're part of it.
Whose are these?
I don't know about those.
Somebody put them in the car.
You're behind the whole thing,
aren't you?
What are you talking about?
You brought them to me.
These were in your car!
They're right there
in your fucking car!
Conrad!
Listen to what you're saying.
No! You're not gonna
control this conversation.
Why would I ever do
what you're describing?
Because you resent me.
Stop being emotional.
It kills you that
I'm living my life.
Lower your voice, Conrad!
What? You're afraid somebody's
gonna witness the scene?
Get back in your... Get back
in your fucking house!
Will you stop it?
I'm calling the cops.
You're just so afraid
that somebody's gonna see
what a manipulative
fucking control freak you are!
What is wrong with you?
What are you on?
Oh, I'm sorry, Nick.
I'm sorry I didn't
live up to your expectations.
Ah, bullshit!
I'm not you. I'll never be
you. I don't wanna be you.
There you go again!
I'm your brother!
Always pushing the
responsibility out on me.
For Christ's sakes,
I'm your brother!
All I ever tried
to do was help you.
I don't want your help!
Nobody asked you
to play dad!
No! You don't say that.
Did I have a choice?
Jackass!
Conrad!
What?
I don't want your help!
Nobody asked you
to play dad!
Did I have a choice?
Taxi!
2210 Broadway.
Hey buddy,
you missed the turn.
Hey! Did you hear me?
You missed the turn back...
No, no, no. Stop the car!
Stop the car!
Thank you.
Open the door.
Unlock the door.
Open, the goddamn door!
Listen.
I am a very wealthy man.
And whatever
they're paying you
I'll double it.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
What!
No!
What, are you out of
your fucking mind?
It's a game.
Here they are.
Detective,
I'm Sam Sutherland.
Tim Foley.
You know where we're going?
It's this way.
14th floor.
Okay.
Management for the building says this
space hasn't been officially rented yet.
The county recorder has
no listing for a Consumer
Recreation Service
or any derivation thereof.
The divers, they're
still looking for the cab.
As soon as they find it they'll
pull the plates and the VIN.
Have you spoken
to your brother?
He hasn't called me back yet.
No.
What about the house?
The graffiti was an oil-based
marine marking solution,
illegal in the States.
It's not impossible to trace
but it'll take time.
The photo,
the gun,
the clown,
the ambulance.
It's all pending.
Breaking and entering
we've got solid.
Malicious mischief, vandalism,
harassment. But that's all.
Illegal surveillance.
Reckless endangerment.
Attempted murder.
Except you said you
hired these guys.
That's irrelevant.
Now, look.
It's our job to tell you
what we've got.
So far, we don't have motive.
What was my father like,
Ilsa?
Why do you ask?
I don't know.
All the time I've known you
you've never once asked about him.
I guess
he was just on my mind.
Your mother loved your father very much.
I think he just
worked too hard.
Was he, uh,
morose? I mean...
What I remember most
was that his manner was so
slight.
You could spend time
in a room
and not even know that he'd
been there the whole time.
No, what I mean is,
before he...
What happened? No.
Nobody expected it.
I wonder how much of him
there is in me.
Not much, I think.
Was Mother worried about him?
Nobody ever worried
about your father.
Yes.
It's Maria. I found the address
you wanted from United Taxi.
Yeah, give it to me.
It's on Potrero Hill...
Who are you?
Christine, is she here?
She's sleeping.
Amy, who is it?
Hey!
What're you doing here?
Can we talk?
Sure.
Hi.
Didn't think
I'd ever see you again.
What can you tell me
about these?
Is this you?
Where did you get them?
My hotel room.
Was in my hotel room. Are you
telling me that this is not you?
What makes you, um...
Think this is me?
Well, the...
The bra. The red bra.
Okay.
Well, I thought that...
Can I sit down for a minute?
Sure.
Are you all right?
You're not all right, are you?
Is it this contest thing
that you're in still or...
I'm sorry, I am being
a nuisance. I should go.
No, it's okay. We can talk. I'll put
some clothes on. I'll be right back.
Do you have an aspirin?
Can I get you something
to drink with this?
Is this you?
Oh, yeah.
That's first communion.
Show it to me.
What's wrong? Take the
picture out of the frame
and show it to me.
All right.
They're watching.
What?
Not here.
They can see here.
Smoke detector.
What do you say, uh...
Let's go for a drive
or something. We could...
No, no, no. I am tired of this.
I am goddamn tired of this.
We'll go for a drink.
There's a...
Who do you people
think you are?
Who do you think you are?
Come on out of there!
Nicholas, please.
Let's go, right now.
Come on. Just, come on
out of there right now!
Now you've done it.
So, what are they
going to do?
Get away from the window.
What the...
What is this?
Wake up,
it's a fucking con.
Get in, get in!
You all right?
Hold on.
Get out of the car.
I could've handed you to them.
And they find me now they...
Get out of the goddamn car!
You don't have a choice!
No one else's gonna tell you
what's going on!
You wanna know? 'Cause if
I'm gone you never will.
I can't believe they didn't even take
the time to get the fucking house right.
Who are they?
I don't know. Nobody
does. I'm an employee.
Then what good are you? I know
things like who you can trust
and that your brother was in it
from beginning... That's a lie.
Yeah? I was your waitress
on your birthday.
Connie told you about CRS that
day. Ever seen me in there before?
Sorry.
I mean, it wasn't his fault. I guess
he thought it was his only way out.
They fleeced him
real good.
How did they get to him?
Same thing to him
they did to you.
What are you talking about?
Have you checked
your accounts?
That night in your office I got the
number to your private line and modem
that gave CRS remote access
to your computer.
You gave them
everything else.
What?
You took their tests, handwriting,
voice samples, psych info.
They used it all
to figure out your passwords.
And Feingold,
the guy who signed you up,
he did 5 years
for hacking Citibank.
They only had to
keep you distracted
while they broke
into your financial network,
transferred your holdings
into dummy accounts...
Overseas operator, please.
Why else were they
willing to shoot at us?
Alamein Bank, Zurich,
Switzerland.
Because
they're finished with you.
Live or dead's the same.
Long as you disappear.
Yeah. Can I have
your code, please?
Yes.
Blue-two-backslash-0-6-0-0.
"D" as in David.
That's right.
The balance?
That's impossible.
They already got it, Nicholas.
They got everything.
You've reached the Sutherlands.
Please leave a message.
As you get this message, Sam, I have
checked them all. I don't know how,
but they have drained
my accounts.
They're trying to kill me. Now you call
the cops. I got one of them right here.
We'll make her testify.
I know how this sounds,
but you call me
on my cellular.
And you be careful.
They...
They cut your card
in half so...
My treat.
You take two sugars, right?
Never mind.
My name's not Christine. It's...
I mean, it's not my real name.
Who fucking cares?
It is just money. You
should be glad you're alive.
I'd rather not talk
about it right now.
All I mean is
someone like you...
How many times
have you done this?
I'm curious.
What?
These scams.
Con games, how many?
Lots.
But, whatever nickel-dime
bullshit you pulled in the past,
this is more than just me.
This is pension plans,
payrolls.
This is $600 million.
Yes.
Nick, it's Sam.
I got your message.
I was disturbed
to say the least.
So, what are we gonna do?
I've been on the phone
for an hour already.
Nicholas,
your funds are intact.
Nothing's been touched.
What are you talking about?
I checked on them myself.
Who is it?
I made the calls.
Nothing's changed.
I'm telling you. Not one cent
is unaccounted for.
Who is it?
My attorney says that
nothing is missing.
He's in on it.
I don't know what the hell is
happening, but stay where you are
until I get there.
Sutherland's in on it.
Nicholas, I have another call.
Give me your precise location.
Nicholas?
We've got to
get out of here.
How did they get to him?
Why did...
I wouldn't worry about it.
What do you mean?
It's out of your hands.
Cellular calls
can be intercepted.
Those calls you made
to B of A, France.
B of A, France, Switzerland,
you were talking to us.
You were talking to us.
Filled in the blanks.
Access codes,
passwords, access codes,
passwords...
Stuff even your lawyer didn't have.
We have it now
so we're done.
Bye, Nicholas.
Things have happened
and it's important that...
Shh, shh, shh!
No money, no identification,
no passport.
What happened to you?
Where to begin...
It's complicated.
It always is.
I was on holiday alone
and I was robbed by two men. Robbed?
And what hotel
were you staying at?
I... I don't remember. I...
Have you gone to the police?
I don't speak Spanish.
And I just need enough
to get out of here.
Oh, we'll help with the local law
enforcement if you wanted to bother.
As far as money is concerned,
can I make a suggestion?
You say you were mugged?
And they
didn't take that watch?
How much is
a watch like that worth?
A couple of hundred at least.
Man with a watch like that doesn't
necessarily have a passport problem.
Excuse me?
Can I have your attention,
please?
Thank you.
Anybody here going to San
Francisco? I need a ride.
I've got $18 and 70...
78 cents
for a ride to San Francisco.
Anybody?
Keep the change.
Thanks, pal.
Conrad Van Orton. Could
you ring his room, please?
One moment, please.
Is there a problem?
You're here for Conrad Van Orton? Yes.
I'm the hotel manager. Pleasure
to meet you. Where's my brother?
Will you come with me, sir?
Wait a minute,
is there trouble?
Sir, this is
a private matter for you.
There was some complaints by
other guests, damage to his room.
We did the best we could
to accommodate his behavior.
His behavior?
Yes, sir.
There was an incident
a few days ago.
A nervous breakdown,
they said.
The police took him.
They left this address
in case anyone came.
It's a hospital in Napa, sir.
I'm terribly sorry.
Elizabeth,
I need to borrow your car.
Nickie,
what happened to you?
I mean...
Look at you. Look at
me. What happened, I...
I don't know. I... There're just
some things I have to do, all right?
I need your car.
Of course, you can have it
if you need it.
Can't I get you
something to eat?
You know that
you're the only person
that I can trust.
Everyone else is...
If Sam Sutherland calls you,
you don't tell him you
talked to me. You lie to him.
And whatever else happens
before he speaks...
Okay, coffee,
English muffin,
and your water.
This bottle
is open. Who opened this
bottle? Yeah, I opened it.
I don't want an opened bottle.
I want an unopened bottle.
I don't want ice in the glass.
I want just a glass,
please.
Nickie, talk to me.
You're scaring me.
I don't even know
what you're saying.
I'm sorry, Liz. I don't
mean it. I'm sorry.
You know, I've been thinking
the last couple of days.
I've had some spare time.
And I wanted to tell you that
I understand why you left me.
And I know
that I resented it.
I want to apologize to you
for shutting you out
and not being there.
And I hope
that you can forgive me.
You're tired. You've
been on the go for days.
There's nothing to forgive.
Then,
pain sets in.
The onset of
a migraine headache.
If this sounds all too
familiar, relief is here at last.
Oh no, you bastards.
Taggarene. For nearly a decade,
doctors have been prescribing...
How did you find me here?
Taggarene is strong medicine for headaches,
toothaches, muscle fatigue, joint pains...
He's an actor.
So if you trust your doctor,
trust Taggarene.
He's an actor on television.
Can't explain now.
Can I borrow
your Yellow Pages?
New Moon Cafe,
best in Chinatown.
Get out of the car, fucker.
Open the door
and leave it running.
You're making
a mistake here.
Get the fuck
out of the car.
I am extremely fragile
right now.
New Moon Cafe.
He does commercials. Do you
know how many customers we have?
Hundreds, thousands.
I know he ordered from you. He
went to Montgomery Street. 1010...
Is there anybody here
that can help me?
He's an actor. He's like one of these
people you have here up on your...
Hey!
Why are you taking my picture?
We were hoping
he could audition today.
He'd really be
perfect for this part.
Oh,
this will break his heart.
Well is there any place
we can contact him?
Well, his beeper's
here on the table.
He took
the kids to the zoo.
The zoo?
That's very, very sweet.
Which zoo? Oh, it's the
one with the white tiger.
Lionel Fisher,
I love your work.
Okay, please.
Look, I, uh...
I got my kids.
Get rid of them.
All right, guys, uh, guys.
Snack time. More
snacks. Here, go, go, go.
That's all. Uh...
It was just a job.
Nothing personal.
You know. I mean,
I play my part,
improvise a little. I mean,
it's what I'm good at...
I need to talk
to who's in charge.
Nobody knows.
I mean nobody
gets a big picture...
Hey, Tammy, Alex cut it out.
Damn it, why do they do that?
Your offices are empty. I need
to find out where they are.
Look,
they own the whole building.
They just move
from floor to floor.
And you work for them,
right?
You can get me in.
No, I can't.
Oh, yes, you can.
You can tell them the police
called. You got to speak to someone.
You tell them I'm gonna
blow the whistle on them.
What whistle?
There's no fucking whistle.
This is very dangerous.
I don't think
that you understand.
Right now
I am
extremely
dangerous.
Michael, guys.
Come on, we're leaving.
Well we're here.
Drive in.
What're you gonna do, anyway?
You won't get
your money back.
I don't care about money.
I'm pulling back the curtain.
I wanna meet the wizard.
He's eyeing us
like Tiffany Towers.
Pull in somewhere
where they won't see you.
Shit. Stay down. Stay down.
You're not allowed
to be here.
They called me back.
I got a fitting.
He's with me.
You don't need me.
Shut up.
Get in.
Oh, my God.
Cuff him to the rail.
What floor?
You're fucked, you both.
They're gonna miss me.
Where? I told you they
hired me over the phone...
Where did you
pick up your checks?
It was a different floor then.
Then guess. I... It went
on this way, sort of...
I don't know.
All right, take it easy.
It's gonna be a surprise.
Oh, fuck!
What are you doing here?
Back from the dead.
Nicholas, you're not
about to shoot anyone.
Turn around.
You're gonna come with me.
Everybody down!
Stop!
All right, what do you
think you're doing?
You tell me!
Who's behind this?
Who did this to me?
Why?
What do you mean, "Why?" How deluded
can you be? Who is responsible for this?
It wasn't you.
It wasn't personal.
It could've been any asshole with a
couple of hundred million in the bank.
Get on that radio, all right?
You get your boss up here.
You tell them
I'm gonna shoot somebody.
Who am I gonna call,
Nicholas? They won't do it.
Oh, yes, they will.
You get somebody up here
because I'm gonna kill you. They
don't care about me, Nicholas.
They'll let me die. You're not
in a position to threaten anyone.
Wait a minute.
Where'd you get that?
What?
That gun.
That's not an automatic.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
The guard had an automatic.
Where did you get the gun?
This is my gun.
But we searched the house.
Well I guess you missed this,
didn't you?
There's a situation up here. We
got a real goddamn gun up here...
Nicholas, it's fake.
It's a part of your game.
Don't you start with me now.
No, no, listen to me.
Don't you fucking start with me.
I'm telling you the truth now.
This is all the game.
Bullshit, all right? Bullshit.
I know what happened to that guy.
They shot that guy, Feingold, Fisher,
they killed him. What did you see?
Think about it. What'd you
see? I saw them kill him.
No, what'd you really
really see, this whole time?
Special effects, squibs.
Squibs like in the movies.
Nicholas. Nicholas, listen.
I've got a real gun
with real goddamned bullets...
Okay, okay.
I'll put it down.
Feingold, Mr. Fisher. He's on the
other side of that door. He's an actor.
You're trying to kill me. No
one's trying to kill you, Nicholas.
Please put that gun down. You're about
to make the biggest mistake of your life.
Nicholas, there was always a safety net.
The taxi, there was a diver. My house,
they shot at us
with blanks.
It's not true.
It is. It's what
you hired us for.
They're waiting on the other
side of that door with champagne.
Nicholas.
Please, goddamn it!
Conrad. Conrad's there.
It's your birthday party.
You stop lying!
Let me show you.
Don't you move.
He's got a gun.
Get back from the door.
You shot him.
Someone...
Someone call an ambulance!
He's dead.
We thought you knew.
How did you let this
get so out of hand?
He wouldn't listen to me.
We went through this
over and over.
The mark is
your responsibility.
You never,
never let
the mark take over.
I'm sorry. He could
have almost killed us.
I had a walkie-talkie.
I used the walkie-talkie.
We're going to jail.
We're all going to jail
for the rest of our lives.
Oh, God.
Nicholas!
We've got him.
He's in the bag.
We have him here.
He came in right on target.
Keep everyone back until we
clear away the breakaway glass.
Mr. Van Orton,
don't open your eyes.
It's just breakaway glass,
but it can still cut you.
Just gonna take a look at you.
I'm gonna check your pulse.
Just take it easy.
That was quite a fall.
Happy birthday, Nickie.
What is this?
It's your birthday present.
I had to do something. You
were becoming such an asshole.
Ladies and gentlemen. My
brother, Nicholas Van Orton.
Amazing. I just wanted
to tell you. Great job.
This was the best ever.
Thank God you jumped.
Because if you didn't,
I was supposed
to throw you off.
Thanks.
We have to head home. We
just wanted to say goodbye.
Rachel.
Sweet dreams.
Thanks, Mel, for coming. I'm
sorry about your car. I...
I think I left it at the zoo.
No problem.
Happy birthday, Nicholas.
I'll call you.
I really will.
Nicholas, I haven't a clue
what this is all about.
Your taste in champagne
is excellent as always.
It was a great entrance.
Yes, and I want you to know that
what happened on Sunday was...
Oh, no, no, please.
I've never been happier
in my whole life.
I thank you.
And my wife thanks you.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you, Sam.
What's this?
This is
the bill.
The bill?
Keep the pen.
Thank you, both.
You wanna split it?
Oh, God, yes, please.
I'll take you up on that.
Oh, my God.
Thank you, Connie.
What happened to that
waitress?
What was her name, uh...
Christine?
She said something
about catching a plane.
I just saw her out front
trying to hail a cab.
Christine?
I, um...
I didn't get a chance
to say goodbye.
Thank you. I...
You know, I never did
ask you your name, did I?
No.
It's
Claire.
So you catching a plane or...
Yeah, we have a gig starting
next week in Australia, so...
Gonna shear some more sheep.
Just a walk-on this time.
Well, when you get back,
maybe, you know,
we could have some dinner.
You don't know
anything about me.
No, I don't.
So you tell me.
Well, what...
Where you're from?
Originally,
Oklahoma.
Colorado?
I've been doing this
for way too long.
You know,
would you like
to have coffee with me
at the airport?