Well, then... Urrmm, now.
I'll begin at the beginnin'.
A fine, soft day
in the spring it was...
...when the train pulled into Castletown,
three hours late as usual...
...and himself got out.
He didn't have the look of
an American tourist at all about him...
...not a camera on him and, what
was worst, not even a fishing-rod.
Castletown?
- Castletown?
- Could you tell me the way to Inisfree?
Inisfree? Aw, five miles
and maybe a half more.
- Do you see that road over there?
- Yeah.
Don't take that one,
it'll do you no good.
Now, the best road to Inisfree,
and many...
Oh, Inisfree you want. Be savin' your
breath, let me direct the gentleman.
Happen to know the way to Knoghenor?
If you knew the way there,
would he be asking the way to Inisfree?
There's many knows Knoghenor
that doesn't know Inisfree.
If you'd take the time to study
your country's history, Mr Maloney...
- ...you'd be the first to admit it.
- Don't send the poor man there.
The fishing is finished
there entirely.
Tell me, Yank,
what is it that you're after?
- Is it trout or salmon?
- All I want is to get to Inisfree.
Ah, now you're talking sense.
The best fishing in the country.
- True.
- Trout as long as your arm.
And salmon! The last one I got,
I expected Jonah to pop out of his mouth.
Ah, Inisfree.
I'd bring you there myself...
...only I got to drive the train.
Hey, was I tellin' you about that trout
I got two summers before last?
- At Inisfree?
- Not at all!
At Ballygar,
over the other end of the country.
My sister's third young one is living
at Inisfree...
...and she'd be only too happy
to show you the road.
- No, no, if she was here.
- It's Inisfree the man wants to go to.
- You see that signpost over there?
- What do you know...
Inisfree, this way.
I wonder, now,
why a man would go to Inisfree.
- Six foot six?
- Four and a half.
- Cincinnati?
- No, Pittsburgh.
Pi... Pitss...
Don't you remember, Seaneen,
and how it was.
The road led up past the chapel,
and it wound, and it wound...
...and there was the field where
Dan Tobin's bull chased you.
It was a lovely little house,
Seaneen, and the roses!
Your father used to tease me about them,
but he was that proud of them, too.
That's nothin'
but a wee humble cottage.
That little place across the brook,
that humble cottage. Who owns it now?
The widow Tillane.
Not that she lives there.
- You think she'd sell it?
- I doubt it.
Don't bet on it 'cause I'm buyin' it.
Why... why would a Yankee
from Pittsburgh want to buy it?
I'll tell you why, Michaleen Oge Flynn,
young small Michael Flynn...
...who used to wipe my runny nose
when I was kid.
Because I'm Sean Thornton, and
I was born in that little cottage.
And I've come home,
and home I'm gonna stay.
Does that answer your questions
once and for all, you nosy little man?
Seaneen Thornton... The...
And look at you now.
What do they feed you,
all you men who are in Pittsburgh?
Steel, and pig-iron furnaces so hot
a man forgets his fear of hell.
When you're hard enough,
tough enough... other things.
Other things, Michaleen.
Now then, here comes myself,
that's me there, walking.
That tall, saintly-looking man.
Peter Lonergan, parish priest.
Good day, Father.
Sean, this is Father Lonergan.
Father, would you believe it?
This is Sean Thornton...
...born right here in Inisfree,
home from America.
- Hello, Father.
- Ah, yes.
I knew your people, Sean.
Your grandfather... He died
in Australia, in a penal colony.
And your father,
he was a good man too.
Bad accident, that. And your mother?
She's dead.
America, when I was twelve.
I'll remember her in the mass tomorrow.
You'll be there, seven o'clock.
- Sure, I will.
- Good.
Sean, I'd like to have a little word
with Michaleen here.
- Sure thing, Father.
- It'll only take a minute.
- It's a little matter...
- Take your time. I'll be up ahead.
(MICHALEEN) Sean!
Hey, is that real?. She couldn't be.
Uh, nonsense, man. It's only a mirage
brought on by your terrible thirst.
Come up, Napoleon.
Over here we pronounce it "Co-han".
Good morning.
None of that now. It's a bold,
sinful man you are, Sean Thornton.
Who told you to playing patty fingers
in the Holy Water?
- Just being polite, that's all.
- What is this?
Maybe you don't know it's a privilege
only for courting couples...
...and then only
when the banns have been read.
And Mary Kate Danaher dippin'
her fingers in as neat as you please.
- What did you say her name was?
- Mary Kate Danaher.
And don't be getting
any notions in your head.
- Mary Kate...
- Forget it, Sean, forget it.
- Put it out of your mind.
- Why? What's the matter?
- She isn't married or anything?
- Married? That one?
Not likely. And her
with her freckles and her temper.
Oh, that red head of hers is no lie.
Still, a man might put up with that
but not with her lack of a fortune.
The wealthiest woman in Inisfree
was the widow Tillane.
She had neither chick nor child,
poor soul...
...but she was well-respected
and good to the poor.
- So you were born there, is that it?
- Yes, ma'am.
All Thorntons were born there,
seven generations.
I see. And what is your thought,
Mr Thornton...
...are you planning to turn
White O' Mornin' into a national shrine?
Perhaps charge tuppence a visit
for a guided tour...
...through the cottage where
the Thorntons were born.
Are you a man of such eminence?
No, not exactly.
My own family has been in Ireland...
...since the Normans came
hundreds of years ago...
...but we've seen no reason
to establish monuments or memorials...
Look, Mrs Tillane, I'm not talking
about memorials or monuments.
Ever since I was a kid living in
a shack near the slag heaps...
...my mother has told me about
Inisfree and White O' Mornin'.
Inisfree has become
another word for heaven to me.
When I quit the... When I decided to come
here, it was with one thought in mind.
Inisfree is far from being a heaven,
Mr Thornton.
Ma'am, Mr Red Will Danaher
wishes to be announced...
...I mean, Squire Danaher.
Watch your muddy boots!
- Mrs Tillane.
- Mr Thornton, from America.
- Aw!
- Boo.
It's him I'm here about, Mrs Tillane.
- (WILL) Is it true?
- Is what true?
That behind me back,
he's trying to steal...
...White O' Mornin'
right from under me nose?
And what concern of yours is this,
Will Danaher?
Concern? Concern enough.
Haven't I made you a fair offer
for that same piece of land?
- And mine, lying right next to yours?
- You may keep your offers.
- Oh, so it's true. You sold it!
- No, I have not.
Oh, I knew it was a dirty lie
the very minute I heard it!
Sure, I said to him...
..."Paggy McFarland, I won't believe that
Sarah'd be selling White O' Mornin'".
(WILL) Why, it would be like building
a fence between your land and mine.
"And for a stranger to move in", says I.
"What would she be doing that for?"
And us so close to an understanding,
you might say.
- So you told him all that?
- That I did.
Down at the pub, I suppose,
in front of all those big ears...
...with pints in their fists
and pipes in their mouths.
You may have the land, Mr Thornton,
for 600 pounds.
- Done!
- No, you can't. 610!
As I remember, you said 700 pounds.
See here, little man... 710!
- How about an even thousand?
- A thousand and...
And... and I'll be saying
good day to you, Mrs Tillane...
...and all here but one.
And I've got you down in my book.
My dad remembers his dad well.
Mike Thornton.
He had shoulders on him like an ox.
I saw him meself this mornin'.
A tall, handsome man,
as I was passin' that chapel.
If you'd pass the pub
as fast as you pass the chapel...
...you'd be better off,
little squint.
Just look at them!
Eating me out of house and home.
Get back to the fields!
There's work to be done.
Isn't it a bit early in the day
for the bottle... even for you?
Feeney, get your book out.
Set down the name,
the one Sean Thornton.
Oh, look at me clean floor!
You dirty little...
- Shut your gob.
- Aw, shut you, little man! Here.
Clean it up yourself,
or there will be no dinner tonight!
There now! Look now,
you mustn't mind himself this day.
That's all the work you're good for,
you little tattletail.
Feeney, have you written
the name I gave you?
I have.
Well, strike a line through it.
That's for him. Sean Thornton...
So... He bought White O' Mornin'
in spite of you.
Good for widow Tillane.
Pay no attention to her at all!
Take no notice.
You do, and there'll be a fine wake
in this house tonight.
After all, he's got more right
to that land than you have!
He'll regret it to his dying day,
if ever he lives that long.
Will it be all right
if I leave my bags in here?
I imagine they'll be safe enough.
If you see a little guy, Michaleen Flynn,
tell him I'm waiting for him in the bar.
It'll be a pleasure,
especially for Michaleen.
Thanks.
Is there anything
you should like now, Yank?
If I think of anything,
I'll let you know.
(BAR IS QUIET)
Evening.
Pleasant night.
- I'll try one of those black beers.
- Oh, the porter. Yes, sir.
Sir, will you join me? Matter of fact,
I'd like to buy everybody a drink.
I do not believe I heard your name,
tall man.
Thornton. Sean Thornton.
And... your father's name?
Mike. Michael Thornton.
He used to live here, by the Mornin'.
I just bought the place back.
That's why I'm here.
Then your grandfather
would be Ol' Sean Thornton.
- Right.
- Bless his memory.
So it's himself you're named after.
Well, now. That being the case...
...it is a pleasant evening
and we will have a drink.
There was a wild colonial boy
Jack Duggan was his name
He was born and bred in Ireland
In a town called Castlemaine
- Good evening, Father.
- Is the rest of the committee here?
- They're waiting.
- Sorry we're late.
- The fishing was bad, was it?
- Fine lot of time we had for that!
- Oh, Michaleen...
- Commandant Forbes.
You can forget about the Commandant.
We're at peace now.
Sure, but I haven't given up hope.
Your Yankee friend
is waitin' in the bar.
Oh, he's here already...
Wait a minute. Who is he anyway?
He's a nice, quiet, peacelovin' man come
home to Ireland to forget his troubles.
Troubles?
Yes, he's a millionaire
like all the Yanks.
But he is eccentric.
Wait till I show you.
What is it?
A bag to sleep in.
A sleeper bag they call it.
I'm tellin' you. The sleeper bag...
Wait till I show you how it operates.
Where does it open?
Hurry up,
I have an important appointment.
- Well, open it up!
- Here.
At the early age of sixteen years
He left his native home
And to Australia's sunny shores
He was inclined to roam
He robbed a wealthy squireen
All arms he did destroy
A terror to Australia was
This wild colonial boy
Sean Thornton, the men of Inisfree
bid you welcome home.
Thank you.
"And the men of Inisfree
bid you welcome home".
- What's wrong with that little speech?
- Oh, you'd be knowin' what.
I'm a man from Inisfree,
and the best man.
And I bid no welcome
to a man fool enough...
...to pay 1000 pounds for a bit
of land that isn't worth 200!
True for you, squire.
(MAN) Didn't I hear of someone
named Danaher bid 810?
Get your book out.
Put his name down: Dermot Fahy.
F-A-H-Y.
No e's, Squireen Danaher.
If you were half the man
you think you are...
...you wouldn't begrudge a Thornton
the right to his birthplace.
What right has he to a land
he's never worked?
It's Thornton land, isn't it?
- You've too much of your own as it is.
- Quiet, if you please.
Parliamentary procedure.
Squire Danaher has the floor.
If I had the floor...
- ...I'd hit that big ape with it.
- Hold on.
I don't blame Mr Danaher for gettin'
on his ear.
Who's on his ear? Why, you and ten like
you couldn't put a Danaher on his ear.
- It's just a way of speaking...
- Mind your ways, then.
The point is, it's already done.
I own the property now,
and since we're neighbours...
Neighbours? Neighbours...
Never!
And if I so much as catch you putting
one foot on my property, I... I...
And, oh, another thing. You keep
away from my sister Mary Kate.
She's not for the likes of you.
Where I come from, we don't talk
about our womenfolk in saloons.
You sort of make a habit of it.
This morning it was widow Tillane.
What's that?
That's true.
It's ashamed you should be.
Hey, look, I'm not accusing Mary Kate.
It's him.
Why, this very moment,
let him deny it if he can.
At the back of the chapel, he took
liberties that he shouldn't have.
- I said "good morning" to her.
- Good morning?
It was "good night"
you had on your mind.
That's a lie.
(MUSIC STOPS)
- That's a what?
- I said "that's a lie".
That's a word I take from no man!
Put up your fists.
- I'm not gonna fight you.
- But I'm gonna...
Thank you.
(FATHER) Danaher!
What's the matter with you?
(FORBES) He's drunk!
Feeney, take him home, will you.
(FEENEY)
Don't soil your knuckles on the man.
- Come on, what do you say?
- Never.
Take the man's hand, or I'll read
your name on a mass on Sunday.
- (FEENEY) Take it.
- I'd join the Church of Ireland first.
As if they'd have you.
Shake his hand like I tell you.
- (FEENEY) Come on, come on.
- Shake hands?
It's a good grip you have. I always
hated a flappy handshake myself.
Father Paul!
Michaleen, introduce me to this quiet,
peacelovin' man of yours.
I have a strange notion
we're going to be friends, Yank.
Give me a minute. Just let
some blood run back into this.
Sean Thornton... His grandfather, a grand
man he was, was hung in Australia.
I could tell you blood-curdlin' stories
about him, but me throat...
(SEAN) All right, come on.
He was born and bred in Ireland
In a town called Castlemaine
He was his father's only son
His mother's pride and joy
And dearly did his parents love
This wild colonial boy
Are you sure you won't change your mind,
and come around home with me?
Don't worry about it.
I've got my sleeping bag, haven't I.
Well, it's a nice, soft night.
So, I think I'll join my comrades,
and talk a little treason.
- Good night, Sean.
- Good night, Michaleen.
(MICHALEEN) God bless you.
(SEAN YELLS)
(MARY KATE SCREAMS)
So bold one you are.
Who gave you leave to be kissin' me?
- So you can talk?
- Yes, I can, I will, and I do.
It's more than talk you'll be gettin'
if you step closer.
- Don't worry. You've got a wallop.
- You'll get over it, I'm thinkin'.
Some things a man doesn't get over
so easily.
Like what supposin'?
Like the sight of a girl coming through
the fields, with the sun on her hair.
Kneeling in church,
with a face like a saint.
Saint, indeed.
And now, coming to a man's house
to clean it for him.
But... that was just my way
of bein' a good Christian act.
I know it was, Mary Kate Danaher,
and it was nice of you.
Not at all.
- Hello.
- Good morning, Mr Thornton.
- How are you, Fa... Doctor...
- No, no. Mr.
And on formal occasions,
the Reverend Mr Playfair.
And this is Mrs Playfair.
(MRS PLAYFAIR) Well, Mr Thornton.
You are a wonder.
It looks the way all the Irish cottages
should... and so seldom do.
And only an American
would have thought of emerald green.
- Red is more durable.
- And the roses! How nice.
You'll need lots of horse manure.
Fertiliser, I mean. Horse is the best.
Oh, I brought you a plant. You know,
"a primrose by a river's brink".
"Brim", not "brink".
The next line ends in "hymn".
Poets are so silly, aren't they?
Oh, I hope you're not one, Mr Thornton.
- Oh no, ma'am, I...
- Thornton.
There's a familiar ring to it.
Ring to it... Thornton...
It's a common name. Thank you
for the plant, Mrs Playfair...
...this is damn... darn...
awfully nice of you.
Oh?
It's a bed. Excuse me.
Morning.
(MAN) That's a fine big bed,
Mr Thornton.
Biggest one I could find.
Is that a bed or a parade ground?
Oh, a man'd have to be a sprinter
to catch his wife in a bed like that.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
Whoa!
Mr Flynn... And what are you
all dressed up for, Michaleen Oge?
I ha...
- I have come...
- Oh, I can see that.
- But from whose pub was it?
- P... pub?
You've a tongue like an adder.
I go about me own business...
...and tell Thorn Seanton
he's well off without you.
Wait a minute. What was that?
Well, if you listened and not
be interruptin' the matchmaker.
I have come...
- ...at the request of Thorn Seanton...
- Sean Thornton.
Shut up.
...bachelor,
and party of the first part...
...to ask of you,
strictly and formally, here...
...Mary Kate Danaher, spinster...
...and party to the second part...
Well?. Go on, you were sayin'?
Me mouth is like a dry crust, and
the sun is that hot, and me pate...
Would you be steppin'
into the parlour?
The house may belong to my brother,
but what's in the parlour belongs to me.
I will then, and I hope there's
a bottle there, whoever it belongs to.
It could be.
You have a fine, steady hand.
To good bargaining.
To resume:...
- ...the party of the first part...
- That's him.
...has instructed me to enquire before
enterin' into formal negotiations...
...whether the party
to the second part...
That's me.
...thinks kindly of the general idea,
or in his own words... American, eh...
...eh, yes, he wants
to know if you go for it.
Go for it?
And if you do,
he'll speak to your brother.
That won't be easy.
Oh, as well I know it.
He'd as soon put his fist into my teeth
as bid me the time of the day.
What did Sean... the party of
the first part, say about my fortune?
He says he doesn't give it...
He says it's a matter of
complete indifference to him.
- He did?
- He says he doesn't give a sh...
He says it's all one to him if you
come in the clothes on your back...
...or without them.
Oh, he did, did he? Well.
A fine opinion
he must have of me...
...if he thinks I'd go to any man
without a proper fortune.
And this you may tell
your Mr Party of the first part:...
...when I wed,
whatever's my own, goes with me.
Get up, little man.
And all this furniture is mine.
And I have that china, and linen, and
50 pounds in gold my father left me...
...and my mother's rings, brooches,
my grandmother's veil, her silver comb...
Thirty pounds odd in notes
and silver...
...I've earned these past 15 years,
that's all.
You're a well propertied woman.
I wouldn't mind marryin' you meself.
Eh, where'd you leave the bottle?
And I'd have you tell him, that I'm no
pauper to be going to him in my shift.
Lo, young May moon is beamin' love
The glow of one's lamp
is gleamin' love
How sweet to row
through Mourner's Grove
While the drowsy world
is dreamin'...
- You know "The Peter And The Ghost"?
- I do not.
Neither do I.
Could you use a little water
in your whiskey?
When I drink whiskey, I drink whiskey,
and when I drink water, I drink water.
Back to business now.
What answer will I give Sean Thornton,
Mary Kate Danaher?
Well, you can tell him
from me that...
...that I go for it.
Here's to steal a few hours
from the night
My dear
- How do I look?
- You look fine.
- Hey, what do I say?
- I'll do all the talkin'.
And I'm suppose to stand here
like a dummy?
Shh, now.
- Will, there's someone coming to call.
- Who?
It's... well...
It's Michaleen Oge Flynn,
and there's a gentleman with him.
Here, Will, put on your coat.
Will Danaher,
they're comin' to the front door.
Since when has the back door
been not good enough?
(MICHALEEN)
God bless all in this house.
(SEAN) Good evening.
(MICHALEEN) Miss Danaher,
we'd like a word with your brother.
Come on in so, and welcome.
Easy now!
Mr Sean Thornton, bachelor,
meet Miss Mary Kate Danaher, spinster.
Miss Danaher, meet Mr Thornton
from Pittsburgh, Massachusetts, USA.
- Good evening, Miss Danaher.
- This...
This way, please.
- Eh, this is my brother...
- Leave the room.
- But...
- I said, leave the room.
- Yes, Will.
- Sit down, that's what chairs are for.
- If you've come for supper, you're late.
- Gracious invitation, but thank you, no.
I don't suppose
there's a drop in the house.
Help yourself to the buttermilk.
Buttermilk?
The Borgias would do better.
We'll come with your permission
to the object of this visit.
You've noticed, I presume, that
I'm wearin' my official black coat.
I have. For your dead friend here.
(WILL) I need no trouble
to arrange any marriages for me.
I see. You've been making fine progress
with widow Tillane in the last ten years.
- Is that what you've come to talk about?
- I have not.
I've come to talk
about your sister and him.
Aw, get out.
If he was the last man on the face
of the earth, I'd still say no.
Now just a minute.
If it's a question
of the girl's fortune...
Why, if it'd be a shilling piece
he wanted with her...
- ...I'd still say no.
- Come on, Michaleen. I told you so.
- I'll explain it to her myself.
- Hey, Yank, I'll count three.
If you're not out of the house
by then, I'll loose the dogs on you.
If you say three,
you'll never hear the man count ten.
- Oh, Mary Kate, we tried.
- We'll see him again some other time.
I thank you anyway,
Sean Thornton, for the asking.
You don't think this changes anything?
It's what you say that counts, not him.
Now, now, Sean.
You've gone too far, that's enough.
Say, what is this?
We're gonna get married, aren't we?
- I don't get it.
- This is Ireland, Sean, not America.
Without her brother's consent
she couldn't, and wouldn't.
I'm sorry for both of you.
Those were the bad days. Sean with a face
as dark as the black hunter he rode.
A fine, ill-tempered pair they were.
It was only a matter of time before
one or the other broke his neck.
We knew things
couldn't go on this way.
Easy, Sean!
Hello, Mary Kate... Danaher.
Good morning, Sean Thornton.
So, we formed a little conspiracy.
The Reverend Mr and Mrs Playfair...
...Michaleen Oge and,
saints forgive us, myself.
And on the day of the Inisfree Races,
we sprung the trap on Red Will Danaher.
Remember, you make your speed
when you hit the water.
- Yes, father.
- And ride carefully, my son.
Yes, mum.
Thornton, no silks.
- Your colours, Thornton.
- Thank you.
- Good luck.
Ladies, gentlemen,
your attention, please!
Will all the lovely ladies...
...who are putting up their bonnets
for the Inisfree Cup...
...please place their bonnets
on the finishing line.
Ladies, your bonnets, please!
- Will you not be putting up your bonnet?
- Indeed, I will not.
- No?
- No!
Okay, Michaleen, the widow's bonnet.
Will all the gentlemen riders
please go to the starting line.
All riders, please.
Crown at 20 to 1 on the Yank.
I'm given 20 to 1 on the Yank...
I'm given 30 to 1...
40 to 1 on Danaher.
Flynn!
If you've done any matchmaking
between Thornton and my widow...
...I'll put you in me pocket.
Ah, so you've heard?
Father, what sort of
a scoundrel is this Yank?
One minute it's me sister,
and the next it's herself.
Well, blame no one but yourself.
If you'd saved me as your matchmaker,
you would've been married long since.
- True, Will, true.
- I'm not saying it's too late yet.
- What do you mean?
- Why has the widow stood you up so long?
- You're a fine looking man.
- I am.
- A rich, propertied man.
- And well she knows it.
- Father, will I tell him?
- Go ahead, Michaleen.
What woman would come into a house
with another woman in it?
If you got rid of Mary Kate,
the widow would be in like a shot.
No.
Yes. You had your chance
and you flubbed it.
You refused Seaneen Thornton,
and he reneged on you.
Now, I doubt if he'd take your sister
if you put 1000 pounds on her.
Father Lonergan?
Well, I can't say it's true,
and I won't say it's not.
- But there's been talk.
- Oh, a lot of talk.
A lot of talk, eh?
Two women in the house,
and one of them a redhead.
Two women.
Three Our Fathers,
and three Hail Marys.
Morning, Mary Kate.
Morning, children.
Don't sit there gawking.
You're gonna put up your bonnet.
- I will do no such shameless thing.
- You will.
I will not!
No bonnet, Mary Kate? What a pity.
Betting will now stop...
...and the sale of all intoxicating
and alcoholic drinks will cease.
I mean it now!
Oh, Sergeant Major,
in your good time, please.
The Yank's holdin' back.
Foul!
Look at that crazy Danaher!
Wouldn't it be wonderful
if he broke his neck?
Maybe he will now, God willing.
Will... Will, come on!
- Foul.
- I didn't see it!
Come on, Sean! Sean...
I mean Paul, Father Paul.
- Thornton!
- He took your bonnet, Sarah.
Fine race! You rode like a trooper.
Trooper... Trooper Thorn, of course!
I knew I'd seen you somewhere before.
Now that you know, I wish you'd
keep it under your hat. Forget it.
- I understand. It'll be our secret.
- Thanks.
Your bonnet, Mrs Tillane.
- A cup for the winner.
- Oh, thank you.
- Flynn... Does your offer still stand?
- Well, eh, that depends.
- You... you mentioned... 500 pounds.
- 350, and not another penny.
Well, I speak to me
principal of the first part, eh?
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
Good morning, good morning. Come on.
Well, now.
The banns having been read...
...and no man objecting...
...I'm permitting this man
to court me sister.
But under the usual conditions.
Mr Flynn?
- Do you assume the full responsibility?
- I do, I do.
And from now on, they'll do the walkin'
and the talkin' under me own eyes.
Well, then.
Let the courting commence.
None of that! Hands to yourself,
and your own side of the road.
- Get onto the other side of the cart.
- Up you go.
(PEOPLE CHEER)
(SEAN) Why do we have
to have you along?
Back in the States I'd honk the horn
and the gal'd come-a-runnin'...
Come-a-runnin'? I'm no woman
to be honked at, and come-a-runnin'.
America... Pro-hi-bi-tion.
Do you see that over there?
That's the ancestral home
of the ancient Flynns.
It was taken from us by... by...
by the Druids.
(FLYNN SINGS TO HIMSELF)
You're the quietest couple I've ever
herded. We'll get nowhere by this rate.
Off you get.
I'll let you do a healthy mile or so...
...just to get you two walking
correctly together.
Now, she's a fine, healthy girl.
No patty fingers, if you please.
- Nice day.
- It is that, Mr Thornton.
- That's a pretty bonnet you have on.
- Bonnet?
Don't you talk to me about bonnets!
After leaving mine stuck up...
Easy now, easy now.
Is this a courting or a fight?
Have the manners not to hit a man
until he's your husband...
...and until he'll hit you back.
I am sorry. I have a fearful temper.
You might as well know about it now,
instead of finding out about it later.
We Danahers are a fighting people.
I can think of a lot of things I'd rather
do to one of them... Miss Danaher.
Shh, Mr Thornton.
What will Mr Flynn be thinkin'?
(SEAN) Can you ride a bike?
Well, what are we waiting for?
Mary Kate Danaher! Sean!
Eh... ep... Come on!
(MICHALEEN) Come back here!
Come back at once!
(MARY KATE SCREAMS)
(MICHALEEN) Come back here!
Come back at once!
Come back here! Come back!
I think you have more sense
than I have meself.
Whoa there, Freddy.
If anybody had told me
six months ago...
...that today I'd be
in a graveyard in Inisfree...
...with a girl like you
that I'm just about to kiss...
- The kiss is a long way off yet!
- Ha?
We just started the courting and
next month we'll walk together...
...and the month after that
there'll be the trashing party...
No.
Maybe we won't have to wait
that month...
Yup.
- ...or for the trashing party...
- No.
- ...or for the walking out together.
And so much the worse for you,
Sean Thornton...
...for I feel the same way
about it myself.
(LOUD THUNDER)
And so they were married in the same
chapel I gave them their baptism.
Later, there was a nice,
quiet little celebration.
(LOUD, CHEERFUL MUSIC)
Oh, as I went out one mornin:
It being the month of May
A farmer and his daughter
abide their bonny way
And the girl had only come in
to the milking of her cow
Sayin' I will an' I must get married,
The humour is on me now
Oh, the humour is on me now,
Oh, the humour is on me now
Sayin' I will an' I must get married,
The humour is on me now
So, at last the daughter married,
she married well-to-do
And loved her darlin' husband
a month, a year, or two
But he was all a tyrant
as he quickly rode about
Sayin' I'm sorry I ever married,
The humour is on me now
Oh, humour is on me now,
Oh, humour is on me now
Sayin' I'm sorry I ever got married,
The humour is on me now
(SINGERS LAUGH)
To a successful conspiracy.
- A toast, to the bride and groom!
- One moment.
There will be no toasts
until we've seen the bride's fortune.
The bride's fortune?
You'll see it, never fear.
We'll see it now, if you please.
The proprieties must be observed.
- Father Lanergan.
- Feeney.
350 pounds gold.
A collection of furnishings, linen,
and pewter goes with the sister...
...of Will Danaher.
Then, a toast.
May their days be long,
and full of happiness.
May their children be many,
and full of health.
And may they live in peace,
and freedom.
Reverend Fathers, ladies and gentlemen.
Attention, please.
Squire Danaher has the floor.
In other words,
he's got somethin' to say to you all.
Thank you.
I have a little announcement to make.
Fill up the glasses. All of them.
Eh, today,
I've given my sister in marriage.
My only sister, and now she's gone
from the house of Danaher.
- But what's in a house without a woman?
- That's true.
That's right, what's a house
without a woman in it?
Yeah, what's a house
Where would any man of us be
without a woman?
- Even Father Lonergan had a mother.
- What do you expect?
Yeah, what do you expect.
What do you expect...
So... So...
- So, without further eloquence...
- Without further eloquence...
So, without further eloquence,
I will give you a toast to myself...
...who is soon to be wed.
All she has to do is to say
that little word.
When's the happy day, Sarah darlin'?
Have you lost the little sense
you were born with?
- What's the matter, Sarah darlin'?
- And don't "darlin"' me.
Who gave you the right to make
such an announcement?
(WILL) But Sarah... They all said...
Why... The Reverend Mr Playfair,
Mrs Reverend, Father Lonergan.
...eh, little Flynn... Michaleen.
- Didn't you tell me...
- Oh, I didn't, I didn't.
Oh, you lied, didn't ya?
You lied, didn't ya?
You all lied! It's bad enough for
you people, but my own priest.
You got her by fraud and falsity.
You put them up to this.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Will, for heaven's sake.
- Danaher, you're crazy!
- Crazy, am I?
This is something you won't get,
now or never!
Now, get out of here. All of you!
(WILL) The Reverend first,
ladies and gentlemen, get out!
- (WILL) Get out!
- Come on, let's go home.
No, not without my fortune.
It's mine, and my mother's before me...
(SOUNDS OF BOXING)
(CROWD SHOUTS WILDLY)
(CROWD'S BOOING)
Steady, Trooper, steady.
Let's go home.
Ever since I was a little girl...
...I've dreamed of havin'
my own things about me.
My spinet... over there...
...and the table here,
and... my own chairs to rest upon.
And...
And the dresser over there
in that corner.
And... my own china and pewter
shinin' about me.
And now...
I didn't know
you felt that way about it but...
...seems like a lot of fuss and grief
over little furniture and stuff.
(MARY KATE)
It is a pretty cottage, isn't it?
(SEAN) I think so.
- Don't touch me. You have no right.
- What do you mean no right?
(MARY KATE) I'll wear your ring,
I'll cook, and I'll wash.
I'll keep the land, but that is all!
Until I've got my dowry safe
about me, I'm no married woman.
I'm the servant I've always been,
without anything of my own.
That's ridiculous! You're my wife,
and fortune...
- What is this?
- Haven't I been trying to tell you?
Not until you have my dowry, you
haven't got any bit of me. Me, myself!
I'd still be dreaming amongst
the things that aren't my own...
...as if I had never met you.
There's 300 years of happy dreamin
in those things of mine, and...
...I want them. I want my dream.
I'll have it and I know it!
- I'll say no other word to you.
- All right.
You'll have your dowry, or daughter
of fortune, or whatever you call it.
Well, get it then.
There will be no locks
or bolts between us, Mary Kate...
...except those
in your own mercenary little heart.
(LAUGHTER AND MUSIC FROM OUTSIDE)
- Sean.
- How'd you sleep?
Don't be shamin' me, please,
in front of your friends.
What...? Oh, okay.
(MEN)
There that I learned all me courtin'
Many lessons I took in the art
The Cupid, the blagger,
while sportin'
An arrow drove straight through me
mush, mush, mush, toor-I-li-anny
Me mush, mush, mush, toor-I-li-ay
So I lathered him
with me shillelagh
For he trod on the tail 'o me
mush, mush, mush, toor-I-li-anny
And just like the dingle before
I lathered him with me shillelagh
For, he trod on the tail
of me coat
Hello, the house! Anyone up?
- Good mornin'!
- Good mornin'.
I... I suppose
it's a bit early to be callin'.
After you left last night,
Mary Kate...
...a couple of us persuaded
Danaher to change his mind.
It's a... what might be called
a sort of a belated wedding present.
My things... My furniture!
We'd brought them over last night,
but due to the circumstances...
Thanks, thanks.
- Okay, easy now.
- God bless all here.
That's right. Oh, be careful.
Over there by the wall.
No, no, no. Turn it around, so
that the light shines on the music.
- That's grand. That's grand now.
- Where do you want this?
- Mighty handy.
- It...
It was my mother's,
and my mother's mother's before.
- Where do I put it?
- Where do you suppose?
(MICHALEEN) Where do you suppose...
- We're sorry about the dowry, Mary Kate.
- We couldn't get him to change his mind.
- Not even Father Lonergan could do it.
- (SEAN) Let him keep it.
- Keep my fortune?
- You've got your tables and chairs.
- What do we care about his money?
- My money.
Let him have it
if it means that much to him.
What manner of man is it
that I've married?
A better one, I think,
that you know, Mary Kate.
Impetuous! Homeric!
(MARY KATE) Oh, Inisfree
My island, I'm returning
From wasted years,
across the wintry sea
And when I come back
To my own dear island
I'll rest awhile
Beside you
Bromwell Creek
Now I know why you have
so many rock walls in this country.
(MARY KATE) Roses!
Are you plantin' roses?
- Yeah.
- A fine farmer you are.
- Not a turnip, or a potato in the field.
- Or children.
(ROOSTER CROWS)
Sorry.
Well, I... I suppose they'll make
a very fine display around the cottage.
- It is a pretty cottage, isn't it?
- I think so.
Let's see now.
We need a plough, and a cultivator,
and seed for planting.
About a horse for the ploughing...
We could sell that hunter of yours.
I'll buy another horse for the ploughing.
Why not a tractor?
Oh, a tractor... Nasty, smelly things.
Besides, they're an awful price.
- With a horse, you get other advantages.
- Yeah. For the roses.
Roses, again.
You...
We could do our shopping
in Castletown...
...and if we put a good foot under us,
we'd be back by suppertime.
- Five miles!
- Well, that's just a...
Good stretch of the legs, huh?
All right, get on your walking shoes.
I'll be a minute.
(HONKING FROM OUTSIDE)
So, you're not a woman
to be honked at, ha?
Why, it's beautiful!
Did you ever see...
It looks like it could fly.
Only one horsepower,
but it's all yours.
- Mine?
- Sure. Think you can drive it?
Hold on to your hat!
(RED WILL) You take care of that,
Feeney.
Let's have another pint.
I'm buying this one.
High time.
- What's that?
- I said, that's fine, squire.
Good health to you all.
- Look, he sold the crossbreds.
- The what?
- The sheep he's been planning on.
- Oh.
Hurry, now is a good time to ask him.
Well, go on.
- Ask him what?
- About my money.
He can't say that
he hasn't got it with him now.
Can't you understand that
I didn't marry you for your fortune?
I don't give...
a hang about the money.
But he does!
That's the whole point of it.
- Now will you go and ask him?
- No. Why shame ourselves?
Shame? The shame's on you, not on me.
Or on me too, if I married a coward.
Is that what you think of me?
What else if you let him rob you
out of my money?
Money! I'm sick of the talk of it. Is
that all you Danahers think about? Money?
(FATHER) Quiet!
He's just behind that rock.
- This is very important...
- Oh, salmon! He's winking at me.
I've been trying to catch this one
for ten years.
I've got to talk to you
about my husband and myself.
There he is.
Father, I... I...
You see...
Father,
could I... tell you in the Irish?
Hush, hush.
(SHE SPEAKS IN GAELIC)
(HE ANSWERS IN GAELIC)
Sleeping bag, Father, with...
...with buttons.
(SHE SPEAKS IN GAELIC)
Woman, Ireland may be a poor country,
God help us...
...but here a married man
sleeps in a bed, not a bag...
...and for your own good...
Help, help, there he is!
I've been waiting for this
for 10 years!
Keep his head up.
- There's that beauty, that...
- Keep his head up. Keep a tight line.
I've got you! I'll get him!
- Tight line it is.
- Keep his head up!
His head is up!
(FATHER) For ten years I have...
Get the net, woman.
Oh, you got him, Father.
Keep his head up, you fool!
Get the net!
Get the net, woman!
- God help us!
- Oh.
Sleeping bags...
If you ever go across the sea
to Ireland
Then maybe at the closin' of your day
You will sit and watch the moon rise
Over Claddagh
And see the sun go down
On Galway Bay
For the breeze is blowin'
across the sea from Ireland
(SINGING STOPS)
You're just in time.
Just done me drink.
- Join us, Sean.
- Oh, you will have a drink, Sean?
No, thanks.
I wanna talk to you, in private.
If there's anythin' you got to say,
say it here.
I'd rather talk in private.
What's the matter? You're among friends.
They fought for you, didn't they?
Maybe they'll do it again.
I'm not askin' anybody
to do my fightin' for me.
Oh, so you're willing to do your own,
are you?
You know what I came for.
I do.
I just want to hear you ask for it.
Just ask for it, Yank.
- You've got 20 pounds on him.
- And so I have.
What if I put one of me fists in me
pocket? Right or left? You choose, go on.
Go on, that's fair enough, isn't it?
(WILL LAUGHS)
The fightin' Thornton!
It was Mr Thornton,
so I brought him in.
Bless my soul. Come in. Sit down.
- Have you tiddled your last wink?
- I have.
- No cheating?
- I have not.
- Do you play tiddly-winks?
- No, I...
Maybe I shouldn't have butted in
like this...
Nonsense. How is your lovely bride?
Fine.
Elizabeth,
say good night to Mr Thornton.
But he's only just come... oh.
Very well. Good night, Mr Thornton.
- Good night.
- Good night, Cyril.
Good night, Elizabeth.
Pleasant dreams.
- Are you sure...
- Good night, Elizabeth.
You're the only one I can level with.
I gotta talk to somebody,
or I'll blow my top.
- Danaher, of course?
- Yeah.
Since you know who I am... or was,
you know why I don't want any fighting.
Yes, I was reading about it again
this evening.
Some men collect butterflies,
some stamps.
My hobby's always been
sporting events.
There it is.
"Trooper Thorn quits ring.
Heavyweight challenger hangs up
gloves after fatal knockout.
Vows he will never fight again".
It's a very understandable reaction.
The papers all say it was an accident.
Just one of those things.
It's just one of those things
in a scrapbook, but...
...when you carry it
around in here...
Tony Gardello was a good egg.
Nice little wife and a home,
a couple of kids. A clean fighter.
I didn't go in there to outbox him.
I went there to beat his brains out.
To drive him into the canvas,
to murder him. That's what I did.
For what? Purse, a piece of the gate.
Lousy money.
And now money
is behind your trouble with Danaher.
They think I'm afraid of fighting.
All the friends I've made, even my wife.
- Well, aren't you in a way?
- Did you ever kill a man?
Well, I have, and all this talk
about her big fortune...
It's not that important.
Perhaps it is to her.
It must be strange to you
from America...
...but it's an old, old custom here,
and believe me, it's a good custom.
The fortune means more to her
than just the money.
Not to me, it isn't.
Not worth fighting for.
- Is your wife's love worth fighting for?
- I don't know.
All I know is that... I won't fight,
unless I'm mad enough to kill...
...and if that means losin' her...
I don't know.
- Maybe she doesn't love me enough.
- It's a difficult situation.
I think you'll find the right answer
in God's good time.
And when that time comes,
I hope I'm still here.
- You're not leaving, are you?
- It's a possibility.
My bishop is coming tomorrow
on his annual visit...
...and I've got such
a small congregation...
...just two o three people
at the service.
He may transfer me.
The place wouldn't be the same
without you.
Elizabeth and I just love this place.
We were born here too, you know.
The bishop's a good egg,
maybe it'll be all right.
Oh, by the way.
Don't underestimate Danaher.
He may be clumsy, but he's got
a tremendous right and a jaw of granite.
I did a little bit of boxing
in my time.
You won't be laughin' now, will you?
It was at Trinity.
"Lightweight champion, 19"...
The year doesn't matter.
It was long, long ago.
All right.
By the way,
would you join me in a glass of...
Oh, no.
No. You'll be in training now,
of course.
- (MARY KATE) Did you have any supper?
- No.
(SEAN) I'm not hungry.
- The drink sometimes does that to a man.
- I haven't had anything to drink.
(SEAN) If you wanna know,
I was talking to the vicar.
- Mr Playfair.
- That's strange.
I had a long talk
with Father Lonergan.
Woman of the house! Where's me tea?
Mary Kate?
(MICHALEEN) Save your breath, boy.
She's gone from you, and small wonder.
What are you talking about?
Where is she?
She came tappin' at me door.
"Will you join me to the train",
says she.
Why?
The very question. "Why", says I.
"Because I love him", says she.
"I love him too much to go on livin'
with a man I'm ashamed of".
- What time was this?
- Time for the Dublin train.
Saddle up my horse, will you, please.
Saddle his horse?
I'll have no part in helpin' you
to put more shame on her.
Saddle his horse...
Dam da dam da, diddle de da...
Well, we're off!
Then, might I suggest that the train
already is four and a half hours late.
Now, is it my fault?
There's a match at Ballygar,
and the champions of all Ireland...
If you knew your country's history
as well as you claim to know it...
...you'd know
that they haven't been beaten...
...west of the Shannon
for the last 22 years.
- True!
- It's a lie!
If this means what I hope it means...
Danaher versus the Yank.
It'll be weeks on the green this time.
Morning.
Good day to you, sir.
Five minutes, did you say? Right!
He's walkin' her back,
the whole long way!
It's Homeric,
that's what it is, Homeric.
- Post a lookout. They may go home first.
- Where's your pistol?.
- In the same place.
- Excuse me, general.
One by land, two by sea,
and I'll follow the lot.
What a day for Inisfree!
On a day like this
I can say only one thing.
Gentlemen,
the drinks are on the house!
Well, they are.
(WOMAN) Darling, here is your shoe!
Why, you...
It's only five miles.
Just a good stretch of the legs.
- You lost your shoe.
- Thank you very kindly, sir.
(WOMAN) Mr... Mr Sean! Here's a good
stick to beat the lovely lady.
Thanks!
(GUNSHOTS FROM OUTSIDE)
I think your in-laws are comin'
to visit you, Squire Danaher.
Danaher, you owe me 350 pounds.
Let's have it.
So, the IRA is in this, too, eh?
If it were, Will Danaher, not a stone
of your fine house'd be standin'.
A beautiful sentiment.
I'll pay you... never.
That breaks all bargains.
(SEAN) You can take your sister back.
It's your custom, not mine.
(SEAN) No fortune, no marriage.
We call it quits.
You'd do this to me, your own wife?
- After what...
- (SEAN) It's done.
There's your dirty money. Take it.
Count it, you spawn, and look.
If ever I see that face of yours again,
I'll push that through it.
Charge it!
I'll be goin' on home now.
I'll have the supper ready for you.
All right, Will, you asked for it.
Three to one given on Danaher.
Three to one...
- I'll have some of that. 10 on Thornton.
- Done! Anyone else?
(MICHALEEN) Gentlemen, if you please.
This is a private fight.
The Marquis of Queensbury rules
will be observed on all occasions.
Mind your nose, squire.
Okay with me, Michaleen!
Thanks.
Non-belligerents will kindly remain
neutral.
Now, shake hands and come out fighting.
I thank you.
Did you hear that, everybody?
The Marquis of Queensbury rules.
- The Marquis of Queensbury rules.
- Mar...
Come on, get up,
Marquis of Queensbury.
I hope
that Thornton beats him senseless.
Mr Thornton is a married man, Sarah.
Who cares about him?
It's that big bully concerns me.
"I'm the best man in Inisfree".
As if I didn't know that.
Call them and tell them to send
reinforcements. There's a riot here.
Five to one on the big chap, Snuffy.
- Given or taken?
- Given.
- You've had enough?
- No.
Well, give a man a hand, then.
Yes, inspector. Thank you, sir.
- What did he say?
- To put five pounds on Danaher's nose.
- Another ten on Thornton!
- Another.
- A pound on Danaher.
- Two pounds on Danaher, please.
Two pounds?
..."hands of a hundred battles,
eye on a thousand besides...
...stood alone on the victorious field,
his buckler bent...
...his broken sword clutched
in his mighty hand...
...the blood of a thousand wounds
oozing from his open veins"...
(NOISE OUTSIDE)
- Father! Father Lonergan!
- Shh, shhh.
- A big fight in the town!
- And in this fish right here.
- I'd put a stop to it but...
- You do that. It's your duty.
But you see,
it was Danaher and Sean Thornton!
- Who?
- Danaher and Sean Thornton.
Why the devil didn't you tell me?
- Shouldn't we put a stop to it?
- We should, lad, we should.
It's our duty, yes, it's our duty.
Come on, come on!
- How's that bettin' going?
- Even money, but don't ruin it.
Well, Danaher, you're a good fight,
I'll say that for you.
When it comes to that,
it's been a pleasure beatin' you.
Thanks.
- Will you take another 20 on Thornton?
- No, the book's closed.
- A pound on Thornton against the squire.
- Go away!
- How about a drink?
- The drink will be on the house.
That's a good idea.
The people of Ballyglon are comin' over
by bus, thousands of them.
That's a good idea, not that I'm tired.
I'm as fresh as a daisy.
You look more like a black-eyed Susan
to me. Let's go.
- Is that a public house?
- Yes, your lordship.
- Are they going in?
- Does that mean that the fight's over?
- No, that's just the end of round one.
Come, keep away, keep away!
Whiskey? No, that'll be too warm,
it'll get your blood up.
Porter is the very thing.
Ah, it's peaceful and quiet in here,
isn't it?
You know...
This has been a fight
I'd come a long way to see.
I hope you can stick around
for the finish.
Don't worry about that!
You know, Yank.
I've taken quite a likin' to you.
I'm gettin' real fond of you, too.
Your widow, me sister...
She could've done a lot worse.
- True, true.
- Poor woman.
- Thanks, fill them up again.
- You buy me no drinks.
- The drinks are on the house, sir.
- I'm takin' no drinks from you, squint.
- I'm buyin' the drinks.
- You can buy me a drink at your wake.
And not before.
I'm buyin'!
Bar towel!
- What time is it?
- Half past five, sir.
Lord, he beat you!
Why... I hope you won't be vexed with me,
but I've lost three pounds to Mrs Delany.
I know I shouldn't have bet but...
There you are, Stuffy, 15 pounds.
- Hello there, Elizabeth.
- Your lordship.
- And what have you been doing all day?
- If you'll excuse me, I'll...
...I'll get your tea, Snuffy.
There was a wild colonial boy
Jack Duggan was his name
He was born and bred in Ireland
In a place called Castlemaine
He was his father's only son
His mother's pride and joy
And dearly did his parents love
This wild colonial boy
Woman of the house!
I brought the brother home to supper.
He's kindly welcome.
God bless all in this house.
- Wipe your feet.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Sit down, sit down.
That's what chairs are for.
Hurry it up!
Well, then. So peace and quiet
came once again to Inisfree...
...and we were... Good heavens,
what's that woman up to now?
Make way,
she'll be runnin' you down with that!
When the Reverend Mr Playfair
comes down...
...I want us all to cheer like
Protestants. Now, spread out!
(CROWD CHEERS)
Hip, hip, hooray! Hip, hip, hooray!
No patty fingers, if you please.
The proprieties at all times.
Hold on to your hats. Come on.