The war criminals will
proceed in orderly fashion
to the main waiting room
and await instructions.
No talking!
Obey the guards!
War criminals must proceed to
the main waiting room!
Those caught talking
will be severely punished!
The Emperor!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
What do they think they're doing?
Stop! It is dangerous!
Go back. Go back. Go!
Are you mad?
They could kill us all!
Go! Go!
Open the door! Open the door!
Mama!
By the command of Her Imperial Majesty,
also called, the compassionate,
and the Blessed, the Respectful, and the
Long-Living, the Empress Dowager commands.
Aisin-Gioro Pu Yi,
son of Prince Chun,
shall be transferred
immediately to the Forbidden
City and will remain
in the great within,
awaiting Her Majesty's
decision. Respect this!
Ar Mo, I am giving you my son.
My son is your son!
Quick! Quick!
I want to go home!
Look, look at all the camels.
And look at the Forbidden City!
Give him to me.
Ar Mo!
Pu Yi, come here.
How small you are. Are you
afraid of me? Everyone is.
I am the Grand Empress Dowager,
and I have lived here
for a long, long time.
And they call me the old Buddha.
This is Peony. Do you like her?
Men, you know, are not allowed
in the Forbidden City after dark.
Even little men like you!
The only man who can live here is
the Emperor.
But the Emperor is on high,
riding the dragon now!
He died today!
Longevity.
These other men, they're not real men.
They're all eunuchs.
And, now, they're all
waiting for me to die.
That is why they're putting my bed in the
middle of the room, under the black pearl.
Little Pu Yi, I have decided that you will
be the new Lord of Ten Thousand Years.
You will be the Son of Heaven.
Are we going home, Papa?
Sssh! Sssh! Sssh!
It will soon be over.
Look!
Papa, cricket!
Cricket! Cricket! Where's the cricket?
Ahh, he is my friend, Your Majesty.
Safe and warm under my arm.
Kept me company on the long journey here.
Ahh, see? He is kowtowing to
Your Majesty.
Now, he can be
the Emperor's cricket!
Can't let anybody in!
His soup is getting cold!
Get out of here!
- Where am I?
- In the People's Republic of China.
Why did you stop me?
You are a criminal!
You must be judged.
I'm the Lord of Ten Thousand Years.
Go.
If you really wanted to die,
you would have succeeded.
You will kill me anyway.
Whatever happens, you'll be kept alive
until you have been judged.
Your Majesty, this is the
Forbidden City.
Ah, look! This little one is Your Majesty's
bedroom. This is where we are.
Am I going home today?
Not today, not yet. A-And
here, look.
This is the Hall of Supreme Harmony
where Your Majesty was crowned.
I give Your Majesty the Gate of
Marshall Valor.
- I give you the maju-gate the... gate!
- Yes.
Yes, and the Palace with
the Loudest Heaven... and... yes.
Your Majesty, your Imperial
bath is ready!
I don't like baths! I don't like
baths! I don't like baths!
I don't like baths anymore!
I don't like baths! I don't like baths!
No bean curd today and no meat!
Is it true I can do anything I want?
Of course, Your Majesty!
Anything you want. You are
the Lord of Ten Thousand Years.
Oh! Oh! Oh, no! Not in my
face! Oh! Oh, no! No!
I'm the Son of Heaven!
- Yes! Oh, yes!
- I am the Son of Heaven!
Ar Mo! I want to go home!
I want to go home! I want to go home!
I want to go home, Ar Mo!
I want to go home.
Once upon a time, there was
a great tree and a great wind.
The tree and the wind were
always fighting,
but when wind came back,
it was angrier and stronger
then ever.
Father.
My lady, she is the new nurse.
This is good breast milk.
Hey!
Come on, hurry!
And that's how you became my child.
I repeat.
Prisoners going to their
cells will walk with
their heads bowed. Keep
your eyes on the ground!
No looking forward or to the side!
The guards will give you directions
and tell you when to turn!
Eyes down! Move!
Pu Chieh.
Your guest is waiting to meet you,
Your Majesty.
Also, your mother has arrived.
You have not seen your mother
for many years, Your Majesty.
He is so small!
He is young, Your Majesty.
Go. Go!
The Emperor's brother,
His Excellency, Pu Chieh.
Ar Mo.
Stay with me.
How's the health of His
Majesty's mother?
It is better, thank you. How
much His Majesty has grown!
My mother has not seen me for
seven years!
Do you remember my face?
No!
The night they came with the horses,
I knew it would be like this.
My brother sees you every day!
Pu Chieh is very excited to meet you.
He often talks about you.
We are all very proud of you.
The kite.
He chose this for you.
Papa!
Some of my clothes are in these boxes.
This is the Imperial row.
My capes are in that big box.
What is that?
My medicines.
- Pills for rectifying the vapors.
- Look, a chamber pot.
These are my birds.
That is my heater,
and this is my camel.
They're turning away!
Of course! Ordinary people are
not allowed to look at the Emperor!
I am too important.
Is it true that you can do
whatever you want?
Of course, I can. If I am naughty, someone
else is punished. One of them!
Stop!
The Emperor will walk.
I have never met other children.
Are they all like you?
I've got three sisters and two friends.
If you come to our house,
you can play with us.
The Emperor never leaves the
Palace.
We play games together!
I know a game, too! Run!
- The ones in the boat are the high consorts.
- High consorts?
The wives of the Emperor
before me.
They say they're my mother,
but they're not! They're not!
We asked you for the
books, so prisoners will
have to pass this around
or read it aloud.
The sooner you begin to learn,
the better. This is a school.
History of the new popular democracy.
Pages 84, 85.
In February 1912,
2 000 years of Imperial rule came to an end
with the abdication of the Manchoo Dynasty.
China became a republic.
It was the year of the Rat.
Are you interested in ancient history?
School...
This is a prison.
A real prison.
I told you to start reading.
You, there, read aloud. Read!
According
According to the treaty between
the empire and the first republic,
the Emperor's taitou was
retained and not abolished.
He would retain his palaces, and he paid
an annual subsidy of four million dollars.
The republic also guaranteed to protect
the Imperial tombs in perpetuity.
In return, the dynasty surrendered forever
its right to rule the country.
Man, his nature originally good.
Let us see what the
Emperor has done.
Your Majesty will do it
again five times.
Five times!
Ten times.
Why are you wearing that?
You are not allowed to wear yellow!
But this is ordinary yellow.
- It is Imperial yellow!
- No, it is not!
We say it is! Only the Emperor
can wear that yellow! Take it off!
- No!
- Take it off!
No! And you're not the Emperor anymore!
There is a new Emperor now!
He has cut off his queue, and instead of a
camel, he has got a car!
What did you say?
You're not the Emperor!
Liar!
You're not the Emperor anymore!
Liar! Liar!
You're not the...
Liar!
You're not the Emperor!
How dare you!
Calm yourselves! Oh!
- You're not the Emperor!
- How dare you!
No! Your Majesty!
Calm yourselves!
Am I the Emperor or not?
Your Majesty will always be the Emperor.
- You see?
- Prove it!
Big Foot, drink it! Go on, drink
the green ink.
I will show you!
See? That is a car! He is the
President of the Republic.
Why is this wall here, Lord
Chamberlain?
It is just a wall, Your Majesty.
Nothing has changed.
You are lying.
High Tutor, am I still the Emperor?
You will always be the Emperor inside
the Forbidden City, but not outside.
I do not understand.
Outside China is now a republic,
with a president.
Where is Ar Mo? Ar Mo?
You are all liars!
- Let me say "good-bye"!
- Hurry! Hurry!
He's my child! Ah!
Ar Mo? Ar Mo?
I do not understand.
Your Majesty is a big boy now.
He cannot have a wet nurse anymore.
It is much better like this.
Much healthier.
But she is not my wet nurse.
She's my butterfly.
Ar Mo! Ar Mo!
This is the detention center of
the Fushun Bureau of Public Security.
And I am the governor!
During the war, this was a
Japanese prison.
Many of you may remember it.
Because you worked with the Japanese,
you were responsible for building it,
and you filled it with innocent people.
How could this happen?
Why did you betray your
country?
What turned you into war
criminals?
We believe that men are
born good!
We believe that the only
way to change is to
discover the truth and
look at it in the face.
That is why you are here.
You will begin by writing the story of your
lives and by confessing your crimes.
Your salvation will lie entirely
in the attitude you take!
I advise you to be frank and sincere.
Otherwise, things can still
go very badly for you.
You have learned that
song very quickly.
That is a good beginning.
It is snowing.
We must stick to the same story, or they
will turn our words against us.
After a few years, the tiny republic had
become as corrupt as the old Empire.
It fell quickly into the hands of ambitious
generals and corrupt bureaucrats.
The era of the warlords had begun. By May
1919, when I received my appointment,
China was in turmoil.
China awake.
Did you know they're now selling
electoral votes on the stock market?
Nothing has changed
with the republic,
either inside or outside
the Forbidden City.
- Except for the bicycles.
- The students are angry.
But what can they do
except shout?
The shops are closing.
Oh, so, they are.
Maybe we'll be late after all.
Shall we take a short cut?
- Yes.
- Use our feet.
Remember, you're one of the
first foreigners with an
official post in the Forbidden
City since Marco Polo.
It makes me very nervous.
The enemy.
Is there a dagger in my back?
Not yet.
My friend, it is not easy
to forgive a foreign
devil who knows Confucius
better than they do.
And grows the finest peonies in Peking!
May the new tutor present himself!
Your Imperial Highness, the new tutor.
The Emperor is honored to
welcome his tutor.
Your tutor is honored to have
been chosen, Your Majesty.
One more time.
Your Imperial Highness,
Mr. Reginald Fleming Johnston.
How do you do, Mr. Johnston?
How do you do, Your Majesty?
Now we will go to school.
Please begin the lesson.
Your Majesty, in my
country, it would be usual
to begin with some kind
of an examination.
The Emperor cannot be examined.
Well, that may have to change.
But first, Your Majesty might
like to ask me some questions.
Where are your ancestors buried?
In Scotland, Your Majesty.
But then, where's your skirt?
In your country, men wear short skirts,
do they not?
No, Your Majesty, Scotsmen do not
wear skirts. They wear kilts.
Kilts.
Kilts. A matter of words, perhaps,
but words are important.
Why are words important?
If you cannot say what you mean, Your
Majesty, you will never mean what you say.
And a gentleman should always
mean what he says.
Ah, yes! A gentleman.
Are you a gentleman?
I would like to be a gentleman,
Your Majesty. I try to be.
I'm not a gentleman. I'm not
allowed to say what I mean.
They are always telling me
what to say.
Your Majesty is still very young.
I thought he might like to see some
English and American magazines.
I have just received them.
I know that you know that I
know that you know that,
that is a dialog between
Confucius and Chuang Tzu.
Concerning respect, Your Majesty.
Who is this "George Washington"?
A famous American, Your Majesty.
A revolutionary General,
the first American President.
Ah! Like Mr. Lenin in Russia?
Not quite.
Does he have a car?
He lived a long time ago, Your Majesty.
I want a car.
I think your mouse is trying to
escape, Your Majesty.
Please do not tell anyone about
my mouse.
The lesson is finished.
Our official taster's a brave man.
Many of my ancestors
have been poisoned, you know.
Does Your Majesty have lunch
like this every day?
Oh, yes! Every day!
Like theater!
I do not know why.
It has always been like that.
This is my royal food.
Your Majesty!
One hundred year eggs.
Snake bow.
Angel's hair.
Garlic sprout, steamed turtle,
goat nipples...
There's a danger of poisoning pots.
My food comes directly
from the high consorts.
Their tasters had already tried them.
It always arrives a bit cold.
How do they kill Emperors in
the West?
The Austrian Emperor was shot, was he not?
No, but his nephew was assassinated
before the Great War.
But the Russian Emperor had
been shot. He was called the Tsar.
- Yes.
- He took lots of our land in Manchuria.
I'm a Manchurian. Even after the republic,
it's still my country.
The-uh... secret, Your Majesty,
is emerging again.
Is something the matter, Your Majesty?
Something is happening.
Silence. Tell them to be quiet.
Silence.
What is happening,
Mr. Johnston?
- Uh, nothing is happening.
- Quiet!
On my way here, Your Majesty, we were
held up by students from the university.
They were protesting against the
republican government,
because it has agreed to give
away Chinese territory to Japan.
Is it true, Mr. Johnston, that many people
out there have had their heads chopped off?
It is true, Your Majesty.
Many heads have been chopped off.
It does stop them thinking.
It is time for the Emperor's rest.
The students are right to be angry.
I'm angry!
But I'm not allowed
to leave the Forbidden City.
I want to go out,
Mr. Johnston!
My lord!
I want to see the city of sounds!
The Emperor awards you with
the order of the Ruby Hat Button,
and with the right to be carried in your
own chair, with four bearers.
The last Emperor died
on the same night
as the Empress Guwalgiya, the night
I was brought to the Forbidden City,
when I was three.
The eunuchs think he was murdered,
but who killed him.
And why?
And who will kill me?
The chair, your excellency.
The traditional gift to eunuchs.
Many thanks. Be grateful.
- If it is official practice,
- Always, sir, always, sir.
In which case, I would like an
official receipt.
Stop!
One, two,
Three, four, five...
Emperor extends his apologies.
Please tell the Emperor
that there is no offense.
Emperor who has been offended.
Ten, eleven, twelve, thirteen...
Even the bicycle was viewed with
suspicion in the Forbidden City.
My present to the Emperor
lead to a lot of trouble.
Change about!
I hope the Emperor has not forgotten
that this is the day for his math class.
For Your Majesty!
My doctor says,
"Bicycles are bad for you."
Bad for you, nonsense!
How does it work?
Oh, it's simple.
Head up and eyes forward!
As in math!
My mother is dead, is she not?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I'm profoundly sorry!
I'm not.
She killed herself.
She swallowed the ball of opium.
I'm going to see her, and my brother.
Open the door. Open the door.
Open the door.
Fallen devil and fallen machine.
Trouble! Nothing but trouble!
- Look where you lead him!
- And you are an old, cruel, ignorant man.
The boy's mother is dead,
and he's not even allowed to see her!
I want to go home!
Stop it, stop it, stay where you are!
Stop it, stay where you are!
You fool! Stay there!
Chang!
Hunchback, Big Foot!
Sir? Give me your hand, sir.
Give me your hand, sir!
Can you not see?
Look at my left ear, please, sir.
Thank you, and my right.
Thank you.
Would you follow my finger, please, sir.
Just the eyes, Your Majesty, not the head.
Well, it's perfectly simple, Johnston.
The Emperor needs spectacles.
Like Harold Lloyd!
Impossible! An Emperor does
not wear spectacles!
That cannot be allowed!
Times have changed,
Your Highnesses!
If His Majesty doesn't get spectacles,
Johnston, he could lose his sight.
Now, please, could you show me
the way out of here?
Your Majesty.
If the Emperor does not get
spectacles, I will resign.
Unfortunately,
our decision is final.
And, unfortunately, what I have to say will
be published in every newspaper in China.
What do you have to say,
Mr. Johnston?
The Emperor has been a prisoner
in his own palace since the day
that he was crowned and has remained
a prisoner since he abdicated.
But now that he's growing up, he may
wonder why he is the only person in China
who may not walk out of
his own front door.
I think the Emperor is the
loneliest boy on earth.
It would be conveniently sad
if he becomes blind.
Blind, Mr. Johnston?
To the expense, Your Excellency.
To the cost of
maintaining one thousand
two hundred eunuchs,
three hundred and fifty
ladies-in-waiting
and one hundred and eighty-five
cooks to buying a hundred
and twenty sable furs a month and
three thousand chickens a week.
To the fact that eight
hundred and forty guards
and employees of the
household department,
plus one Lord Chamberlain,
care only about one thing!
Filling their own rice bowls!
You are very good at accounts,
Mr. Johnston!
The Emperor may have abdicated,
but he's still a symbol
of great importance to many people.
If I did not agree with that,
I would not be here.
And some of us believe that one day soon,
he may be more than a symbol.
The spectacles are a detail.
What do you really want,
Mr. Johnston?
Just the spectacles.
The Princess Wan Jung, Your Majesty.
Seventeen years old.
Princess Wu Chang,
fifteen years old.
The princess De Li, Your Majesty,
and the Princess Fung Ying.
The Princess Wang Ching.
The Princess Shilean,
sixteen years old.
Who is this?
Princess Wen Hsiu,
twelve years old.
She has got a funny face.
Not just one wife. One empress
and one secondary consort.
- Two wives?   - But who did you
choose to be the Empress?
They chose her! She's very old,
Johnston! She's seventeen!
That's not so old, Your Majesty.
What does she look like?
Old fashioned! I want a modern wife,
Johnston, who speaks English and French!
And who can dance the quickstep!
Johnston!
Sir!
I'm going to escape, Johnston.
I've got a suitcase,
and a ticket to England.
I'm going to Oxford University.
Your Majesty, if you get married, you will
become the master of your own house.
A wedding might be a more
practical way to escape.
I suppose she's on her way by now.
It will be all right.
They do everything for you.
Why did you never get married,
Johnston?
Your Mongolian cousin
Prince Demchukedamgruv
has sent you twelve
racing camels.
Plus this.
On behalf of Manchuria.
A lump of coal.
Manchuria...
The secondary consort
welcomes the Empress.
The Empress greets
the secondary consort.
You are doing everything very well.
Thank you.
I rehearsed many times.
What is His Majesty thinking?
I was thinking, if I was the real Emperor,
I would become the ruler of China now.
And what would the Emperor do,
if he could really rule?
I would change everything,
even the way we get married.
Is the Emperor against arranged
marriages?
It is humiliating not to choose
whom you marry!
Even I was not allowed
to choose.
And yet westerners might be amazed
how much happiness can come from
arranged marriages.
That is what old-fashioned women say,
like the high consorts.
In another year or two, His Majesty
will be taller than me.
Is it true the Emperor has a suitcase
under his bed and is going to Oxford?
Will the Emperor take
Wan Jung with him?
Perhaps he would like to
see my face before he decides.
Yes, the Emperor would like to
see the face of the Empress.
It is the Emperor who must
remove the kait'ou.
I also had a tutor like Mr. Johnston.
Miss Windsor. She's American.
Miss Windsor taught me how to
do the dance of the quickstep.
Does the Emperor know how to
do the quickstep?
Will you teach me?
Leave us! Leave us!
If Your Majesty thinks
it is old-fashioned to
make the rain and the
wind with a stranger,
we can be like a modern couple,
to begin with.
A modern couple?
Good night.
You must come to Oxford with me.
I like him! I am sure
I am going to like him!
And he will grow up!
Eyes down!
Report your arrival!
Prisoner 981 reporting.
- Louder!
- Prisoner 981 reporting.
Open the door!
Close the door!
Sit down!
Name?
Aisin-Gioro Pu Yi.
Write it!
Now read that aloud!
Leniency to those who confess,
severity to those who resist,
Redemption to those who gain merits.
Now than, there are two types
of confession.
We call them
toothpaste and water tap.
The toothpaste prisoner
needs to be squeezed every
now and then or else he
forgets to keep confessing.
The water tap man needs one good
hard twist before he starts.
But then everything comes out.
Now, you're an intelligent person.
I'm sure you understand me.
Good.
Then we will begin.
Why do you think you are
in here, 981?
I'm accused of being a traitor, a
collaborator, and a counter-revolutionary.
It is not an accusation!
You are a traitor, you are a collaborator,
and you are a counter-revolutionary!!
Did you write this?
And you call it a confession?
This is nothing but a list of dates!
A child's fairy tale!
What do you want me to confess?
You know what you did and
what others did.
So why don't you
volunteer the information?
I do not understand.
We don't tell people what to confess.
We already know everything about you.
I...
Go on.
I wanted reforms.
What did you want to reform?
Everything.
Chang, you have a house outside
the Forbidden City. Do you not?
- Yes, Your Majesty.
- It has 20 rooms, I understand.
And you also have houses.
Oh, we all do, Your Majesty.
I recently learned that many pieces from
the Imperial collections are on sale
in antique shops in Peking.
Is that true, Cheng?
- Would you do me a favor, Wen Hsiu?
- Of course.
Stop growing.
The Forbidden City is a theater
without an audience.
The audience left long ago
when China became a republic.
- Cut off my queue.
- Your Majesty! Please!
It is heavy!
The Emperor before me was murdered
because he wanted to reform the empire.
Is that not so, Mr. Johnston?
Yes, Your Majesty, probably.
Well, let us see if they will kill me for
reforming the Forbidden City.
Lord Chamberlain! I'm appointing
Mr. Johnston's friend,
the poet and scholar, Chin Hsiao Hsiu,
to be the new Lord Chamberlain.
I want him to supervise a detailed
inventory of the Imperial storerooms!
So that we can learn exactly
how much has been stolen!
Can I sleep here?
I am frightened.
You're brave.
Are you not frightened?
I am excited.
I do not want to escape anymore.
I want to rule.
Kiss me.
Can I stay with you as well?
Get in. Get in.
I used to play a game with the eunuchs.
Trying to guess who is who.
Now I cannot see you!
Wan Jung? Wen Hsiu?
Come underneath the sheet with us.
Your Majesty! The storeroom's
on fire, Your Majesty!
Chang Chinghui, did you
not write a poem about
a spider who gets
caught in his own web?
I did not know Your Majesty had read
my poetry. I'm very honored.
I'm the spider.
The eunuchs set fire to this place to
stop me knowing what they have stolen.
I'm going to expel them
from the Forbidden City.
There are twelve hundred eunuchs,
Your Majesty.
They have been here for
eight hundred years.
It will be dangerous.
Do you think the republican government
would help me?
The republicans will do almost anything
if you know who to speak to.
It must happen quickly.
Before they burn the whole
place with us inside.
I lived with them all my life, Johnston.
They're my family.
Your Majesty, there is no alternative.
- What is happening?
- I don't know.
What are they carrying?
Their organs.
Whatever their crimes,
they cannot be deprived
of the right to be
buried as whole men.
Well?
I have forgot what
I was saying.
You're wasting our time!
We want to know about the Japanese.
How did your friendship
with the Japanese begin?
Who introduced you?
When?
It was... I think it was the new Lord
Chamberlain, Chin Hsiao Hsiu. It was 1924.
Parliament had been dissolved again.
The president had fled.
At first, I thought it was just another a
coup d'etat by just another warlord.
Only this time it was different.
This time it was my turn.
Fifteen, love.
Play.
Your Highness, how shocking.
Thirty love.
Ready?
Thirty, fifteen.
The rotten government of
the republic is in flight!
Now we shall remove the
foreign stench of the
Manchurian rats who still
hide in the Forbidden City.
Mr. Pu Yi and his family have been given
one hour to leave the Forbidden City.
They will be escorted
to the home of his father
and remain there under guard as state
prisoners until further notice.
What are you all looking at?
What are you standing there for?
You always wanted to leave
the Forbidden City.
Now you're got an hour to pack.
So, go! Go!
I always thought I hated it here.
Now, I'm afraid to leave.
Do you think they will kill me?
You must do as they say, Your Majesty,
while I try to reach the British Embassy.
They will give you asylum there.
I'm sure they will.
Chang, take my car to the South gate!
I want you to drive His Majesty.
Your Majesty!
Please, Your Majesty!
What?
But you didn't go to
the British Embassy, did you?
You ended up at the Japanese Embassy.
The Japanese were the only people
prepared to help me.
Help you for nothing?
Japan has an Emperor.
We're almost the same age.
I thought it was kindness.
At the same time, I realized that,
for many Chinese, I was an alien.
Simply because I am Manchurian.
There was even an anti-Manchurian
league who wanted to assassinate me!
So, I went to live in Tientsin.
There was a nice provincial town
with a big port.
In those days, we had a large,
international settlement.
The Japanese thought it would
be safer for me there.
If you had read the books we
gave you more carefully,
you might have learned
that the anti-Manchurian
league was largely
financed by the Japanese.
It was designed to frighten you.
I did not know that at the time.
- Cigarette?
- I do not smoke.
Were the Japanese paying
for you in Tientsin?
Oh, no.
I had to rent a villa,
the Villa Chan, and it was very expensive.
So were the bodyguards.
I spent a lot of money in Tientsin.
Did you still believe in a restoration
of the Imperial system?
Others did.
They were later caught and exiled.
I cannot remember how much jade
and jewelry they made me
spend to buy the friendship of some warlord
or some white Russian general.
I even financed an English
speaking newspaper.
They closed after three days.
It was unreadable.
And what else did you spend
your money on?
Oh, I was never tired of buying pianos,
watches, radios...
As long as they were foreign!
Of course.
Anything Western was good.
Especially Wrigley's chewing gum,
Bayer aspirin, and cars.
While you were in Tientsin,
most of China came
under the control of
General Chiang Kai Shek,
the so-called Nationalists,
the Kuomintang.
What were your relations with them?
None.
I felt useless in Tientsin.
I was twenty-one.
I dreamt of going to the West.
I became a playboy.
Am I blue. Am I blue.
Ain't these tears in my eyes
telling you. Am I blue?
You'd be, too. If each plan with
your girl done fell through.
Was a time, I was her only one.
But now I'm the sad and lonely one.
Boo-Boo-Boo, Boo-Boo-Boo.
Now she's gone and we're
through. Lord, I'm blue.
- Very good.
- Well done.
That's a great ship,
if you're going first-class.
I'm not going anywhere.
Would you like to dance?
You're a brave man. Nobody here
would have danced with me.
Why is that?
- Because I'm Chinese.
- Well, I'm American.
You say California.
I say French Riviera.
San Francisco!
Monte Carlo! Are we really going this time?
- Who's that couple?
- Oh, Henry and Elizabeth.
- The Emperor of China?
- The ex-Emperor and his wife.
- She's beautiful.
- Yes, very.
And who are you?
I'm His Highness's other wife.
- His other wife?
- Number two wife.
Well, some people have the luck.
Ladies and gentlemen!
General Chiang Kai Shek
has taken Shanghai!
The Kuomintang have broken with the Reds
and have knocked them for six!
The Reds are finished!
Sorry about the reception, everyone!
It would be wiser to return to the Japanese
delegation now, Your Majesty.
- Your car is waiting.
- Thank you, Mr. Amakasu.
The general strike in Shanghai
has collapsed.
The international settlement is safe.
Troops of the Kuomintang
are now in full control of the city.
And firm steps are being taken to
restore order in the native areas.
What do you think of General
Chiang Kai Shek?
What should I think of him?
He's just another warlord.
Well, he has mashed
the Communists.
That's good. Except the Communists were
his sworn allies until a few days ago.
I expect he betrayed them
for money.
- You want some gum, Elizabeth?
- Uh-huh.
Wen Hsiu, you want some gum?
I want a divorce.
I do not want to be your
mistress any longer.
I thought you were my
secondary consort.
In the Forbidden City, you were the
Emperor and I was a secondary consort.
But now you are Henry Pu Yi.
Wan Jung is your wife, Elizabeth.
And who am I? I'm nobody.
I did not know you were so unhappy.
You can only have one wife
in the West.
I want a divorce.
No one can divorce me!
I want a divorce!
Come inside with me?
Leave me alone.
Your Ladyship!
Thank you.
I do not need it!
Wen Hsiu?
Elizabeth! Can I come in?
Don't you remember me? I'm dressed like
a pilot, but I still can't fly! Not yet.
Eastern Jewel!
We had dancing classes together!
Yes, just before your marriage.
Silly girl!
Why do people want to get married?
Wen Hsiu has gone.
She will never come back.
Is it so bad?
She was my only friend.
Well, at least now you've got
your husband all to yourself!
And you've got me!
I'll be your friend.
- You smoke opium?
- Be wicked.
It's the best in Shanghai!
Why are you going to Europe?
The place to go is Japan!
It's more fun than anywhere!
It's modern.
How do you know we're going
to Europe? It is a secret.
Oh, I know everything!
I know Chiang Kai Shek has got false teeth.
I even know his nickname,
"cash my check!"
I'm a spy. And I don't
care who knows it.
A spy?
I work for the Japanese
Special Service Bureau,
and I've come to protect you.
The Japanese. They are getting
closer to him every day.
He is sending his brother to the
military academy in Tokyo.
They talk to him about
Manchuria all the time.
And Mr. Amakasu
never says hello to me.
I do not trust the Japanese.
Of course, I'd love to be the
Emperor's new secondary consort!
Eastern Jewel.
If the post is available.
The post is vacant,
my dear cousin.
But you do not fit the part!
Wen Hsiu left the dog behind.
Do you want it?
It is my fault.
It is all my fault.
I came to see you, Your Majesty,
to give you bad news.
Something terrible has happened.
The Imperial tombs of our Manchurian
ancestors have been attacked and robbed
by troops of the Kuomintang.
Chinese soldiers.
A warlord working for
Chiang Kai Shek.
The body of the Empress Dowager
was hacked to pieces.
Her pearl necklace
has become a wedding
present from Chiang Kai
Shek to his new wife.
Prisoner 981 reporting.
Open the door!
Close the door!
Tell me, 981. Do you consider
yourself to be Chinese?
- Of course.
- What is this?
Japan.
And what do you call this part
of China?
- The Northeast.   - And what did
you call it as a child?
Manchuria.
Japan invaded Manchuria on
September eighteenth, 1931
and began to set up a puppet
state called Manchukuo.
Shortly afterwards, a Japanese delegation
paid you a secret visit in Tientsin
to request your collaboration,
which you say you refused.
Speak up!
I've already told you.
I have told you a hundred times.
Tell us again! Tell us
two hundred times!
I refused to collaborate.
You say you refused, but a month
later, on November tenth, 1931,
there you are arriving in Manchuria,
or should I call it Manchukuo?
Now, according to this
so-called confession of
yours, you didn't go
of your own free will!
You insist that you were
kidnapped by the Japanese!
- Yes.
- And taken to Manchuria by force!
- Yes!
- Sit down!
Do you remember a man called
Reginald Fleming Johnston?
He was your tutor.
Yes.
And a good friend, I believe.
After twenty-eight years in China,
Mr. Johnston returned to England.
He became a professor of Oriental
studies at London University,
and he wrote a book. It is called
Twilight in the Forbidden City,
and it is dedicated to you.
I am going to miss you,
Johnston.
I shall miss you, Your Majesty.
Do you think a man can
become Emperor again?
Yes.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
How can we say "Good-bye"?
As we said, "Hello."
Farewell, Mr. Johnston.
Farewell, Your Majesty.
All aboard! All aboard!
Thank you, sir.
Good-bye, Mr. Johnston!
We'll never forget you, Mr. Johnston.
Good-bye! Mr. Johnston!
Good-bye! Good-bye!
All aboard!
On page four-hundred
and forty-nine, Mr. Johnston writes,
The endeavor to make out
that the Emperor had
been kidnapped by the
Japanese is wholly untrue.
He left Tientsin and went to
Manchuria of his own free will.
Johnston was a liar!
What did you say?
I didn't hear you.
Mr. Johnston had left before
I was taken to Manchuria.
He could not have known
what happened.
Sit down!
Is this your confession, 895?
- Yes.
- According to this account,
you prepared the man's things
on the morning of November ninth!
Isn't it unusual for a man who's kidnapped
to have his luggage packed
by his valet the day
before he's kidnapped?
This is what you've written,
isn't it?
Who told you to pack this man's luggage?
These two stories don't fit,
do they?
It was a long time ago.
Perhaps I made a mistake.
You are lying!
You are both lying!
Control yourself!
My family was buried alive
in Manchukuo.
My mother digged her own grave
because of people like them.
Smash the enemies.
Smash them forever.
Enough.
These might help you
to remember the truth.
What made you write that?
It is the truth.
Chen Pao Shen wishes you a safe journey.
You mean he refuses to say
goodbye to me.
He will see me when he comes
to my coronation.
Request a truce.
In case you change your mind.
I am the hereditary ruler of the
Manchurian people.
There can be no Manchukuo
without me.
Do you not see?
The Japanese are using you.
I must try to use them.
The Japanese invasion of Manchuria will be
condemned by the League of Nations
and by every civilized
country on earth!
The Chinese Republic has broken every
promise it ever made to me!
Chinese troops desecrated
the tombs of my ancestors!
And Chinese troops did not defend
Manchuria from the Japanese!
But Manchuria is still China!
China has turned its back
on me.
Please, do not go.
Manchuria is the richest
frontier in Asia!
Coal, oil, railways!
Millions of Chinese immigrants
are going there every year!
I'm going to build my country.
Chen Pao Shen: If you go, you
betray your country.
Which country?
Johnston was wrong,
but he wasn't a liar.
There was no kidnapping!
You went to Manchuria by your own choice,
because you wanted to be Emperor again!
You will rewrite your confessions
from the beginning!
Guard!
Take these people away!
Out!
To heaven.
To earth.
Chen Pao Shen is a fool. How could he
miss the birth of a new country?
It looks like the
inauguration of a factory.
To the moon.
To the sun.
You're an empress again.
What I'm going to be is a pilot!
I'm going to train at a secret base near
Yokohama to learn precision bombing.
I want to bomb Shanghai.
Bomb Shanghai?
I hate China!
I hate you.
The Japanese Army High Command!
Very impressive!
The Japanese Army!
Quickly!
On behalf of the Emperor of Japan,
the commander of the Kantong Army
extends his warmest congratulations on the
occasion of His Majesty's coronation.
Manchukuo will grow into a bright vision.
Japan will always be on
the side of the Emperor.
Uh, may I introduce you?
My wife, the Princess Hiro Saga.
Prime Minister Hsiao Hsiu.
Honorable Chang Chinghui,
Minister of Defense.
The monseigneur,
Monseigneur Colonna.
The Empress and I accept with
great pleasure.
Excuse me, General.
Ahh! And now Mr. Amakasu.
He's the new chief
of the Manchuria
Motion Picture Studio.
Why do you have to spoil this day? Why?
Mr. Amakasu is the most
powerful man in Manchukuo.
What are you talking about?
You did not believe I could be
Emperor again, but I am.
You are blind.
Do you know what it means
to be an empress?
You are an empress!
Why do you not make love to
me anymore?
Because you have become an
opium addict.
Opium killed my mother.
Opium destroyed China.
You can buy opium anywhere
in Manchukuo!
- Shut up!
- In any shop.
Shut up!
Your brother is going
to have a child.
We must have a child.
We must have an heir.
Emperor Hirohito has officially
invited us to Japan.
I'm going alone.
You are staying here.
I would never go to Japan.
Then go to your room!
Ten thousand years to
His Majesty, the Emperor!
Ten thousand years!
Ten thousand years to His Majesty!
To His Majesty, ten thousand years!
I told you, I hate you.
Only because I give you what you need.
Now we're engaged.
- Good morning.
Good morning, sir.
You forgot my toothpowder.
Oh... yes, sir.
Move him!
981!
Collect your things!
I said, collect your things!
Keep to the story.
That is an order.
Upstairs!
Stop!
Your laces are undone.
Do them up!
Thursday, you serve lunch.
Friday, you clean the toilet.
Saturday, you sweep the floor.
I have never been separated
from my family.
You'd better get used to it!
It's not so bad.
People get used to anything.
You do not remember me, do you?
I was the Minister of Trade,
in Manchukuo.
You were all in Manchukuo.
Now I'm the cell leader.
It is important to follow the rules here.
No talking during study sessions!
Where is your gun, Captain?
Where are their swords?
Our weapons have
been removed, Your
Majesty, on orders
of Colonel Yoshioka.
Colonel Yoshioka?
Colonel Yoshioka!
What has happened here?
Why has my guard been disarmed?
Yes, it is very unfortunate, Your Majesty.
There have been many
changes while you were in Tokyo.
Your Majesty, may I present
Masaomi Kobayakawa,
the new Japanese
Ambassador to Manchukuo.
Why is Prime Minister Hsiao
Hsiu not here to receive me?
The Prime Minister has resigned,
Your Majesty.
His son has been assassinated.
- Assassinated?
- By communist bandits, Your Majesty.
I must see him at once.
He refuses to see anyone, Your Majesty.
He has gone to a monastery, far away.
Who are you?
Chang Chinghui, Your Majesty,
Minister of Defense.
Yes.
Of course.
The council meeting will
be at four o'clock,
Your Majesty, before
the state dinner.
The Emperor has been asked to
sign the following.
After careful consideration,
we have decided to nominate
the Honorable Chang
Chinghui as the new Prime
Minister of Manchukuo.
No.
Today, on our return from Japan, we wish
to speak of something more important.
The future of our friendship with Japan.
This is based on mutual respect,
and respect means equality
and independence.
When the two Emperors stood together
and saluted the two national flags,
they recognized that Manchukuo
had come of age.
Manchukuo is not a colony.
Manchukuo is Manchuria.
The relationship between
our two countries is
like the relationship
between these two Emperors.
It is rooted in paternal trust,
in... in the desire to preserve
our ancient traditions,
and in a mutual respect for
our national identities.
Already, we have welcomed the ambassadors
of El Salvador, Costa Rica, the Vatican...
Soon I'm... I'm sure the other
countries will follow.
Chang Chinghui was an idiot.
He thought the open board were there
to decrease production.
But that was just propaganda.
What the Japanese really wanted
was cash, more production!
Of course, they've gotten rid of him.
Well, I had been in the drug business
all my life... opium, heroin.
I could deal with
the green gang in
Shanghai, even with
Chiang Kai Shek.
That is why the Japanese wanted
me to be Prime Minister.
You were right.
I was blind.
I'm going to have a child.
The father is Manchurian.
Colonel Yoshioka, Mr. Amakasu!
I did it for you!
His Majesty forgot to
sign the appointment of
the new Prime Minister,
Mr. Chang Chinghui!
I did not forget.
When an Englishman robs someone,
Your Majesty, he becomes a gentleman.
If he robs a lot, he becomes a knight.
Do you imagine the British run
their Empire as a charity?
If India has to pay for the cost of its own
occupation, so must Manchukuo.
We hope Manchukuo will have an heir.
The Empress is expecting a child.
Yes, Your Majesty,
we are aware of the situation.
This is the name of the father.
His name is Chang!
He is your driver!
All the necessary facts have been recorded.
The man will be punished.
The Emperor cannot allow
his honor to be stained.
The Japanese are the only
divine race on earth.
We will take China,
Hong Kong, Indochina,
Siam, Malaya,
Singapore, and India!
Asia belongs to us!
How long have you been here?
Three years.
You were issued with the same
clothes as everyone else.
Why can't you learn to look
after yourself?
There have been complaints
from your cellmates.
You must learn how to urinate
at night without waking them all up!
The way to do it is to
urinate against the
side of the bucket,
not into the middle!
Yes, comrade.
You still think I'm your
servant, don't you?
This is the last time, the last time.
This is the last time.
Why do you think Big Li has been
in prison all this time?
Or haven't you thought about it?
Because he was my servant.
Yes.
Loyalty is a great quality, isn't it?
So do you think it is unjust that your
loyal servant is punished for serving you?
I think it is not a question of justice.
It is a question of justice!
Even the servant has a choice.
Maybe he had nothing to do with
the political decisions of Manchukuo
or the crimes that happened
around me.
He was the only innocent person there.
Sit down.
Carmen Li is now a free citizen
of the People's Republic of China.
He is being released today.
You have a train to catch.
This is my wife.
We had three children.
You know nothing about me.
Thank you.
For a long time, I thought you kept
him in prison,
because you wanted
someone to look after me.
If you went out on the streets of China
today, and people knew who you were,
somebody would probably try
to kill you!
You talk of your past as if you were
the only one who suffered.
Stop hiding behind
your private story.
Write it again! All of it.
We are all pretending. You are
just pretending you have changed.
You cannot speak like that in here.
That is counter-revolutionary talk.
I know who you all are.
You were a captain of
the Imperial Guard,
and you become a spy
in the palace.
You, the Minister of Trade,
were responsible for the starvation
in Manchukuo.
He...
Prime Minister of Narcotics.
Shut up! The party teaches
us to be new men!
We're working for a new China!
You worked in Amakasu's private office.
You are still the same people!
People do not change.
Guard! Guard!
Guard!
I let it happen.
Guard! Guard!
The second edict, Your Majesty.
Japanese will
be the official language
in Manchukuo schools.
Your Majesty!
The baby was born dead, Your Majesty.
How is the Empress?
It would be better if she goes
to a clinic, somewhere warm.
She's already left,
Your Majesty.
Open the door.
With Manchukuo now firmly
in their grasp, the
Japanese soon controlled
most of North China.
By 1937, they were ready to strike South,
at the heart of the country.
The attack on Shanghai was one of the
first civilian bombing raids in history.
It left thousands homeless,
thousands dead.
Three months later,
Japanese armies were
besieging the provisional
capital at Nanking.
And when the city fell,
the atrocities began.
Trying to terrorize
the rest of China into surrender,
the Japanese High Command
ordered a massacre.
More than two hundred thousand
civilians were systematically executed.
The world watched in horror,
but no help was given.
On December the
seventh, 1941, Japan
attacked the American
fleet at Pearl Harbor.
There was no warning.
Manchukuo, the Japanese
bastion in North China,
was still ruled by the
puppet Emperor, Pu Yi.
But behind the facade of triumph
was a country enslaved.
A country where Japanese
experimenting biological
warfare were carried out
on live human beings.
A country where opium production became
the easiest way to finance the war.
Millions of people were deliberately
turned into drug addicts.
Nine days after the bomb at Hiroshima,
on August the fifteenth, 1945,
Emperor Hirohito announced
the surrender of Japan.
It was the first time his voice
had ever been heard on radio.
You must get to Tokyo, Your Majesty.
You must surrender to
the Americans, not the Russians.
The communists will kill everyone!
Your excellence have reached Habi.
We must leave at once.
There is no room in the plane.
No trucks!
The Empress has returned.
Your Majesty, please.
The Empress must not know you
have seen her like that.
Your Majesty!
Hurry! There is no room on the plane,
The women are looking beat.
We must hurry!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty is leaving now!
Now!
The Russians!
Perhaps you think we are here
to teach men to lie in a new way.
Why did you sign every
accusation made against you?
I didn't stop you from killing
yourself to see you like this.
Someone who signs anything to please
his enemies, to please me!
You knew about a lot of things in
Manchukuo, even the secret agreements.
But you couldn't possibly
have known about the
Japanese biological warfare
experiments in Harbin!
Could you? So why
did you sign these papers?
I was responsible for everything.
You are responsible for what you do!
All your life you thought you were
better than everyone else.
Now you think you're the worst of all!
Why can you not leave me
alone?
You saved my life to make me
a puppet in your own play.
You saved me because I am useful to you.
Is that so terrible, to be useful?
Aisin-Gioro Pu Yi!
By order of the Supreme
People's Court,
the war criminal, Aisin-Gioro
Pu Yi, male, fifty-three years old,
of the Manchu nationality, and from Peking,
has now served
ten years detention!
As a result of remolding through labor and
ideological education during his captivity,
he has shown that he has
genuinely reformed!
In accordance with clause
one of the Special
Pardon Order, he is
therefore to be released!
You see, I will end up living in
prison longer than you.
The Red Guards!
They are so young.
It is dangerous.
Look, over there, Pu Chieh, look!
It is the governor of our prison!
- It cannot be!
- It is! I'm sure it is!
Be careful! Come back!
Comrade, this must be a mistake!
I know this man! He is a good man.
- Who are you?
- I am a gardener.
Join us, comrade, or buzz off!
- But what has he done?
- He has been accused.
- Accused of what?   - Imperialismania!
Reactionary elements! Traitor to country!
- Confess your crimes!
- I have nothing to confess.
Kowtow to Chairman Mao!
- Confess your crimes!
- I have nothing to confess.
Kowtow!
- Confess your crimes!
- Wait!
He's a teacher!
He is a good teacher!
- You! Get out of here!
- You can't do this to him!
Move!
You want to be him?
You are wrong!
He is a good teacher!
Decision of reactionary element!
Stop!
You are not allowed in there!
- Who are you?   - I live here!
I'm the son of the guardian!
Ah, well, I used to live here, too.
That is where I sat.
Who are you?
I was the Emperor of China.
Prove it!
This is the Hall of Supreme Harmony where
the Emperors were crowned.
The last Emperor to be crowned
here was Aisin-Gioro Pu Yi.
He was three years old.
He died in 1967.