- Are yous ready?
- Aye.
On your marks. Get set.
Go!
Stew, Dr Garrigan?
And you, Dr Garrigan?
- I thought that...
- Mother.
...seeing as we've something to celebrate,
we might have a wee drop.
Sherry, right. Great.
- We are very proud of you, Nicholas.
- Very proud.
Not quite as good a degree as mine,
but a fine one nevertheless.
Being a family doctor. Let me tell you,
Nicholas, you've chosen a fine life.
If you'll both raise your glasses,
a toast.
To father and son.
A long future together.
Nicholas, are you all right in there?
I'm fine.
OK, first place you land, you go.
First place you land, you go.
Canada.
What are all the soldiers for?
- Do you speak English?
- Yes.
What are all the soldiers for?
The army's taking over. There is a coup.
- A coup? What? Are we safe?
- Don't worry.
These are General Amin's men.
He fights for the people.
- It's a very happy day for us.
- OK.
- Is that him?
- Yes.
- What do you do in Scotland?
- I'm a doctor, a qualified doctor.
I thought I could maybe use my skills here.
- Monkeys. Look. Look up there, Tolu.
- Do you have monkeys in Scotland?
No, we don't have monkeys in Scotland.
No. If we had monkeys in Scotland,
we'd probably deep-fry them.
This is my stop.
I'm a medical officer overseas.
Dr Garrigan.
- Dr Merrit?
- No. I'm Sarah, David's wife. Welcome.
- Hello.
- David was called out on an emergency.
- I hope everything's OK.
- Just normal business here. Safe journey?
- You know. It was...
- Bloody awful?
A goat up your arse
and your face in someone's armpit.
Last time I did that trip, I nearly asphyxiated.
Right, hop in.
- Actually, I waited for the bus yesterday, too.
- Yeah?
We were getting a little worried about you,
thought you might be caught up in the coup.
It's official now, by the way.
Obote's out. The radio's full of it.
Who's Obote?
- Ex-president.
- Right. And whatshisname.
Amin. He's taken over, yeah?
You've certainly come at a busy time.
Whatever I can do to help.
- Morning, Nicholas.
- Morning.
- So, what do you think?
- Aye, fine.
Come on. Come through.
This is the operating room.
Simple procedures for the most part.
- Morning.
So, how many doctors are there here?
Well, there's me and now there's you.
- Morning, Sister.
- Morning.
You know, the interesting thing is,
80º/% of the locals
still prefer the witch doctor to us.
Sometimes I think we're just
skimming the surface of an ocean.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
There we are.
There we go. Yeah.
OK.
Yes, thank you.
OK, and one more. OK, who's next?
That's a lovely name. OK. Can I see?
You ready? Now, come on, Angela.
Dr Merrit.
What is it?
- Complications with the Mugisha baby.
- I'll go.
No, I better go. I know the mother.
Sorry.
I'll be back in an hour or two.
Bonny.
- Jump in.
- Hi, Bonny.
Hi.
- I hope you don't mind me saying this, but...
- Yeah?
You seem an unlikely candidate
for this kind of work.
Why? Cos I don't wear socks and sandals?
Touché.
I still want to make a difference, you know.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
I wanna have fun, too, though.
A bit of adventure, something different.
That's a lot of things.
Is it?
Doctor.
A beautiful goal for Scotland.
- A good one.
- Bonny, why are the women singing?
You don't know?
The president is coming to the village.
Where's Dr Merrit?
He has gone to town for stores.
Come on. I thought you might be
slightly curious to see the new boss.
I don't work for Amin.
Right. Fine.
I just thought it might be fun.
OK.
Amin.
Uganda.
Uganda. Uganda.
And I want to promise you
this will be a government
of action, not of words.
We will build new schools,
new roads
and new houses.
I may wear
the uniform of a general,
but...
In my heart, I am a simple man
like you.
I know who you are
and everything that you are.
I am you.
Ask my soldiers.
All my life, I never eat food
until my soldiers have eaten first.
It will be like this in Uganda now.
Together, we will make this country better.
And stronger.
And free.
Uganda.
- Have you seen enough now?
- What?
Have you seen enough now?
Just a couple of minutes.
- Can we please go now?
- OK.
They sang just like that for Obote,
until they realised he turned their economy
into his bank account.
- Come on. Give the man a chance.
- I'm serious.
You talk to me in a couple of years.
What's going on?
Jesus.
- What's the problem?
- They're looking for a doctor.
- The president's been hurt in an accident.
- We have to come. We'll follow you.
God. Terrifying.
My hand.
My hand is broken.
Get that farmer out of my sight.
Come. Come here.
I'm Dr Garrigan. I hear you have a problem
with your hand. I'd like to examine it.
There you go.
Could you just raise your thumb like that?
- How's that? Is that OK?
- Yeah.
Sarah, I think we're gonna need a splint. Can
somebody do something about that cow?
I don't think you've broken it.
I think it's just sprained.
Please, it's in pain.
Can you hold that there
with your other hand, please?
Sarah, can you go and talk to that farmer
about his cow, please?
Sarah, how's it going?
- Somebody put that animal out of its misery.
- I am trying to explain to them.
For God's sake.
I'm sorry.
- I couldn't hear myself think.
- You took my gun.
- Yeah.
- Who are you?
Nicholas G... I'm Dr Nicholas Garrigan.
I work at the medical compound in Mogambo.
- I'm a doctor.
- You are British?
I'm Scottish. I'm Scottish.
Scottish.
Why didn't you say so?
I fought with the Scots against the Mau Mau.
Great soldiers. Very brave.
And good people, completely.
Let me tell you, if I could be anything
instead of a Ugandan, I would be a Scot.
Right. Really?
Except for the red hair,
which I am sure is attractive to your women,
but which we Africans,
we find this quite disgusting.
Thank you, Dr Garrigan. A very good job.
Please.
Would you let me have this T-shirt?
My son Campbell, he would love this T-shirt.
- You've got a son called Campbell?
- Yeah.
Maybe you would take my shirt here
in exchange.
Right. Of course. Yeah.
Thank you.
You see? Now you are a general like me.
Salute, please.
Now I must leave.
I bet you that's worth a few bob.
I still can't believe how you shot that cow.
You're mad.
- Anyway, I...
- Do you fancy a wee drink on the porch?
No, thank you. I'm OK, really.
Nicholas, I have to go.
Look, it's fine, all right?
We're just having a drink.
God.
I can't do this.
What?
My husband is a good man.
Christ. I sound ridiculous.
I guess I just need you
to understand why I'm here.
- It's OK. I do understand.
- No, you don't.
- I'm sorry.
- It's OK.
It's just sometimes,
when you're married to
such a very good man,
it's... it makes you feel...
Like shit.
My father's the same.
And...
it's nice to be noticed.
- I can't. I can't.
- Sarah, it's...
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- It's fine.
- No, don't, please.
- Sarah, it's fine.
Please.
Nicholas.
Nicholas, there are some people
here to see you.
I'll be right there, David.
Right. Right.
- Good morning, Dr Garrigan.
- Morning.
My name is Jonah Wasswa,
Minister of Health.
I've been sent by
his Excellency President Amin.
- There is something he would like to ask you.
- What?
Sarah?
Hey. Listen, why don't you tell David
to rearrange the field trip for Friday?
I'll be back as soon as I can. He probably just
wants me to retie his bandages. See you later.
- My name is Masanga.
- Nice to meet you. I'm Nicholas.
Pleased to meet you, Mr Nicholas.
Welcome to the president's car.
They think you are the president.
The president's house.
Please, sit down.
- His Excellency will be with you in a moment.
- Who's this?
- Dr Junju. The previous incumbent.
- Of what?
Of the post
of personal physician to the president.
Hold on to your guns, everyone.
Hold on to your guns.
Good to see you again, Dr Garrigan.
You see, Jonah?
This is the sort of man a president needs,
someone who is not afraid to speak his mind.
So, what do you say, Nicholas?
Will you take the job?
I'm sorry.
You want me to be your physician?
- Do you want to be of service to Uganda?
- Yes, I do.
Then what better way
than to look after the health of its president?
Let me tell you, it will not be a difficult job
because me, myself,
I am a man in perfect physical condition.
Also, I know precisely when I will die.
It came to me in a dream.
So you do not have to worry
about making a mistake.
I'm really sorry. I'm very honoured, but...
Nicholas, I understand.
Me, myself, I did not want to be president,
but the people, they wanted it so.
Listen to me. This is very important.
Here, in Kampala,
you will have a hand in creating
a new health service for this country,
something that will help millions of people.
I'm sorry. I do have a commitment
to the mission in Mogambo
and I'd be letting them down horribly.
You see?
It's the woman, the one I saw you with.
You want to get back to be with her.
Not entirely.
It's the woman. It's the woman.
Why don't you tell her
to come and be here with us?
It's not that simple. It's complicated.
Why?
Is she married?
Yes, she is.
Doctor.
Doctor, you, you are very naughty.
Me?
Now you are even more interesting.
Married woman,
they are always the most passionate.
- It's true.
- They are so grateful.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry for wasting your time.
No, no.
My car will take you back
first thing in the morning.
But, in the meantime,
tonight we are having a state dinner.
- Please, would you join us there?
- I'd very much like that. Thank you.
You have a suit? A dark suit?
No. No, I don't.
How much is this gonna cost me, by the way?
It's OK. It's on president's account.
Can I just...
Stop!
- What's going on?
- Obote's men. They're everywhere.
- Really?
- Yep.
They're communists, you know?
Mind you, Amin's more than
a match for them.
He's ex-British army. King's African Rifles.
Jamshid, pack those up
and have them sent to the High Commission.
OK, thank you.
Yes, he's a little unpredictable,
but he's got a firm hand.
Only thing the African
really understands. Thanks, Jamshid.
Up yours, too, pal.
Bloody English.
Hello.
- Hello there. How do you do?
- Nicholas. I'm so happy you came.
- So am I.
- Please. Please, this way.
I want to introduce you
to my wives. Excuse me.
This is Malyamu. She is my first wife.
She has given me five children.
Hello.
And this one, Nora. She has given me three.
Hi there.
And that here is Kay.
- Yes. This is Dr Nicholas Garrigan.
- Hello.
- He saved my life.
- Really, I just stitched his hand up.
- Don't be so modest.
- It is you I have to thank for the T-shirt.
Right. So you must be Campbell's mother?
- Yes.
- It's a pleasure meeting you.
Come. I have to introduce you
to some people.
Excuse me.
This is British High Commissioner
Mr Perkins.
- How do you do?
- Meet my good friend Dr Nicholas Garrigan.
- And his colleague Mr Stone.
- How do you do?
Yes, we've already met.
- I will talk with you later.
- Right.
We've been hearing
all sorts of things about you.
Yes, I gather the president
has clasped you to his bosom.
- No, no. Not exactly.
- What do you make of him?
I think he's doing
rather a great job. Don't you?
Yes. There's issues to be sorted out,
but, no, he plays a pretty straight bat.
Yes, definitely one of us.
Anyway, it's very good
to have another Englishman around.
- Scot.
- What?
I'm a Scotsman.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Friends, I am speaking with you now
because if I wait until later,
you will be too drunk to hear my voice.
Here is where civilisation began.
Here in Africa.
Here is where the Greeks
stole their philosophy
and the Arabs took their medicine.
We Ugandans
must be more proud of this history.
We are an independent African nation,
living in peace and economic power.
- Black power.
- Yes.
Just like all you people
thought would never be possible.
And now we will go through to dinner.
The food tonight, it is all local,
special food.
And none of it is human flesh.
This is my last.
Dr Garrigan, please come quickly.
The president is very sick.
They have poisoned me.
They are trying to assassinate me.
Nicholas.
I just have to examine your stomach.
Obote's people are everywhere.
They want me dead, Nicholas.
OK, I just need to do this. OK?
One more, one more.
OK. OK. OK.
OK, I think I know what this is.
Let me listen, just listen.
OK. Yeah. OK.
I think I know what this is. Bear with me.
There we are. OK?
I'm gonna ask you
to sit on this pouf right here.
What is this? What is this?
I'll just hold it against your stomach.
I'll ask you to stand up in three.
One, two, three.
Go.
I feel better, much better.
Yes, you are a good doctor. Thank you.
In future, remember
not to mix beer with aspirin.
- That was the cause?
- I think so. Yes.
I am ashamed that you saw me like that.
I was frightened.
I'm a doctor. Everything that passes
between us is confidential.
OK? I've taken an oath.
But a man who shows fear,
he is weak and he is a slave.
Well, if you're afraid of dying,
it shows you have a life worth keeping.
You see? You are a doctor,
and also a philosopher.
Yes. I do have a good life now.
Please. Please, sit.
Sit here.
I come from a very poor family.
I think you should know this.
My father, he left me when I was a child.
The British army, it became my home.
They took me as a cleaner in the kitchen,
cleaning pots.
They used to beat me.
"Build this wall, Amin."
"Dig this latrine, Amin."
And now, here I am,
the President of Uganda.
And who put me here?
It was the British.
What a story.
- Good night, Nicholas.
- Good night, sir.
- Hello. Sarah, it's Nicholas.
- Nicholas, where are you?
I'm still in Kampala, actually.
Thank you.
The president's offered me ajob.
Normally, I wouldn't even consider it,
but, under the circumstances,
I thought it might be quite a good idea.
I see.
- David will be disappointed.
- Well, I'll write to David, of course I will.
Of course.
I just hope you can do as much good there
as you could've done here.
Look, somebody's calling me. I'd better go.
Sure.
All right. Listen, bye, Sarah. I'll be in touch.
Bye.
When you're not treating the president or his
family, the hospital could use your expertise.
This is one of our new medical wards.
Further down the corridor are the operating
theatres, which the president has paid for.
- Yes, sir.
- Hi, Doctor.
Welcome to Mulago. Dr...?
Garrigan. Hello.
I do hope you find the hospital
up to the standard you're used to.
Excuse me. Who was that?
Your predecessor Dr Junju.
- Never mind him.
- Excuse me, sir.
He's here.
- Excuse me a moment.
- Of course.
- Hello.
- Jolly nice to meet you.
Dr Garrigan.
Just topping up on quinine.
- So, you decided to stay?
- Yes, I did.
Excellent. I just wanted to say that if there's
anything we can possibly help you with,
please don't hesitate.
What? You're my new best friend now?
Do just stay in touch.
Why?
Well, given that we were
so intimately involved
with the President coming to power,
the foreign office has asked me
to point out our awareness
of your very unique personal relationship
with President Amin.
Should you find the need to clarify your
status regarding details of that relationship,
we would of course welcome any clarification
you might feel the need to share with us.
Is there some special school
where you people learn to talk that bollocks?
Do, please, stay in touch.
You take care now.
This man is going to kill the president.
So Nicholas walks up to that cow
and he shoots it in the head.
On your marks. Get set.
Go!
Amin. Amin.
I won.
- OK. Here, Nicholas.
- No, no, no.
- Before I forget, I need to ask a favour.
- Anything.
I will be in Libya next week, and I need you
to attend a meeting in my place.
- What kind of meeting?
- A simple matter of taste and common sense.
I cannot think of anyone better than you.
Gentlemen. Please, don't get up.
The president sends his apologies.
He's been called away at short notice
and he's asked me to step in.
- And you are?
- Nicholas Garrigan. His doctor.
- His doctor?
- Yes.
- And you are?
- I'm the Austrian foreign minister.
This is Dr Rommel,
one of our leading architects,
and Dr Bruner
from the institute of civil engineering.
Together, we are the first bid.
Bid, right.
For what, precisely?
I love it.
Good choice. Modern, elegant.
A symbol of Uganda's future.
Here is where we will have
the next Pan-African Congress.
- Nice.
- My two closest advisers.
Tweedledum and Tweedledee.
- Look what Nicholas has designed for me.
- Nice.
- I didn't design anything. It was...
- Nonsense.
You have a wonderful eye.
Jonah, he has no taste.
Look at him.
Even his suits, they look silly.
Is that not right, Jonah?
- What is it you want, Jonah?
- I have ministerial papers for your signature.
Go. I will sign them later.
I do not like the way that man looks at me.
- Do you think he looks at me strangely?
- No.
No, I can't say that I've noticed.
OK, enlargement of the mediastinum
and reticulonodular lung patterns
all indicating pulmonary TB.
Yeah, but it could be...
What was that?
Makindye prison,
where Obote's people are being held.
Can you hear that?
Dr Garrigan. Dr Garrigan.
Please come quickly.
The president's son is sick.
What's wrong with him?
Can you hear me, child?
I'm begging you to stop it, Mackenzie.
- OK. Thank you. You can step away.
- Stop it, Mackenzie, please.
- Hi. Your son's epileptic?
- I don't know.
- What? Has he been like this before, then?
- Yes.
Right, OK. Can you hold his knees up
against his chest? The other hand back here.
- This is Campbell?
- This is Mackenzie.
Mackenzie. Right.
Mackenzie, I am Dr Garrigan, OK?
We're gonna sort you out.
We'll get you to hospital.
No, no. The president will not allow it.
You must do what you can do from here.
- The child has to go to hospital.
- Please.
Please.
It's OK. Mamma's here.
Mamma's here. It's OK. Mamma's here.
OK. OK.
There you are. OK.
- There we are.
- Thank you. Thank you, Doctor.
I thought I was losing him.
It's OK. He's gonna be fine.
Could you move the toys
from that bed, please?
Big boy.
Big boy. Here we go.
- OK, baby. I'm so sorry. Sorry.
- It's OK. Don't say sorry.
Don't say sorry.
- So this is where you live?
- Yes.
Why not stay with the other wives?
Since I had Mackenzie, my husband
prefers us to be somewhere more private.
This is ridiculous.
I think your child has epilepsy.
It's a perfectly treatable condition.
- The president does visit you here?
- He visits the children, not me.
I'm a bad omen.
OK.
I'm gonna make an appointment
for Mackenzie at the hospital. All right?
I will tell the president
how helpful you have been.
Morning, Nicholas.
I could not go
without thanking you for helping my son.
- Don't mention it.
- I bring you a small gift.
No doctor should be without his ambulance.
- For me?
- Yes, come, come. This is yours here.
- What do you think?
- Are you serious? It's a fantastic gift.
Are you happy now? Let's try it. Drive me to
the airport. I have to fly to Libya on business.
- Don't you think I should get dressed?
- Quickly. Quickly.
- Now?
- Yes.
I'll just be a minute.
- Are you comfortable here?
- Very much, thank you.
So it was Obote's men
who attacked the prison, yeah?
- Yes.
- Right.
We heard the gunfire
all the way at the hospital.
- Yes. My soldiers, they held them off.
- We thought there'd be lots of casualties.
Do you want to drive your car? I want
to see you drive your car. Please. Come.
- Come.
- OK.
So, you do not like the way I treat my son.
No. No, I don't.
Hiding him away like that, it's ruining his life.
- That boy has everything he wants.
- Except the treatment that could save him.
He has comfort, a luxury life.
Money, sir, is no substitute for anything.
Nicholas, you have never been poor.
What about Kay? Don't you think...?
Do not speak about things
you do not understand.
But the way you are concerned,
it has touched me
and I will consider.
You know, I like this type
of frank conversation.
Yes, I respect your honesty
and your opinion completely.
Drive. Drive.
Drive past. Drive.
Drive.
Obote's men. I'm sure of it.
If I had not been in your car...
It is in my dream. They cannot kill me.
It is in my dream.
Somebody told his men my travel plans.
Somebody has betrayed me.
I cannot trust anybody.
I'm surrounded by traitors.
Masanga.
Nicholas. Nicholas.
You know Masanga.
He is one of my people.
He will handle
all of my security matters from now on.
Yes, sir.
- You will take care of me and this country.
- Yes, sir.
Where is Jonah Wasswa?
Where is he? I need my minister.
A minister should be by his president's side.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
And you call yourself my closest adviser.
You see? You see? These loyal soldiers,
already they have captured the criminals.
Do not pity them, Nicholas.
These men here, they wanted you dead.
Why did you try to kill me?
I will not die until I say.
Look at me.
You work for him. Obote.
That drunk, silly man.
You want to kill me for that drunk, silly man?
Uganda loves me
because I am loyal
and I am fair.
I am your president.
Come, Nicholas. This is no place for us.
These, I can read you later. And the rest,
that's just pro forma papers for you to sign.
I've left a small list of medical equipment
at the end for my old surgery in Mogambo.
Is there anything else, Nicholas?
Nicholas.
It's probably nothing, sir.
What?
Nicholas,
you are my closest adviser.
Please, tell me what is on your mind.
Last night, I went to the Holiday Inn
and had a drink.
And I saw Jonah Wasswa there
speaking to some white guy in the bar.
Something about it just didn't seem right.
It's probably nothing,
but you might wanna have a talk with him.
Just a talk.
Like I say, it's probably nothing.
Good night, sir.
- How are you?
- Very well. How are you?
I'm very well.
That is very good, Mackenzie.
- Very good. Go show your brother.
- OK.
Hiya.
Hi, ya.
He's looking much better.
Much better.
That other one is Campbell.
He is the one who got your T-shirt.
You're a man of taste.
Mummy. Mummy.
- Please. Goodbye.
- OK.
- He keeps pushing me, Mummy.
- OK, stop it.
Stop it, Mackenzie.
Garrigan.
- Daydreaming?
- Looking at you, Stone, I hope so.
I thought you'd be with the president
on his trip to London.
- No. I'm needed here.
- I do hope the man hasn't blown up again.
- What?
- I was reading this article in the Times.
I don't know if you've seen it. It seems ajudge
who ruled against Amin has gone missing.
- He hasn't been seen for five days.
- I'm sure there's a logical explanation.
The thing is, we've been getting reports
up and down the country of the same thing -
people speaking out against the regime
just disappearing.
No. If you're gonna accuse the president,
just come out and say it.
I was just hoping you might be able to
give us a little clarification.
Fuck your clarifications, Stone. Fuck them.
You people amaze me, you know.
The first sign of an independent leader
achieving something, what do you do?
You spit your dummy because you can't
stand the idea that he's done it without you.
I know he's a bit rough,
but what do you expect?
Do you think Obote's people
are sitting around waiting for clarifications?
Look at me.
This is Africa.
You meet violence with violence.
Anything else and you're dead.
Then perhaps you'd be so kind
as to explain to me
the whereabouts of Health Minister Wasswa.
What?
Well, he's missing, too.
But, as you say, I'm sure
there's some perfectly normal explanation.
I'm having drinks later
with the man who wrote the article.
Perhaps you'd like to join us,
shed some light on the matter.
- Fine. I will.
- About six o'clockish?
- Can I help?
- I need to see the minister.
I'm afraid she's busy.
You were right.
The health minister has gone missing.
- Apparently, he's fled to Tanzania.
- What? Jonah Wasswa?
He's embezzled several
hundred thousand pounds of ministry funds.
Some people are suggesting
that he's joined up with Obote's exiles.
- I find that very hard to believe.
- He was sealing a major pharmaceutical deal.
Life-saving penicillin for the masses.
I should know. I set up the meeting
with his South African counterpart
at the Holiday Inn.
So, this embezzlement,
is it on the record?
- Yes. Yes, it is.
- And I can quote you in the paper?
- I'm sorry, quote me?
- Not directly, of course.
As a government spokesman.
Government spokesman?
OK.
Mr President.
I've come to say goodbye.
I'm going home.
Mr President.
I got you. I got him.
Nicholas, meet my body double, Muyenga.
Look at him. Everything the same, except...
What do you say, Nicholas?
Is he as handsome as me?
- No. No he's not.
- You see?
You see? Nicholas agrees.
You are much more ugly than me, Muyenga.
Look. Look, Nicholas. I have others also.
All part of Captain Masanga's plan
for my security.
- Clever.
- Yep.
Nicholas.
My Nicholas.
What is all this about your going home?
You once told me that you respected me
because I wasn't afraid to speak my mind.
Speak.
It's this business with Wasswa.
I can't.
It fucking stinks. I can't help going back to
that moment when I asked you to talk to him.
This isn't me.
I have to go home now.
You cannot.
- What?
- Your work is not finished here yet.
But I didn't come here to finish anything.
You promised to me
that you would help to build a new Uganda.
You swore an oath.
The oath is a doctor's oath of confidentiality.
We all take it.
- It's got nothing to do with Uganda.
- Nothing?
Nothing comes from nothing.
You have a conscience. I know you do.
That is why you came here in the first place.
Or are you like all the other British?
Just here to fuck and to take away?
No.
Why else would I trust you with my family?
You are like my own son.
I'm Nicholas Garrigan.
And I'm from Scotland.
It's my home. I want to...
Your home is here.
Please. Just... Please.
Do not be a silly boy.
If you go now, what will they think
about you and Jonah Wasswa?
What are you talking about? I said talk to him.
Do not pretend to yourself
that you did not know.
You are a stronger man than that.
I didn't want him to die, though.
But you did it.
Why? You want to know why?
You did it
because you love me.
You have stepped
deep into the heart of my country.
Uganda.
Uganda embraces you.
Nicholas.
What you need is to have some fun.
Hey, Nicholas. Where have you been?
I want you to meet Betty.
And this here is her sister Joy.
Joy is going to look after you this weekend.
Joy.
- Hi.
And now, let the games begin.
Nicholas, you didn't know
we had Ugandan cowboys.
Finance minister.
Come here.
Can I have another whisky, please?
Let me tell you, Nicholas,
you've chosen a fine life.
You want to kill me for that drunk, silly man?
Nicholas.
Dr Garrigan.
Jesus fucking Christ, you look so lovely.
You know something? I shouldn't be here.
I should be in Scotland with my dad.
I should be looking after little old ladies
cos here I've fucked up.
Kay, I fucked up. I fucked up.
Not here.
- Walk with me.
- What?
Walk with me.
I'm fucking doomed.
Do you know he's got
go-go dancers after me now?
Where are we going?
I don't know.
- Nicky.
- Shit. It's the go-go dancer.
Through here. Come on.
Just follow me.
Fuck it.
He has always been like this.
He just chose not to show you until now.
Nicholas.
You have to find a way to get out.
He still listens to me.
He cannot trust anybody any more.
I'll wait, until things get really bad.
They are.
Really bad.
- Nothing.
- What?
I just had this mad image of me and you
sitting at my mother and father's dinner table.
"More stew, Mrs Amin?"
Nicholas.
You've got to get out.
- What is going on?
- I don't know.
What if somebody saw us?
- Just wait two minutes and then come out.
- Yeah.
Go. Go, go, go.
Shit.
Dr Garrigan.
It's four in the morning.
Can I have a word with you?
- Whisky?
- OK.
They've...
they've taken my passport.
You were saying that
if there was ever anything you could do.
I need to get out of here while I still can.
I was hoping
you might be able to help in that.
- Please.
- "Please." That's a nice touch.
Have you any idea
what's going on in this country, Dr Garrigan?
Some.
In the countryside,
they're not even bothering to dig graves.
They're simply feeding them
to the crocodiles.
Right here in Kampala, right under our noses,
he's wiped out the entire political opposition.
Thousands of Acholi and Langi tribesmen
from the army.
He's hardly even bothering
to cover it up any more.
Even members of his own cabinet.
Your friend, the health minister.
This is a man who was actually
trying to help his country.
Idi always seems to get it wrong, doesn't he?
Jesus fucking Christ.
Get me out of here.
You earn your passage first.
What?
You know what they're calling you?
His white monkey.
I'm his doctor.
- It's not my job to judge the man.
- "I'm his doctor."
Is that your defence?
How pathetic. Fuck off, Garrigan.
We don't just hand out passports
to chimps like you.
Particularly not chimps
with blood on their hands.
Look, you, I'm a citizen and I have rights.
Fuck your rights.
You do as I say or you don't get out of here.
You're his doctor.
You have unprecedented access to him.
Obviously, we'd help you with...
anything you needed.
You want me to kill him?
Amidst rumours of human-rights violations
and mismanagement,
the situation in Uganda
has deteriorated badly in recent months.
...ten new hospitals has had to be
deferred and all the rest of those...
Getting any definite information
from the country has become harder.
...has accused the British
of attempting to assassinate him.
...and so his policies
are growing ever more unpredictable.
The British government
has broken its promises to Uganda.
Because of this, I have decided
to expel all Asians from this country.
And these people, they are leeches.
They milk the cow,
but they do not want to feed the cow.
No longer. They have 90 days to leave.
They are too sick to leave.
Take your hands off him.
This is a sick man. How dare you?
I don't care where you get your orders from.
You cannot come into a hospital...
They're forcing our sick relatives to leave.
This is a hospital.
You get your men out of here now.
I'm complaining personally to the president.
You all right?
I'll see to this.
You're trying to help your people,
I understand that, but Uganda isn't ready, sir.
You expel the Asians now,
this economy will be on its knees,
not to mention the damage you'll do
to your reputation abroad.
Is that what you came here for?
To plead for your fucking Asian tailor?
These things do not concern you.
You are nothing but a doctor.
You are a nobody.
Get out.
Sarah.
Hello.
- What have we done?
- Who...? Kay, is that you?
He is going to kill us, Nicholas.
He is going to kill us.
I have to get it out of me.
He will kill me, Nicholas.
I have to get it out.
- What are we going to do?
- I don't know.
I want you to do it. Please.
You're a doctor. I know you can do it.
- I know you can do it, Nicholas.
- No, we can't.
I can't do that.
This isn't some simple procedure.
It has to be done under clinical conditions.
I have to...
If you don't do something now,
I'm going to have to find a place to go.
I'll have to get it done in one of the villages.
Is that what you want?
No, you don't.
Come here. Whatever you do,
you don't do that. All right?
I'm gonna sort something out.
Promise me you'll stay in the house.
Please promise me you'll stay in the house.
Promise me this...
promise this is going to be all right.
I promise.
We'll do it first thing in the morning.
Kay Amin?
- The president's wife?
- Yes.
- No. We couldn't do that here, not at Mulago.
- Why not?
It's the president's hospital.
He's bound to find out.
- We could do this discreetly.
- No.
He would kill her and us.
- It's too much to risk.
- What choice does she have?
Some backstreet job in a village somewhere?
Come on, Thomas.
You know what that means.
It's the only choice you've left her.
But I don't expect
it crossed your mind to wonder.
A white man with a black woman.
What does she need with such things?
Fine.
I'll do it myself.
The president wants to see you. Now.
My head is exploding.
I can't think. I can't sleep.
Look at this. Look at this.
The British newspapers say I am a madman.
The American newspapers
say I am a cannibal.
I am a cannibal?
These are lies.
I should throw them out for good.
Only Ugandan press from now on.
- You want something for the headache?
- No.
- Something to help you sleep, perhaps?
- Later. I want you to tell me what to do.
- You want me to tell you what to do?
- Yes. You are my adviser.
You are the only one I can trust in here.
You should've told me
not to throw the Asians out in the first place.
- I did.
- But you did not persuade me, Nicholas.
You did not persuade me.
Tell me what to do here.
Don't throw the journalists out.
They're only gonna write more lies about you.
You invite them to meet you face to face.
You charm them.
You show them what kind of a man you are.
You think this will work?
I think that's the Amin they need to see.
Thank you.
Thank you very much, Nicholas.
What would I do without my Nicholas?
Is there something going on here?
No. No.
No.
- Is there?
- No.
No.
- Are you sure, Nicholas?
- Yes.
Yes.
Give me a booster,
something to make me feel strong again.
Sir.
- Where are you going, Nicholas?
- I have something that I have to attend to.
No.
You have to stay here.
I need you for the press conference.
This is all very well, your Excellency,
but what about the reports of mass killings?
Who have you been talking with?
The British?
Go. Look around Uganda for missing people.
Go anywhere you please.
So, why would the British
spread these rumours?
Because they hate me.
Because I refuse to recognise South Africa,
a racist regime that they support.
- Also, they are jealous of me.
- Why?
Because while they are starving
with their strikes and with their protests,
the people of Uganda
are eating beef and driving big cars.
I have created the Save Britain Fund.
We Ugandans, we like to help friends,
so the Ugandans have got together
and saved three tons of food and vegetables
for their friends in England.
Because they are having
economic difficulties, let me assure you here.
Kay.
Kay, it's OK. It's Nick.
- What?
- I'm sorry.
She went to the village.
They had to take her to hospital.
It's been reported that you crowned yourself
the last king of Scotland.
My good friends the Scottish people have
seen how I have defeated the English here
and they want me
to do the same for them there.
Yeah. This woman here.
Did you write to the queen of England,
offering yourself as a lover?
You are very cheeky.
And this is what happens
when you betray the president.
This is what happens when you betray him.
I'm not. I enjoy it.
I could spend the rest of my life getting laid.
There should be more to it
than a lot of little tingles.
They say she has a clitoris
halfway down her throat.
Is this possible?
Medically?
Almost all aberrations of nature are possible.
I made an example of her
because she betrayed me.
I brought you those headache pills
that you asked for.
Good.
Is there anything else?
No. No, that's all.
Then go.
We are busy here.
Morning.
Come on.
- Shit.
- Hello? Yes.
Come on.
Yes, sir.
Nicholas, there you are.
Were you trying to run away from me?
No. No.
I need you at the airport right away
to help me with the hostages.
- Hostages?
- Yes.
An Air France aeroplane has been hijacked
by our Palestinian brothers.
They have landed here at Entebbe.
The eyes of the world are on Uganda today.
Come, Nicholas. To work.
How many passengers?
250?
How many of them are Zionist?
And television - plenty of television cameras.
Please, tell them to take the hostages
to the terminal building.
Mr President, the press is waiting for you, sir.
I wanted to assure you that the hostages
will get the best medical care.
I have made my own doctor available.
Doctor. Doctor, what's the situation here?
One woman with a heart condition
has gone to hospital, cases of shock,
and we're giving malaria pills to everyone.
- Who's not been seen by a doctor?
- We haven't.
OK, how many of you are there?
- Yourself? You've not been seen yet?
- Malaria pills. How is everybody?
Thank you very much.
OK. OK, anybody else?
OK. Take these three. The nurse
is gonna come round with water. Nurse.
Thomas.
Thomas, can you take these, please?
I'll be two minutes.
No. Don't.
Spit.
Look at you.
Is there one thing
you have done that is good?
Did you think this was all a game?
"I will go to Africa
and I will play the white man
with the natives."
Is that what you thought?
We are not a game, Nicholas.
We are real.
This room here,
it is real.
I think your death
will be the first real thing
that has happened to you.
Listen to me, Nicholas.
Listen. I know.
Yes.
I know about you
and Kay.
How could you do that to me?
I am the father of this nation, Nicholas,
and you have
most grossly offended your father.
You're a child.
That's what makes you so fucking scary.
In my village,
when you steal the wife of an elder,
they take you to a tree
and they hang you by your skin.
Each time you scream,
the evil comes out of you.
Sometimes it can take three days
for your evil to be spent.
Pull him up.
Good evening.
I have good news.
The Israeli government
has agreed to negotiate.
So, as a gesture of good faith,
all non-lsraeli hostages will be released.
I have arranged personally
an aeroplane to come and collect you.
Yes.
He'll be here when we come back.
This way, Israelis.
Israelis, here.
They have sent a plane.
They are releasing some of the hostages.
If you go now,
you will reach them before they leave.
Here, put this on.
Why are you doing this?
Frankly,
I don't know.
You deserve to die,
but dead, you can do nothing.
Alive, you might just be able
to redeem yourself.
I don't understand.
I am tired of hatred, Dr Garrigan.
This country is drowning in it.
We deserve better.
Go home. Tell the world the truth about Amin.
They will believe you.
You are a white man.
- What about you?
- My fate is in God's hands.
Go. Now, before they come back.
- Thank you.
- Go.
Go.
Thomas.
Stop.
Where is the doctor?
I don't know.
Destination Paris.
My wife.
There are many people
who have brokered relations with Israel.
They are not only Muslims,
they are also Christians. This particular...
Visiontext Subtitles: Chris Wallace
ENGLISH