Subtitles made by www.roylenferink.nl
The white zone is for
immediate loading and unloading
of passengers only.
No parking.
American 1493, Newark tower.
Wind 050 at 6. Go to land
on runway four-right.
Yeah. You live here or you commute?
I actually live here.
I live in a little town about an
hour north of here called Marlton.
I live in Denver. I came in last night.
You see all those
thunderstorms last night?
I didn't think I was gonna get in.
You know, I picked this up...
No, I haven't done it yet.
I'm still working on them, trying
to get certain days off.
And it looks like the only way I
can get it is to bid the reserve.
Yeah, you know, I go
back to the Training Center.
I have a month on, month off, so
I'll be giving check rides out in Denver.
Oh, that ain't too bad.
At least you should be home.
You cut it close today.
Come on through.
Yes. Next, please.
All right, go ahead.
Okay, please raise your arms. Thanks.
Just come right through.
All right, okay.
Thank you. You're good.
Nice flight.
Thank you.
No, that's fine. Okay.
She's got a crush on
that maintenance man.
See you later, guys. Oops. Oh, sorry.
I keep taking that. Damn.
As I go over here and build my nest,
you want to go outside
and do the walkaround?
Yeah.
I'll be with you in about five minutes.
All right. I'll be here. All righty.
Okay, I'll call her now.
Well, is it a complicated graphic?
'Cause if it's really... Excuse me.
Take care. Okay, bye.
...and I'll call you right back.
And, Kevin...
Drive south. We'll be there in time.
Did you get the word about
putting on some extra fuel?
Yeah. Yeah, doing it now. Okay, thanks.
Good morning.
Congratulations on the promotion, Ben.
Well, thank you very much.
Good morning. Congratulations, sir.
Well, thank you. Good morning.
Good morning. I'm
happy to see you all awake.
John. How are you this morning, sir?
Mr. Sliney, good morning to you.
You know the fellows. Yes, I do.
How are you? How are you?
Good to see you. Good to see you.
Good morning. How are you?
How was that midshift?
Rough. Yeah.
The floor is yours. Hold on,
and I'll see you at the 8:30.
Thanks, John. I'll catch up with you.
Yes. Good.
Ready for a brief? Yes, sir.
All right, sir, we've got a small
system in the southwest.
Nothing too big.
Shouldn't be a big problem.
Some low ceilings over
San Francisco, nothing major.
That system finally
moved off to the east.
And we've got clear skies.
Good. It'll be a good
day on the East Coast.
Yeah, what time is that fog
supposed to lift in the west? Do you know?
We're looking early afternoon.
Excellent. Excellent.
The President moving out of
Sarasota today up to Andrews.
Got restrictions in place till 10:30.
Standard ops in the morning,
normal morning restrictions in New York.
Yeah, he always wants to fly right
when traffic's the heaviest.
Thanks. See you, fellows.
New York cranking up?
Yes, sir.
All right. Good.
What is that? Coordinators down there?
That's right. It
needs to be diverted south.
Dallas/Fort Worth, go ahead. Yeah.
Can you guys hear me back there?
Do you guys have sugars up there?
Okay. Thanks.
Steal us a newspaper, that'd be great.
What'd she say the movie
was? Knight's Tale?
Knight's Tale.
Yeah, for cockpit access knock,
let's use three and one.
Three and one? Yeah.
Got you. Yup. That'll get you in.
Shipley and Mark do that.
I just didn't want to.
It wasn't the right time.
Yeah, it's Jeremy.
Hey, two things.
First, speaking of Shipley,
that e-mail that he sent,
when you respond to it,
CC me a copy of the response.
Isn't that sweet? Yeah,
we're getting a, you know...
No, don't send it
to Kevin. I'm so sorry...
No, it'd just go to waste on Joe.
He'd be just as happy with Ripple.
Ladies and gentlemen, we
will now begin boarding
our first class and Premier
Club passengers
for United 93, with
non-stop service to San Francisco.
I will call you back. Okay, bye.
Any passengers requiring
additional assistance
may also board at this time.
Now boarding through
Gate 17, United 93's...
Hello. Give this to you?
Thank you. Welcome aboard.
Hi.
Good morning, welcome aboard.
How are you today?
Excuse me, I'm gonna
follow him down there.
Good morning. Got your seat number?
Right down here on the right side.
Good morning, everybody.
And, sir, can I get you something to drink
while you're waiting for take-off?
Coffee would be great
with cream and no sugar.
Okay.
Good morning. Thank you.
Here you go.
Have a nice flight. Thank you.
Hi.
Thank you, very much. You're welcome.
Enjoy your flight. Here you go.
Thank you, sir.
Good morning, sir.
There you go, have a nice flight.
Good morning.
I'm just looking for 19.
Nineteen? Right down this way.
What seat?
Hi. How are you? Good. How are you?
Good morning. Good morning.
Hi.
Perfect.
Let me give you a hand with that.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Did you talk to the guys from Sony?
Sounds good.
Good morning!
Looks good, Captain.
All right, great, thanks.
Turn the lights off.
Number one, runway four-right.
Final call for Flight 93,
non-stop service to San Francisco.
All passengers must
make their way to Gate 19.
You're clear. Have a nice flight.
All right, clear to 5,000 feet as filed.
Squawk is 5273.
It's Tom. Hey, what's going on?
Is that supposed to be the latest one?
Where are you?
Oh, good morning, sir. Hi.
You just made it. 4D.
Thanks.
Welcome aboard.
Is that the last one? Last one.
All right, great. I'll see you later.
I think we're ready for you to close.
Watch your hands.
Thanks so much.
Alaskan Airlines,
contact Bradley. Approach 13532.
US Air, 2682, Boston Center, roger.
Charlie Echo 7821, roger.
Get back down to 7,000.
Am-X, 7281, contact
Boston 133.42. Have a nice day.
And American 11,
Boston Center. Good morning.
Boston Center, American 11 is
with you. Climbing to 14,000.
And American 11, turn 20
degrees to the right.
Roger. 20 degrees to the
right. American 11.
US Air 8720, Boston Center, roger.
Ladies and gentlemen, please make
sure your tray tables are up,
your seat backs are in their
full upright position,
and please switch off all
cellular phones... Cut it a little close.
...and any other electronic
devices. I know. One of those mornings.
Flight attendants, arm your
doors for departure.
You going home?
Yeah. Just here for work.
Your seat belt, please.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Ladies and gentlemen,
from the flight deck,
my name is Jason Dahl and
I'll be your captain today.
With me is First Officer Lee Homer,
and together, the two of us
will fly you to San Francisco.
En route time today is
5 hours and 25 minutes.
That'll put us on the gate in San Francisco
on time or a little bit early,
maybe a little bit before
11:00 local time.
It's a beautiful day for flying,
and our forecast across the country
is much as you see it here.
In just a few moments,
our flight attendants will be showing you
a very important safety demonstration.
Whether you are a frequent flyer
or a first-time traveler,
I urge you to put down
your reading materials
and pay attention to this
very important information.
Thank you, and welcome aboard.
United 93, ops.
Tail north. Then clear to push.
Okay. Tail north.
Clear to push us. Start.
Okay, tail north.
Brakes released. Cleared to push.
Yeah, good morning.
This is Rich Sullivan with the
11:15 strategic planning telcon.
We're updating advisory number 23.
First issue, we're showing
15-minute departure delays out of Newark.
Give us an update there.
I just spoke to Pete.
They're gonna try and get those
reduced or eliminated.
They're gonna get Washington
to reduce their restrictions,
so probably it'll clear up
in about a half hour or so.
Okay, we're gonna lessen the restrictions
or eliminate them on the Newark departures.
And the departure delays
should be coming down here very soon.
Next, we got a large-scale
military exercise off the East Coast today.
All the offshore routes
are gonna be closed at 1400.
All the traffic will have to be moved
inland. Any questions on that?
This is JetBlue. Is Amber
761 available for offloads today?
Don't go for it.
No exceptions.
They're gonna have to wait.
All the offshore routes
are gonna be closed.
Everyone's gonna be
moved inland. And that's it.
Anybody have anything else
for the morning plan?
Okay, we'll do the next telcon at 1315.
Good job.
US Air 29, contact Boston approach
on 120.6. Good day.
Glens Falls. After Glens Falls...
And American 11, climb,
maintain flight level 350.
Air Canada 129, Boston Center.
U.S. Air 129, contact Boston.
That's for American 11.
Climb maintain flight level 350.
Come on.
American 11, Boston. How do
you hear? Boston Center.
Hey, Greg? Yeah?
Try American 11 again.
See if he's on your frequency,
if he came back to you.
American 11, Boston Center.
How do you read?
American flight 11,
Boston Center. Do you read?
There are also two window exits
located over the wings.
Each exit is marked
with a sign overhead.
Look around to locate the
two exits nearest to your seat.
In some cases, the
nearest exit may be behind you.
In an evacuation, exit path
lights will automatically illuminate
to guide you to an exit.
A life vest is located under your seat.
It can be identified by a red tab.
Do not remove it unless directed
by a flight attendant.
Taxi clearance. Stand by.
We've got your release. I
want you to move up in the line
behind the United 757.
Good morning, ground. United
93, Gate 17, ready to taxi.
We have Alpha.
United 93, taxi runway four-left
via Bravo Romeo Bravo.
Hold short of Victor.
Roger. Said four-left
Bravo Romeo Bravo.
Hold short Victor. United 93.
And American 11 on emergency frequency,
if you hear Boston,
come up on frequency 127.82.
Am-X 7281, contact Boston on 133.42.
Athens, Boston.
Do me a favor, you got that
United 175 out there.
Can you have them take a look and see
if you can get a visual on American 11?
767.
United 175, turn 20 degrees
to your left, vector for traffic.
In your turn, look for traffic 12 o'clock
to 1 o'clock, about 15 miles.
He's tracking
south-southwestbound. Altitude's unknown.
It's an American 767. Let me know
if you get a visual on him.
Am-X 7281,
proceed direct O'Neill,
resume all navigation.
US Air 312, contact Boston on 133.42.
November 3622. Tango, roger.
Just be quiet and you'll be okay.
We are returning to the airport.
Call in Boston Center.
Say again, please.
Hey, John! Come here!
What's going on?
Aircraft, call in Boston.
Say again, please.
This guy here just
contacted me. I heard some verbiage
over the background. It was
not American, it was foreign.
They said something about
taking over the cockpit,
"Stay calm, we're
going back to the airport."
I have no idea who it was. I
think we have a hijack situation here.
What makes you think that's a hijacker?
Just trust me.
I heard the guy in my ear, okay?
I heard the guy in my ear. All right.
You need to check it out.
Command Center East. Tony.
Hey, Ben, we're doing a
coffee run. You want some coffee?
No, I'm filled up with coffee.
How are they doing on those restrictions
out of New York, Al?
Tell them they got them reduced. So La
Guardia, in fact, is now out of delays.
Newark's gonna stay a while, though.
Good job. Good job. Excellent.
Excellent.
Rich, you need to monitor this.
Yeah, let me take this
stuff. I got to get to the 8:30, so...
Command Center East. Toby.
Hey, Walsh.
Hey, Ben! Ben, hang on.
Yes?
Listen, we're just getting a preliminary
report from Boston Center.
They think they've got a hijacking.
A hijacking?
It's American 11. A heavy 767.
Departed Boston for LA.
Where is he now?
He's about 50, 60 west of Boston.
You got a squawk 7500?
No, I don't think so.
They heard some kind of
suspicious transmission,
so they're checking on it... All right.
It's very preliminary. All right.
When you get some hard information,
let me know and I'll brief the staff.
Thanks.
Did someone say "hijack"?
Everything okay? Yeah.
Good. Before we get started...
Well, that was a
possible hijack. American... What?
Yeah. Hijack?
Anybody remember...
Haven't seen that in years.
Yeah, I know. When was
the last time we had a hijack?
It's been quite a
while, quite a while. '91, '90.
I can't even remember precisely.
Yeah, I know.
No, no. It's Boston to LAX, American 11.
Yeah, they're on it and they're
gonna keep me informed.
I'll brief you. Okay.
Hey, ground. United 93.
What's our sequence?
United 93, follow the
Continental and Delta.
You're number 15 for the
departure. Monitor tower.
Air Canada 273, turn left...
Well, folks, from the flight
deck, Captain Dahl.
Looks like we've run into a little
bit of rush hour traffic
here at Newark this morning,
and that's a typical day at Newark.
I count 15 airplanes
ahead of us for departure,
and they're getting them off
about one every two minutes,
so unfortunately it's
gonna be about a 30-minute delay
until we get airborne.
I apologize for the delay
and I appreciate your patience,
and I'll get back to you
with an update. Thank you.
Yes?
Is everything okay?
Yeah, it's just fine. Just a
normal delay out of Newark.
Excuse me, can I have a pillow
and a blanket, please?
What did you say?
Guys, just keep your
planes away from him, man.
I have no idea what this guy's doing.
What do we have, Pete?
I gave all my aircraft
over to Greg already.
He's working them.
I'm holding onto this.
This guy right here
is the only guy I have.
He's westbound right now. I
heard some voices in my ears.
Flight 11, American Airlines?
But no 7500 code?
No, I had no 7500 code. Nothing.
American 11, Boston Center.
American 11, how do you hear?
No, see, that doesn't make sense.
What's up, Pete? Where are we at?
I just put it up into the speaker here,
if we hear anything back, but
right now we just have the guy.
He's due westbound. He's climbing...
I'm going back to the
airport. That's it.
That's it right here.
Somebody's got to pull
these fucking tapes right now.
Pull the tapes now from 0800 on.
To all personnel, NORAD exercise
commencing in five minutes.
Huntress. Weapons. Sergeant Powell.
Okay, and remember
this is a NORAD exercise.
Right now we have Russian Bears penetrating
the ADIZ up off Alaska,
so you'll want your tracker techs
keeping their eyes open.
Okay, stand by, one second.
Dawne, go out and see
what Powell's so excited about.
Yes, sir.
Powell, what do you got?
Hey, I got a hijack
on the phone. Boston.
Is this a sim?
No, real world. Come on, where's EET?
No, it's a no-shit hijack. It's Boston.
Serious?
Yes. All right.
Okay, thanks.
Well, okay, give them a call.
Yeah, we have a possible hijack.
General update. Tell
them we're ready here. Okay?
Can do, sir.
Sir? Yeah.
We have a real world situation here.
We have American Airlines flight 11.
It's a 757 out of Boston to LAX.
Ninety-two passengers on
it, and it's at 7500.
Still squawking? No, sir.
Okay. Get Nasypany to the floor!
All operational personnel to the floor!
Major Nasypany, report to the
operations floor immediately.
All operations personnel
report to the ops room...
This is Colonel Marr here.
Get me General Arnold.
Here you go.
Folks, Captain Dahl
again with an update.
We're making some progress now.
We're about number four for departure.
I'll get with you when we're
number one. Thanks for your patience.
We just want to take your
order for breakfast after take-off.
You're gonna get it.
We have a hot breakfast,
which is, like, an omelet,
roll and fruit.
I'll take that. Thanks very much.
Okay, great.
I'm sorry for the delay. We'll be
out of here as soon as we can.
I understand. Thank you.
Would you mind bringing me some
water with my breakfast?
I have to take some pills.
Sure. No worries.
I'd just as soon stay out
of the more populated areas.
Well, here are the falls.
If we go up there, we'll be all right.
I'd like to get up in that high country.
Go ahead, sir.
Good morning, Major.
We got a possible hijack
in progress out of Boston.
American Airlines 757. They're
not squawking. Let's find them.
Copy that.
All right, let's go.
Listen up, everybody!
All right, look, we got
a possible hijack.
This is real world. Possible hijack.
Surveillance, get your tracking
techs on scopes.
I want two on a scope. Copy that.
I wanna know if he pops up again.
ID, get on the phones with the
FAA. Let's get his last known position.
Copy. Weapons.
Otis to battle stations. Copy that.
Do you have a call sign or anything?
Battle stations. Copy.
American Airlines 11.
American Airlines 11 is the call sign.
Sir, it's confirmed.
And now the aircraft is NORDO.
We get a lot of that crap.
Somebody's making phony transmissions
on the radio...
If it's not confirmed, it's
probably a lost radio call or something.
Command Center. Tony.
Stand by one second.
Yesterday, we had two
ground delay programs.
One at Atlanta and one at O'Hare.
And we had 850 aircraft delayed.
Hit a 56-minute average
and a very modest 47,600 delay minutes.
Benny, that is like, $2,000 a
minute we are talking about.
You are into a hole already for...
No, no, no. ...90 million bucks, Ben.
They're not even my delays.
I started today.
Ben, we need you on the floor.
We're getting more information
on that American 11.
Oh, all right.
Listen, excuse me, John... Yeah.
...and, folks, I'm gonna
go out and take care of this.
We're getting some more updates Okay.
And I'll brief you as soon
as I get some more information.
What do you got?
American Airlines
contacted Boston Center.
Apparently, a flight attendant
onboard the aircraft
via telephone called the
company and she said that
the aircraft is being hijacked and one
or more people have been stabbed.
Stabbed on the plane?
Yeah. Just confirm...
American Airlines gave this information
to Boston who called us.
Is the aircraft still on
course? The last I heard.
Let's get an update
from Tony. All right.
All right, stand by.
This is Boston on
the line right now. Yeah.
They don't know anything more.
There was a suspicious
transmission, the controller heard it,
and they're pulling tapes to see exactly
what was said on the frequency.
And American Airlines is
the one that called them.
Who is it? The ops manager
of Boston Center.
Hi, this is Ben Sliney.
Boston thought it may
have been a... They heard
some kind of oddball Yes. Transmission.
Right. So she called the company,
she said their airplane
was being hijacked...
All right. Has he changed altitude?
...don't know if it's a
person or people who've been stabbed.
All right.
All right, we're
pulling it up now, and, listen,
if you get any further information on
the track or the altitude, let me know.
All right. Keep me advised.
Thanks. Yeah. Thanks.
All right, look, the...
That aircraft has made a turn southbound
and they're not tracking him any longer.
They're not getting any Mode
C altitude information.
And I see our track has gone ghost on
it, but they do say he's heading southbound.
I want us to get in touch
with New York Center
and let them know he's coming. Let's
get everything out of its way
and even give New York TRACON a call
because he may be trying to head
for one of the New York airports.
Okay, right.
Information's that American 11...
Maybe we should get in
touch with headquarters
and start briefing them on this
now. Yeah, I'll call immediately.
Thanks.
Folks, Captain Dahl with some good news.
We're currently
number one for departure.
We'll be airborne shortly.
Flight attendants,
prepare for take-off, please.
You know, I try and drop
as many trips as I can.
I like to be home with my babies. Yeah.
Yeah.
Did you bring some good magazines
to keep yourself awake?
I don't think I've gotten through a magazine
in I can't tell you how long.
We have some planes. Just stay
quiet and you'll be okay.
We are returning to the airport.
We have some planes. Just stay
quiet and you'll be okay.
We are returning to the airport.
Planes.
We have some planes.
Yeah, it's Bob here.
It's "planes." Planes. Plural.
Definitely, yeah.
United 93, wind 050 at 6.
Runway four-left.
Clear for take-off.
010 up to 5,000. Clear for take
off. Four-left. United 93.
010, 5,000. Here we go.
Welcome to New York Center.
Altimeter is 2996.
Maintain speed 310...
...speed of 300 knots or greater.
Maintain flight level 220 and
maintain a speed of 300 knots.
Roger, you got it.
New York. Thumbser.
Yeah, Boston.
New York. United 175.
All right, thank you.
I got it. All right.
Hey, Dave? Yeah?
American 11 looking
as a possible hijacking.
It may be going back
into Kennedy. Hijack?
They say they heard something,
that there might be intrusion
into the cockpit.
All right, just let me know
if you hear anything,
anything unusual or anything.
I'll watch him.
He's not squawking 7500.
So just keep it normal.
No, he's not doing anything.
I'll keep an eye on him. I got it.
Just keep an eye on him. Will do.
What's going on? We got a hijack.
It might be a hijack, I don't
know. It's American 11.
It's going down. You got a hijack?
We haven't had a hijack in
20 years. I don't know.
Listen, I don't know. What
do you want me to tell you?
I just gotta watch him. That's all.
Chris, you got that? Thumbser.
United 175 heavy, New York, go ahead.
...west of Kennedy by 15
southbound descending, it's American 11.
We're not sure what the problem is yet.
Possible hijacking, we're not sure.
Passenger said something
about they're up front.
Roger, United 175 heavy.
Well, I'll pass it along.
Wait, I'll talk to him. Paul!
Hold on. Paul,
United 175 heavy just called.
He said he heard a
suspicious transmission on the radio
as he was climbing out of Logan.
He said something about, "Everybody
stay in your seats."
He doesn't know who it came
from, but it came out
and he said it was...
He just heard it as he
was climbing out... United 175?
United 175 heavy, yes.
And what about American 11? American
11 's still... It's nothing.
He's just still going slow, you know.
He might be going into Newark
or Kennedy or something,
I don't know. You know, I have no idea.
Continental 1002, Newark
Tower. Good morning.
Why don't you try the next one down?
An arctic fish. How about "char"?
Ladies and gentlemen, Captain Dahl.
As we make this turn, those of
you on the left side of the airplane
have a beautiful view of lower Manhattan
and the New York City skyline.
Looks nice out there. Huh?
Looks nice out there.
What do you mean there's no one
there? Well, you guys must have a backup.
Whatever information they got,
they got to give it to us right away.
All right, good.
Hijack controller, no
one at the desk. No backup.
Looks like they're
on vacation. No backup?
There's no backup.
There's no one at the desk.
Who were you talking to downstairs?
I'm talking to this guy.
He's in the conference room.
There's nobody else in there.
I'm relaying the information,
and then he's moving...
We got it. We got the tapes. Boston
Center got the tapes pulled.
They said, "We have some
planes." Hold on.
That's what he said,
"We have some planes."
That was the suspicious transmission.
Was there any voice recognition?
I'm tracking it.
Jesus Christ.
Med Express 77, maintain 10,000.
The Kennedy altimeter's 2996.
Keep an eye on it. Now watch.
Delta 351, altimeter 2992.
Chilean 4369, New York altimeter, 2996.
Paul, what do you got? Hey,
Mike, how you doing?
American 11. Possible hijacking
on American 11.
He's southbound, 767.
Nobody's talking to him.
I just called the room up
and let them know about it.
They're not tracking
him either, right now.
Where was the target last time?
Last time it was tracked
in New York at Kennedy.
He's heading for the south.
American 11, New York.
What do you want me to check?
Target's gone.
Paul. Paul, the target for American
11 just disappeared.
Just disappeared where?
Right around Manhattan.
It just disappeared?
It was right there. It just disappeared.
I was talking to the other
aircraft. The target just disappeared.
Call Kennedy up. Find out if they have it.
We don't know where American is, all right?
Call Kennedy tower up, see
if they have him down there,
and call Newark tower and
see if they have him there.
Okay.
What do we got, boys? Anything?
All right, sir, you need me to
go ahead and start a recall for you?
Yes, initiate that.
Okay, great.
What's the status with Otis?
Are those planes ready?
Foxy, what you got? You got anything?
MCC, battle stations call made 0838.
Otis attained battle stations at 40.
08? Colonel, 0840,
slams at battle stations.
Otis at battle stations. Copy.
Get me something. Nothing's squawking.
MCC, Boston lost American 11.
They don't see him anymore
on their scopes.
They think maybe he went
below radar coverage.
They have no idea where he is.
We've got Otis. Have the battle ready.
We need scramble authority.
Copy that.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Okay, let's get those
Otis birds in the air!
Scramble Otis!
This is Huntress with an active
air defense scramble.
I repeat, active air defense scramble.
Time is 0846.
I authenticate November-November.
Greg, look at the
World Trade Center. What?
Look at the Trade
Center, man. Bob, you see that?
Man, that's a lot of smoke.
I can't believe that.
Yeah, take a look at the
World Trade Center.
No, I have no idea.
I'm getting reports from numerous
aircraft about smoke in Manhattan.
A lot of smoke.
A lot of smoke coming
out of the North Tower.
Thumbser, go ahead.
The American was over Manhattan
A small plane? Is that
confirmed? When I lost any sign of...
Ben, I just got...
New York called. Yeah?
They got smoke out of
the World Trade Center.
Smoke? They think a small plane
A small plane? Has crashed into it.
Small plane. I don't know.
That's what they're telling me.
A small plane went
into the World Trade Center.
You might want to have a look. Okay.
Sir.
CNN's reporting a light civil
aircraft has just hit the World Trade Center.
MCC?
MCC, CNN has just reported a light aircraft
has hit the World Trade Center.
Bill, get me CNN up on
screen three, will you?
Ben? Yeah.
New York Center called.
They were tracking the
primary target, they've lost it.
They said they'd lost American 11.
Where did they lose it at?
Somewhere over the city.
Over the city? Yeah.
He's down over the city? They don't know
if he's under the radar
coverage out there or not.
All right. Get in touch with the metro
towers, see if they got a visual.
Hey, it's coming up now.
I'll call TRACON, see if...
Jesus. Oh, my...
We're getting reports
this morning, that a plane
has crashed into one of the towers
of the World Trade Center.
CNN Center right now is just beginning
to work on this story.
Obviously calling our sources and
trying to figure out exactly what happened.
But clearly something relatively devastating
happening this morning there
in the south end of
the island... I don't know.
I'll tell you what, that
is not a small plane. No way.
It's huge.
A Cessna would have bounced off that.
Look at the size of that hole!
Look at all them people sitting...
I got a bad feeling about this.
I'll tell you right now.
Is that American 11? Is that
who they were tracking?
Nobody's telling us
anything. No info. I have no info.
Well, which way are we
looking here? If we're looking...
It looks like the sun's on that side of
the building, so we're looking north.
He came from our left. He
had to come from the west.
That aircraft came in from
the west into that building.
Who could it be?
Now where's American 11?
You know what I want you to do?
Get in touch with the NYPD.
See if they have any information on
what caused that in the Trade Center.
Look at the size of that explosion.
Sean, you're on the air right now.
What can you tell us about...
And, folks, Captain Dahl.
We've reached our
cruising altitude of 35,000 feet
and I'm going ahead and turn the
"Fasten Seat Belts" sign off.
That is your signal you are
safe to move about the cabin.
We got the seatbelt sign off.
However, when you are in your seats
I'll ask you to keep your
seatbelts loosely fastened,
as you never know when we'll
get some bumps we're not expecting.
Our flying time today again
is 5 hours and 25 minutes,
and in spite of that
short delay back there in Newark
I'm still projecting an
on-time arrival in San Francisco.
I'll update you on the weather
as we get a little closer.
In the interim now, I'll ask
you to sit back and enjoy
the outstanding service of
our fine flight attendants.
If there's anything we in the cockpit can
do to make your ride more enjoyable,
please don't hesitate to ask.
Thank you.
Hey, can I get a copy of the manifest?
Oh, sure.
Thanks. Here you go.
I appreciate it.
Yeah, no problem.
Looks pretty good, huh?
I love these light loads.
I do, too.
I knew you were gonna say
that, so I've planned.
We've got...
We have reservations there.
And there.
Fedex 7852, we heard it was a small plane
that hit the World Trade Center.
That's the last that we heard. Roger.
Eagle 755, you
contact departure on 126.8.
I gave you that Eagle
755 also, okay? Another one?
Yeah, Eagle 755. 755. Got it.
Toggle 9445, you
contact approach on 120.8.
Chris, I need you to
take this one also. Got it.
Hey, Dave, you got an untracked target
five miles east of Allentown.
Thank you.
United 175, I need you to
reset your transponder squawk 2374.
United 175, New York.
You read the radio?
Call American 11 again.
I'll try him again.
Paul, neither airport had
one. Maybe... He must've landed.
Newark heard nothing from
him, Kennedy heard...
Try the towers again. I'll try again.
He's gotta be somewhere.
He's gotta go somewhere.
United 175, New York. If
you read the radio, ident.
Traffic's 9 o'clock and seven.
Southwestbound Delta Boeing
73, same altitude.
United 175, New York.
United...
Paul, United. I think we got another
one. The guy has dropped his transponder off.
United 175, New York.
He's out by Allentown.
United 175. Thumbser.
If you have United 175, you need to
switch him back to... The traffic room.
No, I'm not talking to him. I'm
not talking to him. I know.
Delta 2433, stand by.
I can't take any more airplanes.
He's busy enough. We'll take care
of it. We'll take care of it.
We'll take care of it. They're
standing by, right now.
Watch that Delta 2315. He's
aimed right at him. The same altitude.
He's starting to get close
to him. You see that?
Please.
Give me a chance to
work. Just stay back!
Just give me a chance
to work here, all right?
United 175, New York,
if you read the radio,
you have traffic at your 9
o'clock and four miles southwestbound,
same altitude. It's a Boeing 73.
I'm telling you this is another
hijack. I'm telling you.
United 175, traffic is
your 9 o'clock in five miles.
Jesus. Do you have that Delta?
Delta! Delta 2315, traffic 2 o'clock!
Five miles, southeastbound, 757.
Traffic, three miles.
Turn him. Turn him.
1 o'clock! Turn to one and a half.
Heading southeastbound. 12 o'clock now!
No distance! He's right on top of you!
I'm telling you right now.
This is another hijacking.
Delta 2315, he's right on
top of you. This is a hijacking.
Delta 2315, you still there?
That's a roger, New York. We
are clear. Delta 2315. Over.
Paul, he just went behind him.
Holy shit. Good. Good.
Good job, sir. Good job.
She was sitting inside her apartment,
and she looked up and saw the side
of the World Trade Center...
All right. Thank you much.
...explode into flames and black smoke.
Excuse me. If they hijacked them...
New York Center says they got
confirmation that it was a commercial airliner
that hit the Trade Center.
Well, that's it.
That was American 11.
It had to be American 11.
What the hell is going on?
But how could he hit the building?
I mean, why would he hit the
building? Even if it is American 11, why...
It's clear and fifty. You
don't get a pilot flying a plane...
Either they're gonna
ditch it in the Hudson...
They're not gonna do this.
There's no way. No way.
Jesus, how many people
are in that building?
Ben? Ben?
I'm sorry, New York Center wants
you on the phone right now.
Yeah. Yes, New York.
Wait a minute, hold on. They
think they got another hijack,
and it's headed for New
York. Another one?
We got another hijack?
All right, United 175.
Get him up on there.
How many people are in that building?
Where is that military liaison?
Can somebody help us out?
We need some help here.
We're trying to get
the military involved.
We can't get anybody at headquarters.
All right, listen, you take care of
your house, we'll take care of this business.
Okay. Let me know if anything
else develops.
United 175, and it's
headed straight for New York.
United 175, New York. United 175.
United 175, New York.
United 175 here. This guy's at,
like, 10,000 feet a minute,
and he's still going down.
I heard. I heard.
United 175, New York.
This guy's dropping like
a manhole cover now, Paul.
He's still descending eastbound
towards New York.
This aircraft is going down,
I'm telling you right now.
Call the military up.
Find out where they are. Okay.
Are you listening to me?
This guy is going straight down
into the ground, I'm telling you.
He's not answering me.
We're not talking to
him. He's descending.
It's like 6,000 to
8,000 feet a minute now.
Dave, you still not
talking to that guy? No, I'm not.
He's going right through
everybody else's traffic.
The target's gone. It's gone.
The target's gone. The target's gone.
We don't have him anymore.
We just lost him.
All right, hold on. Hold on.
I got a primary on a target.
Where? He's rapidly descending.
Can you see that right here?
He's coming down
quick, yeah. Can you see that?
Well, who is it?
I don't know.
You see him out the window?
Is he out there?
Yeah, descending rapidly.
No, there he is. There he is.
Where? Right there.
Over the Verrazano Bridge.
Oh, yeah. Look how fast he's going.
No, he's going right up
the Hudson River center.
Oh, my God.
Jesus! Shit!
What? How does he do that?
There was then an explosion
inside... Damn it!
The building's exploding right now!
You got people running up the street!
I don't know what the hell is going on.
Did you see that? Did you see that, sir?
I'll have to call you back.
Oh, my God.
American, stand by.
Holy shit!
Jesus Christ.
Be advised there's a major
incident over New York right now.
Shawna, what do you got?
What do you got, Shawna?
Boston said that...
Boston just said they have
another hijacked aircraft. United 175.
Copy that. We've got another hijack.
We've got two hijacks.
175, also out of Boston.
Are they... Does Boston... Is...
Get on with FAA. Who was that?
There's no confirmation, sir.
MCC, we need our planes over Manhattan.
We need those Otis birds
over Manhattan now.
You got it! All right, weapons! Weapons!
You want any sugar in your coffee?
I'm fine for now, thanks.
What would you like to drink?
I'm glued to this.
Coffee or juice?
Yeah, I'll take some coffee. Hi, guys.
You know, I'm gonna
serve you guys after first,
'cause there's only six, if that's okay.
It was a beautiful take-off.
So you're still okay with the hot?
All right, well, then, we'll
bring you something to drink after that.
Yeah, it's like football
with no padding. Here you go, sir.
Hope you all enjoy this.
And I'll be right with you, guys.
And here we go. All right.
Why don't we turn
this around? Thank you.
If you could help me. Thank you.
Yeah, that would be great. Thank you.
Thanks a lot. Enjoy.
New York Center wants everything
stopped going to their airports and through...
All right, Tony, issue a ground
stop for New York Center.
Nothing goes into New York Center.
Got it. At least the first
tier on that. Yeah.
In fact... Hey, you know what?
Let's stop Boston, New York,
and then maybe stop Washington, too.
Yeah, whatever's necessary.
Just get them stopped now.
I don't want any more planes
on their frequency taking off.
Boston, we have no confirmation...
Copy type and tail.
Foxy!
I'm hearing about another hijack.
Keep your ears open.
Too much traffic. We can't
get the clearance.
That's not acceptable.
They're not giving it to us.
If you need to, get on the
line and get the clearance for them,
but don't take that from them.
Where are those Otis planes?
Are we over Manhattan yet?
What's going on? MCC.
What's the status on Otis, Foxy?
We're still trying
to get a clearance, sir.
We're getting no clearance from the FAA
to get those birds over Manhattan.
What do you want me to tell weapons?
Screw the FAA. Send those
Otis planes now.
Get them over Manhattan.
He says forget about the FAA.
Get those birds over Manhattan now.
United 93, Cleveland
Center. Good morning.
United 93, Cleveland Center,
119.7. Good day.
You have the aircraft.
I have the aircraft.
Hi. Breakfast, guys.
Here's one with juice.
Thank you.
I'm bringing the other one
with coffee in one second.
Thank you very much. Enjoy,
guys. See you later.
Thanks, Deb. See you in a bit.
What do you need over here?
But you know, with girls I can't, I
could never, you know, I couldn't control...
As soon as I get on the ground,
I'll give her a call.
You have kids? Yeah, I do.
I have a 11 -month-old
daughter.
Eleven months. How's that? You
getting any sleep at night?
She's finally beginning to settle down
now, so everything's looking good.
My anniversary's coming up, I'm
taking my wife to London for a couple days.
Well, that should be good. Yeah, I've
been to London a couple times.
You know, we're gonna do the usual.
A little sightseeing, do a
couple plays and just kind of get away.
I've got Otis in the air,
and two more at Langley.
Four planes. That's all I've got.
I'm gonna need some support.
I'm gonna need more planes.
I've got Otis headed to Manhattan and...
No, the FAA is giving us problems.
All the other fighter planes that
are on the East Coast. Oceana.
No, I sent them anyway.
Right now, Langley's
sitting at battle stations, sir.
Copy that.
Okay. MCC!
Boston is telling us
American 11 is still in the air.
What? American 11 is still in the air.
We don't know who those planes are.
American 11 is still
flying? Headed towards Washington.
God damn it!
All right, surveillance, we got
American 11, heading towards Washington now!
Let's go. I want you to light up
every track south of New York over Jersey.
Colonel. Colonel. Hang on. Hang on, sir.
Yes, go, MCC.
Boston is saying that American 11
is heading towards Washington
now. That it's not one of the flights
that went into the Trade Centers, but
it's heading towards Washington.
We gotta scramble those
Langley birds right now.
What the fuck? Hold on, sir.
Scramble Langley.
Scramble Langley to Washington.
Scramble Langley, weapons. Copy that.
Scramble them to Washington.
Scramble Langley.
No, we just got a report.
We're getting bad stuff from the FAA.
Bad stuff from the FAA all around.
They just told us that 11 was still flying.
We thought 11 went into the tower.
All parties acknowledge
with initials. Command posts.
Tower. Approach. Giant Killer.
Gentlemen, gentlemen!
Here's what I want.
I want you to contact all the centers.
I want to know about any
aircraft that they deem suspicious.
There's NORDO or lost
transponder, off-course, change altitude.
And let's get it on that board down there
and start sharing this information.
Particularly with the military.
Where is that military liaison?
Go get him. Yeah, tell him
I need to speak to him now.
Indy Center just called. They're
missing an American 77.
They lost it 25 minutes ago.
It deviated off... American 77.
American 77. Out of Indianapolis Center.
They said that he lost his transponder
after he turned off-course.
We got an American 77 out of
Dulles, lost the transponder.
All right, I need... I want
last-known position, speed and altitude.
I want it in his track. I
want to know where he's heading.
We just had two go into the city.
And, you know, anything is suspect now, especially
if he's heading toward the city.
I need last-known position and track.
All right, do you know
who that second airplane was?
Okay. If you find out, let me know.
Boston's tracking
another one, Delta 1989.
He's another
Boston-to-LAX, 767.
Right now he's on course.
They are talking to him, but
they're very concerned about that flight
because it's the exact
same profile as these last two.
All right, so listen, fellas. I want you to
get a ground stop out across the nation.
I don't want anybody else
coming into our airspace.
How many have I got airborne
now? 4,000 or 5,000.
Huh? Between 4,000 and 5,000.
4,200. 4,200? Jesus Christ.
All right, no more
departures anywhere. You got that?
Call Boston. Call Cleveland.
No more departures.
Copy. Boston-to-LA and
that's Delta 1989, suspected hijack.
Eagle flight 248,
contact Cleveland Center, 134.6.
John, there's a suspected hijack
from Center at Boston, all right?
I need you to confirm
when you can, all right?
Let me know if you
hear anything. Delta 1989.
I'll let you know. Soon as I can.
United 93, Cleveland Center. Go ahead.
Cleveland Center, United 93.
Level 350. Still have that light chop.
"Beware cockpit intrusion."
"Two aircraft hit
the World Trade Center."
But we just left Newark.
The weather was beautiful.
That's gotta be student pilots.
I'm gonna... Let me just confirm this.
What have you got? Do
we have anything on 11?
You're spotting nothing?
Come on, guys. Beat the bushes. Where
is this guy? What's he doing?
I got two F-16s ready to turn
and burn toward Washington.
I need to know the ROE, sir.
Sir, what do you want me to do
when we intercept American 11?
Do we give them nines in their
nose, sir? I need to know that.
If we engage, when do we engage?
How do we get the authority
to get... Colonel, I need to know
with these Langley birds what I'm
gonna do. Rules of engagement, sir.
Do we shoot this flight down?
How high up do we have to go? SecDef?
Vice President?
The President has to make
the call. Yes, sir.
Sir, I need rules of engagement.
What do I do, sir?
Yes, sir. Hold on.
MCC, I'm on with CONR right now,
requesting clarification
for rules of engagement.
Yeah.
We'll let you know
when Langley's airborne.
Yes, sir. ID type and tail. Yes, sir.
All right, thank you, sir.
We have no shoot-down authority.
No shoot-down authority at this time.
It is ID type and tail.
ID type and tail.
Shoot-down authority comes from
the President and the President only.
How long is it gonna take
to get that authority, sir?
Where the hell is the liaison?
Boston's stopping.
Boston's already stopped their...
Good.
You gotta work the military on this one.
Colonel, listen. We got
a bad situation going on.
I need you to do everything you can
to get these lines of communication open.
We got at least two planes
into that goddamn building.
We got multiple situations
going on. We've given you people...
Listen, I know it's not your job to do
this, but you've gotta do what you can.
We gotta get jets on every one
of those aircraft on that board.
Are you in direct contact with the Pentagon
or are you talking to some liaison?
No, no, no, I'm talking to them.
They understand the gravity of the
situation. I'll give you the best update I can...
No, I need action is what
I need. I understand.
I need action. I understand.
Exactly.
And long, long quarters
with hardly any breaks.
And, yeah, it's...
You take out all your aggression
and all your, you know,
all your shit for the day.
I think golf is pretty
much all I'm up for now.
Yeah? Well, not like you have
time for anything else.
You know, but you can make time, though.
No, you're right.
You're absolutely right. That's
why I had to... I mean...
When I left school, I knew I just
had to continue rugby in some way.
So there were...
There was, like,
this league that started.
It's kind of like a city league.
It's kind of my outlet.
Would you like anything to drink?
No. I'm fine, thank you.
Sure? Yes.
There you are.
Thank you.
Have a nice morning. Thank you.
Excuse me.
Here you go, sir. Thank you, my dear.
You're welcome.
Not having breakfast?
No, thank you. I'm gonna
go to sleep in a minute.
A little early?
You wouldn't have any Scotch
you could put in there, would you?
Lt'd be $4. No, I'm just kidding.
Thank you. You're welcome.
Thank you.
Care for coffee?
Oh, yes.
And, you know, you're
coming up the Jersey Turnpike.
And I'll tell you, New York was like,
it was like Emerald City, you know?
Yeah. Beautiful.
It was beautiful.
The sun coming up behind the buildings.
Time for a drink, even for dinner?
Yeah, sounds great.
We've got three kids at home, so that's
a full-time job right there.
And you wanted the hot breakfast, right?
Everything okay here? Good.
He's got a bomb!
Get back! Get back!
What's going on?
Move! Don't stop! Go! Go!
Open the door. Open the door
and nobody will be hurt.
Jesus Christ. Go! Go!
Sit down and fasten your seat belts!
Do it!
No, no.
You want to get that?
You got the aircraft?
I have the airplane.
Go! Go! Go!
Get out of here, get out of here! Mayday!
Get out of here!
No!
Tom.
He started to scream, and somebody said,
"Get out of here, get out of here."
No!
No! No, please, no!
Jesus Christ.
There's a guy who got stabbed.
He what? They stabbed this guy.
In first class, they stabbed
him. It's the truth.
Who is that? There's a
bomb, there's a man with a bomb.
What? And they have stabbed a passenger.
Oh, my God! Where's Debbie?
The men took her. They
took Debbie. They grabbed her.
Where is Debbie?
They're taking over the
plane. They took Debbie.
What?
United 93, air traffic for you is
1 o'clock, 12 miles eastbound 371.
United 1523, did you hear somebody,
did you hear some other aircraft
on the frequency here?
Fuck!
Anything?
United 93, Cleveland.
Verify your altitude.
United 93, Cleveland. How do you hear?
United 93, Cleveland.
Verify your altitude.
Tom, I'm getting no response out of
a United 93. No response at all.
Ninety-three? Correct.
All right.
Delta 1989, Cleveland
Center, 2249. Good day.
Delta 1989, roger.
Hey, Tom. Delta just
called in. He sounds good.
This guy here? I
don't think it's a hijack.
He took a turn of a 330 heading.
It doesn't matter.
They said he was hijacked.
They placed a phone call.
Keep working him, all right?
I'm just telling you.
I don't know if we have one or two,
but I know he is descending on
his own without a clearance.
Wait a minute. Delta. What about Delta?
Delta's answering. Delta's fine so far. The
only one I don't have is the United 93.
He's not responding, and he is...
He was descending on his own.
He appears to be climbing now.
Cleveland just called.
There's a United 93,
the controller heard screams
coming from the cockpit.
Sounds like the American 11. Jesus.
This is starting to look like a pattern.
Where was that aircraft
last known? Do you know?
Which way is he heading?
We gotta get track information
on these guys.
He was a Newark-to-San
Francisco flight. He's still on course.
All right, get all the adjacent
centers. Notify them.
In every direction.
And keep me advised on flight 93.
Hey, Ben? Ben? Delta's
fine. He's not a hijack.
Cleveland just called.
Delta's not? Good.
Take him off the board. Delta 1989.
Yeah. Yes, sir. Four planes.
That's all I've got.
I can't defend the whole
Eastern Seaboard with four planes.
What do you got?
Washington's on the phone. They said
they've got American 77 lost.
He just went missing, out of Dulles.
He's supposed to go to LAX.
This is another one?
What? What did she say?
American 77 coming out of Dulles
heading west, going to LAX.
Light me up every
track, guys. What do you got?
I don't know how many more there could be
in the air, sir, but the point is this.
We've gotta get them before they're
within range of Washington.
We gotta get them
before they're 60 miles,
50 miles minimum, or
we're not gonna have a play.
We're not gonna be able
to protect the Capitol.
Come on. Come on, guys.
Answer it, please, answer.
Oh, my God, there he
is. He's on the floor.
We need something to bandage him with.
Anybody a doctor? Medic?
She's an EMT.
I keep trying to call the cockpit.
I can't get through.
I need you to move over.
What is going on?
Okay. Okay.
Oh, come on.
United 93, do you hear Cleveland
Center? Ident, please.
Yes, I did, 797, and we
couldn't tell what it was, either.
Okay. United 93, Cleveland.
If you hear the Center, ident.
I got you.
Hi, my name is Sandy Bradshaw.
I'm on United flight 93
from Newark to San Francisco.
The airplane has been hijacked
by three guys with knives.
One of them's got, like, a bomb
strapped around his waist.
How many did you guys see? Three.
She thinks there were three. You were
sitting in first class, right?
They said there were... They saw three.
No, they stabbed a first
class passenger.
Thank you.
Did they answer?
What did they say? They couldn't
tell me anything.
They didn't tell you anything at all?
It was just the maintenance department.
I got through to United. I got
through on the maintenance line.
I told them that the plane was
hijacked. I mean, I don't know what else to say.
I don't know what to do.
He didn't tell us anything!
He's a maintenance guy!
No, no, no! You back!
You back! You back!
Okay. Sit! You!
Ziad!
You heard that also? Yes, sir. Twice.
Roger. We heard that also. Just wanted
to confirm it wasn't from interference.
Victor, 956. Victor, 956, go.
I wanted to answer your call.
We did hear that yelling, too.
Copy that.
I think we're turning.
Wait. We're turning. Are we turning?
That means it's all right. It's okay...
We're gonna go back to the airport.
They're going to ask for ransom. What?
I hope so.
In 1977 in Mogadishu, they
asked, you know, for money.
They will ask for ransom.
They will let us go.
We're going back to the
airport, all right?
We're going back to the airport.
They're trained to deal
with this situation. Okay?
And they'll get us down on
the ground, all right? Okay?
I'm a pilot. I've been flying all
my life. But it's... I just...
What? Something's wrong here.
We're okay.
Anybody know where 77 is?
Cleveland Center was the
last one to talk to United 93.
Cleveland Center is the
last one who spoke to United 93.
But what about the military
response on this?
I'm talking to them now. I'm
letting them know where we are with this.
Listen, you got to get somebody...
Where are they when we need them?
...down the hallway to talk to them.
They are supposed to be
liaisoning with the military.
And I've got this colonel here,
he's not giving me the answers I need.
We're giving you the best we can,
sir. The best information I've got.
We're trying to get this
CAP established over New York.
I don't give a shit about the CAP!
Listen to me. I've got
a board full of planes.
American 77's missing!
United 93 another suspected hijack.
Where are those fighter
jets? Are they...
You've got to get them into position
to do something about these aircraft.
We've got Selfridge on
the command post right now.
They've got two jets that can
fly from Alpena right now.
Get them on frequency. Hand
them off to that. Copy that.
What do you got, Foxy? What do you got?
We got two F-16s out of Selfridge,
Chevy flight, airborne,
coming to our freq now.
They're unarmed, but
that's all we've got. Copy that.
We're gonna need more support
and I've got to know, sir.
When they get there, what can they do?
...for a real world military mission.
I understand it's a commercial
airliner, sir.
There will be casualties. But what...
Think about what happens
if they hit the ground.
Think of what... If they
hit the Capitol, sir.
Go ahead, MCC. Go ahead, go ahead.
We got two F-16s coming out of
Selfridge, but they're unarmed.
But how many more are out
there? That's the question.
We've got a report of at least
one more. May we engage?
I think we shouldn't provoke them.
Just do what they want.
And then they'll land and let
us go and let the authorities...
Shouldn't somebody try to talk to them?
The police, they'll take care of them.
Give them what they want.
Maybe we can negotiate with them.
Quiet.
Just listen to me, sweetie, I want
you to call the authorities...
I'm calling from the Airfone.
You believe me, don't you, Mom?
Did he stab him?
We got to go up there.
Just take us back to the airport...
It's all right. It's just us.
Let us see the passenger.
Just the passenger.
Richard, it's Jeremy.
I'm on the plane. Let me talk to Lyzzie.
Okay... You.
There's the passenger he stabbed.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. We're just checking the passenger.
Did you contact the pilot?
No, nobody said anything. We can't
get through to the cockpit.
We can't get through.
Okay, okay, okay.
Sir, okay. Okay, sir.
We're United flight 93. We've been hijacked.
There's three men with knives.
One of them has a bomb
strapped around his waist.
See if he has a pulse. Is he breathing?
No, there's nothing. There's nothing.
Ahmed.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
You've got to come back
here. What is it?
Come back here, come back here. What?
Oh, my God. Come on. Come on. Come on.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Stewardess, what's happening
up there? What is happening?
This is awful. Listen...
What is happening?
Just... We're going back to the airport.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Call the pilot. Listen...
I don't know.
We're just finding out
what we can find out.
Get back here. Get back here.
Listen, listen, listen.
Listen! The pilots are on the ground.
That was the pilots. They're
on the ground outside the cockpit.
They're on the floor.
She saw the pilot what?
What? What did she say?
The stewardess just said the pilots
aren't flying the plane.
She saw two bodies in front
of the cockpit on the floor.
They said they saw the pilot
and the co-pilot on the floor.
Oh, Jesus.
Flight United 93, call in.
MCC? Cleveland is saying that Delta
1989 is considered a hijack.
They're considering Delta 1989 a hijack.
We got Delta 1989,
suspected hijack, heading west.
Hit me up every track.
Did you copy that, sir?
Two planes? Yes.
This is a second plane, sir, coming in.
We got the one going west out of
Boston, and American 11 coming into Washington.
We still got the Selfridge planes, sir.
Yes, sir. These guys are not armed.
These fighters are not
armed, and we could ram...
If we ram them and eject, sir. Do
we have the authority, though?
Just spoke to Cleveland, they said
that US Air 2619 was headed towards Chicago.
They've just evacuated the Sears Tower.
Jesus Christ!
United 93 is now reported as NORDO.
No transponder, and now
heading eastbound, over Cleveland.
Let me know what the hell is going on.
Six miles southwest of the White House,
Boston Center's tracking
a primary moving fast.
Call Dulles tower.
Give me this again. Give me this again.
Can you get me some
verification on that?
Sir, we have a VFR aircraft
southwest of Washington,
headed straight in now.
Sir, I got another flight
coming up south.
We have a plane headed
toward the Capitol.
I got an unidentified plane...
Yes. I need to know about
the ROE. Can we engage?
I want you to give me a
30-mile circle around Reagan National.
Right now, you hit me up
every track on every aircraft.
Do we have any communication
with the President at all?
Where are the fighters?
How long can that take?
Air Force One's taken off.
They don't know anything about
it. They don't know where he's going.
Ben, they're evacuating the White House!
All right, thanks, Carol.
They're evacuating it right now.
Hey, are we gonna get an
intercept on this, though?
Okay. Good!
Go get yourself out of
your chair and go down...
There's no coordination between
what NORAD has and what we have.
You know where they're headed.
Just get the fighters up there!
How about the Vice President, sir? Do we
have a location on the Vice President?
Well, then the Vice President
can make the call.
The Vice President can make
the call. We can engage.
Holy shit.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir. What's the
ETA on those Langley birds?
Foxy!
Spiders are airborne at 0930,
but they brought them out on an
eastbound heading rather than our northbound.
We're gonna get them turned
as soon as possible.
What the fuck? They're what?
They're heading east?
What the hell is wrong out
there? Why are those planes off-course?
It looks like they came out on a standard
scramble heading instead of the one I gave.
We're trying to get clearance
to turn them now.
How the fuck did they get out there?
I don't know, sir.
What the fuck are they doing
out over the water?
I don't care, God damn it, if they
break windows, you turn them back over land!
Roll quad sevens. Turn them
towards Washington now.
Keep looking for him.
It was a plane that crashed
at the Pentagon.
And the Pentagon is being evacuated.
There is a large fire there,
and that is the smoke you see
in the shot that you are looking at now.
Whether that fire is in
the building itself or outside,
we have not yet confirmed.
There is a fire on the
Mall in Washington.
The cause of the fire in the Mall
in Washington, we cannot yet tell you.
Oh, my gosh!
Foxy! Sir.
I want those Langley
birds over Washington.
...that two planes have
crashed into the World Trade Center.
Surveillance, I want you to
hit up tracks west of Cleveland...
Get back into position.
...heading towards Las Vegas. Hit up.
Light me up every track
you've got. Let's go.
Let's go, let's go! Let's keep
going here! Let's keep working!
ID, what do you got? All right,
he's off-course, he's deviated,
and we don't know why.
Confirmed. Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Confirmed hijackings.
That's the question.
What are we going to do now?
There's a lot of confusion here
at the Pentagon. It appears that
something hit the Pentagon on the
outside of the fifth corridor,
on the Army corridor.
Several Army officers I talked
to reported hearing a big explosion.
Listen, I'm not taking any more chances.
We got stuff flying around
we have no control over.
And I don't want a board full of these
planes hitting every building on the East Coast.
This is a national emergency.
Everyone lands, regardless of destination.
That's gonna cost billions.
Just do it!
We have hundreds of international
flights coming in.
They're already in the air.
No. No, I don't want any more international
flights crossing the borders.
They'll have to go back
where they came from.
Nobody's coming into
the country from now on.
Everyone? Everyone.
Shut off the East Coast. Shut off
all the internationals from Europe.
Shut off South America,
shut off the West Coast,
nothing over the top, either.
We're gonna call Canada on that?
Yeah, Canada, too.
We're gonna shut down the airspace.
No, I can't exempt anybody.
Nobody comes in, and nobody takes off.
Land them all. Take a moment.
Think about this.
We're gonna shut down
the entire country right now?
That's right. Listen, we're
at war with someone,
and until we figure out what to
do about it, we're shutting down.
That's it. We're finished.
...can handle the emergency situation.
I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
Does anybody know about the pilot yet?
They don't know.
No. They don't know.
What?
Two planes hit the World Trade Center.
In New York. The World Trade
Center. Two planes.
My wife says that there was an explosion
at the World Trade Center.
What did he say?
Tell the stewardesses two
planes hit the World Trade Center.
Two planes hit the World Trade
Center. Tell the stewardesses.
What about the five planes?
Someone pass that back.
Just a second. Right.
It doesn't make sense. Are you
sure you heard that right?
Two planes just hit
the World Trade Center.
Two planes have crashed
into the World Trade Center.
What are they doing?
Two planes just hit
the World Trade Center.
Two planes hit the World Trade Center.
What did he say?
I don't know. I didn't hear.
It's on the news.
Yeah, it's on the news, yeah.
Where are you guys hearing this?
Somebody from up there
said it. Ask up there.
Sandy, take her back, take her back.
It's airplanes.
They bombed the World Trade Center?
One after the other
hit the World Trade Center.
Lyzzie, is it... It's
planes. It's not a bomb.
It's two airplanes. It's not a bomb.
It's airplanes. What?
It's one after the other.
One after the other
hit the World Trade Center.
Airplanes, one after the
other, hit the World Trade Center.
Where did this... Who's hearing this?
Where did they come from?
He said it was on the news?
I'm on line with my wife.
Are you hearing this? What'd they say?
Two planes hit the World
Trade Center. Is that right?
Do they mean prop planes?
Whose planes? What airline?
Is it United?
Okay, sweetie, I will call
you back, I promise.
I just talked to my wife. Two
planes have hit the World Trade Center.
There are five jets
that have been hijacked.
Are we one of them, or are we the sixth?
Lyzzie, Lyzzie, Lyzzie.
Lyzzie, not the Trade
Center, right? But the...
Into the Pentagon. It's on the news.
It's on the news, yeah. There was an...
There was an explosion at the Pentagon.
Just tell them that. That's all we know.
Hey, listen, there was an
explosion at the Pentagon.
An explosion at the Pentagon.
Not a fire, an explosion.
United 93, I understand you
have a bomb onboard. Go ahead.
Executive 956, did you understand
that transmission?
Affirmative. He said there
was a bomb onboard.
Executive 956 turning 180.
Executive 956.
American 1060, do you
see anybody northwest of you?
Can you see back that far there?
Do you have a visual on him now?
Got him. We're looking now, sir.
United 93, Cleveland.
United 93, call in.
United 93, United...
Put your seat belts on!
Oh, my God!
We're okay, we're okay. No, we're okay.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Hey, this is a suicide mission.
We have to do something. They
are not gonna land this plane.
They are not gonna
take us back to the airport.
I don't think there's any
other option we have.
If we're gonna die, we're gonna die.
They're flying us into a
building. We're gonna die.
We should not interfere with them.
There's a lot of us,
but we gotta do something.
You see how low we are?
Is there a weapon? Is there
something we can use?
Go back. You go back.
Stewardess, listen to
me. Are you listening?
I'm listening.
Go back and you get
everything you can...
You get every weapon you can.
Get whatever we can use as a weapon.
But what are we gonna do?
We don't... I... We'll figure
that out, but get every weapon we can.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
Okay. Okay.
Go get it. Get everything you can.
Okay, we need every big
guy. Every big guy.
Every big guy. Luggage.
Luggage. We need weapons.
Get back here. Get back here.
Get back here. Okay.
We need to boil water.
For what? We gotta get water?
We gotta get weapons.
Promise me that Emmy
is going to know
that I just love her very much.
What else can we use? What else?
Wine bottles. Forks, knives.
The guy that I was sitting in front of said
that he doesn't think the bomb is real.
That's all I know.
He's on his way back.
Come up with a plan, I'm gonna
calm the other passengers
and we'll go along with whatever
plan you come up with.
You've gotta...
Sit down. Sit down!
Oh, God.
So, what do we do? What do you have?
We got the forks, knives, hot water...
Hot water...
Yeah, I gave him the fire extinguisher.
Just let them go.
Hey! Sit! Sit! Just let them
go. Just let them go.
Hey, come on.
Okay.
They have a bomb!
Do you really think he'd get
a bomb onboard this plane?
Yeah, that guy in front of you said
he didn't think it was real.
I know. That's what I think, too.
How does he get a bomb
onboard this plane?
Jack, are you there?
Wake up, sweetie.
Okay.
I just want to tell you I love you.
We're going back to the airport.
I love you. I gotta
give the phone to Linda now.
Bye, Dad.
I just love you more than
anything. Know that.
I, well...
Please tell my family I love
them, too. Bye, honey.
Please give my love to Mom and Dad.
And I really, really love you.
My safe is in the bedroom in the closet.
The combination is 302 and 0913
and it should open. My will is inside.
I'm trained in hand-to-hand,
I'm trained in judo. So...
Okay. So we go up right behind you.
We have to go very fast.
Okay. Absolutely.
And I'm gonna... I don't give a
fuck if that thing is real or not.
I'm going to get his arm, I'm gonna get
his arm and I'm gonna break his arm.
We need a plan. We need a plan.
We're gonna do something.
Ahmed. Ahmed!
What is he doing? Oh, my God.
Hey, no talk!
So what...
Hey! You!
What is it? What?
Stop! Somebody else?
Okay! Okay! Okay! Oh, my God.
Okay.
Just stay calm. Just stay calm.
You guys are all right?
Sit! Sit!
Hey, sit! Sit!
Oh, my God!
Get your seat belts on!
You're not supposed to be able
to see the ground that low, are you?
No, and not this fast!
Hello? 911?
911.
Yes, hijacking in progress.
I'm in the bathroom. United flight 93.
Yeah, I love you, too, Fred.
Goodbye.
You call your people.
Oh, Christ, it's not real. I understand.
It's not real, so I
can handle it myself.
Go for the detonator first.
How do we get into the cockpit door?
Breakaway panels.
Just take him down.
You go after me...
Absolutely. ...but you go fast. Listen.
I'm listening! But we need to
know who's gonna fucking fly the plane!
Go for his throat! What?
He said he could fly!
He said he can fly! He can fly a plane.
Listen, I think we might have a pilot.
They said there's a pilot onboard!
We got a pilot. What? Who? Who?
Which one? This guy right here.
Down there. Third row.
On the right. Third row, third row.
Okay! Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
You were a pilot? Yeah.
I mean, a single engine,
I mean, you know?
Right. Right, right.
You can fly this plane?
I don't know. I mean, I'll try. Okay.
'Cause we're gonna get you up there.
I understand. That's why
we've gotta do something right now.
You got a plan? Come on!
Now, we're gonna take you up
to the front of the plane.
You can come up behind us. Okay.
If you can get me in there,
I think I might be able to land it,
but I need a lot of help from the ground.
I can talk you down. I can talk
you down. I did eight years ATC.
Okay. You did? Listen.
When you get me in there,
you've gotta get ahold of the controls,
because if he does anything sudden,
we don't have enough room,
to pull out of it. Okay? You gotta
get him off the controls.
What the fuck is he doing? I don't know.
Okay, there's a pilot.
We've got to get the pilot.
We have to do something, right?
I mean, he's all over the place.
I understand.
We are alone up here.
Nobody is going to help us.
We've got to do it. Okay?
Who is the pilot?
I don't know.
Hi, Mom, it's me.
I'm on the plane that's been hijacked.
I'm just calling to tell you
that I love you, and goodbye.
This really kind woman handed me the
phone and she said to call you.
If I don't make it out of this alive, will you
please promise that you'll call my family?
Thank you.
Just tell them I love them.
Tell my wife and my boys
that I love them.
Here, take these. There's more.
Pass these along. Here.
Who is the fucking pilot?
In the brown shirt.
Phil, Phil, it's me. I've been
on a plane that's been hijacked.
Listen, a bunch of
the guys have got together
and they said that we're gonna, like,
try and take over the plane.
But, baby, I promise you, if I get
out of this, I'm quitting tomorrow.
I'll quit tomorrow. I promise,
I'll quit tomorrow.
And tell my babies I love them.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done On Earth
as it is in heaven.
And forgive us our trespasses as we forgive
those who trespass against us.
I don't want to be here.
Baby, I don't want to be here. Baby...
We're gonna break into the cockpit,
and we're gonna fly it.
No, it's gonna be okay.
I love you, too.
You guys, come on, let's go, let's go.
Come on, guys, what are we waiting
for? Let's roll. Come on. Let's go already.
No messing around, boys.
We got no choice, no choice, no choice.
Oh, Jesus, let's go.
Get yourself going. Come on.
Hey!
Go!
Get the bomb! Get the bomb!
Saeed! Ziad!
Get his thumb off the trigger!
Get his hand, get his hand!
Get the bomb!
I got it! I got it!
It's a fake! It's a fake!
The bomb's a fake! It's a fake!
Forward!
Look out!
Son of a bitch! Come here, you!
God damn it!
Go, go, go!
No!
Get the knife! Get
the knife! Grab his hand!
Get it!
Get the pilot!
No! No! Come on!
Get him up! Get him up!
Come on, come on, you can do it.
Bring it up here!
Move it!
Move it! Come on, move it!
Shit.
If we don't get in there, we'll all die!
Ziad!
Move it!
Bring the pilot up!
Get him up! Grab his
hands! Grab his hands!
Pull it up!
I can't pull! I can't!