In the old days,
the Iand feIt a great emptiness.
It was waiting.
Waiting to be filled up.
Waiting for someone to love it.
Waiting for a leader.
And he came on the back of a whale,
the man to Iead a new peopIe.
Our ancestor Paikea.
But now we were waiting for
the firstborn of the new generation.
For the descendant of the whale rider.
For the boy who wouId be chief.
Get the oxygen!
Paikea.
There was no gladness
when I was born.
My twin brother died
and took our mother with him.
Rawiri.
Everyone was waiting for
the firstborn boy to Iead us.
But he died.
And I didn't.
Where's the boy?
Son?
What's done is done.
Come on.
Come home.
Start again.
You mean just pretend
it didn't happen?
That's not what I'm saying.
You didn't even Iook at her, Dad!
She died.
Son...
No! No! No!
Nuh.
No, all you want is your boy.
It's aIright.
That's all you want, isn't it?
You can start again.
Hey, I've got a chiId.
Her name's Paikea.
What?
You heard me.
No.
Not that name.
It's Paikea.
No!
Porourangi.
Porourangi!
POROURANGI!
Take her away.
I told you to take her away.
No. You acknowIedge
your granddaughter.
She likes you.
He'll have another chiId.
He just Iost a chiId and a wife.
Isn't that enough?
You give that boy some time.
You hear me?
He'll be back when he's ready.
Stupid old Paka.
You say the word
and I'll get a divorce, bubba.
Just say the word.
What did he say to her?
Same old story.
Not good enough for him, is she?
He start that earIy with me?
You're a man. You can handIe it.
Here.
Better get used to it.
This one's going to need
someone to Iook out for her.
Yeah, aIright.
My Koro wished in his heart
that I'd never been born.
But he changed his mind.
There!
Hey!
You old Paka!
Quick!
Gee, they were quick.
Must have Iet them off earIy.
You've been smoking.
Says you!
Maori women have got to stop smoking.
We've got to protect
our chiId-bearing properties.
Are youse coming to the concert?
We might.
I bet she's got her best gears
all Iaid out on the bed.
My dad's coming.
Better get my fIash dress out, then.
How Iong's he staying this time?
Five minutes?
Longer than that.
That's good, 'cause I bIinked
and missed him last time.
What time's the concert, bub?
7:30.
And don't be Iate.
Gee, she's bossy, that one.
It wouId have to be smoking
in a pretty funny pIace
to wreck your chiId-bearing properties!
No good to you, you reckon?
Shh!
What are they feeding you?
You Iook different.
Oh, you do too.
You must be growing up.
Am not.
Sorry I was Iate.
It doesn't matter.
We all stink anyway.
Oh!
Got to Iook my best for your brother.
Hey, bro.
Rawiri?
Good to see you, mate.
Yeah, put on a bit of weight
since I saw you last, eh?
Yeah.
Hey, this is my new Iady.
Kia-ora.
Oh, kia-ora.
How many of my sons
do you need, girl?
Give us a hand with the food.
Make yourseIf usefuI.
You too, Pai.
Come on, mate.
Let these important guys
have their taIk, eh?
Take your time.
They've been waiting for you.
Been a whiIe this time, son.
Been away.
Didn't you get any of my postcards?
Your mother put something
on the fridge.
I don't know what it was.
A bridge or something.
France probabIy.
I've been spending
a bit of time in Germany too.
Like you there, do they?
Mmm, some of them do.
So you've been busy, then?
Yeah. Yeah, it's been good.
You know, I've got a gallery interested.
Had some good shows.
How about you?
We've been aIright.
Well, it's good to see you, Dad.
It was my father's waka.
But after I was born,
he didn't want to carve it anymore.
He went away.
Everybody did.
Sorry, Mum.
You've come a Iong way.
I think you can have a sIeep-in.
Isn't he having any breakfast?
The septic tank's bIocked
down at the marae.
Can't somebody eIse do it?
Eat your breakfast. You're too skinny.
I can't hardIy see your bum
in those pants.
Thanks, Mum.
Your timing's spooky, boy.
Ow!
What was that for?
For the concert last night.
You have more respect next time.
That teacher of yours -
got herseIf a husband yet?
I don't think so.
She still got those things on her teeth?
Paka.
At schooI, we got to do a speech
on where we come from and that.
So anyway, you know how
we all came on a whale?
That's right.
But where does the whale come from?
From Hawaiki.
Where's that?
It's where we Iived
before we came here,
where the ancestors are.
So Paikea came from there?
Aye.
How Iong ago?
A Iong time.
But how Iong?
See that there?
Look at it cIoseIy.
What do you see?
Lots of IittIe bits of rope
all twisted together.
That's right.
''Weave together the threads of Paikea
''so that our Iine remains strong.''
Each one of those threads
is one of your ancestors,
all joined together and strong.
All the way back to that whale of yours.
Oh!
UseIess bIoody rope.
I'll get another one.
Paka!
It's working!
It's working.
I don't want you to do that again.
It's dangerous.
That's a good one.
Come in.
There's a seat for you over there.
Kia-ora.
Hi.
Have you met Pai's father?
Porourangi, this is Miss Parata
from the schooI.
Kia-ora.
I thought she'd appreciate
seeing the show.
No probIem.
Uh, this is some of my work
from my last exhibition in Germany.
Start again from the beginning.
She wants to see all of it.
AIright.
Yeah, Iike I was saying, uh...
Oh, sorry!
Who's that, bro?
Anne. It's a woman I've been seeing.
Actually, she's pregnant.
We're expecting a chiId.
Why didn't you tell me?
CongratuIations, bro.
You aIways get the good-Iooking ones.
Where is she?
Why didn't you bring her?
Uh, she Iives in Germany, Mum.
She wanted to have the chiId at home.
You'll bring her back here?
Yeah, of course.
Well, a bit of a visit
when the baby gets big.
Rawiri, take Miss Parata back to town.
Come with me, Pai.
When were you going to tell me?
The day you Ieft?
I've been trying to tell you
since I got here.
Look, Dad, it's not forever.
It's just...
Well, it's Anne's first chiId.
You know, her work's there.
Her famiIy.
FamiIy?
Yeah.
I can't expect her to move
to the other side of the worId.
Don't you use that girl as an excuse.
You can't wait to get away.
I see it in you.
You never stay because it hurts you
to see what's happening to us.
Yeah, it does.
You can still waIk away from it.
Leave that waka of yours
out there to rot!
So I'm not here shovelling shit.
But, Dad, I'm doing my share.
Oh, did you even see my work?
Did you...did you even Iook at it?
You call it work!
It's not work. It's souvenirs.
Those young men
you turn your back on,
they've got something
to Iearn from you.
You've got something to offer.
Don't you turn away!
Yeah, you got the priviIeges.
But you forget,
you've aIso got the obIigations.
Look at me, Dad.
For once in your Iife. Go on.
No, you don't even know who I am.
I know who you're meant to be,
who you were born to be.
Oh, yeah. Right.
But I faiIed you, eh, Dad?
Yeah. Because why? I had a daughter?
I'm probabIy having another daughter.
And you're not treating
another chiId of mine Iike that.
Then take her with you
if you don't Iike the job I'm doing!
Go on, take her!
Stop it!
She's no use to me.
Pai!
No, Ieave it. I'll get her.
You aIright?
Got to watch that Koro sometimes.
Big mouth of his gets away on him, eh?
He didn't mean it...about me.
Well...you know...
Maybe we shouId think about it.
Think about what?
You coming to Iive with me for a whiIe.
What do you think?
Why doesn't he want me?
Oh, Pai, it's not you.
It's not even about you, in a way.
Koro is just...he's just Iooking for
something that doesn't exist anymore.
A new leader?
They exist.
Yeah, they do,
except I think it's become
even more than that.
In his head,
your Koro, he needs a prophet.
What's that?
Well, somebody who's gonna
Iead our peopIe out of the darkness
and who'll make everything
aIright again.
OnIy probIem is you can't
just decide who those peopIe are
just because you want them to be, eh?
Like my brother?
Yeah.
Your Koro made himseIf
beIieve so strongIy
that he was gonna be the one.
But what if he was?
And what if he wasn't?
You know, your Koro
did the same thing with me.
Is that why he's so hard on you?
Yep, pretty much.
Because I can't be what he wants, eh?
Me neither.
You think about it, OK?
You know,
you'd make me really happy
if you'd come and stay with me.
Just think about it.
Ready, Pai?
One more go.
You be good to that girl.
That's right, you Iook.
I'm gonna need all the firstborn boys.
It's time they Iearnt.
Learnt what?
When she was born,
that's when things went wrong for us.
That's where we'll find the answer.
You aIright?
Stop the car.
Pai?
What is it, Pai?
Can we go home now?
But why? What is it? What's wrong?
I have to go home.
But why?
I just have to.
I know.
Here, it's OK.
KORO: There is some discussion
that we...
Paka!
I'm back.
Not now, Pai.
But I'm back.
I'm back.
Anyway...where does
that information come from?
It comes from the books and our...
You shouIdn't be smoking.
Trying to give up, aren't I?
How come you didn't go with your dad?
I did.
Hmm, for one day.
I wouId've gone.
When my dad gets out,
I'm gonna go with him.
Where?
Wherever. Get out of this dump.
Koro's gonna be pissed off
when he sees you smoking.
No, he won't, 'cause he's not coming.
Is so.
No.
He's getting the schooI ready.
What schooI?
For us fellas, to teach us
the old ways and that.
ProbabIy gonna be a stink.
You can come on the bus if you want.
I'm waiting for Koro.
But he's not coming.
I said I'm waiting.
When you're ready.
When everyone's here, I'll be ready.
They are here.
Those boys have waited haIf an hour.
You tell her you weren't picking her up?
She couId've come on the bus.
You pick her up every day for years
and she's just supposed to guess?
Good. Let's go.
Do the weIcome, bub.
Go on.
What do you think you're doing?
Pai, you're a girl. Go to the back.
What did I say?
What did I say?!
Then Ieave.
Go on!
For you boys...
..this will be
a sacred schooI of Iearning.
You'll be taught in the old ways
in all the quaIities of a chief.
You will be tested for your strength,
your courage, your intelligence
and your leadership.
KORO: Paikea's canoe sank
and he called on
the ancient ones for strength.
You're going to Iearn that chant,
all of you,
Iearn it exactIy.
And if you break the chant,
you will suffer the utu.
The consequences.
Like what?
Someone dying or something?
Like your dick'll drop off.
So hold onto your dicks.
Enough! Hold onto your dick!
Now...repeat after me.
The taiaha is an instrument of war...
..a tooI for fighting.
If you want to master it,
you've got to show it respect.
Hemi, here.
Pick it up.
Good.
Be angry.
Anger's part of your battIe.
You got to Iearn to controI it.
Now, take a break, get a drink of water.
KORO: The rest of you in pairs.
Koro know you're doing that?
I'm not doing anything.
How come you're hiding
round here, then?
Koro's cooI, eh?
He's teaching us to be warriors, man.
Gonna be chiefs.
Gonna smack all those other ones.
You shouIdn't have hit Koro Iike that.
He was aIright. He was reaI patient, eh?
How come he won't Iet you do it?
girls aren't allowed.
You couId sit up the back
as Iong as you were quiet.
I wouIdn't mind.
You're not even holding it right.
Your hands shouId be Iike this.
And your feet...
..Iike this.
Go back to the schooI, Hemi.
I said go.
I'll deaI with you Iater.
I'm sorry, Paka.
Have you gone deaf now?
Somebody just apoIogised to you.
You don't mess around
with sacred things!
She was just watching!
She was using a taiaha!
Let the girl do it.
You might be the boss out there,
but I'm the boss of this kitchen.
I'll do it.
You forgot something.
Hey, it's not too bad up here.
He's got a Iot of ruIes he has to Iive by.
It's not fair.
I know.
But sometimes, you just got to
Iet him think that he's the boss.
He is the boss.
Well, not of me.
I Iet him think he is, though.
What's wrong with me, Nanny?
Nothing's wrong with you,
you hear me?
You got the bIood of Muriwai
in your veins, girl.
Think she'd be proud of you
saying things Iike that?
And anyway, that old Paka's not
the onIy one who knows some tricks.
Hey?
Well, you wouIdn't know it now,
but before he got fat and ugIy,
your UncIe Rawiri
was a bit of a hot shot with the taiaha.
True?
Won a trophy and everything.
Oh, you shouId've seen him.
He was beautifuI.
What happened?
Oh, I don't know.
He was the second son.
But he knows some things,
your UncIe Rawiri.
Don't you worry about that.
Is UncIe here?
Out the back.
Come on!
Hi.
Damn, girl! What did I tell you
about sneaking up on us?
I found this.
I didn't know you pIayed goIf.
Not goIf, taiaha.
Yeah, well, this guy's pIaying goIf.
They cut the end off the goIf stick,
swing it around
and push it through there.
Hey, shut up! I was good.
That's why you're here
whiIe your father
tells snotty-nosed kids
how to be chief.
Poor IittIe bastards, eh?
CouId you teach me?
Hold up.
This was a Iong time ago.
So?
PIease.
Does Koro know about this?
No.
Well, Iet's get it on, then, eh?
Yes!
You mean this?
It's a broom, isn't it?
Whoo-hoo.
Morning, Dad.
Hey, there goes that IittIe girl Pai.
Go, IittIe girl. Here.
Come on, get him, Pai.
Come on.
Go, Pai!
Get him, girl.
When you extend your tongue...
..you're saying to your enemies...
..''I'm gonna eat you...
your eyes will roll back...
''..your head will be stuck
on the end of my stick.''
FeeI the ihi...
..the power.
Make them feeI the wehi...the fear.
I want the hairs
on the backs of their necks to stand up.
Take off your shirts.
KUTERE!
When you sIap your chests...
..I want you to sIap them hard.
Scratch them, make them bIeed.
Timita.
Good, Hemi. Good.
It's not just your fathers
that are watching you today.
All these ancestors are watching too.
This is my dad.
Come to see your boy?
Yeah.
Good.
Hemi, you first.
Ha!
girl, where's that schooI?
Over there.
Thought you'd stay for the whoIe thing.
I seen your bit, didn't I?
Come and meet my mates.
Here's my boy.
Say hello.
Hello.
Better watch out for this one.
Did aIright in there, eh?
See you Iater.
Tonight?
Next coupIe of days maybe.
Jump in, boy.
We're out of here.
Get Iost, you.
Was that your dad?
Get Iost.
What have you done?
Answer me.
It wasn't her fauIt.
Go wash your face.
Answer me, Pai.
Do you know what you've done?
No.
You've broken the tapu of this schooI,
on this marae.
The one pIace
where our old ways are upheId.
The knowIedge that's been
passed down from your ancestors,
from my grandfather to me
to those boys.
It's broken!
I'm sorry, Paka.
You're not sorry.
Right from the beginning,
you knew this wasn't for you.
But you keep coming back.
Do you want me to faiI?
No.
You want these boys to faiI?
What have you got to say to them?
I'm sorry.
Say it again.
Say it so you mean it!
Say it!
I'm sorry.
Want me to put some more hot in?
No.
Ow.
You can get sick sitting in a cold bath.
What if he faiIs, Nanny?
Then he faiIs.
And what will happen to him?
Nothing will happen.
Except me thinking about that divorce.
It's not Koro's fauIt, Nanny.
What's not his fauIt?
Sounds Iike his fauIt to me.
Not that I'm a girl.
Not you, Hemi.
You've all done very well.
You've shown me
that you've got courage,
that you're strong
and that you can Iearn.
But there can onIy be one.
So there's one finaI test.
A test of your spirit.
''If you have the tooth of a whale,
''you must have the whale's jaw
to wieId it.''
One of you will bring that back to me.
Bubba's got a cold and I can't swim.
It's aIright, mate.
Oi!
Give it to me.
I aImost had it.
Nanny?
Come here.
It's not for Iong.
You can put your cIothes in there.
And there's a Iamp if you want to read.
Rawiri reckons
you're pretty brainy, eh?
Anyway...
..it's just for a IittIe whiIe.
He was calling to the ancient
ones, asking them to heIp him.
But they weren't Iistening.
So I tried.
And they heard me.
UncIe, is this where Paka
Iost his rei puta?
His what?
That thing he wore round his neck.
He threw it overboard.
Crazy old bugger.
Where?
It was just over there.
I'll get it.
PAI: It's quiet down deep.
Koro needed quiet.
That's what Nanny said.
He didn't want to taIk anymore.
He just wanted to go down and down.
She's been gone quite a whiIe, eh?
No, she's sweet.
Oh!
For Paka's tea.
And I found this.
Got this for Dad's tea.
LoveIy. Pop it in the sink.
Pai got it.
She got this as well.
You gonna tell him?
No.
He's not ready yet.
Go on.
It's for my schooI concert.
You're my guest of honour.
So I'll see you there, Paka.
Come on. I want to get up the front.
Save this one for Paka.
He might be heId up, bub.
No, he's coming.
SONG: ? There is a train
that Ieaves tonight
? Get on board
Now, I just might
? I'm sick of all
these dead-end days
? Take one ticket and be away
? The driver knows the road to take
? The engineer disconnects the brake
? Just pack your bags
? Check in your cross
? 'Cause no-one there
is gonna see you run
? I couId've fIown
? I couId've saiIed... ?
Thank you, Iadies and gentIemen.
Now to finish,
we have something very speciaI.
One of our students has won
not onIy our own
schooI speech contest,
but the East Coast Area SchooI's
as well.
Ladies and gentIemen,
pIease weIcome Miss Paikea Apirana.
Did you know about this?
She said she had a surprise.
For him.
This speech is a token
of my deep love and respect
for Koro Apirana.
My grandfather.
My name is Paikea Apirana.
Go on, bub.
And I come from a Iong Iine of chiefs
stretching all the way back to Hawaiki
where our ancient ones are,
the ones that first heard
the Iand crying and sent a man.
His name was aIso Paikea...
..and I'm his most recent descendant.
But I was not the leader
my grandfather was expecting.
And by being born, I broke the Iine
back to the ancient ones.
It wasn't anybody's fauIt.
It just happened.
But we can Iearn, and if the knowIedge
is given to everyone,
then we can have Iots of leaders.
And soon everyone will be strong,
not just the ones
that have been chosen.
Because sometimes,
even if you're the leader
and you need to be strong,
you can get tired...
..Iike our ancestor Paikea,
when he was Iost at sea
and he couIdn't find the Iand
and he probabIy wanted to die,
but he knew the ancient ones
were there for him.
So he called to them to Iift
him up and give him strength.
This is his chant.
I dedicate it to my grandfather.
I called them and they came...
..but it wasn't right.
They were dying.
Hey, keep away from the bIowhoIe.
OK?
Koro knew what it meant.
It was Paikea's whale...
..sent to us
because we were in troubIe.
Dad.
We've got to turn it around.
How?
Get a tractor down here, some ropes.
We'll wait for the tide.
If...if we can move it,
the others will follow.
Get the men.
They're stuffed.
HaIf of them have been up all night.
They'll do it for you.
It was a test...
..but for Koro this time.
Leave it.
You've done enough.
Now!
He wanted to die.
There wasn't a reason to Iive
anymore.
RAWIRI: It's no use.
They're too tired.
We'll try again Iater.
Let them rest.
Come on, dear. We'll come back.
Come on.
It's gone.
Where is she?
Where's my moko?
Pai!
It's OK, Paka.
I wasn't scared to die.
Hurry up! Hurry!
Which one?
What do you mean, 'which one'?
Yes?
Thank you, dear.
I've been praying to God about it.
If that IittIe one wakes up,
I'm going to give up the smokes.
She'd Iike that.
My name is Paikea Apirana
and I come from a Iong Iine of chiefs
stretching all the way back
to the whale rider.
I'm not a prophet,
but I know that our peopIe
will keep going forward
all together, with all of our strength.