Want to see it again, little girl?
It shouldn't frighten you.
Sorry. Nothing until matinee tomorrow.
- Lady, would you mind taking off your hat?
- Excuse me.
Attagirl, Janey. Show them how.
Thank you, folks. Thank you very much.
One final request, all right?
I've Written a Letter to Daddy.
All right, thank you.
I've written a letter to Daddy
His address is heaven above
I've written, "Dear Daddy, we miss you
"And wish you were with us to love!"
Instead of a stamp I put kisses
The postman says that's best to do
I've written this letter to Daddy
Saying, "I love you"
I've written a letter to Daddy
Thank you very much.
Well, what do we have here?
All for you.
Jane, isn't that a beautiful doll?
Thank you, young man,
that's a gorgeous doll.
Folks, have you ever seen
such a lovely doll?
All right, children, thank you.
Now, folks, please don't forget,
there's a genuine Baby Jane doll...
waiting for each one of you
right out in the foyer.
All you have to do is go out there
and collect her. Kids, remember...
you can tell your moms
that each and every one of...
these genuine, beautiful, great big dolls...
is an exact replica
of your own Baby Jane Hudson.
Thank you.
Baby Jane dolls. Only $3.25.
There they are.
Very beautiful, natural hair.
I won't! I don't wanna go back
to that old hotel!
I don't have to take a nap
and you can't make me!
Don't act up, sweetheart. You've got
to take your nap. You know that.
No, I don't know, and I'm not going to!
You don't want all these nice friends
of yours out here...
to think you're a bad little girl, do you?
I don't care. I want an ice cream.
- Janey, I told you...
- I want it!
I make the money,
so I can have what I want!
Janey, that's enough.
Leave me alone. I need an ice cream!
Well, if you need an ice cream,
I guess you better have some.
I mean, it's pretty hot and all.
But, remember,
this is the last time this week.
All right, Daddy. Blanche wants some, too.
We gotta have some ice cream
for Blanche.
I don't want anything.
What do you think you're trying to do?
I always say it's the parents' fault
in cases like this.
I'm really disappointed.
It sure is a hot day today.
You're the lucky one though, Blanche,
really you are.
Someday it's going to be you
that's getting all the attention.
And when that happens, I...
I want you to try to be kinder
to Jane and your father...
than they are to you now.
Do you know what I mean?
I hope you'll try and remember that.
I won't forget.
You bet I won't forget.
The Seltzer Agency sent you?
- Think there's any chance for me?
- That depends if Mr. Weber likes you.
What type does he like?
A lot of personality.
I'll catch on, watch me.
Boy, oh, boy!
With my money
I should make a picture like that, huh?
Good morning, Mr. Weber. I'm Miss Brent.
Yes. Won't you come
a little closer, please?
She's got a Southern accent
like I got a Southern accent.
I know it's 11:00.
I'll be there when I get there.
- Yes, what is it?
- Mr. Gardner is here to see you.
Gardner?
I'll come out.
I'll be right back, Miss Brent.
Help yourself to cigarettes.
- Make yourself at home.
- Then the job is mine?
Need you ask?
Kill it.
What do you think, Ben?
What's thinking got to do with it, huh?
She stinks, doesn't she?
They say the end's pretty good.
Maybe we should've seen it through.
Please.
You gonna want that picture
again today, Mr. Golden?
I don't think anybody's ever gonna
want that picture again.
When the old man hired
them Hudson sisters...
how come he had to hire
the back end of the act, too?
Boy, what a no-talent broad
that Baby Jane is.
Why can't she stay sober?
Jane's got her pride.
She's a very sensitive girl.
Your very sensitive girl guzzled her way
through six cases of Scotch...
and slugged two studio cops.
Not to mention one or two other
less savory items of publicity...
before we got
that so-called epic in the can.
Anyway, you don't have to talk to Jane.
If Blanche'd only let us out of
that clause in the contract...
which says we have to make
a picture with Jane...
for every picture
that we make with Blanche...
then Baby Jane's contract
won't be any problem.
- You see, that's what we pay lawyers for.
- Possibly.
But somehow,
I can't see Blanche doing that.
You know, I don't get it.
Blanche Hudson's the biggest thing
in movies today.
She can write her own ticket.
She's got script approval.
She's got more money than she knows
what to do with...
You know, she just bought that
tremendous place Valentino used to have.
It's gonna take her a year to fix it up
the way she wants it before they move in.
Well, I guess they can manage
to struggle on where they are now.
My point is she ought to have
sense enough to know that...
she can't make a star
out of Baby Jane again.
Blanche doesn't have
any illusions like that.
But she's a very fine person, Ben.
She's never gonna forget
those early years...
what her sister did for her.
She told me that herself.
Well, I tell you,
she's not doing Baby Jane any favor.
Someday, sooner or later,
that girl's gonna end up in a home.
You're going to their party
at the Grove tonight, aren't you?
Did you ever try refusing
one of Blanche's invitations?
Do me a favor, Marty, will you?
You talk to Blanche.
Try to make her understand.
- I'll do my best.
- Thanks.
Remind me to send you one of those
Baby Jane dolls for Christmas.
I've got mine for this year.
I don't get it, Marty.
What do they make monsters like this for?
For Blanche Hudson.
That's our problem.
You go to bed.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, dear.
Hello, beautiful.
How about a little souvenir?
- Let go of that, will you?
- Come on, don't be like that.
Thanks.
Isn't she great?
Sorry to break in on this fine old
Blanche Hudson movie, folks.
But you'll be glad I did
when you see what I have right here...
for that favorite pooch of yours.
And lliad means quality.
So when your dog says, "woof woof"...
- feed him lliad, the classic dog food.
- Shut up!
Lliad will bring the sheen...
Oh, my goodness, I remember
the first time I saw that picture.
I thought it was just wonderful.
When was that?
Let's see now, as I recall, your father
took me to see it at the old Majestic.
It was before we were married.
She must be about 150 by now.
As a matter of fact, dear,
I think Blanche Hudson...
is just a few years older than I am.
- Really?
- Yes, dear, really.
Well, how come we never see her around?
We've been living next door to them
for six months now...
and the only one I ever see
is that fat sister slouching around.
Don't they ever have company?
I mean, it must be awful.
You know, Julie says
that sister is kind of peculiar.
- Did you ever notice that?
- No, I never have.
Well, that's what Julie told me.
She said that she was supposed
to be responsible for the accident...
that crippled her sister, Blanche.
That all happened
a very long time ago, dear.
Maybe you shouldn't pay much attention
to everything Julie Fowler says.
There's too many people here
with nothing else to do but talk.
Maybe so, but Julie's folks
have lived here a long time.
I guess she should know.
Turn up the volume, dear.
We're missing the picture.
- Will you have a little champagne?
- No, thank you.
You wanna tell poppa your troubles?
Somebody you love?
Jack, please try to understand.
I married you because...
I was knocked silly and it was a refuge.
I found out tonight that
this boy's in trouble, maybe alone.
And it's blinding me.
I can't think of anything else.
He should've held that shot longer.
I told him that when we were rehearsing,
also when we shot it.
But he wouldn't listen.
- How are you?
- Swell.
It's still a pretty good picture.
... and Gemini.
Tommy, you don't have to say anything.
I'll just sit here.
Enjoying yourself?
Jane, what are you doing? I was...
I was watching.
Then you're an idiot.
I won't have you speak to me like that.
Poor thing.
Poor baby.
Quiet down.
Good morning, Miss Hudson.
I hope I'm not intruding.
I just couldn't resist cutting these flowers
for your sister...
after seeing her show yesterday.
You must be very proud
of her new success...
on television, I mean.
I can't tell you how nice it is...
to be seeing
all of her old pictures like this.
I'll tell her you said so.
You know, my daughter and I
would just love to meet her one day.
- Perhaps she could...
- Mrs. Bates, my sister doesn't ever go out.
She's not fit to receive visitors.
I am sorry to hear that.
I'd no idea that...
Well, I hope she likes the flowers.
Thanks.
You miserable...
Jane, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to ring for my breakfast.
I was just wondering who
all those people were at the back door.
Wasn't anything.
Just that nosy Mrs. Bates
going on about your picture last night.
Really? Did she like it?
She liked it.
I remember when it first came out,
it had a tremendous reception.
The critics described it as brilliant.
Do you remember
what year you made that picture?
But of course.
You must, too.
In 1934, right after I did Moonglow.
I made a picture that year, too.
Oh, yes, it was that comedy
directed by Lloyd, wasn't it?
No, it wasn't. It was a love story.
The Longest Night.
Marty McDonald said
it was the best thing I ever did.
They never even released it
in the United States.
Golden was very upset.
He told me the company had
a very bad year and they couldn't afford...
No, they didn't. They had a great year.
They didn't want to show my film.
They were too busy giving a big build-up
to that crap you were turning out.
I'll clean the cage.
That would be Elvira.
Come in, Elvira.
- How are you today?
- Fine.
You've seen Jane.
I don't think she's feeling very well today.
Did you speak to that Dr. Shelby
about Miss Jane like you said?
No, I haven't yet. It's rather difficult.
I don't want to upset her again
if I can help it.
But she'll be upset anyway, Miss Blanche.
And the longer you leave it,
the worse it's gonna be.
I know.
But I was just hoping
it wouldn't be necessary.
I think she seems much better lately.
It's none of my business...
but she's been drinking again.
You know that, don't you?
No, I hadn't noticed.
I don't think it does her any real harm.
I think I understand her.
You do, huh?
Then you ought to take a look at this.
- What are these?
- I guess it's what you'd call fan mail.
How kind people are.
You better look at them...
and then you can tell me
whether or not you've seen them before.
- Did you read them?
- No.
- But they've been opened.
- That's right, they all have.
And there's one in here
marked "personal."
"The other night, my husband and I
watched that lovely old movie of yours:
"Last Honeymoon.
"I remember saying to my husband
at the time...
"that seeing you again
was just like meeting an old friend."
That's charming. That's really charming.
The point is you never saw them before,
did you?
- No.
- I thought not.
I'm sorry, I thought you ought to know.
But I don't understand.
Where'd they come from?
Where'd you find them?
In the trash barrel, that's where.
They're from that television station that's
been running your old movies, aren't they?
- You mean Jane...
- Who else?
She must have thought
they were advertisements.
Then why would she open
the one marked "personal"?
And what about this?
You might as well see this, too.
Writing those dirty words.
I can't even remember the last time
I saw words like that written down.
But why would she do a thing like this?
You know what makes her
do things like this.
She's sick,
and she's not getting any better.
In fact, the last month
she's been getting a lot worse.
If you don't believe me...
then why are you selling this house
and planning to move out?
You said this last month...
she's been a lot worse.
- Do you think she knows?
- About selling the house?
How could she?
You don't have anything in writing.
We're sisters, Elvira.
We know each other very well.
I think she's jealous...
because of those old movies of yours
they're showing on television this week.
Anyway, in six weeks
you'll have to hand over the house...
and then she'll have to know.
How do I tell her? How?
If you'd just speak to that Dr. Shelby,
maybe he could tell her.
No, it ought to be me.
I can't let a stranger tell her.
But he's a doctor, Miss Blanche.
And she's a sick woman.
Elvira, you didn't know her
when she was a child.
- When she was young.
- I've seen those pictures she keeps.
It wasn't that she was just pretty.
She was different. She was so alive.
I was cleaning the cage.
The bird got out.
But where is it now?
It flew out the window.
Did you let that bird out
on purpose, Miss Jane?
I just told you, I was cleaning the cage
and the bird flew out the window.
I'm sorry.
She did that on purpose.
Believe me, she did it on purpose.
Never mind.
Maybe he'll come back.
You won't change your mind, will you?
About coming to live with me?
You know I don't go back on my word,
Miss Blanche.
But you've got to make up your mind
about finding somewhere for Miss Jane...
where they can look after her properly.
I have.
I have made up my mind.
I'm going to call Dr. Shelby today.
I know, Miss Blanche.
It's just that I have to be sure
I'm doing the right thing for her.
Hello, is this Johnson's?
I want to order some liquor.
It's Jane Hudson.
What do you mean
you can't fill any more orders for me?
My sister did?
Wait a minute, I'll put her on.
Blanche, would you speak
to this man from Johnson's?
Hello. Who is this, please?
Oh, yes, Mr. Carlston.
Yes, this is Blanche Hudson.
What seems to be the trouble?
I'm afraid there's been
some misunderstanding.
I certainly didn't mean to suggest
that you shouldn't fill any orders for her.
After all, we do pay our bills, don't we?
Yes, fine.
Would you, please?
I'll put her on.
Okay, then?
Good. I'd like to order
six bottles of Scotch...
and three bottles of gin.
The same brands. And as soon as possible.
I just told Miss Blanche. I'm going
downtown to see a man about jury duty.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Hello?
I've written a letter to Daddy
His address is heaven above
I've written, "Dear Daddy, we miss you
"And wish you were with us to love!"
Instead of a stamp I put kisses
The postman said
The postman says
that's best to do
I've written a letter to Daddy
Saying, "I love you"
Now when I'm very good
And do as I am told
I'm Mama 's little angel
And Papa says I'm good as gold
But when I'm very bad
And answer back and sass
Then I'm Mama 's little devil
And Papa says I've got the brass
Now I wish that you would tell me
'Cause I'm much too young to know
All right, Blanche Hudson!
Miss Big Fat Movie Star.
Miss Rotten Stinking Actress.
Press a button, ring a bell...
and you think the whole damn world
comes running, don't you?
Lunch, Miss Hudson?
Why, certainly, Miss Hudson.
I'm sure we can find something
appropriate for you, Miss Hudson!
You brought my lunch. A bit early, isn't it?
Then what were you ringing for?
I wanted to tell you
something's wrong with the telephone.
Maybe it's been
left off the hook downstairs.
Is that so?
Who did you wanna call, Blanche?
Actually, I wanted to call Bert Hanley.
- Our business manager?
- Yes.
There's something
I've been meaning to discuss with you.
Well?
I'm afraid I have bad news about money.
You see, the point is Bert thinks
we'll probably have to sell the house.
Why should we have to
sell the house, Blanche?
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
Our financial position
is such that we just...
We can't afford to...
We've got plenty of money invested.
I know.
Yes, that's quite true...
but some of those investments
aren't paying much.
When did our business manager
tell you all this?
Early last week, I think.
He didn't call here last week.
I know that, too.
No, we didn't actually speak
on the telephone.
He wrote me a letter.
He didn't write you any letter.
There hasn't been a letter from his office...
- Yes, Jane, there has.
- You're a liar. You always were.
Bert Hanley didn't write you any letter
or call you on the phone...
telling you to sell the house.
You called him four weeks ago
and told him to sell it.
I did nothing of the sort.
Don't you think I know everything
that goes on in this house?
You've been spying on me.
What do you think?
You are disgusting.
After all I've done for you, you spy on me,
when all I'm trying to do is help.
Who are you trying to help, Blanche?
What are you planning to do with me
when you've sold the house?
What'd you have in mind?
Some nice little place...
where they could look after me?
Better not tire yourself out
using the phone anymore.
If there are any calls,
I'll take them downstairs.
Eat your lunch, it'll get cold.
Jane, please wait.
Jane, I want to talk to you. Please.
Jane, I want to talk to...
Telephone, Mother.
All right, dear.
- I called this morning and placed an ad.
- Did we give you a reference number?
Here it is. You want to check the copy?
That's fine.
You want this to go in
the Personal column or the want ads?
I always think the Personal column's nicer,
don't you?
That's an eight-line ad. That'll be $6.30.
And who's placing this ad?
- We have to know.
- Why, I am.
Yeah, I know, but who for?
When you're placing an ad
for someone to do a job for you...
we have to have your name for the record.
My name is Jane Hudson.
Maybe you remember me.
I'm Baby Jane Hudson.
Sure.
Thank you.
This will be in the paper tomorrow.
Who the hell was Baby Jane Hudson?
"Please call Dr. Shelby at OL-61656...
"and ask him to come here
to the house immediately."
Under no circumstances...
let my sister see...
the contents...
of this note.
Blanche Hudson.
Miss Hudson, how nice to see you.
- I was just going to call on you.
- Why?
I wanted to ask you about
the flowers I brought over for your sister.
They don't last very long
this time of year...
and I thought perhaps
you'd like some more.
- You could've saved yourself the trouble.
- But it's no trouble at all.
I've just been cutting some,
that's why I came over.
- I always think it's nice to have flowers...
- Mrs. Bates...
I guess if my sister needed flowers,
we could afford to buy them.
What's the matter, Mother?
You look like you've been in a fight.
I'm not sure that I haven't been.
That Jane Hudson makes me so mad,
I could kill her!
That's a good idea.
What'll we use?
Did you have a nice drive?
What are you talking about?
Nothing, dear. It's so long
since you were out of the house...
I thought perhaps you'd gone
for a drive or something.
You know, I was thinking...
it's ever so long since we had a talk.
You know, a real talk
about the future and everything.
I didn't want you to be worried
about the house.
Even if I do have to sell it,
we'll still be together.
Blanche, you're not going to
sell this house.
Daddy bought this house.
And he bought it for me.
You don't think I remember that, do you?
You're wrong, Jane. You've just forgotten.
I bought this house for the two of us
when I signed my first contract.
You don't think I remember anything,
do you?
There're a whole lot of things I remember.
And you never paid for this house.
Baby Jane Hudson made the money
that paid for this house, that's who.
You don't know what you're saying.
You aren't ever gonna sell this house.
And you aren't ever gonna leave it, either.
Do you remember when I first came back
after the accident?
You promised you wouldn't ever talk
about that again.
I know I did...
but I'm still in this chair.
After all those years, I'm still in this chair.
Doesn't that give you
some kind of responsibility?
Jane, I'm just trying to explain to you
how things really are.
You wouldn't be able to do
these awful things to me...
if I weren't still in this chair.
But you are, Blanche. You are in that chair.
And tell me, what are these awful things
I'm supposed to be doing to you?
Well, I meant...
you wouldn't have to work so hard.
And I was thinking...
maybe Elvira could come in more often.
Maybe she could even live with us.
We don't need Elvira.
But you get so tired...
There's so much to do,
and you're not well.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I should get a checkup
or something.
That would be wonderful.
Perhaps we can find a really good doctor.
We could get hold of
that nice Dr. Shelby, couldn't we?
Let's see...
what's his number again?
"And under no circumstances...
"tell my sister the contents of this note."
It's not me that needs a doctor, Blanche.
Hello, lovey.
Now, don't stop for me.
What did the doctor say?
He says it's no use my trying to go back
to work for another six months.
Didn't he even give you
anything new to take?
He says it's arthritis.
And the only thing for me to do is
not to try and work until it clears up.
Did he suggest what we're going to use
for money in the meantime?
No, dear. But he's ever such a nice man.
Now, lovey, never you mind, anyway.
You know, we've still got a bit of savings.
You're my little worrier.
That's nice.
You've found something, have you?
You don't have to get so excited.
You haven't even seen what it is yet.
No, dear, but it's a possibility, isn't it?
I mean, there aren't that many jobs
that'd be suitable...
for someone with your qualifications.
What qualifications?
Well, you know, serious music and all that.
This sounds like just the ticket, doesn't it?
- You're gonna call?
- Call who?
These people.
- Might as well.
- Now?
Well, it wouldn't be a lot of bloody use
calling next week, would it?
No, dear.
Mom, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you call for me?
Tell them you're my secretary
or something.
All right, dear, I'll do that.
Listen, I won't let on who I am.
You see, I'll just tell them,
"I'm Mr. Flagg's seck-er-tary."
Secretary.
Do you know, I do believe your old mom...
would be a jolly good secretary at that.
Don't you think?
Hello?
This is Jane Hudson.
About the ad.
Who is this?
This is Mr. Flagg's secretary.
His secretary.
Mr. Flagg is very interested...
and he'd like to know
if he could have an appointment.
I think you'll find he's very well-qualified.
Sure, I'd be glad to give Mr. Flagg
an appointment.
Well, now, let me see...
how about 4:00 this afternoon?
I think that would be fine.
Well, I'll be expecting him then.
Thanks.
It's all fixed, lovey.
Your old mom's managed everything...
hasn't she?
Oh, shut up!
Stop it!
- What do you want this time?
- Who was on the telephone?
None of your business.
What were you ringing for?
I'm hungry, Jane.
Of course you're hungry.
You didn't eat your dinner.
But you forgot my breakfast.
I didn't forget your breakfast.
I didn't bring your breakfast...
because you didn't eat your din-din.
We're right back where we started.
When I was on the stage,
you had to depend on me for everything.
Even the food you ate came from me.
Now you have to depend on me
for your food again.
So, you see,
we're right back where we started.
Why are you doing this to me? Why?
Doing what?
Making me afraid to eat,
trying to make me starve myself.
Don't be silly.
If you starve, you die.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You really must be sick.
Did you ever stop to think that...
if anything happened to me,
I mean, anything bad...
there wouldn't be any money for you?
I wouldn't be here to sign the checks.
You wouldn't even have pocket money.
Did you ever think of that?
Yeah, I've thought about that.
Why didn't you eat your dinner?
Because I'm afraid. You made me afraid.
I thought you were supposed to be
the big girl in this family.
Nothing wrong with it.
You're just a neurotic, Blanche.
You know that? You're just a neurotic.
- Good morning, Elvira.
- Good morning.
- Please, Jane, I'm so hungry.
- I have to go now.
But just a little, please.
No. You didn't eat your din-din,
so you'll have to wait till lunchtime.
Jane, please, don't do this to me.
Jane, please!
- Good morning, Elvira.
- Good morning, Miss Jane.
I wanna talk to you.
- I want to apologize.
- Apologize?
I wasn't feeling so well yesterday,
so I was unkind to you.
I want to make it up.
I got up this morning and fixed the house.
So you can have the whole day off.
Here's your $15.
Thanks, but does Miss...
What I mean is does Miss Blanche know
about my taking the day off?
Sure, she knows.
All right, if you say so.
See you next Tuesday then.
Have a good time.
Goodbye.
Bye.
- Who was that at the door earlier?
- Elvira.
Where is she now? In the kitchen?
No. I gave her the day off.
She has a pretty hard time, considering.
I told her to come back next week.
You know we got rats in the cellar?
Good afternoon.
Mr. Flagg?
Yes, I'm Edwin Flagg.
I have an appointment
with a Miss Hudson for 4:00.
I'm Jane Hudson.
My, you're right on time, aren't you?
Yes, I believe I am.
Come in.
We can talk here in the living room.
I say, what a perfectly charming room.
- So you're Edwin Flagg?
- Yes, that's right.
I'll bring you some tea. You like tea?
Oh, yes. I'm quite fond of tea.
You must've guessed that I'm English.
Oh, really? How nice for you.
Here, let me help you.
That's a terribly big burden
for such a little girl.
Thank you. You're very kind.
It's so hot today.
Did you drive here in your car?
Well, actually I took a cab.
It's a bit of a nuisance,
but I had to put my car in for servicing.
- Cream or lemon?
- Cream.
Sugar?
My, it looks good.
I always think it's nice to break bread...
- with strangers, don't you?
- Oh, yes, indeed.
I don't think you actually mentioned
the exact nature of...
I've been retired for some time now.
I've been taking care of someone
in my family who's sick.
And now you're free to return
to your profession?
Yes.
And what exactly...
I mean, I take it you are a soloist.
Some instrument?
I wonder if you can guess who I am.
Can you give me a hint?
Well, it's not really fair to make you guess.
I'm Baby Jane Hudson.
Do you mean
you're really the Baby Jane Hudson?
Yes, I am.
And I'm going to revive my act
exactly as I used to do it.
Of course, some arrangements
will have to be brought up to date.
Music changes so much, doesn't it?
And they're desperate for new acts.
Television, Las Vegas,
and all the clubs and...
There are a lot of people
who remember me, lots of them.
I don't see how you could fail.
You know, I had a kind of a feeling...
the minute I opened that door
and saw you standing there.
I just knew we were going to be friends.
I've been thinking about costumes.
Costumes?
Yes. I took some of my old ones
down to be copied.
- You think that's a good idea?
- Of course.
But I don't quite remember...
How silly of me, Edwin. How could you?
But I do want your opinion. I really do.
All my scrapbooks and stuff
are in the rehearsal room.
You can look at them
and tell me what you think.
- You'd like to see them, wouldn't you?
- Well, of course.
I wish Daddy could be here right now.
"You can never lose your talent,"
he used to tell me.
"You can lose everything else
but you can't lose your talent."
I think you'll find these clippings
very interesting.
Daddy saved them for me
from the very first.
He used to put them in special books.
I always liked that picture.
It's so sad.
- Will you excuse me?
- Certainly.
You always spoil everything, don't you?
- No, Jane. I just wanted to know...
- Who is down there? I'll tell you.
I got a friend down there.
Someone who's come to see me.
He doesn't even know you exist.
And you don't like that, do you?
You're wrong.
I've always wanted you to have friends.
- That's what I've always wanted.
- Then how come I never had any?
Well, maybe you weren't...
I mean, maybe you were
just too independent.
No, that's not why.
You always stopped me
from having friends, that's why!
Not anymore, Jane.
I'm pleased that you have a friend.
That's what you need.
- Sure!
- I was just hoping maybe...
I could meet him and we could have
a nice talk, just the three of us.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
Then you could tell him
a whole lot of lies about me.
Scare him off...
or maybe have him for yourself.
I've written a letter to Daddy
His address is heaven above
That's wonderful!
I've written a letter to Daddy
His address is heaven above
I've written, "Dear Daddy, we miss you
"And wish you were with us to love!"
Instead of a stamp I put kisses
The postman says that's best to do
I've written a letter to Daddy
Saying, "I love you"
Edwin, you certainly can play, can't you?
- And you certainly can sing.
- Oh, thank you.
I can see you've done
this kind of work before.
No, not really.
Actually, I've spent most of my time
on serious music.
Composing, and that sort of thing.
So this will be your first contact
with show business?
Not exactly.
You see, my father was quite well-known
as an actor.
In the movies? Maybe I worked with him.
I shouldn't think so.
He's been dead quite a long time now.
I lost my daddy
when I was quite young, too.
Of course, he was more
in the classical tradition as an actor.
Shakespeare and that sort of thing.
People used to say Daddy
could've been a star in his own right.
- He was a musician, too.
- What instrument?
Piano and banjo.
That's very interesting.
The banjo's a very native
American instrument.
Of course, my father was British...
but he never really got a chance
out here in Hollywood.
That's too bad.
It's funny, really.
Because actually he came from
a rather distinguished family, socially...
and yet nearly all the parts he had
were playing menials, butlers and such.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
I don't think my mother
ever really appreciated...
what he was trying to do.
I know what you mean.
It's very hard for an artist
when people don't understand.
- I remember when...
- I sometimes try to explain to her...
that if you're going to produce
anything decent...
in the way of serious music...
you must have the right atmosphere.
But, of course,
Dehlia can't understand that.
Dehlia? Who's Dehlia?
You might not think it to look at her,
but she is my mother.
For a minute, I thought you had...
a wife or a lady friend
tucked away somewhere.
Oh, no. Nothing like that.
How much were you actually
thinking of paying?
Paying?
What do you think?
How about $100?
A week, of course.
- I think that would be fair.
- Then that's settled.
I don't like talking about money, do you?
No. It's not that important, is it?
Not like relationships between people.
But the thing is, if I'm going to move out
and give up my pupils...
I'll have to know for sure.
When were you thinking of starting?
Just when could you let me
have some money?
Well, I've got some family matters
to take care of.
That should take about a week or so.
Then I couldn't see why
we couldn't start rehearsing right away.
Tell you what, Edwin...
I'll pay you first thing Wednesday,
a month in advance.
It's done.
How about going to dinner
somewhere nice?
That sounds fine.
Why don't you come with me now?
I've got to pick up my costumes...
and then we could go on to dinner
from there.
I promised Dehlia I'd be home for supper.
Well, I'll drive you home then.
I'm so excited!
You know, I know everything
is going to go just marvelously.
I have to go up and change.
I won't be a minute.
This is really
a rather charming neighborhood.
Yes, I've always found it very pleasant.
I just can't wait to get started rehearsing.
We're going to be a great team,
the two of us.
I'm sure we are.
I'll see you Wednesday. Bye.
This is Blanche, Blanche Hudson.
I need your help. Is the doctor there?
I must talk to him.
He's with a patient right now.
But I have to talk to him. I've got to.
Hold on, please.
I'll see if I can interrupt him.
- Dr. Shelby?
- Yes, Blanche.
Miss Hill tells me you're a little upset.
What's the trouble?
You must come. I need you here.
No. It's about my sister.
I need your help. I need you here.
Here at the house.
No. It's nothing like that.
It's the way she's behaving.
You've got to come over right away.
Please, before she comes back.
I don't quite understand.
Is this some kind of emotional
disturbance you're talking about?
Yes, she's emotionally disturbed.
She's unbalanced.
I don't know, Doctor.
Are you trying to tell me
that she's violent?
Yes, she is.
I'm not sure.
Very well.
We aren't getting anywhere like this.
I'll come over right away.
That was...
I know who it was.
No, Jane, it really was.
And I know what you're trying to do.
I'm not trying to do anything.
Honestly, Jane.
This is Blanche Hudson again.
Could I speak to the doctor?
Yes, certainly. Hold on, please.
I'll try and catch him.
Hello, Blanche. I'm on my way now.
I'm so glad I caught you in time.
Dr. Shelby, we're not going to
need you after all.
I know, but Jane has gone
to another doctor.
- Another doctor?
- Yes. Another doctor.
Well, if she's chosen to go
to someone else...
After all,
we really can't interfere, can we...
if Jane's chosen to go to another doctor?
I'm very sorry.
Goodbye, Doctor.
I thought I told you
not to come back until next week.
Yes, but I had a free day,
so I thought I'd come by and see...
- if there was anything needed doing.
- There isn't.
So you could've saved yourself
the trouble.
I was gonna write you a note,
but now I may as well tell you.
We're not gonna be needing you anymore.
- But I don't understand.
- We're closing up the house.
Blanche wants to take a smaller place
at the beach.
The doctor thinks that's best for her
so that's what we'll do.
Don't worry, you'll be paid for today.
I'll send you a check.
I'm not worried about any pay.
I'd like to see Miss Blanche before I go.
Well, you can't. She's asleep.
That's all right. I don't mind waiting.
I do, I've got to leave,
so just give me the keys to the house.
I'm sorry, I don't have the keys.
I must've left them at home.
Anyway, go. You're fired.
Miss Blanche?
Miss Blanche, are you awake?
Are you all right in there?
Wait now, and I'll go find the key.
Thank you.
- Good morning, Miss Hudson.
- Good morning.
How's Miss Blanche these days?
She's just fine.
Your deposit slip?
Well, Blanche wanted me
to get it all in cash this time.
- I guess she has some special reason.
- Yes, but doesn't she normally...
I mean, if she isn't going to deposit
her monthly check...
she usually gives us a call
and tells us what she wants us to do.
- Didn't she call?
- I don't think so.
I guess she must still be asleep.
She gave me that check last night.
I see. Just a moment, please.
I guess that'll be all right, Miss Hudson.
- Fifties and twenties all right?
- Yes, please.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Bye now.
Miss Blanche, I'll tell you right now,
if that sister of yours...
has gone and given you sleeping pills
just to keep you quiet...
while she's out doing I don't know what...
I'm sure as hell
gonna call the police on her.
It's all right, Miss Blanche.
I'm glad I caught you.
I hope you don't mind, there's something
I've been meaning to ask you.
I'm kind of short of help around the house.
I was wondering if you'd mind
my asking your cleaning lady...
to give me a couple of days a week.
As far as I'm concerned,
you can have her as often as you want.
My sister and I are moving,
so we won't want her anymore.
But you'll have to call her because
she isn't here. I've already sent her home.
But I just saw her.
Yes, but I sent her home.
No, but that's impossible.
I saw her go in the house
a few minutes ago.
- In the house?
- Yes.
So you finally decided to come back, huh?
What're you doing here?
- I told you, you were fired.
- Never mind all that.
I want to know
what's going on around here.
- But you said you didn't have your key.
- It just so happens that I did.
So now you can tell me what you mean
by locking Miss Blanche in her room.
This is my house and I can do what I like.
It doesn't matter whose house it is.
You've got to act like a grown woman,
like everybody else.
Suppose there was a fire and
Miss Blanche was locked in her room?
Well, there wasn't.
You open that door
and stop all this nonsense!
- Then give me the key.
- No.
She's asleep. I gave her a pill.
You did?
Then you better give me that key
and be quick about it.
I won't, and you can't make me.
I'm not afraid of you.
All right, Miss Hudson.
I'm not going to fool with you.
If you won't give me that key,
I'll go right down and call the police.
You'll be sorry.
Give me that key.
I didn't mean her any harm.
You better not have done her any harm.
My God, Miss Blanche.
What has she done to you?
I'll get it off in a minute.
Don't worry, Miss Blanche.
I'll get you down from here.
You just rest easy.
Going out, are you, dear?
- You know I am.
- Having dinner with her?
I'm forgotten.
You won't be back too late,
will you, lovey?
Who knows?
You could've been better than all of them.
But they didn't want that.
They just didn't love you enough.
You know that?
Miss Hudson?
I'm sorry, Edwin.
I can't let you in.
Not now.
To hell with it!
I can't let you in.
Not now.
What am I going to do?
Miss Hudson, I thought...
I didn't know there was anyone in here.
I just came home and saw a light...
and I thought perhaps
you'd left the lights of your car on.
- I've had that happen to me.
- That's all right, Mrs. Bates.
I had that happen to me once, it's no joke.
You wake up in the morning
and find you've got a dead battery.
No joke.
Well, as long as everything's all right...
- I guess I'll just say good night.
- Good night.
That doesn't prove anything.
- Now what do you think you'll do?
- I'll manage, lovey.
I suppose you think I'm making all this up.
- I wouldn't know.
- Hazel should know, shouldn't she?
She worked in the same studio
and that's when it all happened.
Just after one of those studio parties...
and right in front of her own house.
Jane Hudson drove a car straight
at her own sister and crippled her for life.
Come on, you mean she tried to kill her?
Yes, she did.
She tried to murder her own sister.
How is it they didn't arrest her then?
They would've,
but the studio had it all hushed up...
on account of Blanche Hudson's career.
That sounds very likely.
Yes, doesn't it? So the fine woman
you've chosen to run around with...
turns out to be broke
and a murderer, as well.
- I see!
- Well, it's true!
All right then,
I'll ask her about it when I see her again.
You wouldn't see a woman like that again?
Why not? You just told me
she's got a rich sister.
But you haven't heard the worst of it yet.
- You mean there's more?
- Yes, there is.
After she'd run down her own sister,
your precious Jane Hudson...
ran off and left her there to die,
like some poor animal.
She ran off and disappeared
for three whole days.
What happened then?
Don't tell me they couldn't find her.
They found her, all right.
They found her in some hotel room...
with a man that
she'd never even seen before.
Why should that upset you?
Isn't that how I was conceived?
Yes, this is Miss Hudson.
She left.
About a week ago.
We have a report here filed by her cousin,
listing her as a missing person.
Did she tell you what her plans were,
anything like that?
No, I don't know a thing.
We have some other addresses to check.
Maybe we'll come up with something.
Otherwise we'll probably be
getting in touch with you again.
Meanwhile, if you do hear from her,
we would appreciate you letting us know.
The police are looking for Elvira.
It wasn't my fault. She wouldn't go away.
You heard her,
she wouldn't leave me alone.
I don't know what to do, Blanche.
What am I going to do?
If they find her, we'll have to run away.
That's what we'll do. We'll just go away.
But then I wouldn't see Edwin anymore.
He wouldn't like what I did.
It wasn't my fault,
but he wouldn't like what I did.
I don't care. We'll just go to the beach.
We'll go and live at the seashore
all the time, like we used to...
when I was little and Daddy was there.
And maybe we'll have friends.
People would come and see us.
I'd like that.
Blanche, listen to me.
You know I always wanted
everything to be nice, don't you?
I don't see how Elvira
could make me do a thing like that.
I just don't understand.
It was like that time in the hotel room...
when they came and told me
that you were hurt and that I'd done it.
And there was a big man there,
a policeman.
And he hit me and he slapped me and...
I tried to tell him that
I couldn't do a thing like that.
Not to my own sister.
He said I was a liar.
The accident, it...
No, it wasn't an accident.
I did it. You told me so yourself.
I must tell you.
I don't want to talk about it!
Every time I think about something nice,
you remind me of the bad things.
I only want to talk about the nice things.
Remember when Daddy and I
used to rehearse at the beach?
I'd be dancing on the sand...
and all the people
would come and watch...
all crowd around
to see Baby Jane Hudson.
What'll I do?
- Let them in.
- But what if...
It may be Edwin.
Of course. It's Edwin.
You want to make him tell on me.
No, Jane.
Please.
Wait for me.
Yes.
I'm sorry, but we just picked up
this young man in front of your house.
Says he's on his way in to see you.
Is that right?
- I don't understand.
- They're trying to say I'm drunk.
We'll just say that
you're a little happy, okay?
Who's happy?
I'm not happy.
So now you know.
That's right. So now we know.
Sorry to have bothered you, Miss Hudson.
Good night.
I have the money. Really, I have.
But don't be mean to me.
- You promised me.
- I know I did, and I have the money.
Look, let's go in the kitchen
and have a drink together.
It's nice there.
And then we can be friends again...
and everything.
- I've got something else for you, too.
- What?
It's a surprise. Would you like to have...
You're gonna like your present.
You're really gonna like it.
Drink your drink, Edwin.
I'll go get it for you.
This is my very own.
It's a genuine Baby Jane Doll.
I used to give them
to all my really good friends...
the people that I worked with.
- They made them for me.
- Marvelous.
- Specially.
- Very lifelike.
Now, Jane, you talk to nice Mr. Flagg...
and nice Mr. Flagg will have his money
in a minute.
You're not comfy like that, are you?
Let's go bye-bye.
Here comes the Super Chief.
Stop it!
What was that?
Nothing. I didn't do anything.
She'll take you away from me.
Please...
help me.
She's dying.
For God's sake.
Get away from me!
Edwin, I've got your money.
Edwin, you forgot your money!
He hates me.
Stop.
He's going to tell.
You've got to help me.
We've got to leave.
Please, Blanche.
Help me.
I like this place.
We can just sit here for a while.
And pretty soon the sun will come up
and it will be nice.
You should look at the sea.
It has all lights on it.
You used to like that.
We interrupt this program
to bring you a special news bulletin.
At 11... 25 this morning,
all local law-enforcement agencies...
had assigned Special Details...
to the kidnap-slaying mystery
that surrounds the famed Hudson sisters.
It is believed that Blanche Hudson,
film great of the early '30s...
has been forcibly abducted by her sister,
former child star, Baby Jane Hudson...
from the family home
on North McCadden in Hollywood...
sometime between the hours of
10... 00 p.m. And 10... 30 p.m. Last evening.
With the exception of one witness...
who reportedly saw the Hudson car,
a 1940 or 1941 black convertible...
heading west on Wilshire
and Santa Monica...
no report has been received to date
concerning the missing sisters.
- So you found that colored woman.
- They found her, all right.
Sure is a rotten way
to get your picture in the papers.
You reckon you'll find that Baby Jane,
or whatever her name is?
Sure, we'll find her.
But I guess maybe it'll be too late.
Officer, there's a car down there
parked right out in the road.
I almost got stuck in the sand
when I tried to get around it.
- You mean that old Lincoln convertible?
- That's right.
That was parked there
when we opened up this morning.
The keys are there, but I didn't
want to move it. I thought maybe...
What do you figure?
Cops. How do you figure cops?
This is it.
You must be hot.
Help me.
I'm afraid.
Find someone...
- a doctor.
- I can't.
If I die...
you'll be alone.
But they'll be mean to me,
like they were before.
They'll be kind.
I don't want to hear.
Jane, I'm dying.
There's no time.
You must listen.
I made you...
waste your whole life...
thinking you'd crippled me.
Please stop.
You didn't do it, Jane.
I did it myself.
Don't you understand?
I crippled myself.
You weren't driving that night.
You weren't driving.
You were too drunk.
I wouldn't let you drive.
I made you go open the gates.
I watched you get out of the car.
You'd been so cruel to me at the party.
Imitating me...
making people laugh at me.
I watched you get out of the car.
I wanted to run you down...
crush you.
But you saw the car coming.
I hit the gates.
Snapped my spine.
Then, you mean...
all this time we could've been friends?
You were frightened and ran away.
I managed to crawl out of the car
and up to the gates.
When they found me...
they assumed it was your fault.
You were so drunk and confused.
You didn't know any better.
www.moviesubtitles.org