Dad!
Kids..., Kids...
Jacobs!
Kids' going missing
on Khayelitsha.
People coming do
on it, you know.
Still trying to confirm.
Any way.
Hi, Dan.
Where is it?
At Botanical gardens.
I will drop the boys off school
and I arrived right there...
Tom! Gary!
Hey, are you kidding me?
Go and put on your clothes.
Mom would let me...
Come on boys.
Did you called Brian I've
left several messages.
- Sokhela.
- Hello.
Fletcher? Do you work
in the field now?
I needed to change senior.
You get your money as well.
How long the Around 20.
20 years old.
Died around 2 am, multiple
wounds no bullet.
Melee Weapons No.
Someone beat her to
death with the fists.
Rape?
Sexual intercourse.
Rape, I'll tell you later.
This is what we found on it.
Video club membership card.
Judith...
Botha.
What fucking you doing?
It's me.
Nice meet to you, boy.
- Speak a while...
- Fucking lunatic.
It's not loaded.
What are you doing here?
That is it?
The rest stashed in
the Cayman Islands.
What do you think?
That's we have to go
to Pension Support?
Charles! Your mom is not
exactly act as a student.
She has a new
boyfriend, doesn't she?
Dentist.
Big business!
So he is my Dad now?
And how must I pay for my flat?
Flat?
Yeah, Marjorie and I
are living together.
Marjorie?
Why don't you come
and live here?
You know I got this ass for you.
It's too much traffic
around here.
Do you even know
this one's name?
I know she's got a nice ass.
I stop pass grandpa's grave.
What's going take view of getting
around putting his name on his stone?
Come here!
You look like hell.
Me too I'm glad to see you.
Because she's keeping it's spirits.
She's tougher than she looks.
What about the kids?
I don't think they understand.
When we looks at Mother's hair.
Tom says:
"Mommy's leaves are falling.
Please wait.
He's aged Since the World Cup.
I'll let you do the talking.
Nils Botha?
Hello, sir.
I am the Detective Dan Fletcher from
the serious violent criminal Unit.
And this is Detective
Brian Epkeen.
What's going on here?
Do you know where your
daughter Judith is?
At home, I imagine.
No, she's not at the flat, and
the cell phone does not answer.
Could you...
Could you please give
us her description of
height and
weight...
5 foot 5... (1.68 m)
- What's going on here?
- Something wrong, Nils?
What's going on?
We found the body of a young
woman in botanical gardens.
The body hasn't been
identified yet,
But she had a video
club membership card.
And her name, Judith Botha. Do you know
what your daughter did last night?
Judith and Nicole were
studying for the medium exams.
Nicole?
My daughter. Judith and
Nocole are close friends.
Thank you, Janet.
We, we just got hold that Judith still
on the beach with her boyfriend,
Phone switched off.
She lent her video club card to
her friend Nicole, yesterday.
You could do help, Judith.
Yes, we've done it before.
Nicole told her parents she spending
the night in my place to study,
tetapi pada hakikatnya,
dia keluar.
You know where, with whom?
We weren't see much
nor chat lately.
You are in the same university?
Thanks, Janet.
Yes. She wasn't come
to classes any more.
In the last three months
Something changed.
Like she wasn't the same person.
I can't explain why but...
she's becoming visive.
This is me.
Between.
What's going on?
Everything is alright.
A draping blood pressure.
Nothing too serious.
I was hanging out kids
and with other ladies.
Alongside Khayelitsha.
I got a bit of the flash.
It happens, you know.
You too, Mama.
You are working much too hard,
much too hard!
You know that there is
a child lost in there?
Have you gone to see Adams?
They haven't notice
anything suspect.
Naturally. Nobody cares about
these children, you know.
Mom...
You all shave talks
about you, you know.
Thank you.
Do you see the way
she's looking at you?
Stop.
Ali, she is beautiful!
Mom, stop it.
Ok, Ok. How about
Chicken and dumpling?
Sounds good?
Good.
Former rugby world
champion Stewart Weitz
call the press conference
late this afternoon.
Set the violent crimes lean for
Africa into just another fail of.
Some kind of rust beast raped
and murdered my daughter.
If the police in this country are incapable
offer protecting it's citizens …
Jika polis di negara ini tidak mampu
untuk melindungi rakyatnya...
Please...
Stop it!
Stop them!
Let me go!
Stop.
- Take I.
- Hey, what's going on?
Stop it!
Come on, boy
I just want to see how you are.
Get out of there!
How are you?
You are late.
You exactly you are
hoping to find?
Well, come from
the call we lead.
My daughter was
raped and murdered
by one of these degenerate
that hit the country.
You will find nothing here.
Yeah, but we don't know that
your daughter was raped.
Tick? It is the town of drug.
We are dealing with a rich kid.
Not an abuse.
No, she does.
The medical exam
unfold result of blood
revealed the presence of
ammonia and ephedrine.
We suggest she was using tik.
It possible some one
drugged did the abuser?
She has sexual intercourses,
but she wasn't raped.
A man, the priority
is to find a partner.
Is he the killer?
Or, he'd come forward by now.
It's possible.
But it could be that he just sold her
the Tick and doesn't want the problem.
In any case, we are
looking for him.
- What about the DNA samples.
- Nothing useful there.
- Have you spoken to the Attorney General?
- Three times already.
Nicole Weitz's father called
to complain the cop he chat
up at his place this morning.
Brian is a first-grade
detective. I trust him.
He's a mess.
Ruby!
What are you doing here?
I was just in the
neighborhood for work.
Haven't they fired you?
Lovely place you got.
Is David here?
He is at his girlfriend's.
- Margaret.
- Marjorie, Brian!
And he is studying for
his finals tomorrow.
- He drop in to see me yesterday.
- I heard.
He wanted to get an own flat.
I was thinking...
Since when you have been more
interest David than your cock?
Ever since he started
have a cute girlfriend.
Look...
I thought maybe we
can go 50/50 on it?
Fuck you. Why don't you start paying
me your chance-support by your own?
I am broke. Your dentist is rich and
famous, he can help you as well.
Rick is not going
pay for your son!
Just tell him the price
for bunting you!
Can't we just talk normally?
You are not normal.
I can change.
You?
- It that your car down there?
- Baby!
Me, Brian.
The famous Brian.
You want coming for a drink?
Have a lucky day.
I am sorry.
It's alright
I'm late.
So you remembered!
- Blond.
- I reserve a lot of lovely fantasies anymore!
Turn around.
Please kindly save your trip to the
emergency room before bed time!
All those boys are so violent!
Next time Brian can bring one
of his lady friends around.
What about Ali? When we
can meet his girlfriend?
I do not know.
- He called me a mess?
- And what did you say?
I lied. I said that you
are not total fork up.
Kruger is right.
I am a mess.
- Lot's of Kruger's want to talk.
- Don't start again, Claire.
Must remind you unit C10?
There, during the apartheid.
It was Kruger who
promote me to captain.
That's wonderful. But how many Black
man he killed and tortured Vlakplaas?
Do not tell me he was
one of those bastards.
We decided that we will
go to live together.
The past is the past.
So can we play cards?
Kruger was amnestied.
Of course he is amnestied! Kruger and
all the other murders amnestied!
It's so easy that you pay before
misguide Force of Commission,
You confessed all the
evil degent And presto,
bang, all was forgiven.
Just like that...
Instantly. Absolution
is pendently absurd!
A slage exaggeration,
don't you think?
We were too easy
among us to breaks.
They got we key,
Free as fucking birds.
Prosper than ever as if
nothing had happened.
Would you have preferred?
Retribution?
More death?
Not retribution, Ali.
Justice.
I would prefer justice.
Claire, If there's
one at the table.
Who possibly want to
take revenge? Is Ali.
But it turns out he's...
Strength and intelligence.
To forgive!
"If you want to make peace
With your enemies,."
" Working with your enemies."
" Then they become
your partners ..."
Mandela.
So.
Are you hiding the cards?
We are hiding the cards.
And the girls?
- No even one last beer.
- I got my in my car.
And your car keep
your slitch's wait.
Blonde? Brown? Or both?
I will tell you that tomorrow.
List of the expense judge to Nicole
Weitz credit card over of the past.
Petrol, restaurants, clothes...
Nightclub.
I am Captain Ali Sokhela.
Have you ever seen this girl?
That's the girl who
was killed, right?
Yeah, I saw her on
the newspapers, yes.
That girl was found of
a botanical gardens?
She came several times. She
was here the night she dead.
What did I tell you!
I saw her.
I Knew is her.
She was talking to Zina.
- Zina.
- The girl on the show.
Zina?
Captain Ali Sokhela.
I'm a Serious of
violent crimes Unit.
Oh, there.
Do you recognize her?
You have seen?
I didn't smash her head in, if
that you would have to ask.
They saw you talking to her.
So what were you talking about?
- I'll wait outside.
- Last Wednesday.
She came up to me after
the performance.
We had a drink together.
Was she alone?
She came alone.
She didn't leave alone.
I spent the night with her.
These overprotected kids.
One day or another,
they want to
experiment new things.
And you?
What are you looking for?
- Me.
- Yes.
I like man.
Around 40,
Prefer being black.
But I won't say no to little
treat, from time to time.
Was she in her normal
state, that night?
What do you call " Normal state"
when we making love?
We found drugs,
Tik in her blood.
Were you doing that for her?
That night was clean.
All she had was Loving
potion I had made for her,
From the plants. Iboga.
Do you like to try?
In another life, perhaps.
Nicole came to see me again.
She came to see me at the
club again Last Friday night.
Night of her death.
She wanted to buy Loving
potion I made for her.
She wants to party
with some guy.
I recognized the little drugs
and his name is Stan.
Stan...
That's all I know.
Thank you.
Why don't you sleep over?
Because I do not sleep.
Good night.
Go!
Brian!
What are you doing!
Key is on the kitchen table.
Just Drop in a flower pot.
According to the records
made from herself
Nicole went to the Muizenberg
beach after leaving the club.
It's a lot drug Dealer
goes all over there.
Hey, the Stan, the dancer mention
to you, Didn't you say he dealt?
Yeah, which area is it?
Which area? She might have come by there to
pick him up before her going to the party.
At botanical gardens.
Area 2.
- Who made the pretty picture?
- Janet emailed me that this morning.
Have you notice the name
Janet always calls?
This was an email.
I think she wants your body.
It's just that between a full-time
sport fucker And a humorless workholic
and me. She chose
the nice guy.
Ah, she is in love, Obvious.
It is possible.
For sure.
She wants you, Dan.
Take there, over here.
Have you seen this girl?
Hello, sir.
No, sorry.
I 'll go and check it out.
We are looking for
a man named Stan.
Do not know.
Never heard of him?
Stan,
Mystery man.
Unknown.
And she?
Give me one of those.
Can you give me one those too?
Thanks.
What are you doing around here?
I am looking for a guy.
His name is Stan.
Never heard
Stan is a Tik Dealer.
We told you we don't know.
There has been a murder.
We need to talk to him.
Go!
Don't move!
Do not move, I tell you.
Drop it!
Drop the gun!
Loose!
What do you want?
Do not move!
Listen.
We are looking into a murder of a
young girl in the botanical gardens.
Nothing more. We
want nothing here.
What are you looking for?
- Kneeling.
- Calm!
Fuck nigga!
You are freaking out, right?
Do not freak out.
Listen.
We are just police.
Lifting a hand!
You know what they are
doing to the police?
Do not be silly.
We told you to shut the fuck up!
So why I own a questioning?
'Cause you seem like
an honest girl.
You think so?
I'm always honest, now?
Get your hands up!
Here,
Picnic on chickens,
have you understood?
What do you want?
A chicken wing?
Move!
This asshole, won't listen!
Fuck your dirty mouth
on ground, cop.
Now it is loaded.
Don't be stupid!
You do not understand yet?
Shut!
Cut his hands!
No! No!
Don't do that!
- It's okay, This!
- You bled?
We'll fry the chicken.
No. Do not do that!
Kapten Ali Sokhela.
I need the relief,
Muizenberg beach.
Right away!
Hurry!
Fast!
Little sister? This is Stan.
Stan?
Sorry, Father, I will come.
Stan? What do you do?
If one seeks me say you
do not know where I am.
- But...
- Shouldn't I stay.
What do I do with the other?
For now, do not worry about it.
Make as usual. Pigs.
They will pay you. Ok! Bye.
Where think you are going?
Cat wants to see you.
The guys of the beach...
They not just drug,
Thugs break.
They have bring new weapons,
walk-talkies, night
vision goggles.
They were organized. As if they
were protecting something.
We found this at the beach yard.
Thank you.
Get out of me!
Don't touch me.
It's getting worse and worse.
Cat and his gang control in
this area for 2-3 years ago
I doubt if anyone Deal at Muizenberg
beach, without knowing about it.
It's been a while not see.
Who's your good looking friend?
We want to talk to Cat.
Not here.
A friendly discussion.
I told you he is not here.
Not taking time for my nigga.
I want to talk to him.
Let's... let.
Let him in.
OK, boss.
Captain Ali Sokhela,
Senior of violent crimes Unit.
I think it is my criminal
department here.
I came to talk.
But I can come back accompanied.
And it will not be discussed.
You are here.
Speaking.
A new gang
on the Muizenberg beach.
With a new products.
A rubbish.
A kind of tik.
I am looking for a
boy named Stan.
Do not know Stan. We
do not sell Tick.
- One of my people was killed.
- I know nothing.
Do you recognize this one?
Never seen that ugly mug.
This one?
No more.
Ever notice.
I told your guy
control the area.
He tells me that the
people in your territory
dealing drug, and you
know nothing of it.
And you, you realize anything?
Seems you know more than I know.
I hope that you
told me the truth.
Hey, how's going?
This is the same drug Nicole Weitz
took the night of her death.
It's exactly the same synthetic
methamphetamine cocktail
but when I did further
analysis I discovered
add a couple of
unknown molecule.
With an unknown molecule.
You mean
you do not know all of
the molecule exists?
You can't imagine what's
been invented to new ()LSD.
From... companies are falling along
with themselves just to searching
new molecules that
affects the brain.
For resistance to
fear, pain, fatigue,
suppression traumatic
memories...
I'll buy it.
Those rat inhaled drug
in a short while ago.
Basically after flash
last about 2 to3 minutes,
couples and hierarchical social
go down the drain.
Phase 2 is not quite as pretty.
Apathy,
Loss of sensory bearings,
Antisocial Even
paranoid behavior.
Now look what happens
when increased dosage.
Hysteria, extremely aggressive.
Suicide in past for some.
And when human being take this
shit? The kind of reactions...
Same thing.
All depends the
dose administered.
What about Nicole Weitz?
Considerately might she took,
God only knows...
You know not hold
your man, chatting.
Cam, I said: Only the
kids in the townships.
This son of a bitch Stan
I think he can cut.
Welcome to you.
Hi Rasta.
Stan, you can not spend
your life afraid.
You see my friend here?
Repeat them all.
Everything you told me. All!
Police on a beach
what they want?
What? I can not hear.
For me.
As the cam?
Girls.
What girl?
White . The daughter of rugby.
That one botanical gardens?
You know her?
I have been selling cam.
We slept together.
Why did you kill her, stupid?
- At night, she farted a Lead.
- You have to take her tick?
Too...
She was too busy.
She wanted to get high.
We started kissing
but she started to hit me.
She scratched me. Really crazy!
She crushed my balls.
I freaked out.
Who is it?
Men who pay you.
Do not worry about it.
Must clean the house
from the beach.
And other children's bitch?
Keep it cool. It can
still serve us.
I was not expecting you.
This was the last time.
I will not come back, Maia.
What did I do wrong?
We have an agreement.
Now you are free.
I do not want to be free.
Do not worry.
I will continue to help you.
You found someone else?
Stop it.
You have. You meet
someone else!
A real woman? What
she has I don't?
- Stop.
- Tell me!
- Stop it.
- You fuck her?
- Do you already fucked her.
- Shut up!
He got where it hurts!
You will not become a man,
Small Zulu!
Listening to you!
There you are.
You're almost on time.
Kruger isn't here?
Claire doesn't want anyone
from the department here.
Did you tell Kruger I was
slow dancing with some chick
when you guys were
getting chopped up?
I was in charge of
this operation.
I am the one that agreed to
let Dan investigated with us,
not you.
Do not play the boss with me.
We'll see it.
Here she is . She is here.
Come on, boys.
Stay with Chloe for a little
while, I'll be right there.
Claire...
I wish to thank you both for the
support you gave us when I fell ill.
And anything you did
for Dan at that time.
But I do not want help
from you anymore.
Of any sort. Do you understand?
And I do not want you to
attend cremation ceremony.
I know.
You're sorry.
She needs time.
Something isn't easy to forgive.
Yes, well...
Let's hope she's not as...
breaky as you are.
Hi, Janet.
Dan's wife doesn't want
anyone from the department.
I can stay for a while, anyhow.
Do not worry, I will
give my distance.
As you like. I am going.
Captain!
I took the liberty of checking out
a few things on the Internet.
For around the hut
with where Dan was.
There is nothing except one isolated
house about a half km away.
I tried to find out who
lives there. No one.
The house was sold 8 months ago. The said
agency attends presale never saw the owner.
The entire action
shore cooperation.
And money was transferred from
offshore accounts in Cayman Islands.
If you want, I can try to
find those behind this.
Good work. Thank you very much.
How would you like
to join my team?
Congratulations, Jane.
I hope you don't mind that.
Someday an insomniac Zulu
calling you announced
dispense justice remuneration.
Did you lose something?
Let's just say I am looking.
For what?
I knew that I would be looking.
- You come riding around very often.
- Every morning.
Isn't it?
You know who lives here?
You've seen anyone around?
So are you a policeman?
Depends who's asking.
I saw a 4x4 once.
- When.
- About ten days ago.
What kind?
The big kind, dark.
If I show you pictures would
you recognize the model?
We can always try.
4 o'clock this afternoon,
policical Hall.
Detective Brian Epkeen...
It is an order?
An invitation.
Ok, then I will be there.
Fucking bird.
Good morning.
Do you remember me?
I am looking for kids
They fight another day.
Do you have an idea
where they can be?
- Thanks.
- Sir...
The kid was getting inside...
Never came out.
- Thanks.
- Nothing.
No. It is a big thing,
high on the leggy
very ugly.
That's it.
Are you sure?
I have good eyes.
- What color.
- Green.
The 4x4.
Oh, Black.
- Anything else.
- No. It's too far away.
Sorry, I have to run.
But you will be available
if we need you?
Of course.
How about tonight?
That's it. I saw this
child several times.
It's horrible...
12 years old!
- Suicide? Are you sure?
- We think it's possible side effect.
Some new drugs certainly
near the area.
But the last time I saw him I didn't
make a note that he was on drugs.
What I learn to him, he was
with another kid at his age.
Simon belong to a gang out street
kids all hang out in gang stage.
You had medical files
for the reserve?
Sure, but haven't seen them
in a while. As they vanished.
- You told the police?
- What?
The lost kids.
We must tell them!
Pardon, but the police couldn't
care less about street kids.
And I am been kind
of saying that.
And this is another kid there.
You look awful!
Try to sleep, Ali.
Those kids are disappearing
I'm looking into myself.
Oh, that's right, my son.
If your girlfriends happen
to see one of them...
- Ok.
- I am not ask to mention it to people.
Not finding any municipality.
Do not run, Mom.
Agree?
Why you just say it in my
face that I am sick and old.
Mama...
You're sick and you're old.
Epkeen...
It's not appear Afrikaans' name.
Yeah, Nah.
My father was...
State prosecutor
during apartheid.
Member of the National's Party.
Religions, you know.
Pure and hard.
So, I took my Mama's name
when I've turned 17.
How many you want?
- Three.
- Three?
You make me hungry.
- Was a good trip.
- No. Miserable.
Five hours later in Airport
Zurich is under snow.
But it was worth it. They
are very interested.
- How?
- 40.
For Health.
When the trunk will
be in Zurich...
We must act quickly. One
police found a house.
You have it all cleaned up?
Yes.
In 2 or 3 days, everything
will be finished.
In the meantime, we
will give police hull.
Shit.
Sleep well?
I have to run.
I completely forgot it's my turn
to drop the kids to nurses.
- Kids? I don't think you have kids.
- I don't . My boyfriend does.
Hey! I'm waiting there!
I'm here.
I know, I know, bullshit.
Kate Montgomery. A jogger,
found her this morning
6: 30.
She lives up here,
In the houses with
her father, Tony.
Tony Montgomery...
A singer?
Yes. We havn't been
able to look it in yet.
Another student?
No, costumes system
in the movies.
You couldn't introduce me
to a girl live for change?
What do we have here?
At first glance, looks like
might have some procedure
same as Nicole Weitz, but...
She put on fight.
It leaves him no chance.
I want the DNA result today.
Do my best.
But, still something new...
B... Z... K...
" Bazokhala ."
" Bazokhala "?
Zulu war cry.
This means that...
" We will make them cry."
I told her was proof.
Did she running on the
beach every morning?
She is a...
She was a healthy fleetly girl,
Perfect normal.
Nicole Weitz's father said too.
Think it could be
the same killer.
Hey, this is David.
I was not in.
At 99.9 % match the DNA hair
found on the victim's hand.
Stan Kwalana, 32 years old.
Drug dealing,
robbery, voilence...
Zulu?
It says that he's colored.
But his certainly had
name is Zuluish.
Dad must be Zulu, his mother
colored. But... I am just guessing.
Are you... into my terms
of by for that me now.
Let me guess you happen
to be in this area?
I am in charge of investigating
Kate Montgomery's death.
She recently worked as a
star on video apparently.
On where you came up
production assistant.
Three months ago, and...
I am trying to piece together
of her personality perform.
It's bullshit.
- And I am the one you come see.
- Her death doesn't seem to bother you.
I barely knew the girl.
Ruby,
Did you answer my questions?
Go ahead, detective.
When did you see Kate
for the last time?
That's enough, Brian, this
is really ridiculous.
To the best of your acknowledge.
Was she taking drugs?
How on earth could I know?
Drugs and showbiz are exactly
all together, isn't it?
- I do not work in showbiz.
- No.
But what do dentist with stars,
you should be invisted to
center lating dinner parties,
with DV news readers, Top
models... I do not know.
You're not getting
any better with age.
Someone who claimed
they hated vulgarity...
Did David pass his exam?
- Call him and you will find out.
- He won't answer my calls.
Top of his class, Brian.
And learn look approud of inspect
whatever, Not thanks to you.
Is there anything else you can tell
me about Kate Montgomery, Miss?
" Mrs.".
Rick and I are getting married.
And here.
You never learnt, ehm?
Still g hunting
guys fuck around.
The screw over to you.
Fuck you!
Who do you think you are?
Asshole.
Hi, Ricky boy.
You bastard!
Have a larkish swim!
Where are you?
Nowhere special.
- Why.
- Someone send us a present.
- You need me.
- Yes!
Found in the trash
containers of the.
Police Station.
Well, we found Stan.
Claw marks.
Don't you think it's
too good to be true?
This head which leads
us on the tray...
Stan is illiterate.
He couldn't even
write his own name.
And he's get kids writing
on young girls' corpses?
I don't think so.
You can not...
Quiet!
You don't like my gift?
I hear about your
friend on beach.
Do not tell me you
know how to read.
I got girls read for me...
- Do you know something about literature?
- I have the Holy Bible on my ass.
Where you found?
These bastards, catch them all.
Any other, where are they?
On the other way!
Are you alright?
Move, move!
Move out the way!
He's fine.
Is he? Where is he?
The man who kill Nicole
Weitz and Kate Montgomery
has been positively
identified by DNA.
Stan Kwalana was a known drug
dealer as far as we know
did not belong to any extremist
political organization
I wish to stress the fact.
That our police force
did a remarkable job.
Couple of days rest
of me, on it's feet.
Did you find anything?
There're only two 4x4s at
this type in the area.
One belongs to a 77 year
old man who only takes as
a good art.
And the other, belongs to a
private security company,
DPS.
- Epkeen, come with me. I want to talk
to you - As soon as I finished it.
Did you verify whether the company has a
home security contract for the beach house?
Did you heard the
investigation is over?
- Doesn't the body you kill was illiterate.
- Should he?
How could Stan written
" bazokhala "?
The girl has his hair in her
hand, and we have the DNA.
Set up.
Won't you have be that for
once you did a good job?
Is the company has a home contract
surveillance for beach home?
I forbid you answer that!
Rick Van Der Verkuizen wait a
pleasing file charges against you.
So We're waiting for you to appear
in court, I am suspending you.
Sehingga anda menghabiskan di hadapan
hakim, saya menggantung anda.
In other words, get out! Now!
You're a shit, Kruger.
An ass the Fucking
piece of shit!
Fuck you, Epkeen!
Fuck you!
Hi!
What the holly you doing here?
Marjorie?
Brian. Father of...
Good evening, sir.
How did you find where I was?
I am a cop. I heard
about your exams.
I wanna take you congratulate.
- And you get a celebrate?
- I hope so!
I am going to wait you inside.
Bye, sir.
Good manners, eh?
She seems nice.
Mom said you came
around ass her.
You are jealous, isn't that?
Of what?
Sleeping with the dention-King?
I do not think so.
You leave mama alone.
You've done enough hurt of this.
For the deposit on your flat,
and for being a shit Dad.
Detective...
Detective!
Sorry.
Hi, Jane.
I checked for the
security company.
You know, DPS, the
security company?
Woo, woo Wait a second.
Look, I am listening.
DPS
The security company,
Officially, there is no
contract for the beach house.
But I took liberty of hacking
DPS's computer systems.
Over the past 6 months.
The offshore companies
that own the house.
Paid of three million
rand to DPS!
Shit...
enough monitor and
drugs in the houses.
In the DPS's cunstom files.
It is South African
cellphone number
that listed full of
the offshore company.
Dr Joost Opperman. It's the
cellphone number belongs to him.
- What kind of doctor.
- A geeky researcher.
A genius molecular
chemistry founder creak.
Opperman.
Type " Opperman, Project Coast..."
That's it.
The Bastards who are
part of Beach project.
You haven't heard about it?
You are too young.
A nut.
A secret project. Scientists and
medical officers by the regime
to develop chemical weapons
virus, this kind of shit.
Anything can come up prevent
blacks increase any number.
Dr Opperman.
Testify before the Truth and
Reconciliation Commision.
Of course.
Government gave us carte blanch.
We have 200 scientists.
Our mission is to develop
might calling...
ethnic bomb.
Could you be more specific?
A chemical weapons.
A molecule capable to desolating
the black population.
But I was following the Chain of
command by orders from my top.
Not my place to question them.
These girls
is.
Just the tip of the iceberg.
Opperman has developed molecules
that makes people go crazy
and was stashed in dark.
He use Cat's gang to dumped it off
from streets in the town shop?
That would explain why
Kids are disappearing.
They must kill each
other or themselves.
And the youth you
find in the pipe.
Yeah, but what about
Nicole Weitz?
Probably not part of the plan.
The beach house was their
lab, Stan was watching over.
He must has taken
advantage of the seller.
In most of the bright ideas to sell
tick to white kids on the side.
Where is this Dr. Opperman?
He left the country after
remit by the commission.
It's like he
vanishes in the air.
If you like, I can try to
track his bank account.
My friend Kruger's
lock the same.
As well, we will not
go to tell him.
Didn't you have an
operation last night?
Go and check out the
security company.
What the fuck you doing?
I am going to see Cat.
We leave tonight.
I need you clean everything.
And do not forget
the girl for pigs.
Fucking psychopath.
Mom?
Hello, Ali, are you alright?
Are you feeling better?
Do not worry, I am a true Zulu.
What's that noise?
They just open the
window of my room.
- You must be careful of...
- Draft.
Yes.
I know.
You know, one of my
friend Mahimbo...
She thinks she saw one of
your kids, about a week ago.
Where?
Near the Lengezi church.
There is a girl there
the minist of priests,
holding the soup kitchen for
the poor in this neighborhood.
She's been in contact
with these kids.
Does not make you tired, Mom.
Do not forget that
I also a Zulu.
As much as you!
I know.
Yes, Janet.
Guess who is in charge of the
logistics of Project Coast?
The young officer,
name Frank Debeer.
Who is now the owner
of DPS Company.
Looking for something?
Hello, Brian? Can you hear me?
Thank you, Janet.
Is this vehicle yours?
Belongs the company.
Are you the owner, Mr...?
Debeer. Yes, I am. Why?
Do you use it often?
Use for around! I asked you why!
I am asking you. To
change of tone of voice.
This is a security agency not
a tourist information centre.
I am investigating
a car accident.
A 4x4 lucky was
involved a passerby.
I am the only one use it.
You keep it cleaned. 'Em?
It is against the law?
Can I take a look?
Thank you for your cooperation.
It's good to another's still
honest citizens like yourself,
in this criminals
messed of the country.
Get out of here!
Go back to Shebeen?
Yeah! I want to bring
Cat for questioning.
You want get us killed? Last
time wasn't enough for you?
Round up your men.
Round them up!
Didn't you heard?
The investigation is over.
Go and rest.
Yes?
Who are they?
Did you lose them?
Don't take any ris.
Don't forget you are talking to a
man that was suspended, anyhow.
Ok.
Come on!
Knock, knock!
Any one home?
Miss!
Good morning. What are
you doing here, old Mam?
Come on, man!
Back in your car, hands on the
steering wheel, and the door opened.
You're early, Dave...
Shhh!
See, there is a
good looking one.
Where is Cat?
He cleaned up shop
before leaving.
We won't be seen him around.
You just seen?
It can be peace,
they won't talk.
And you?
I'm not fool.
I know, that crazy. I stashed.
Besides will never on talk.
You know where he is?
This is not a nigga that would
scare me. You're so clean you.
You are drunk!
You are risking being the rape?
What is the address?
Dr Joost Opperman,
February 2nd, 2012.
I'm resuming my research within
the Paramentize of Project Coast,
But was very
different objective.
8 Februari 2012.
Phase 1 of the MAO
clinical trial.
Opperman have received with the
bank transfer for months now.
Opperman menerima pemindahan
tetap untuk beberapa bulan.
Like salary.
Yeah, but who's paying him?
Two seconds.
Dr Joost Opperman,
March 17th, 2012
in order to find out the proper
methods to avoid Side effects,
we developed clinical curtical
tobe tested on humans,
The young population with loyalty
were frasted through Tik addiction.
After long bury
of trial and ever
guilty suicidal reactions or
normally aggressive behavior
we are able to confirm today
the test was conclusive.
Bingo. Covence from Sutigos...
This molecules will enable us to develop a
new medicinal product for revolutionize of.
A new medicinal that will
treat all forms of depression
with no side effects.
This medication that
making us blockbuster.
- Watcha.
- Yes, sir.
Good evening, sir.
- What church is that?
- Lengezi.
It's a mass grave, with
children and teenagers.
Bodies been eaten by the pigs.
Beasts...
How do you find this place?
The Minister found maid was
murdered, with another woman.
Is it here?
- Brian.
- Ruby.
You have to come now!
Who are these guy?
Ruby!
Listen to me,
detective by the hot.
Get over to your ex-wife's place
on the double with hard disk,
And everything you
stole from my office.
If you are not here in 20 min, I
am starting having fun with her.
She has a nice ass.
You piece of shit. You
fucking touch her...
Where is Cat?
Ali! Call me back, Fuck sick!
Ruby!
Brian!
Sit.
Stop it!
Search him.
In my back pocket.
Did you make a copy?
I do not have time, Your fuck.
Drop and listening.
Fuck you!
Are you crazy!
- You are sick.
- Be quiet, please.
What's the use of a
gun, if it not loaded?
You're going to kill us, aren't you?
We've got nothing to do with him!
He's an asshole.
I'm sure we can
find an agreement.
I have money. Lots of money.
What is your suggest?
How much do you want?
Give me a price.
I am paying you.
Two million for you.
I still need her.
Three million, for
the two of us.
Four.
Two million. And
I'll let you go.
Don't you leave me, Rick?
Why are you going
to with such a man?
This is your fault!
Shit!
Let me have my computer, I'll
transfer money right away.
You fucking break.
- You'll be Ok.
- You mother fucker.
You can everything
in a computer now.
It's... It's amazing efficient
Jesses Christ Brian, what
are these fucking animals?
Do not worry.
- I'll set you free.
- Where is the way
I want them to think it's
a effect of jealousy
I'll take care of the trunks.
We'll meet at the airfield.
Your ankle is untied. You could
make to the next start, right?
Oh yeah?
And to get out, I 'll put
myself. We are locked in!
- I 'll deal with that.
- How?
Don't tell me you
forgot how hard did I?
Such a dick.
Hell on the deal smash
with your head?
No brain no pain. eh?
You didn't get any
better with age.
I probably won't.
Get better with age.
But I always love
you, you bitch.
Fuck you.
- Brian.
- Run!
Run, you bastard!
What the fuck you doing?
- Fucker of bitch.
- Do you fucking touch!
- You gonna watch this!
- Ruby!
I'll fucking kill you, bitch!
Come here.
I'll show you, bitch.
Fucking bitch!
I'll show you, bitch!
I am sorry.
Klaasens Jalan Bishopscourt.
Do not forget the ambulance.
You know where Ali is?
He's been unreachable
all morning.
The last time I talk to him is last
night, he asked Some information about
a farm in Namibia.
- You look worse than usual.
- I will tell you.
What are you doing here?
I spoke to Janet.
Can I take a look?
We got everything
to lock them up.
Opperman, the lab...
Ali! Are you listening to me?
It won't bring them back.
Your mother, Dan, and
all the others...
It won't bring them back.
Fucker, do you hear me?
Not this way.
Not you.
Don't you dare give me lessons!
I know this shit by heart.
I've been recited for 40 years!
Brian, Let go my weapon.
- Loose.
- Not this way.
Loose!
What are you doing
here, you dirt...
Mister Ali, you're not
going to shoot me?
Motherfucker, there is the
other white. He is the devil.
Please not do that.
Just saying...
I made a copy.
Please...
Forgive me, please.
I see something, Two o'clock.
Thanks.
If I take a second stand
and grave as well.
Someone else died?
A few years ago.
It's taken me a
while to arouded.